<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-06-19T12:32:02Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-53" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I would like to start this week’s column by paying tribute to the victims of the attack that occurred in Nottingham. Three horrific murders took place and several families have lost their loved ones. It was an incredibly dark day for our city, and I don’t think the people of Nottinghamshire will…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-53</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Doncaster Royal Infirmary opens specialist bereavement suite</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/doncaster-royal-infirmary-opens-specialist-bereavement-suite" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A specialist facility dedicated to providing solace and support for families navigating the heart-breaking journey of baby loss has opened on Thursday 15 June at Doncaster Royal Infirmary (DRI).
The Serenity Suite aims to provide a private and comforting environment where families can find solace,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/doncaster-royal-infirmary-opens-specialist-bereavement-suite</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recognising the value of small charities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/recognising-value-small-charities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP is celebrating the work of charities that provide vital support to local communities in Buckinghamshire as part of Small Charity Week 19 – 23 June.
During the Covid-19 pandemic and the ongoing cost-of-living crisis, small charities have been the lifeblood of communities in England.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/recognising-value-small-charities</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-204" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Procurement Bill completed its remaining stages in the House of Commons on Tuesday before the Bill was sent back to the Lords for consideration of the changes that the House of Commons has made. The Bill will establish a set of transformative new rules which rip up bureaucratic EU regulations…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-204</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz speaks in debate about the importance of hospices]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-in-debate-about-the-importance-of-hospices/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=13042</id>
		<updated>2023-06-19T10:51:30Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-19T10:51:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I spoke in a Westminster Hall debate on the importance of hospices. MPs from all parties shared deeply personal stories of how hospices have cared for their loved ones so well, and comforted their family and friends at such a difficult time. &#160; I responded on behalf of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-in-debate-about-the-importance-of-hospices/">Liz speaks in debate about the importance of hospices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-in-debate-about-the-importance-of-hospices/"><![CDATA[<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-13042-1" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WHD-Hospices-14.06.23-Uncompressed-2.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WHD-Hospices-14.06.23-Uncompressed-2.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WHD-Hospices-14.06.23-Uncompressed-2.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Yesterday I spoke in a Westminster Hall debate on the importance of hospices.</p>
<p>MPs from all parties shared deeply personal stories of how hospices have cared for their loved ones so well, and comforted their family and friends at such a difficult time. &nbsp;</p>
<p>I responded on behalf of the Labour Party, talking about the importance of a ‘good death’ and the support hospices need to make this a reality for those in their care. You can read my full speech&nbsp;<a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-14/debates/F64AC72C-608E-4E5A-B859-2BC3B86BD4C9/details#contribution-DA72AB33-6CEE-40A6-95DB-8EB62D551B64">here</a>, and see a clip above.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-in-debate-about-the-importance-of-hospices/">Liz speaks in debate about the importance of hospices</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/WHD-Hospices-14.06.23-Uncompressed-2.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="23116052" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Written Answers from the Department for Energy Security and Net Zero – number of electric cars</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/06/19/written-answers-from-the-department-for-energy-security-and-net-zero-number-of-electric-cars/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;I thought more EVs were tge big aim yet no forecasts offered. Need to evaluate the success of all the subsidies and EV promotion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;Department for Business and Trade provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (187012):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;Question:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To ask the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, what estimate the Government has made of the potential maximum number of electric cars the UK will be able to produce in (a) two and (b) five years time. (187012) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;Tabled on: 02 June 2023&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;Answer:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Ms Nusrat Ghani&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;This information is commercially sensitive to companies and not held centrally.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"&gt;The answer was submitted on 09 Jun 2023 at 12:03.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I thought more EVs were tge big aim yet no forecasts offered. Need to evaluate the success of all the subsidies and EV promotion.   Department for Business and Trade provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (187012): Question: To ask the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, what estimate the Government…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=35345</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T04:00:50Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T04:00:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Welcomes Government Funding to Boost Skills Training</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-welcomes-government-funding-boost-skills-training" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has welcomed the Government’s £48 million investment through the Skills Investment Fund, boosting the rollout of Higher Technical Qualifications (HTQs) and equipping students from all backgrounds with the high-quality, higher-level skills needed to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-welcomes-government-funding-boost-skills-training</id>
    <published>2023-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support for Elswick Swimming Pool</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/06/support-for-elswick-swimming-pool/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ElswickPool?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ElswickPool&lt;/a&gt; is a vital enabler of mental and physical health for communities in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Newcastle?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Newcastle&lt;/a&gt;. ????????&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like many leisure centres, they’re struggling to make ends meet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tory Minister claims money is available but our pool in Elswick has not received any&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2b07.png" alt="⬇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/UP1lhuWRoH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/UP1lhuWRoH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah ???? (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1669349686946439172?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 15, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chi Onwurah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elswick swimming pool is a wonderful enabler of physical and mental health, serving communities who have some of the highest levels of deprivation and health inequalities in the country. It could do more if social prescribing were enabled, but instead, it faces an absolute crisis because of rising energy costs and the cost of living crisis hitting income. The Minister says that money is available, but it has received none. Can he tell me what he is doing to ensure that Elswick swimming pool survives and thrives?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-15/debates/BADBAB8F-8E33-4A53-A68D-06554607B9A4/SwimmingPoolsLeisureCentresAndSportsGrounds#contribution-7A0DFB73-C685-4D1B-BAFF-7D3717C3987A"&gt;https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-15/debates/BADBAB8F-8E33-4A53-A68D-06554607B9A4/SwimmingPoolsLeisureCentresAndSportsGrounds#contribution-7A0DFB73-C685-4D1B-BAFF-7D3717C3987A&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">.@ElswickPool is a vital enabler of mental and physical health for communities in #Newcastle. ???????? But like many leisure centres, they’re struggling to make ends meet. The Tory Minister claims money is available but our pool in Elswick has not… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13636</id>
    <published>2023-06-17T13:36:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-17T13:36:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Barnehurst Ward Coffee Morning</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/barnehurst-ward-coffee-morning" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Saturday 17th June, Barnehurst Ward held a Coffee Morning at Anne Rawlings House. 
The event was attended by Rt Hon Sir David Evennett and Ward Councillors Brian Bishop and Howard Jackson.
 
 </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/barnehurst-ward-coffee-morning</id>
    <published>2023-06-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-94/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">My week in Westminster began at the <a title="https://endchildpoverty.org.uk/child-poverty/" href="https://endchildpoverty.org.uk/child-poverty/">End Child Poverty Coalition</a> event to discuss new research by Loughborough University, which found that more than one-in-five children in Welsh Local Authorities live in poverty. The rates are highest in Blaenau Gwent (30.3%) and Ceredigion (30%), and lowest in Monmouthshire (21.4%), but even this is more than one in five. I have been a member of the <a title="https://www.bevanfoundation.org/" href="https://www.bevanfoundation.org/">Bevan Foundation</a> for many years, and its Head of Policy, Dr Stefan Evans, said that the research shows that this is a problem in all Welsh communities and should be viewed as a national problem, not an urban/rural or a valleys/cities problem. Across Wales, 27.9% of children live in poverty after housing costs, and before housing costs a staggering 79.8% of children living in poverty live in working households. At UK level, the Coalition is calling for the two-child limit on Universal Credit to be scrapped because of the proven link between this policy and poverty rates in larger families. I have signed <a title="https://edm.parliament.uk/early-day-motion/60973/end-child-poverty-coalition-all-kids-count-campaign" href="https://edm.parliament.uk/early-day-motion/60973/end-child-poverty-coalition-all-kids-count-campaign">EDM 1238</a>, started by Kim Johnson MP, which calls on the Department for Work and Pensions to repeal the two-child limit for all benefits payments.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The <a title="https://www.neural.org.uk/" href="https://www.neural.org.uk/">Neurological Alliance</a> held its “Back the 1-in-6” Campaign event in Parliament of which I am a determined supporter. The “My Neuro Survey” found that on average 12,000 people in an England constituency, 11,000 in Scotland or Northern Ireland constituency, and 9,000 in a Wales constituency live with a neurological condition. The campaign calls on governments to set up a Neuro Taskforce to deliver change through addressing heath and care workforce shortages, by providing a framework to support collaboration and sharing best practice, which occurred in the Older People’s Housing Taskforce, and the Rare Diseases Framework. The campaign is requesting the UK Government Minister for Health, Helen Whately MP, to meet with the Coalition.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I was honoured to be re-elected vice chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Industrial Heritage at its AGM. It was an evidence session for the APPG inquiry into the challenges facing preserving heritage buildings, and we heard from speakers Richard McDonald, Senior Regeneration Officer at Wigan Council; Dr Joanna O’Hara, Somerset Council; and Niall Murphy, Glasgow City Council. They highlighted the danger that heritage is at risk, and the importance of social community values, identity, family connections, climate crisis, which extend from old mills and factories, local housing, to water courses. There are legislative challenges, in that the Town and Country Planning Act was enacted in 1990, so is outdated; VAT is 20% for refurbishment, but zero for new builds; and there’s a business rate exemption for empty buildings which completely contradicts attempts to bring back empty heritage buildings into use. There is an ongoing issue with broadening qualifications to include traditional industrial heritage skills, for example architecture, surveyors, tradespeople do not have the skills necessary to work in the industrial heritage sector, and many apprenticeships do not include traditional skills. There needs to be heritage education from primary schools through to lifelong learning.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a long-time supporter of people with Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD), I attended Takeda’s parliamentary event celebrating best practice across the UK and exploring the future of IBD care. The event brought together national policymakers, clinical leaders, and patient representatives to celebrate success stories from around the UK where improvements to IBD care and NHS services are being spearheaded by clinicians, discuss what more support can be given, and tackle socioeconomic and geographical disparities. Takeda is committed to putting the patient first and support several education and awareness raising GI programmes. Please download the “<a title="https://www.ittakesguts.org.uk/share/in-my-shoes-app" href="https://www.ittakesguts.org.uk/share/in-my-shoes-app">In My Shoes</a>” App developed by Crohn’s &amp; Colitis UK and visit <a title="https://www.takeda.com/" href="https://www.takeda.com/">Takeda</a> to experience what life is like living with IBD.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended a confidential meeting of the Ukraine APPG with Ukraine Civil Leaders who are in the UK to meet representatives from Parliament, charities and civil society to give detailed briefings on the extent of the destruction that Putin has inflicted on the people in communities in Ukraine, and the vast sums of money needed to rebuild its infrastructure and society. The Institute of Legislative Ideas (ILI) has produced a “Compensation Road Map”. ILI is an independent legal think tank working in the field of anti-corruption policy in co-operation with public and civil partners. For seven years it has worked on anti-corruption legislation proofing, corruption risk assessment, non-conviction forfeiture and asset recovery. Compensation of damages to Ukraine through Russian aggression would include: Russian Federation assets, private Russian individuals assets involved in the conflict. The ILI estimates Ukraine’s losses from the war are £411bn plus flood damage caused by the dam destruction; frozen assets of RF and its accomplices at £397bn, but after 15 months of war only £12m assets have been confiscated, and 99% of this amount by Ukraine. But the damage increases every hour: 75,000 residential buildings; 2,500 educational institutions; 500 hospitals; 100 energy infrastructure facilities; and 400 cultural and 120 religious buildings. The ILI recommends 5 steps to enable compensation for damage: auditing all Russian assets and synchronise all data; criminalisation of sanctions evasion; improvement and new civil procedures for confiscation of assets of war collaborators; effective management of frozen assets; and global compensation mechanism through a multilateral international agreement. 43 countries have signed an agreement to create a register of Ukraine’s losses from Russian aggression, for an initial three years, located in The Hague. The EU has mobilised more than €200bn euros in Russian Bank assets since the war began, but it is unclear whether this will be used to rebuild war hit Ukraine.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended the launch of Dan Cardan MP’s <a title="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-06/debates/26AF1B7E-0BCC-4490-9721-435E3029AFB6/CareSupporters" href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-06/debates/26AF1B7E-0BCC-4490-9721-435E3029AFB6/CareSupporters">Ten Minute Rule Bill</a>, which advocates maintaining the right to contact in care settings in England. We heard from people who have suffered when they were denied contact in hospitals and care settings. Dan has worked with Tracey Crouch MP, Daisy Cooper MP, and Liz Saville-Roberts MP to create a Bill that would allow an essential care supporter to have ability to maintain contact with close relatives and friends in care settings. Rights for Residents, John’s Campaign, and Residents and Relatives Association fully support the Bill. Support is not an optional extra, and is absolutely vital for dignified care. It must be recognised in law, and I was in the Chamber to listen to Dan introduce the Bill.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">There were two <a title="https://apdawg.co.uk/" href="https://apdawg.co.uk/">All-Party Dog Advisory Welfare Group</a> (APDAWG) events in Parliament this week. I was proud to be re-elected a vice-chair at the AGM of the APDAWG with Dr Marc Abraham re-elected as chair. Marc laid out the next twelve month’s important activity including working with parliamentary colleagues and government to provide solutions to reduce the number of dog attacks in the UK. This issue and many other issues affecting dog welfare, such as illegal breeding and puppy imports, greyhound racing, illegal ear lopping, and puppies bred to design, affects all our constituents, whether dog owners or not, and there is cross-party support for dog welfare and human health, and we need to make the necessary changes to improve these matters without delay.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The APDAWG also held its #DogBiteReform third evidence session on its enquiry “Dog Bite Problem”. Wayne David MP’s constituent Emma Whitfield, mother of Jack Lis who was tragically mauled by an American XL Bully, gave video evidence and we heard from a panel of experts in the room, including experts from canine, human, and forensic fields. We discussed possible practical, workable, and efficient solutions to reducing dog bite attacks and fatalities in the UK, including dog licensing, improved dog bite education in schools, regulation of dog trainers and behaviourists, centralising the microchip database, and much more.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended the Active Travel event hosted by <a title="https://www.brompton.com/" href="https://www.brompton.com/">Brompton Bikes</a> and met its managing director Julian Scriven. There were other stakeholders present and we all spoke about the benefits of active travel, but that the impact of UK Government cuts has severely set back progress on sustainable modes of transport across the UK. In March 2023, UK Government announced a funding cut of £200 million to the active travel budget in England which will undermine progress to ensure people can access cycling and its economic, social, and environmental benefits, a will make it impossible to reach UK Government net zero targets. Brompton Bikes was created in 1975 by Andrew Richie who wanted an easy way to travel around cities. Brompton now exports to 47 countries and are the biggest manufacturer of bikes in the UK employing over 800 in their Greenford factory where all bikes are made by hand. In 2011, Brompton Bike Hire was set up, and data shows that one in four people who hire a Brompton go on to buy one within 12 months, so change to active travel. It is crucial that people who want to cycle are given the support and opportunity to do so, and funding for cycle infrastructure is vital.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I dropped into the <a title="https://wearetempo.org/" href="https://wearetempo.org/">Tempo Time Credits</a> event to learn about the Tempo project that provides a platform for businesses and organisations to recognise and reward the invaluable work of a volunteer. Tempo’s vision is to help generate resilience in communities, from the bottom up, giving those on the outskirts of society the opportunity to show their value through volunteering and rewarding them for it. The Time Credits Programmes are uniquely designed not only to ensure that volunteers feel valued for contributing even the smallest amounts of time but also to enable people to have their time valued in ways that are meaningful to them.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As chair of the APPG for Sepsis I met with <a title="https://sepsistrust.org/" href="https://sepsistrust.org/">UK Sepsis Trust</a>, and the APPG secretariat, to make plans for events to promote World Sepsis Day, which is on 13th September.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a vice-chair of the Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) APPG, chaired by John Howell MP, I attended a meeting to discuss Ombudsmen. We heard from ombudsmen about their role in the dispute resolution landscape in the UK and how should different organisational mechanisms (public and private), internal complaints procedures, ombudsmen services, and pre and post legal issue dispute resolution processes fit together. The meeting was organised by <a title="https://www.ciarb.org/" href="https://www.ciarb.org/">CIArb</a> who act as secretariat for the APPG for ADR.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I met some amazing young carers who had made their first journey to Westminster to speak to members of the APPG for Young Carers and Young Adult Carers. It was an absolute pleasure to meet these wonderful young adults who care for members of their families. To mark <a title="https://www.carersweek.org/" href="https://www.carersweek.org/">Carers Week 2023</a>, the APPG has launched its first ever parliamentary inquiry focused specifically on young carers and young adult carers. The inquiry will explore the impact of caring on life opportunities for young carers and will recommend what the UK Government and other partners should do to help the life chances of young carers and young adult carers. The inquiry is supported by 11 youth advisers, including two inquiry co-chairs, from across England and the secretariat is Carers’ Trust. The online call for evidence was opened at the event and it closes on 23rd July. The deadline for evidence from young carers will close on 31st August. There will be evidence hearings in September and the report will be published in November.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">There was a vote to approve the Committee on Standards motion report on Margaret Ferrier MP, which was carried by 185 to 40 votes.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended an event about the importance of clean air in our communities organised by Afzal Khan MP for Manchester Gorton, which featured a <a title="https://www.afzalkhan.org.uk/news/2020/11/10/have-your-say-on-the-greater-manchester-clean-air-plan-now/" href="https://www.afzalkhan.org.uk/news/2020/11/10/have-your-say-on-the-greater-manchester-clean-air-plan-now/">short film</a> made by GPs and people from his constituency.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I was honoured to be re-elected a vice-chair at the AGM of the APPG for No Recourse to Public Funds (NRPF). Kate Osamor MP was re-elected chair. After the AGM we had a confidential discussion about “Domestic Abuse and NRPF – how can we increase protections for migrant women?” Speakers included from Latin American Women’s Rights Service, Elizabeth Jimenez-Yanez; Asmita Sood from Southall Black Sisters (SBS); Apsana Begum MP, chair of APPG on Domestic Violence and Abuse; and speakers with lived experience of Domestic Abuse and NRPF.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To celebrate World Oceans Day, I attended the <a title="http://thewi.org.u.k./endplasticsoup" href="http://thewi.org.u.k./endplasticsoup">Women’s Institute</a> (WI) and Marine Conservation Society event to tackle micro plastic pollution. Micro plastics are plastic particles of 5mm or smaller and can enter the environment from synthetic textiles, tyre and brake wear, City dust and plastic hurdle spillage. Once in the environment they are extremely difficult to remove and have been found in human food chains, biodiversity and wildlife, human blood, lungs, and affect health of human cells. However, this can be reduced by: fibre capture washing machine filters; and tyrewear. Alberto Costa MP has introduced a “Microplastic Filters (Washing Machine) Bill” which I support. It would require all washing machines in UK from 2025 to be fitted with microplastic fibre capture filters which capture fibres before they travel to wastewater treatment plants, and receives its Second Reading on 23rd November 2023. The WI’s End Plastic Soup campaign began in 2017, and its “In a Spin” report found at least 9.4 trillion micro plastics were released through the domestic washing process every week, and the WI became the secretariat to the APPG on Microplastics in 2020. In 2021 they published a report including six holistic recommendations informed by 20 relevant stakeholders to tackle microplastics in UK. The WI Wash Clothes Well: only wash clothes when needed; fill washing machine to maximum which produces less friction between clothes; low temperature helps reduce microplastic fibres and CO2 emissions; do not flush dryer lint down the drain, put in bin; avoid sensitive wash cycles.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended the Carers UK Week event and met some amazing adult carers. We heard from AgeUK, Carers Trust, Carers UK, MNDA, Oxfam, Rethink Mental Illness, and the Lewy Body Society. <a title="http://carersweek.org/2023report" href="http://carersweek.org/2023report">Research from these stakeholders has found</a> that millions of people in the UK are providing unpaid care or support to a family member, friend or neighbour. The value of the unpaid care is a staggering £162bn per annum. 50% of the public have provided unpaid care, 75% of people who provide unpaid care do not identify themselves as a career, 20% of people over 65 are caring. These stakeholders are calling on UK Government to: establish a cross-departmental Ministerial Group to better identify unpaid carers, and ensure they get support; deliver an England national strategy, and deliver existing plans in Wales, Scotland and Northern Ireland; improve NHS legislation to place a duty on NHS to identify carers and promote their health and wellbeing; improve funding of social care, review Carers Allowance, implement the Carers Leave Act and enhance rights to flexible working.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I attended the launch of Emma Lewell-Buck MP’s Healthy Start Scheme (Take Up) Bill which, she presented in the Chamber on 14th June. The Bill would ensure that families eligible for this scheme are automatically registered to receive it. The scheme is a lifeline for many pregnant women and families with young children providing access to fruit, vegetables, milk and vitamins which helps children get the best start in life. Uptake in England is only 64%. <a title="https://www.sustainweb.org/childrens-food-campaign/" href="https://www.sustainweb.org/childrens-food-campaign/">Sustain</a> estimate that 200,000 families are missing out on £68 million pounds of nutritious food. In Wales there will be an estimated cash shortfall of £2,481,681 in 2023. The Department for Health and Social Care knows which families are missing out but is failing to come up with a solution. Emma’s Bill would widen take up but allow families to opt out if they wish.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><a title="https://www.cats.org.uk/" href="https://www.cats.org.uk/">Cats Protection</a> and <a title="https://www.dogstrust.org.uk/" href="https://www.dogstrust.org.uk/">Dogs Trust</a> held a Pet-Friendly Housing event in Parliament to call on the UK Government to reform the private rented sector (PRS) to make it fair to pets and owners. Both charities welcome the proposals in the Renters (Reform) Bill to give tenants the right to request a pet in their property, which the landlord must consider and cannot unreasonably refuse. Pets are part of the family, and any legislative changes must be fair and equitable. A survey by these pet charities found that 46% of landlords say they will allow pets, but only 9% of owners advertise their properties as pet-friendly. Damage to properties is sited as main reason for not allowing pets, but only 20-21% of properties were damaged, and 73% of landlords reported no problems. 94% and 98% of tenants say that their cats and dogs respectively have a positive impact on their lives. In June 2022 the UK Government published “A fairer private rented sector” which pledges to give tenants the right to request a pet in their property, which will be in the Bill. The Bill will amend the Tenant Fees Act 2019 so that landlords can require insurance to cover any damage caused by pets living in their property, but this could put added financial burdens on pet owners who are already struggling with the cost-of-living crisis; more properties out of reach and more pets being relinquished. Dogs Trust recommends using its Pet CV3 which shows tenants the steps they have taken to be responsible pet owners. The benefits a pet friendly private rented sector include: tenants feel more at home; tenants stay longer; fewer pets are relinquished from homes to organisations such as Cats Protection, Hope Rescue, and Dogs Trust. Both charities have been working with landlords, letting agencies and property industry since “Lets With Pets” was set up by Dogs Trust in 2009, and “Purrfect Landlords” by Cats Protection in 2018.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">At the APPG for Archives we discussed “<a title="https://www.campaignforrecords.org/" href="https://www.campaignforrecords.org/">Campaign for Records – Democracy and Rights in the Digital Age</a>”. The availability of evidence is vital for justice, for truth, and for democracy. Record keepers (archivists, records managers, conservators) keep information safe for the public, which can be used as facts to improve trust in government and maintain democracy. Government cannot be held to account if there are no recorded accounts or these cannot be accessed. The transparency and availability of public records is key to increasing trust in government and counteracting conspiracy theories, as recent events in the USA have made clear. The Information and Records Management Society and the Archives and Records Association (ARA) have combined to create the Campaign, because outdated legislation, multiple loopholes, lack of intellectual investment by record makers, and lack of resource to prepare for digital records are putting public records at risk. We were briefed by Gary Tuscan vice-chair of ARA’s Chief Archivists in Local Government Group; Reynold Leming, chair of Information and Records Management Society; and John Baines, National Association of Data Protection Officers.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I was honoured to be re-elected as a vice-chair at the AGM of the APPG for Steel and Metal-Related Industries meeting. We discussed the <a title="https://www.swic.cymru/" href="https://www.swic.cymru/">South Wales Industrial Cluster</a> (SWIC) with guest speaker Dr Chris Williams, who coincidentally lives in Neath. Chris is Head of Industrial Decarbonisation Wales, with 30 years’ experience in the steel industry. Chris told us how the Cluster impacts on steel. South Wales is home to a significant industrial base including the UK’s largest integrated steel works, one of 7 oil refineries and one of only 4 Nickel refineries in Europe. There are also several other energy intensive manufacturing plants and industries within diverse sectors including steel recycling, cement, paper, glass, mineral wool, and chemicals, food and general manufacturing. The SWIC was set up in 2019 and plans to achieve: net zero industries by 2040; retention of 113,000 jobs and an increase in jobs overall; unlocking £30bn investment opportunities in the region; growing the £6bn Gross Value Added from South Wales industry. SWIC’s holistic to decarbonisation has three objectives: through a just transition, deliver internationally competitive and sustainable low carbon industries; exploit significant renewable power capabilities available in South Wales to develop world leading infrastructure to decarbonise our industries; create a globally-recognised agile region that is innovative, opportunity driven, highly skilled, and capable of exploiting the huge clean growth opportunities that net zero offers South Wales.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The main business in the Chamber were the Official Opposition Day debates, which were topics that are devolved to Wales. The first debate was on <a title="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-07/debates/1D7B6570-4E2D-4ED1-80A4-7101A07E2A44/MentalHealthTreatmentAndSupport" href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-07/debates/1D7B6570-4E2D-4ED1-80A4-7101A07E2A44/MentalHealthTreatmentAndSupport">Mental Health Treatment and Support</a>, and the UK Government laid an amendment. The opposition didn’t vote on the UK Government amendment, and it was won by 278 to nil. The main motion was lost by 185 to 40 votes. The second debate was Accountability and Scrutiny of Teesworks which was initially raised in the Chamber a few weeks ago by Andy McDonald MP for Middlesbrough. The motion was defeated by 166 to 272.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">My week ended back in Neath at the Launch of the new E-bikes Project at the <a title="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1668287049303220224?cxt=HHwWgIDT0e-O-aYuAAAA" href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1668287049303220224?cxt=HHwWgIDT0e-O-aYuAAAA">Canolfan Maerdy Fun Day</a> in Tairgwaith. Also in attendance was Cllr Sonia Reynolds and the HM Vice-Lord Lieutenant of West Glamorgan, Mr Philip Hunkin. It was a fantastic day for all and credit is due to the amazing volunteers who made it happen.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My week in Westminster began at the End Child Poverty Coalition event to discuss new research by Loughborough University, which found that more than one-in-five children in Welsh Local Authorities live in poverty. The rates are highest in Blaenau Gwent (30.3%) and Ceredigion (30%), and lowest in Monmouthshire (21.4%), but even this is more than […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2746</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T16:15:43Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T16:15:43Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>I was pleased to speak to Ben Wright on Radio 4’s Westminster Hour on Sunday night about Keir Starmer’s call for a General Election following the resignations of the former Prime Minister and two of his supporters. There will now be at least 2 by-elections in July and potentially and third later this year all about the same issues but all taking place in very different parts of the country. We also have the issue of Margaret Ferrier’s seat in Scotland potentially coming vacant in the summer.</p>
<p>We cannot continue over the next 6 or 12 months with a government more focussed on party management than addressing the needs of the country. Who knows if there will be more by-elections in the coming months, causing yet more disruption and distraction from the issues that really matter to people.</p>
<p>I joined a debate in Westminster Hall on the new hospital programmes, predominantly in London, however the issue of hospitals is not a localised issue. We quickly learned that the Government’s promise of a new hospital programme was not a promise of 40 new hospitals. They are not all hospitals and there certainly are not 40 of them.</p>
<p>According to the National Audit Office, the NHS estate does not meet the demands of a modern health service. The growth in backlog maintenance risks harm to patients, and the need for capital is being consistently underestimated. Billions of pounds of capital spending have been diverted to cover inadequate revenue funding, and yet some restrictive ringfencing on some capital budgets means there are huge underspends even though the NHS estate is crying out for investment.</p>
<p>In July 2020, the Public Accounts Committee recommended a capital strategy and guidance, including expectations on how backlog maintenance costs will be addressed alongside other priorities.<br/>
In October 2021, the NHS Confederation stated that NHS leaders had concerns about safety standards because they cannot sufficiently maintain their estate, enable positive digital innovations and reduce the elective backlog without further worsening health inequalities. It described a disjointed and opaque allocation system and unresolved issues about how integrated care systems will allocate and prioritise capital spend. Where is the Government action on any of this?</p>
<p>I saw the impact of the cuts to the health service during a visit to Hull with Wes Streeting MP and the Shadow Health team. We went to see Bransholme Health Centre, the Urgent Treatment Centre, the Jean Bishop Integrated Care Centre and Hull Royal Infirmary Emergency Department. The incredible work that the doctors, nurses, healthcare assistants and all the other hospital staff are doing in very difficult circumstances is always inspiring. We saw some fantastic services for frail patients to help keep them from falls and maintain independence, but the staff are so clearly at breaking point. Our health service needs support – it deserves our support, because I do not know where we would be without them and their care and dedication.</p>
<p>In Bristol, it was wonderful to visit New Oak Primary and meet with staff and see the work being done with some exceptional young people. This is a fantastic, nurturing environment for our young people. The teachers, teaching assistants, and SEND staff have created a great atmosphere for learning and there is support for every student and their needs. I got to speak to some of the students and they quizzed me on my job as an MP. It’s great to spend time with some inquiring minds and those who have such bright ideas about the future!  And to all the year 11’s moving on, good luck for whatever comes next.</p>
<p>This week we marked the anniversary of the Grenfell Tower fire, which took the lives of 72 people. We remember the victims, and stand with their loved ones and the Grenfell community as they pursue justice and campaign for change.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575.</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/">Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to speak to Ben Wright on Radio 4’s Westminster Hour on Sunday night about Keir Starmer’s call […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/">Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3549</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T15:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T15:00:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill Holds Adjournment Debate on Heating Rural Homes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/16/sir-bill-holds-adjournment-debate-on-heating-rural-homes/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Tuesday evening, Sir Bill Wiggin, Member of Parliament for North Herefordshire, held an Adjournment Debate on Heating Rural Homes. Sir Bill called on the Government to rethink its 2026 oil-fired boiler ban and recognise that rural homes were not... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/16/sir-bill-holds-adjournment-debate-on-heating-rural-homes/#more-4776">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4776</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T14:26:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T14:26:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greyfriars Bobby star remembered</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13755/greyfriars-bobby-star-remembered" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Edinburgh honoured the life of its second most famous canine with a special event earlier today (Friday 16 June).</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13755/greyfriars-bobby-star-remembered</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T15:22:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T15:22:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Major Step Forward for Aldridge Station</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/a-major-step-forward-for-aldridge-station/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am absolutely delighted that the Department for Transport has given the conditional approval to start the work on an outline business case to build and open a train station in Aldridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since first being elected in 2015 I have been campaigning to reinstate the station in Aldridge and by securing Government backing we are taking a major step forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this has only being possible because of the foresight and determination of our West Midlands Mayor Andy Street who remains committed to an integrated public transport system across the West Midlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reopening of Aldridge Station will bring major benefits to our local community and will open up access for local residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today represents another major step forward on this journey and I will of course continue to keep you updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am absolutely delighted that the Department for Transport has given the conditional approval to start the work on an outline business case to build and open a train station […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4762</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T12:04:28Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T12:04:28Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shadow Skills Minister visits London Bus Apprenticeship Academy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/16/shadow-skills-minister-visits-london-bus-apprenticeship-academy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/16/shadow-skills-minister-visits-london-bus-apprenticeship-academy/">Shadow Skills Minister visits London Bus Apprenticeship Academy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/16/shadow-skills-minister-visits-london-bus-apprenticeship-academy/">Shadow Skills Minister visits London Bus Apprenticeship Academy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5229</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T11:22:18Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T11:22:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Improving the Nation’s Water Security</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/improving-nations-water-security" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7428" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">16 June 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Improving the Nation’s Water Security</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Philip Dunne, Chair of the Environmental Audit Committee, writes for the <em><a href="https://www.express.co.uk/news/politics/1781056/tory-mp-water-security-climate-change-reservoir">Daily Express</a>.</em></p>

<p>The heat wave we are experiencing is squeezing our precious water supplies. Schools have even closed their doors after taps ran dry because demand for water outstripped supply.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.philipdunne.com/sites/philipdunne.com/files/2023-06/express_article.jpg" width="421" height="633" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>It is only likely to get worse as time goes on. Future projections of hotter, drier summers could result in reduced water levels, with some rivers potentially losing half of their water. </p>

<p>There will also be greater demand for water to drink, keep cool and sustain gardens and crops.</p>

<p>However, we can alleviate the pressure on the system.</p>

<p>Thinking about water efficiency at home must become the norm, from shorter showers to installing water butts in gardens. </p>

<p>Smart meters for water can help create a water-saving culture as we do for gas and electricity. These devices are already helping people conserve energy.</p>

<p>Farmers will need more water to grow their crops and feed the nation.</p>

<p>The Government is already making it easier for some farmers to build larger on-farm reservoirs to water crops during hot and challenging summers. We need to do more.</p>

<p>Astonishingly, we have not built a drinking water reservoir since 1991 despite our population increasing by 10 million in the decades since. </p>

<p>According to the National Infrastructure Commission, we must build 30 more reservoirs and new pipelines to move water supplies around the country.</p>

<p>The three planned reservoirs in Oxfordshire, Lincolnshire and Cambridgeshire are very welcome.</p>

<p>But there is more to do. Unacceptably, we lose over one trillion litres of water in England and Wales through leaky pipes. Clearly, the water sector desperately needs to upgrade its ageing infrastructure. </p>

<p>Delivering the investment the Government announced earlier this year to boost water resilience will be transformative.</p>

<p>We must take these crucial steps to keep our taps running as our summers get hotter: we can't delay.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7428 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T11:12:46Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T11:12:46Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John calls on Government to enable Britain&#8217;s world-leading Open Banking success in other sectors too]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/16/john-calls-on-government-to-enable-britains-world-leading-open-banking-success-in-other-sectors-too/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5758</id>
		<updated>2023-06-16T10:39:15Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-16T10:39:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/16/john-calls-on-government-to-enable-britains-world-leading-open-banking-success-in-other-sectors-too/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PRIDE MONTH: FIGHTING FOR EQUALITY</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/16/pride-month-fighting-for-equality/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martin spoke in the Backbench Business Debate on Pride Month. Here is an extract of his speech transcribed via&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-15/debates/EA123D7E-5A79-46AC-9EDE-36C945F1FF84/details#contribution-C82444EC-7C5D-4E4E-9E50-EBB78E5604C5"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): &lt;/strong&gt;I congratulate the hon. Member for Carshalton and Wallington (Elliot Colburn) on bringing the debate to the House. I am a vice-chair of the all-party parliamentary group on global lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT+) rights along with him and the hon. Members for Wallasey (Dame Angela Eagle) and for Darlington (Peter Gibson).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I begin by associating myself with some of the comments made by the hon. Member for Wallasey about funding, which is a critical issue when we are dealing with hate targeting the LGBT community. I cannot underestimate the impact of dark money in feeding the far right wing in the United States. This House really needs to get a grip on that, especially in relation to Scottish Limited Partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The right hon. Member for Exeter (Mr Bradshaw) was elected back in 1997. Many of us watched his election, because what we saw was an openly gay man standing for this House, even with so much thrown against him. We were glad, even on the SNP Benches, that he was elected; it was a great moment for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I also want to mention someone who never got into this House, because of the profoundly disturbing campaign against him during the election campaign in Bermondsey in the ’80s: Peter Tatchell. Peter is a Marmite person for many, but the campaign led against him back then exposes that all the political parties represented here have many different aspects to their history. Even those of us in the SNP have had issues around LGBTQ rights. Every political party has its history, and not all of it is great in standing up for equality. Peter should have had the opportunity to be here. I think he is a great loss to parliamentary democracy, but he campaigns vigorously outside this House and many people, including myself, are very grateful for that.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;amp;memberId=4615"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;amp;memberId=4615"&gt;Lloyd&lt;/a&gt; Russell-Moyle (Labour, Brighton Kemptown):&lt;/strong&gt; Peter has run a successful campaign to try to get an apology from the Metropolitan police and other police forces around the UK. The Metropolitan police made an apology as recently as last week, after his campaign success. Should that not lead to other police forces around the country apologising for their treatment of LGBT people historically?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): &lt;/strong&gt;The hon. Gentleman is right; yes, is the simple answer. Peter also eventually got an apology from the Ministry of Defence for serving veterans who were so badly treated because of their sexuality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I think I am the first openly LGBTQ Member for West Dunbartonshire, but like the right hon. Member for Exeter, that was not the first time I was elected. That was 31 years ago, to the old Clydebank District Council. It is a shipyard town, a burgh town—for the avoidance of doubt for&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Hansard&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;that is spelled b, u, r, g, h. Growing up in a very working-class, Irish-Catholic background, sexuality, for many reasons, was never discussed, whether LGBTQ or anything else, because we had to deal with so many other profound issues of class and how that impacted our lives through poverty.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I was honoured to be elected back in 1992, but I did not come out to many of my friends until many years later. Actually, I came out before that. What am I saying? My mind has gone very foggy in my old age. I came out to my friends Neil and Stephen when I was 19, and their first reaction was, “Alright. Okay, tell us something we didn’t know; can we go to the Radnor Park pub for a pint? Right, okay, nae bother.” They, like me, are very open individuals—Stephen especially, because of his trade union involvement. As a heterosexual man and a trade unionist, he is keenly aware now, as he was back then, about dignity and equality for all.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But I was a lucky one. There were so many in my community, not just my hometown of Clydebank, but across Dumbarton and the Vale of Leven who did not get that support and whose lives were ended through sheer ignorance and hate—and that is not just those who died because of HIV and AIDS and the traumas that we in the community went through. That is why in 2015 I was glad that my sexuality was not an issue for anybody —absolutely no one. That said, it might be now!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Why are these issues important? It is important to reflect on where some of us, of a certain age, have come from, and why we believe it is so important that so many of the people behind us—those younger folk, who are under 50-odd—require that support. That is why I am grateful for the work of organisations such as the Equality Network in Scotland, the Time for Inclusive&amp;nbsp;Education—TIE—campaign, Scottish Trans and LGBT Youth Scotland. Ignorance breeds hate, and with hate comes oppression. That is why I said earlier that all the political parties represented in the House have a sometimes dark history when it comes to LGBT rights, but it is also relevant to the issue of our relationships, in this House, with other countries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have already heard mention of the Commonwealth. I have to be open about this: I am not a big fan, and that is not just because I am a member of the LGBT community. I keep being given the same answer—that the Commonwealth is doing a lot to promote LGBTQ issues—but I have to say that in the last 10 years it has not been doing enough to stop the dreadful ramping up of hate that we are now seeing in Uganda and many other countries. That brings me back to the point made by the right hon. Member for Wallasey about the systemic use of dark money, coming through the Russian Federation, possibly being used in the Scottish limited partnerships, going through Ukraine into the United States and then feeding into the entire continent of Africa. We have already talked about Uganda, where LGBTQ people are subject to life imprisonment or possibly the death penalty; that is an extraordinary state of affairs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To my mind—and this is a personal issue—the Commonwealth is failing LGBTQ citizens in the majority of countries. It is an absolute disgrace, but how has it come about? Let us be clear: it is a hangover from a imperial and colonial legal system, based on white supremacy, racism and homophobia, which was imposed on many of those nations and is now being manipulated by dark money. We need to recognise that the foundations of those principles go to the heart of the reactionary right wing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have heard about books being banned in the United States, and possibly being burnt next. I grew up in a community that was obliterated during the second world war. For people like me, the Nazi regime is not the ghost of some distant past but something that has had a dreadful, post-traumatic effect on our entire community. We need only look at what the regime did in the lead-up to taking full power after the Weimar Republic to understand how we now see ourselves in many parts of the world, notably the United States, where school boards are banning books that refer to dignity and equality. We know where that leads.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 1935 the Nazis revised paragraph 175 of the existing statute of the German criminal code that banned sexual relations between men. Under the new Nazi version of the statute, a wide range of intimate and sexual behaviours could be, and were, punished as crimes. As a consequence, between 5,000 and 15,000 men were imprisoned in concentration camps for being “homosexuell”. This group of prisoners were typically required to wear a pink triangle on their camp uniforms as part of the prisoner classification system. Many, but not all, of those pink-triangle prisoners identified as gay; notably, it would be gay men who were given that definition. The pink triangle called attention to this prisoner population as a distinct group. It is dreadful to think that even within the concentration camps there was a division of terror and hate, but that is the reality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is important for us to remind ourselves that that constant narrative of hate needs to be exposed. It needs to be taken head-on, not only by this Government but by other Governments. I am glad that the Minister for Equalities is on the Front Bench, because I know he is a keen advocate of LGBTQ issues and that, as other Members have suggested, he will speak up in Government. However, I think he needs to give some answers to questions about conversion therapy, and he needs to give answers to my Parliament in Scotland—the one that I participate in and vote for—about why it is not being allowed to proceed with its Gender Recognition Reform (Scotland) Bill. That is an extraordinary position for a devolved Administration in the 21st century to find itself in, especially given Scotland’s history in relation to homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We have come so far in Scotland. We did not decriminalise homosexuality until 1980; I think it was done in 1967 in England and Wales. That gives us some idea of the utterly dreadful situations that the LGBT community faced in Scotland. What a difference; what a change. We can look at other European nations as well. I come from a very strong Irish Catholic background, and I never thought in a month of Sundays that the Republic of Ireland would have a referendum on equal marriage. Let us get the wording right first of all: it is “equal marriage”, not “same-sex marriage”. My marriage to my husband is the same as that of anyone else in the Chamber. It is not different; it is equal. My sexuality is irrelevant. That is what the law is about when it comes to equal marriage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let us consider what has happened in countries such as Ireland and Malta. The fact that in Ireland, a public referendum for the entire citizenry of the Catholic nation endorsed equal marriage was extraordinary, and the subsequent election of an openly LGBT Taoiseach was the most profound change. Gender recognition in Ireland came about because of a public discourse. It was not just about politicians; it was about people’s assemblies coming together to discuss the deep issues that may supposedly divide people. The Irish people made up their minds and said, “Get on with it”, and in 2015 the Dáil—and, of course, the Oireachtas, because it went forward to the Seanad—said yes. That led to the Gender Recognition Act 2015. Where was the hoo-hah in Ireland? There was none, and since then a review has been more forthright in its support for the trans community in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me end by emphasising this point to the Minister: Pride is a demonstration. It is not just about parties. Some of us are mindful of the people who did not make it this far: we are mindful of the black and Latino trans women in California who, in the 1950s, were the bedrock of LGBT rights, and other black and Latino trans women in New York— people like Marsha P. Johnson—were the bedrock of gay rights for white gay men like me. They turned up, and that is why I am here today. I am turning up in memory of them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I hope the Minister will answer the answer the questions about conversion therapy and about why his Government think that the Government of Scotland do not have the right to a gender recognition Bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch the debate in full &lt;a href="https://parliamentlive.tv/event/index/3cb5f7b7-44dd-4693-9b63-5fca3a41a244?in=12:41:46"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://martindocherty.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/House_of_Commons_15_06_23_13_54_58.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Martin spoke in the Backbench Business Debate on Pride Month. Here is an extract of his speech transcribed via Hansard: Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): I congratulate the hon. Member for Carshalton and Wallington (Elliot Colburn) on bringing the debate to the House. I am a vice-chair of the all-party parliamentary group on global lesbian, ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="PRIDE MONTH: FIGHTING FOR EQUALITY" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/16/pride-month-fighting-for-equality/#more-1821768" aria-label="More on PRIDE MONTH: FIGHTING FOR EQUALITY">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821768</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T10:09:30Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T10:09:30Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Backbench Business Debate"/>
    <category term="Equal Marriage"/>
    <category term="LGBTQ"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Pride Month"/>
    <category term="Speech"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bink Strikes Under Councils’ Nightmare Coalition</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/bink-strikes-under-councils-nightmare-coalition/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bink-strikes-under-councils-nightmare-coalition" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p><strong>Welwyn Hatfield’s local MP, Grant Shapps, has responded to Welwyn Hatfield Borough Council’s announcement that bin collection staff will begin industrial action on Monday 19th June.</strong></p>



<p>The council – now jointly run by a coalition of Lib Dem and Labour councillors – announced on Thursday that Urbaser’s refuse collection staff will strike in a dispute with Unite the Union. No timeframe was provided for how long the strike is expected to last.</p>



<p>Blue recycling bins, brown garden waste bins and green food waste caddies will not be collected through the duration of the strike, although the council’s statement says black bin refuse will be “prioritised” during this time.</p>



<p>The strike is set to begin precisely a month after the joint Lib Dem-Labour administration was announced, and comes right after a twenty-year period of Conservative council rule in which there was never a strike of this type or scale.</p>



<p>Mr Shapps commented on the announced strikes:</p>



<p>“There was never a strike like this over the twenty years that the Conservatives ran the council. People up and down Welwyn Hatfield are very worried, especially as it comes so soon after the Lib Dem-Labour coalition was formed.</p>



<p>He continued:</p>



<p>“Residents will be hoping this isn’t the kind of thing they can come to expect with a Lib Dem-Labour coalition of chaos. The longer the council fails to deal with these strikes, the worse it’ll be for everyone in Welwyn Hatfield. The council must work quickly to reach an agreement to ensure the disruption ends quickly.</p>



<p>“In the meantime, I stand ready to do what I can to advise or assist anyone in Welwyn Hatfield as the local MP.”</p>



<p>The council’s advice states that black bin collections will be prioritised and that residents should still put their black bin out on the normal collection day. The full council statement, which includes guidance and advice about the situation, can be found here: https://www.welhat.gov.uk/rubbish-recycling/changes-bin-collections-due-industrial-action </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/bink-strikes-under-councils-nightmare-coalition/">Bink Strikes Under Councils’ Nightmare Coalition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Welwyn Hatfield’s local MP, Grant Shapps, has responded to Welwyn Hatfield Borough Council’s announcement that bin collection staff will begin industrial action on Monday 19th June. The council – now jointly run by a coalition of Lib Dem and Labour councillors – announced on Thursday that Urbaser’s refuse collection staff will strike in a dispute […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/bink-strikes-under-councils-nightmare-coalition/">Bink Strikes Under Councils’ Nightmare Coalition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Yarwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=48602</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T10:01:13Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T10:01:13Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/06/16/snp-opposition-day-debate-on-the-need-for-a-dedicated-cost-of-living-committee/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10882</id>
		<updated>2023-06-16T09:23:37Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-16T09:20:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[During an SNP Opposition Day Debate in Westminster on Wednesday 14th June, my colleagues and I called for the UK Government to set up a dedicated Cost Of Living Committee &#8211; to better understand the impact of Brexit and the cost-of-living crisis and to explore possible solutions to these matters. In rural constituencies like Argyll ... <a title="SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/06/16/snp-opposition-day-debate-on-the-need-for-a-dedicated-cost-of-living-committee/" aria-label="More on SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/House_of_Commons_14_06_23_15_30_03_V1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="13578289" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne backs animal welfare campaign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-animal-welfare-campaign/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-backs-animal-welfare-campaign" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236632" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Gwynne-backs-animal.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, joined the RSCPA earlier this week to discuss the urgent need for animal welfare legislation to secure a better future for animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RSPCA is asking the UK Government to ensure it passes the legislation it committed to, which was included in the recently dropped Kept Animals Bill, on primates as pets, live exports, puppy smuggling and Livestock Worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Government announced its decision to scrap its pledges on animal welfare, a decision Gwynne has branded “shameful”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the event, Gwynne and the RSPCA also discussed the need for strengthening dog breeding laws, ensuring animal welfare is protected in trade agreements, strengthening protections for wild animals and calling for animal welfare to be taught in schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Andrew Gwynne said: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m proud to be supporting the RSPCA. The Government’s decision to scrap the kept animals bill was appalling, and I’ll keep putting pressure on them in Westminster to think again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Britain can and should be a world leader in animal welfare. I look forward to working alongside the RSCPA to make that a reality.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harriet Main, public affairs manager at the RSPCA added:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re really pleased that Andrew attended our drop-in event to find out how &lt;strong&gt;he&lt;/strong&gt; can support the RSPCA in their mission to progress animal welfare standards as well as providing information to his constituents.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There are pressing issues on the political agenda, but the commitments made to animal welfare need to remain intact. We want a firm commitment from the Government that positive changes are on the horizon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-236634" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-1024x783.jpg" alt="" width="690" height="527" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-1024x783.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-300x229.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-768x587.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-1536x1175.jpg 1536w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-2048x1566.jpg 2048w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/0C3A3093-Enhanced-NR-1080x826.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 690px) 100vw, 690px" /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Pictured above: Gwynne with an RSPCA inspector at a Parliamentary event earlier this week.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-animal-welfare-campaign/"&gt;Gwynne backs animal welfare campaign&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, joined the RSCPA earlier this week to discuss the urgent need for animal welfare legislation to secure a better future for animals. The RSPCA is asking the UK Government to ensure it passes the legislation it committed to, which was included in the recently dropped Kept Animals Bill, […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-animal-welfare-campaign/">Gwynne backs animal welfare campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236631</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T17:23:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T17:23:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rat-Running Taskforce – Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/rat-running-taskforce-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2726" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">15 June 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Rat-Running Taskforce – Update</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span>As part of my ongoing campaign to support the South of the A47 Taskforce that I helped convene in order to address rat-running concerns in the Corridor between the Wood Lane/Berry’s Lane junction at Honingham and the A11 at Wymondham, I welcomed the chance to engage again with the Taskforce in recent days.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Although much progress has been made as the Taskforce have worked with Norfolk County Council Highways to develop a package of mitigation measures aimed at alleviating existing rat-running while also preparing in advance for any likely impacts of the A47 dualling between North Tuddenham and Easton (as well as the Norwich Western Link), I am conscious that there remain some local concerns about specific routes along this Corridor that appear to have been missed in the mitigation package.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>That’s why I have contacted NCC Highways again to suggest another rat-running meeting in the coming weeks to look at what more can be done for those one or two locations worried that they are not included in the proposals.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Rest assured, I am firmly committed to supporting these communities – and will continue to hold the key stakeholders to account in order to deliver the mitigation improvements we need to see.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Full details of my work with the Taskforce can be found on my website </span></span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/a47-rat-running-campaign-and-taskforce"><span>here</span></a>.</span></span></span></p>

<p> </p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2021-06/george_freeman_yaxham.jpg" width="540" height="325" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2726 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T15:46:29Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T15:46:29Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>‘A shining example’ - MP praises Friends of Kents Bank Station group</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442401/a-shining-example-mp-praises-friends-of-kents-bank-station-group"/>
  <updated>2023-06-15T15:44:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442401/a-shining-example-mp-praises-friends-of-kents-bank-station-group</id>
  <summary type="text">This morning, local MP Tim Farron visited Kents Bank railway station in Grange-over-Sands to pay tribute to the hard work of the Friends of Kents Bank Station group.
Following the closure of its shop, post office, pub, cafe, and two hotels between 2014 and 2018, Kents Bank was left without any community meeting place.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This morning, local MP Tim Farron visited Kents Bank railway station in Grange-over-Sands to pay tribute to the hard work of the Friends of Kents Bank Station group.</p>
<p>Following the closure of its shop, post office, pub, cafe, and two hotels between 2014 and 2018, Kents Bank was left without any community meeting place.</p>
<p>But a group of almost 40 volunteers decided to take matters into their own hands to turn the station into a true community facility which now boasts a library, exhibition, and a community garden.</p>
<p>In October, the group were named as runners-up in the 'Station Friends and Adopters at the Heart of Communities' category at the Community Rail Awards 2022.</p>
<p>Speaking after the visit, Tim said: <em>"It was a joy to meet of some of the brilliant and dedicated volunteers who make up the Friends of Kents Bank Station.</em></p>
<p><em>"Thanks to their tireless efforts, the station has been transformed into a real hub for the local area.</em></p>
<p><em>"They are an absolute shining example of what can be achieved when people come together to make a difference in their community.</em></p>
<p><em>"I'd encourage everyone to pay this wonderful station a visit."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Critics Must Allow Debate]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=7054</id>
		<updated>2023-06-15T15:33:54Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-15T15:33:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="division"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="government"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="labour"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="politics"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="tory"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s become fashionable to claim our politics is broken and, given the recent behaviour of a few leaders, it’s easy to understand why, but are some of the loudest critics also breaking our politics? I’m talking about the intolerant activists, those who never stand for election to anything but assume they’re always right and know<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Critics Must Allow Debate</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6589" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-6/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6589" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>It&#8217;s become fashionable to claim our politics is broken and, given the recent behaviour of a few leaders, it’s easy to understand why, but are some of the loudest critics also breaking our politics?</p>



<p>I’m talking about the intolerant activists, those who never stand for election to anything but assume they’re always right and know what other people must give up. We see it in the cavalier behaviour of protestors like ‘Just Stop Oil’ and their contempt for the opinions of others. It’s also standard behaviour for ‘keyboard warriors’, who direct streams of social media abuse at anyone daring to question their views.</p>



<p>Birmingham is a large and diverse city. We need to accommodate conflicting pressures and different views. It isn’t always easy.</p>



<p>I acknowledge the needs of the transgender community but consider those with concerns or who want women’s only spaces also have a totally valid point. They can’t just be shouted down. Even on relatively simple issues like cycling, there are those obsessed with demonising all car drivers and attacking anyone not sharing their views. I doubt their behaviour wins many converts. Like a religious cult, it’s a politics based on closing down anyone with doubts. I see it drive normal people away from politics and other community groups.</p>



<p>I want politicians to up their game and treat the public with much more respect, but I also want a politics that allows debate and follows a process we can all understand. Small groups can’t have everything they want, no matter how much they disrupt or abuse. Practical politics requires consensus and efforts to balance the interests of all. As I often say, we might not always agree but it’s good to listen and show respect for others. It’s ironic that those who frequently denounce the behaviour of housing estate youths have no problem with the same antics when practised by their middle-class friends. Often, those who are most critical of our politics show the least respect for others. We need more reasoned arguments and less abuse, that would go a long way to mending the way we do our politics.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Long-Haul Struggle for Freedom, Peace and Security</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/freedom-peace-security/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine spoke about her recent experience on a visit to Estonia during a debate on Global Military Operations. In her speech, Catherine began by paying tribute to those serving in the UK’s armed forces and highlighted the importance of the UK standing with Nato allies and alongside Ukraine. Catherine cautioned against slow response to the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/freedom-peace-security/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Long-Haul Struggle for Freedom, Peace and Security</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7952</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T14:54:26Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T14:54:26Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Foreign Affairs &amp; Defence"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="defence"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
    <category term="NATO"/>
    <category term="Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Ashford Jobs Fair Success</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-jobs-fair-success" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Everyone who has ever put on an event will know the feeling of worry beforehand. Will it work? Will anyone come?
I needed to have no such worries last week about my latest Jobs Fair in the Job Centre at County Square. Employers from the public, private and voluntary sectors filled the room with…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-jobs-fair-success</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Basingstoke MP visits Manor Field schools</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-visits-manor-field-schools" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maria Miller MP recently visited Manor Field Infant and Junior schools to catch-up with pupils and teachers. 
Maria said, “I want all schools in Basingstoke to be ‘Good’ or ‘Outstanding’, so that they can help offer children the best start in life.
“Both Manor Field infant and junior schools have ‘…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-visits-manor-field-schools</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Presents Petition to Save Withernsea Bus Depot to East Yorkshire Buses </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-presents-petition-save-withernsea-bus-depot-east-yorkshire-buses" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Thanks to your readers, 1178 people in Withernsea have signed the petition to save the thirty jobs at Withernsea Bus Depot on Bannister Street.  
I’m taken aback. I knew people cared but it’s incredible how much everyone in Withernsea wants to keep these thirty jobs here.  
Now it’s time for me to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-presents-petition-save-withernsea-bus-depot-east-yorkshire-buses</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MONTHLY CASEWORK SUMMARY</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/monthly-casework-summary" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 Behind the scenes, MPs receive a significant number of emails from local residents asking for support with a variety of important personal issues.
Have a look, and see some of the things that I’ve been helping local residents with...
 If there’s anything I can do for you, please do get in touch.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/monthly-casework-summary</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Sadly today marks 6 years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower"/>
		<published>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</published>
		<updated>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="OppDay proposing Cost of Living Committee 14 06 23" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o-LlRhpaDPg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f4cd.png" alt="📍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; We now come to the Opposition Day Motion in the name of Dr Phillipa Whitford on Cost of Living and Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much, Madam Deputy Speaker. I rise to move the motion in my name and those of my colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cost of living crisis is the number one issue for most of our constituents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How to keep a roof over their heads with the rising cost of mortgages or rent. How to put food on the table when food inflation in the UK is the highest in Europe. How to pay energy bills that doubled in just a year. And how to cope with overall inflation, which is far outstripping wage growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It therefore deserves serious focus by this parliament to find solutions. The government are already patting themselves on the back, that inflation has eased from 10.1% to 7.8%. Of course, that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean prices are falling, just that they are increasing at a slightly slower rate. Now, there&amp;#8217;s no question that the Covid pandemic and the war in Ukraine have contributed to the current crisis, particularly the latter&amp;#8217;s impact on global energy prices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the UK is the only G7 country not to have recovered to pre pandemic economic health. And consumers in the UK have faced the biggest energy price rises in Europe. . Despite the current easing of the inflation rate, it&amp;#8217;s still higher than the OECD the EU, and the US. So why does the UK have the highest inflation and poorest growth projections among similar economies?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple. The disaster that dare not speak its name Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we approach the seventh anniversary of the referendum, one of its key architects may have just left the stage, but Brexit&amp;#8217;s disastrous legacy will impact people across the nations of the UK for years to come. I know as a doctor that the first step in dealing with any problem is to admit that you have one. But both this government and the Labour Party appear to be in complete denial about the contribution of Brexit to the cost of living crisis. And until I will, yes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;J&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oanna Cherry:&lt;/strong&gt; Just on the point about the Labour Party. Labour Party are obviously keen to regain seats in Scotland from the SNP, obviously we hope they don&amp;#8217;t. But why does she think the Labour Party are ignoring the impact of Brexit even in Scotland when the overwhelming position of the Scots is they want to remain in the European Union?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I thank my Honourable friend for her contribution. I think it&amp;#8217;s quite clear we saw the discomfort of the Labour party on Brexit for really quite a number of years. Because their approach to Brexit had flip flopped backwards and forwards, so they simply avoid the topic. And until recently, you would also think that there&amp;#8217;d been an omerta in the mainstream media whenever discussing the UK&amp;#8217;s economic performance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite previously campaigning against Brexit, as I said, the Labour leader is now clear that he won&amp;#8217;t consider rejoining the EU, the Customs Union, or the single market. He claims he can somehow reduce trade friction, which has cut exports by 15% and cost 4% of G D P. But just as Brexiters claim the problems are just that the Brexit isn&amp;#8217;t Brexity enough, we now have Labour claiming that they will make Brexit work. It can&amp;#8217;t work. But if he wants to reduce some of the damage of Brexit, the Labour leader should support the idea of a committee to identify proposals that could be put to the EU prior to the review of the trade and cooperation agreement in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, what&amp;#8217;s the plan? Close his eyes, click his red heels together and make a wish. Talk about not reading the room. Just as polls show a majority across the UK recognise Brexit&amp;#8217;s a mess and would support rejoining the EU, the supposedly official opposition have lashed themselves to the mast of the floundering Tory Brexit ship.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not quite sure why they&amp;#8217;re called the official opposition when they don&amp;#8217;t seem to do much opposing and just go along with the policies of this Tory government. Whether it&amp;#8217;s on Brexit, on immigration, outsourcing the NHS in England to private companies, or denying the right of the Scottish people to choose their own future. Labour may have abandoned almost all of their previous pledges, and don&amp;#8217;t offer much real change after the next election, but the politicians who have caused the current damage to the UK economy are those with their bahookies squarely planted on the government benches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tory austerity may initially have made the Treasury balance sheet look better. But 13 years of benefit cuts and public sector pay freezes have sucked money out of local economies, leading to dead high streets and rising poverty, particularly among children, pensioners and disabled people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Austerity also meant that health and care services were already struggling when Covid hit. And the workforce shortages that hamper all four UK health services have been exacerbated by the loss of freedom of movement, meaning they&amp;#8217;re all struggling to catch up the backlog. The cost of energy is a major contributor to the cost of living crisis, but while global energy prices have risen due to the Ukraine war, the problem is also exacerbated by Tory policy over decades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It was their poster girl, Mrs. Thatcher, who put the profits of oil, gas, and electricity into private hands. This has left the UK fully exposed to global price rises, despite the UK and Scotland&amp;#8217;s energy potential. Also, unlike France with its nationalized power supplier, which has been able to limit price increases to 4%, the UK has been unable to do this. While the energy support payments were welcome, they had a limited impact on energy bills, which had doubled in a year. And the UK government didn&amp;#8217;t follow other European countries such as Germany, Spain, Ireland, and the Netherlands, in substantially cutting VAT on energy bills. Even though rising prices means such a VAT cut could have been revenue neutral.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brexiters actually promised cheaper food. Hard to believe. But that has turned out to be a complete crock with food inflation in the UK at over 19%, as I say, the highest in Europe. The cost of basic foods and supermarket brands are rising even faster, meaning that those on lower incomes are facing a dramatic surge in food costs with more people resorting to food banks or missing meals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Almost 30% of the UK&amp;#8217;s food comes from the EU, so there will be another surge in food prices next winter, when the UK introduces the full customs checks on food stuffs, which will be imported from the EU.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairi Black: &lt;/strong&gt;Would she agree with me that it&amp;#8217;s also an absolute scandal that during a cost of living crisis where we&amp;#8217;re seeing prices such as she&amp;#8217;s described, that we have produce going to waste in Scotland because we don&amp;#8217;t have enough people to actually pick the fruit in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I thank my Honourable friend for that point, and it&amp;#8217;s an issue, while soft fruit is a particular issue in Scotland, this is actually an issue right across the UK cause of the lack of European staff in harvesting. And, and we are seeing, as you, she says, food rotting in the fields. But we&amp;#8217;re also seeing it in other sectors, there&amp;#8217;s hardly a sector that isn&amp;#8217;t struggling for workforce.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With regards the income checks on incoming food stuffs from the EU, the former ill- named Brexit Opportunities Minister delayed the checks for the fourth time last year. At the time, he suggested that they would cost a billion pounds and described them as an act of self-harm. Duh. And I could have told them that in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of this, the now infamous mini budget, which tanked the pound and the stock market while the chancellor was still on his feet, sent mortgage costs spiraling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The current relentless rise in interest rates in response to inflation is making home ownership unattainable for young families as well as pushing up rents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Grant: &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;m grateful to Honourable friend for giving way, she&amp;#8217;s rightly appoint to disastrous mini budget that was imposed on us by our previous Prime Minister. Does she think the leader of the Scottish Conservative Party Group in the Scottish Parliament can have any credibility, having initially demanded the Scottish Government implement those disastrous policies and now demanding that spend billions of pounds tighten tox too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;re, I, I think more appropriately getting down on their knees in the Holyrood chamber to apologize would be an appropriate response. Despite the abuse they gave the Scottish government for not following such crazy policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I thank the Honourable lady for giving away. I was, had the honour to be a member of the Scottish Parliament for some 12 years, and the minister opposite served in Scottish Parliament and I know a good deal about the committee system. Indeed, I chaired it. And members who were not members, members of Scottish Parliament who were not members of the committee, could come and speak at the committee in fact, or was never, never not allowed. I am not a member of any committee in this place. There are only three members of my party are members of committees, cause of the size. This means, but with the structure of this committee, the door is locked against me applying for a place on this committee, and I feel disenfranchised, and I do not see why my constituents should not be given the chance of their representative to have a voice. So I cannot vote for the structure of committees as it stands. No, look at it&amp;#8217;s sloppy work. Very sloppy work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In actual fact, that&amp;#8217;s incorrect. There will be members from the three devolved nations. It will be as is described, a significantly large committee, which might indeed provide place for the Honourable member or one of his other colleagues from a devolved nation who would have space. So it&amp;#8217;s, it&amp;#8217;s nonsense. There is no, there is no exclusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Linden:&lt;/strong&gt; Forgive me, I wonder if she might lend me her order paper cause mines might be out of date, but the one I&amp;#8217;ve got doesn&amp;#8217;t show any amendment from the Honourable Gentleman or indeed from his party to try and change the composition of that committee. Am I reading the order paper wrong or is the Honourable gentleman just perhaps a little bit of touch?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think the Honourable member is reading the order paper wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The combination of rising energy, food, and housing costs on top of years of benefit cuts and stagnant wages means the sums simply don&amp;#8217;t add up for many families. The Scottish Government is trying to use the now very limited powers of devolution to mitigate the crisis, particularly for those on the lowest incomes. However, the Scottish budget for day-to-day running of services is less in real terms than in 2010 with no uplift for inflation. And as we all know, no significant borrowing powers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite this, the Scottish Government has provided additional funding for the Fuel Insecurity Fund and Scottish Welfare Fund. Low income families are now supported through five childhood grants, including the Scottish Child Payment, which together provide 10,000 pounds of support during the early years and will provide over 20,000 by the age of 16.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wonder, would she not agree with me that the way to improve the situation for everyone, not just in the devolved nation, throughout the United Kingdom as a whole, is for those who are elected in Scotland, to the Scottish Parliament, to work hands in glove with those of us who are elected here, and particularly the other government for Scotland and the United Kingdom. Rather than set up another cumbersome committee, which is a process. Would it not be better to work together for the benefit of everyone in the United Kingdom?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, I think the Honourable lady knows well that on things like trade deals, Brexit, we see very little consultation, genuine consultation, between the government here and the devolved government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the Honourable lady is also well aware of how devolution is being rolled back and hollowed down legislation undermined. And that has been passed. No, I&amp;#8217;m sorry. I&amp;#8217;ve just given way to the Honourable lady.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Institute of Fiscal Studies analysis of the Scottish Tax and Benefit System showed that it was more progressive. . With almost 30% of low income families 2000 pounds a year better off in Scotland. But Scotland aspires to something more radical than just mitigating Westminster austerity, such as the two child limit or the six year benefit freeze. Our vision is to be a fairer, greener nation. Scottish government founded the Wellbeing Economy Governments Group in 2018 with Iceland and New Zealand, and Finland and Wales joined later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A wellbeing economy doesn&amp;#8217;t just focus on GDP, which includes the profits of damaging sectors such as the tobacco industry, but invests in the physical and mental health, social economic, and environmental wellbeing of every citizen. It&amp;#8217;s a holistic approach, which recognizes that our society and economy depends on the success of every individual, every family, and every community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in addition to the targeted anti-poverty measures, the Scottish government invests in the wellbeing of all those living in Scotland. From the baby box, which welcomes the birth of a child. University tuition, which allows our young people to reach their full potential. To the free personal care, which allows older people to stay in their own homes for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But with the tightening limitations of devolution, the Scottish government doesn&amp;#8217;t have power over its own economy. . Or control of taxation and social security, that are required to deliver the wellbeing economy we aspire to. We all know we need a different type of economy by the end of this decade, or we will leave our grandchildren to face climate collapse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The pandemic brought everything to a standstill. Which gave us a unique opportunity to decide what kind of economy and society we wanted to rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stewart Hosie: &lt;/strong&gt;Before my Honourable friend goes on to talk about the kind of economy we want to see, I wonder if she&amp;#8217;d make an observation. That in an important debate on the cost of living and its evil twin Brexit, the day after an urgent question on the Tory&amp;#8217;s mortgage crisis, that here we are in this chamber with one Tory back bencher, two Labour back benchers. Does that not tell the Scottish people everything they need to know about how little unionism really cares for ordinary people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;. Well, the proposal for this economy, as I said at the beginning, is not just for the people of Scotland. It&amp;#8217;s actually for the people of the Four Nations of the UK. The review of the TCA will come up in 2026, and while it&amp;#8217;s not possible to make Brexit work, it is possible to mitigate some of its worst effects. But for that, you need to understand what Brexit&amp;#8217;s doing to the UK&amp;#8217;s society and economy, and have proposals that you can bring to the EU and ask for change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the opportunity to change to a different economy and society hasn&amp;#8217;t been taken. We already see poverty and inequality rising. And the climate emergency being pushed off the action list, including by Labour, who have just U-turned on their pledge to invest 28 billion pounds in the transition to a green economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the climate crisis can&amp;#8217;t wait. Scotland is blessed with extensive green energy potential. From wind and tidal power to green hydrogen and pump storage hydro. The current government has failed to support Scotland&amp;#8217;s green energy potential. And sadly, there is now little reason to expect much change under Labour either.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drew Hendry: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you. I&amp;#8217;m grateful to my Honourable friend for giving way. She talks about Scotland&amp;#8217;s energy opportunities and indeed green hydrogen is one of the key ones. There does she agree with me? It&amp;#8217;s perhaps illuminating that the Foreign Secretary himself doesn&amp;#8217;t even know about those opportunities or has taken the opportunity to engage with the US in their Inflation Reduction Act in terms of the supply pipeline for that, does she think it&amp;#8217;s absolutely indicative of the state of the government of this place in terms of the relationship with the needs of the Scottish people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, I sit on the Scottish Affairs Committee and we have done an inquiry into hydrogen and we&amp;#8217;ve also covered some of the other issues around green energy. And it&amp;#8217;s been clear from the UK Minister that they do not support the Scottish vision of actually being able to export green hydrogen. We know Germany is desperate for green hydrogen, particularly with the Ruhr area in North Rhine-Westphalia because it&amp;#8217;s crucial for heavy industry, but the UK government are not interested in that, and therefore, Scotland&amp;#8217;s potential for such a lucrative export is going to be held back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I, I&amp;#8217;m grateful for the honourable member giving away, particularly as she&amp;#8217;s raised an issue that we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at some length in the Scottish Affairs Committee, that, that of the future of hydrogen, carbon capture and storage, and such like. But does the Honourable member agree, or does she, does she believe that it&amp;#8217;s appropriate, given that energy policy and international national trade are both reserved functions, that it is appropriate for Scottish government ministers to be having direct discussions with, and officials, with federal German government ministers and officials on that matter?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously, obviously we&amp;#8217;re just continuing the Scottish Affairs Committee diatribe from Monday, but the job of the Scottish government, Scottish Ministers, Scottish MSPs, and those of us who are here, is to promote Scotland in the world, to make sure we extract as much business into Scotland and as much investment. And because of that because of the efforts of Scottish ministers and MSPs, Scotland is second only to London in foreign direct investment, and that&amp;#8217;s how we intend to keep it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would say that the key reasons for independence can be summarized in having the powers to tackle the problems that we have. It&amp;#8217;s not that independence itself just sprinkles fairy dust. We could tackle things like poverty, but we don&amp;#8217;t have the levers. But also being able to invest in our incredible natural resources for the benefit of all of our citizens. And most importantly, to be in control of our own future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Being independent would mean that we would never again have a disaster like Brexit, forced on us against our will. . . Those living in Scotland would get to choose their own governments. And therefore drive decisions about our future. And with over 70% of Scots supporting membership of the EU, I have no doubt that our most prosperous future is as a modern, independent European country, just like many of our very successful neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;#038;title=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/" data-a2a-title="Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/"&gt;Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>  📍 We now come to the Opposition Day Motion in the name of Dr ... <a title="Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/">Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Parliamentary Assistant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2755</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T15:51:37Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T15:51:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="Cost of Living Crisis"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali at Urgent Question on Mortgages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_at_urgent_question_on_mortgages" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>On Tuesday 13 June, Rushanara outlined in Parliament how Liz Truss and Kwasi Kwartend crashed the UK economy, sending mortgages sky rocketing with the country continuing to face the fall out.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_at_urgent_question_on_mortgages</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T15:52:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T15:52:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex urges Ministers to rethink Wynyard secondary school application in light of further housing developments]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/alex-urges-ministers-to-rethink-wynyard-secondary-school-application-in-light-of-further-housing-developments/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14678</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T13:36:04Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T13:36:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ministers have been urged by Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham to rethink their decision to reject an application for a new secondary school to serve the Wynyard area following an increase in house building in the area – and with proposals for more homes in the pipeline. An application for a secondary school was submitted [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/alex-urges-ministers-to-rethink-wynyard-secondary-school-application-in-light-of-further-housing-developments/">Alex urges Ministers to rethink Wynyard secondary school application in light of further housing developments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin calls for support for hospices </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-support-hospices" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">During a debate in Parliament today on support for hospices, Robin paid tribute to the teams at St David's Hospice and Tŷ Gobaith hospices and called for greater financial support for hospices.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-support-hospices</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WHIT FRIDAY FUN]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=498</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T09:11:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T09:10:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton MP welcomes four million more people in work since Conservatives came to power in 2010, giving 326,337 more people in North West the security of a job</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-four-million-more-people-work-conservatives-came-power-2010-giving" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scott Benton MP welcomes four million more people in work since Conservatives came to power in 2010, giving 326,337 more people in North West the security of a job
New figures show there are four million more people in work since the Conservatives came to power in 2010 and 326,337 more people in a…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-four-million-more-people-work-conservatives-came-power-2010-giving</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MacNeil calls for compensation for Uist businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses in Uist affected by the lack of Lochboisdale sailings in the month of June.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said: “People&amp;#8217;s jobs and livelihoods have been badly affected. The increased ferry traffic since RET has brought greater economic activity and as a result people have risen to meet the opportunities presented, and therefore cannot afford the financial hit when expected services don&amp;#8217;t materialise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given that practical alternatives to provide a ferry service, admittedly lesser than was timetabled, did not materialise, then the only other course of action is for businesses to be compensated for their loss.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Increased demand is placing greater strain on the ferry service with more people travelling in recent years, but that is not a fault the people in Uist should bear with a hit to their back pocket.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I do hope the Scottish Government will do the right, fair and decent thing, and compensate businesses.&amp;nbsp; It would be to their great credit if they did.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":29149039,"permalink":"https:\/\/angusmacneilsnp.com\/2023\/06\/12\/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses\/"}'  class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3780" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/angus/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png" data-orig-size="768,1024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="angus" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=529" data-id="3780" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-3780" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=113 113w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225 225w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4205</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sturgeon must be suspended from the SNP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following the arrest of Nicola Sturgeon on Sunday, and given the scale of the police investigation and the potential repercussions, the former First Minister should really be suspended from the SNP.
SNP MSP Michelle Thomson has said Sturgeon should lose the SNP whip, joining calls from the Scottish…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Consultation</h2>
<p>Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the County Council, Surrey has launched a consultation to seek views about three different potential options for the village.</p>
<p>The proposals are pretty wide-ranging, and it is important that everyone in Ewell gets the chance to give their views about the options, and indeed can suggest things that might be done as well or instead. You can find details of the consultation by following this link.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled">https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled</a>.</p>
<p>I am afraid that I am a little late to alert you about the drop in events, but you have the whole of June to make your views known.</p>
<h2>Charities Fair – Friday 23rd June</h2>
<p>For those of you who are looking for an opportunity to volunteer for a local charity, a reminder that my latest Charity Volunteers Fair is being held at St Paul’s Church, Howell Hill, between 4pm and 6pm on Friday June 23<sup>rd</sup>. For those of you who do not know the church, it is beyond Ewell East station on the road to Cheam.</p>
<p>Please do come along. There will be a wide range of local charities presenting what they do and looking for help.</p>
<h2>The Horton Arts Centre</h2>
<p>The Horton Arts Centre – Epsom’s beautifully renovated former chapel – has asked me to tell you that it is celebrating being open for one year. The award-winning heritage venue is planning a wide range of performances, courses and events this summer and the café-bar is open all day Tuesday to Saturday plus every Friday night.</p>
<p>A free photography exhibition by Epsom Camera Club is now running until 17 June and highlights coming up include a series of authentic Spanish classical music and dance concerts, performed in the round, 18-19 July.</p>
<p>See their website for more details: thehortonepsom.org or call 01372 747662.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Day</h2>
<p>And one more date for your diary. The organisers have asked me to let you know that Ewell Village Fair this year is on the 15<sup>th</sup>. It’s always a good day out. And many thanks and congratulations to everyone involved in Ashtead Rotary for organising another really good Ashtead Village Day on Saturday.</p>
<p>I hope you are well and have a good summer.</p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters. Ewell Village Consultation Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6430</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span data-contrast="auto">Small and micro businesses in our community are feeling the weight of the economic crisis. The dual impact of rising inflation and the cost-of-living crisis is putting a strain on their small operations, and it’s clear they need our support more than ever.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">One of the most significant challenges many of our smaller businesses face is the VAT threshold, currently set at £85,000. In practical terms, this means that once a business hits this turnover, it must register for VAT, which brings with it a host of additional costs. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Understandably, this is causing a lot of worry for our business owners, many of whom are hesitant to expand their operations because of these potential costs.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">The Federation of Small Businesses (FSB) has come up with a solution that I wholeheartedly support – they’re calling for an increase in the VAT threshold from £85,000 to £100,000. This isn’t just about numbers on a balance sheet. It’s about giving our local businesses the confidence to grow and continue to support our local economy.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Previous studies by the FSB indicate that 24% of small businesses perceive the VAT limit as an obstacle to expansion, as they try to prevent the abrupt expenses associated with exceeding this limit in an effort to maintain customer affordability. The predicament has become more acute due to the rising inflation and ongoing impacts of Brexit, making growth a costly endeavour for small businesses.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">I’ve thrown my full weight behind this campaign, and <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Small-Business-VAT-UK-Letter.pdf">I’ve written to the Minister for Small Business</a> and the Chancellor urging them to do the same. This isn’t a complex issue – it’s a straightforward intervention that could make a world of difference to our small businesses.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">These are not just any businesses – these businesses are operating out of homes, markets, and local shops, providing services that range from personal care to home assistance. They are the entrepreneurs who take that bold step to start their own businesses, providing the day to day services that keep our families and our communities on track. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">They need our support, and they need it now.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">If you’re a small business owner in Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch, and Strathspey, I want to hear from you. I want to know your concerns and how I can best represent you. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Let me know if you want to keep in touch: </span><a href="https://mailchi.mp/drewhendrymp/small-business"><span data-contrast="none">https://mailchi.mp/drewhendrymp/small-business</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Small and micro businesses in our community are feeling the weight of the economic crisis. The dual impact of rising inflation and the cost-of-living crisis is putting a strain on their small operations, and it’s clear they need our support more than ever.  One of the most significant challenges many of our smaller businesses face …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7507</id>
    <published>2023-06-11T06:01:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-11T06:01:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Business"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It is with a with a heavy heart and after much consideration, that I announce my decision not to stand again as your Member of Parliament at the next election. Serving as your representative has been an honour and a privilege, especially as it allowed me to serve the city in which I was born, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/">Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5157</id>
    <published>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed Closure of Girlguiding Activity Centres]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1785</id>
		<updated>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcoming Local School Funding </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/welcoming-local-school-funding" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As part of the £450 million investment to improve schools across the country including Sir William Borlase's Grammar School and the Gerrards Cross CofE school. It is great to see our very own Lent Rise School is set to undergo significant improvements, which include:
 Upgraded mechanical systems…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/welcoming-local-school-funding</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Update on Small Boat Crossings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/an-update-on-small-boat-crossings/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Prime Minister Rishi Sunak visited the Kent coast to meet with members of the Border Force team at Dover. Stopping illegal migration from small boat crossings in the Channel is one of the top priorities for the government. We must bring to an end these dangerous journeys that have led to loss […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6306</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Star Column – on proposals to house asylum seekers in Stradey Park Hotel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/06/llanelli-star-column-on-proposals-to-house-asylum-seekers-in-stradey-park-hotel/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;We have all been shocked by the proposal by the Conservative UK Government to use the Stradey Park Hotel as emergency accommodation for 200 asylum seekers from July. Tory Ministers are scrabbling around looking for more hotel accommodation, because of their monumental failure to process the backlog of asylum claims, so those from safe countries could be sent home.   &lt;a&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This proposal
shows the utter arrogance of Tory Ministers who have failed to properly consult
surrounding communities, the Welsh Government, Carmarthenshire County Council,
the police and many others and, following secretive talks with the hotel
owners, rejected all other alternatives and&amp;nbsp;run roughshod over local
opinion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wales is a
welcoming country and, here in Llanelli, we have proudly played our part down
the years in supporting those who have fled war and persecution elsewhere in
the world in pursuit of safety.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this
proposal is unworkable, risks putting extra pressure on local services and
creates a situation that could prove problematic for nearby residents and for
the asylum seekers themselves.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I will continue
to vigorously oppose this plan for those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Together with
local councillors, I am actively campaigning to reverse this plan and we are
doing everything we can to stand up for the communities we represent.&amp;nbsp; We
have offered our support to the Action Committee set up by local residents and
are urging people to sign their petition, either online or in person.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Parliament, I
have already questioned the Minister for Immigration directly to emphasise the
strength of opposition against this and requested urgent meetings with him,
Clearsprings (an intermediary that manages the accommodation) and the hotel
owners themselves to keep up the pressure for this proposal to be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I know that the
County Council are also exploring all options open to them too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a fast
moving situation and I will do my best to keep people informed of what is
happening and to let them how they can get involved to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We have all been shocked by the proposal by the Conservative UK Government to use the Stradey Park Hotel as emergency accommodation for 200 asylum seekers from July. Tory Ministers are scrabbling around looking for more hotel accommodation, because of their monumental failure to process the backlog of asylum claims, so those from safe countries […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8868</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T10:36:35Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T10:36:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/data-reveals-long-mental-health-waiting-lists-dagenham-rainham" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;span property="schema:name"&gt;Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span rel="schema:author"&gt;&lt;span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang=""&gt;Andrew&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-06-07T10:19:00+00:00"&gt;Wed, 06/07/2023 - 11:19&lt;/span&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1208 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To save lives, the Government must set new targets to tackle the ‘silent disease’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/to-save-lives-the-government-must-set-new-targets-to-tackle-the-silent-disease/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith has been vocal on the issue of Osteoporosis, which affects half of all women and a fifth of all men over 50. It is characterised by a loss of bone density, leaving people vulnerable to breaks and fractures. Because symptoms often aren’t noticed until a serious break, osteoporosis has been called the ‘silent disease’.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Raising the issue in Parliament, Judith highlighted the shocking reality of the condition:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Many of these will be serious hip fractures, and as many people will die from these fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Questioning the Minister, Judith asked why such a serious condition is so often overlooked in healthcare:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Can the Minister explain why not even one of the 63 key performance indicators set by NHS England for Integrated Care Boards sets a target for fracture prevention?’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Maria Caulfield MP, Minister for Women’s Health Strategy, thanked Judith for her longstanding work on bone health. The Minister also highlighted measures the Government is undertaking to tackle Osteoporosis:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘NHS England is expanding fracture services for higher risk women who do have Osteoporosis to prevent falls in the first place.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the Government’s claims to be stepping up fracture services, the limits of the current services mean that 74,000 preventable fractures will occur over the next five years, costing the NHS £665 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making fracture prevention a key performance target could lead to stronger delivery of these services, preventing unnecessary pain, giving patients the level of care they deserve, and saving vital NHS resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Following the exchange, Judith said that Government support for fracture prevention was still inadequate:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Whilst Bradford offers a trailblazing service for those with Osteoporosis, this is not always the case nationally.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘The argument for investing in the prevention of fractures is clear: To save money and save lives, we need a government with the sense to invest in the future of women’s health in this country.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;???? As many people die from hip fractures as from lung disease or diabetes &amp;#8211; but osteoporosis is often overlooked in healthcare.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; While Bradford &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BTHFT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BTHFT&lt;/a&gt; has a trailblazing service, this isn&amp;#39;t the case nationally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;????This needs to improve. &lt;a href="https://t.co/c4MTw9LtoB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/c4MTw9LtoB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1666090988975321088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/FLS-Report-2022-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" alt="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith Cummins MP on Tuesday called for the government to step up and provide 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services in England.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Osteoporosis is a long-term health condition characterised by weak bones prone to breaking or fracture. It affects 3.5m people across the UK: a fifth of men and half&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: fracture, people, services, judith, england, fractures, nhs, health, osteoporosis, will&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SDP3245-0810-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" alt="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked: “Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, government, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" alt="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, minister, health, bradford, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;Government has 'lots of words - but very little action'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/SDP3245-0255-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" alt="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In her latest editorial in the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus, Judith talks about her recent work on a range of important local and national issues: I hope that people have managed to get a break during the summer. Over the summer months we saw terrible events unfold in Afghanistan. Afghanistan is&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, will, care, people, issue, local, bradford, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed. Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives. Judith has been vocal on the issue […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2741</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Asylum Backlog &amp; Small Boats on Channel 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/asylum-backlog-small-boats-on-channel-4/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>joshuatuck</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3459</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My statement on the continued closure of the High Wycombe driving test centre</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/06/my-statement-on-the-continued-closure-of-the-high-wycombe-driving-test-centre/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I understand the frustration the continued closure of the driving test centre is causing. I share that frustration. Constituents are routinely writing to me requesting an update on its planned reopening, illustrating the reasons I believe it is essential we have a functional driving test centre in High Wycombe. As many of my constituents know, we have, of course, been here before. Twice now, I have worked with key stakeholders in our area to save the driving test centre in […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18663</id>
    <published>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#DrivingTestCentre"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Driving Test Centre"/>
    <category term="High Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>London Road Level Crossing Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Barrier down time at the London Road level crossing has long been a cause of concern in Bicester. This is an issue which I have worked on since I was first elected, chairing meetings with previous administrations at the District and County Council, and meeting multiple Rail Ministers to discuss it…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update</id>
    <published>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The new Executive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/22/the-new-executive/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor David Mellen will remain as Leader of the council, continuing the hard work of continuing the hard work of himself, Cllr Adele Williams, Cllr Sally Longford and all previous and current executive and backbench members. He is responsible for continuing devolution, strategic regeneration, development and work on the city’s ambitious plan to be carbon neutral by 2028, as well as promoting the vision of the council and supporting all of his Portfolio Holders in their work. There is much work to be done over the next term and the new executive will be key in achieving the goals Nottingham Labour want for the city.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Audra Wynter has been confirmed as the new Deputy Leader and she will have responsibility for the finance and HR portfolios. With a background in finance work, Councillor Wynter will ensure the council remains on track in delivering a balanced budget and sticking to the Medium-Term Financial Plan, while delivering high-quality services for residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-small-font-size"&gt;Councillor Corall Jenkins will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Energy, Environment and Waste Services and Parks. She will have responsibility for key services such as bin collection and disposal, keeping our city’s streets clean and maintaining all of our wonderful parks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Cheryl Barnard will remain as Portfolio Holder for Children, Young People and Education. She will continue to be responsible for leading our children’s services, working with Ofsted to improve it where necessary, ensuring children’s safeguarding and working with academy trusts across the city on schools, ensuring attendance and working to reduce exclusions, so that all children get the best start in life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Steve Battlemuch will be taking up the reins as Portfolio Holder for Skills, Growth, Economic Development and Property. He will lead on skills and employment, ensuring that the workforce in the city is prepared for any changes in the way we work, and that the people of this city have the right opportunities. He will also oversee the management of the city centre, attracting investment and helping to ensure that Nottingham is promoted nationally and internationally to business and tourism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Jay Hayes has been confirmed as the new Portfolio Holder for Housing. He will lead on managing the council housing service, student housing, private rented properties and areas such as selective licensing and homelessness. Housing is incredibly important, all those who live in the city deserve to have a property that is safe, secure and that can be called home, whether they rent in the private sector or have social housing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sajid Mohammed will lead as Portfolio Holder for Neighbourhoods, Safety and Inclusion. This covers areas such as community protection, domestic violence work, licensing, taxi strategy and more. It is so important that Nottingham is a safe place to work and live in. Councillor Mohammed with many years of experience of community work and as director of Himmah will bring the required expertise to lead in these vital areas, and he will also lead on refugee and asylum seeker work, to ensure that Nottingham is a welcoming city for all, and that those vulnerable refugees and asylum seekers can integrate and make new lives in Nottingham.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Pavlos Kotsonis will continue as Portfolio Holder for Leisure and Culture. He will ensure that we continue to offer an outstanding events programme. He will also oversee the reopening and flourishing of the Castle, the continued running of Wollaton Hall and Newstead Abbey as well as leisure centres, markets, libraries and community centres across the city. Access to cultural events and key things like libraries and leisure centres is so important for allowing the people of the city to thrive and create.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Linda Woodings will also remain as Portfolio Holder for Adult Social Care and Health. She will continue to work on Public Health and Wellbeing, tackling health inequalities and working to reduce smoking prevalence, working on mental health and generally improving the health of residents in the city. She will also lead on independent living. All of these will help to improve the quality and length of life for residents in the city for years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, Councillor Angela Kandola will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Highways, Transport and Planning. She will oversee public transport such as buses and the tram. She will also lead on greener transport such as cycling and cycling links in the city, ensure highways are correctly managed and repaired as well as the Workplace Parking Levy to help increase public transport usage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is just a short summary of the responsibilities that the Executive will have for the next year. They will bring both their expertise and new views to help ensure that there is strong and effective political leadership at the council. This will continue both our journey with the Improvement and Assurance Board but also enable us to bring in the pledges that we made to the residents of the city in our manifesto in the May local elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=3074</id>
    <published>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Arboretum"/>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="Berridge"/>
    <category term="Bestwood"/>
    <category term="Bilborough"/>
    <category term="Bulwell"/>
    <category term="Bulwell Forest"/>
    <category term="Castle"/>
    <category term="Dales"/>
    <category term="election"/>
    <category term="Housing"/>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/2023/05/17/april-newsletter-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>liamtaggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=333</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3374</id>
		<updated>2023-05-16T11:22:21Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-16T11:22:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; Dear Constituent, Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve been on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Illegal migration bill update:</u></strong></p>



<p>The main piece of legislation that has been going through the House of Commons in the last few weeks is the Illegal Migration Bill. I’ve heard from a number of constituents with a diverse range of views on this topic. On the 26<sup>th</sup> of April the bill completed its remaining stages in the Commons and is now moving through the House of Lords, before it will return to the Commons for a final review.</p>



<p>This Bill is set to enhance the powers of the Government to tackle illegal migration, including the ability to remove illegal migrants from the UK to safe countries, new ways to determine ages of migrants without formal identification, additional protections for child migrants, and tougher sentences for those found guilty of people smuggling. The Bill was also amended during its remaining stages to include the Government’s commitment to review the safe and legal routes that are available.</p>



<p>It is clear that we need an asylum system that does work for those families truly in need, but is also tough on those who are trying to exploit the process to gain entry to the UK and on human traffickers who are exploiting vulnerable people and worsening the crisis. The new bill tackles the latter problems, while leaving open safe and legal routes for those in need.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sewage &amp; storm overflows update:</u></strong></p>



<p>Another key development in Parliament was new plans to further increase water quality targets and reduce sewage being released into our waterways.</p>



<p>The Government has announced its plan to enshrine the Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published last August, into law through the Environment Act. This will make its target to reduce storm overflows legally binding. The Government’s Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published in August 2022, set out stringent targets to protect people and the environment and is backed up by up to £56 billion capital investment, which is the largest infrastructure programme in water company history.</p>



<p>Further, the Government is now consulting on proposals for unlimited fines to be imposed on water companies that break the rules. More than £142 million has already been levied in fines since 2015 and I am aware that money from fines and penalties will now be channelled back into the environment.</p>



<p><strong><u>East Midlands APPG:</u></strong></p>



<p>Outside the Chamber, the focus seemed to be local issues over the last few weeks, and we had another meeting of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on the East Midlands. This group brings together MPs from across the Chamber to discuss issues that are especially important to our region.</p>



<p>The most recent meeting was on the future of Infrastructure in the East Midlands. We heard from the East Midlands Chamber of Commerce and East Midlands Councils on infrastructure in our area and the need for infrastructure investment to fulfil our environmental commitments, to make it easier for people living here to travel and get to work, and to encourage businesses to move here.</p>



<p>Moving forward, we will continue to push for our region to receive funding in the future, by collecting evidence on the wider benefits of infrastructure projects to the local economy and local businesses and use this in future proposals for funding.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ferrero sustainable palm oil event:</u></strong></p>



<p>I was also able to welcome Ferrero, who own the Thornton’s factory in Somercotes, to Parliament. They hosted an event alongside Chester Zoo and the Orangutan Land Trust on Sustainable Palm Oil, where they discussed the damage palm oil farming has inflicted on jungles and local habitats of orangutans around the world. While many food producers have moved away from palm oil for these reasons, the same problems of deforestation and habitat destruction continue to persist regardless of the plant used.</p>



<p>Because of this, Ferrero highlighted the use of certified sustainable palm-oil to that avoids these poor practices by working with local wildlife experts, stopping further deforestation for farming land, and reducing the impact on the environment.</p>



<p>It was great to hear from a business that operates locally in our area that is tackling global issues and to talk to the charitable organisations that were supporting these efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="667" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3376" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg 1000w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Amber Valley Borough Council elections 4th May 2023 &amp; Parish/Town Council elections:</u></strong></p>



<p>On the 4th May 2023, elections were held for Amber Valley Borough Council. For the first time in a long time, elections were held for all 42 councillors over 18 wards (rather than the previous recent system of electing a third of councillors each year).</p>



<p>As a result of the election, the Labour Group took control of the Council and have 26 councillors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all who were elected and I look forward to working with the new Borough Council where needed and holding them to account where necessary too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find your borough councillor <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All the parish and town councils in Amber Valley were also up for election. You can find the results of these <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections/parish-and-town-councils/">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Access to Cash &#8211; Nationwide Heanor:</u></strong></p>



<p>I know for many constituents a key concern has been the closures of bank branches in our area.</p>



<p>Although banking is increasingly moving online, in-person branches are still relied upon by many in our communities and are staples in our high streets. People need access to bank branches so that they can speak to someone in person about their accounts and finances.</p>



<p>I was able to visit Nationwide in Heanor to discuss this issue and was reassured that they understood the important role they play on our high streets and intend to stay open for the foreseeable future.</p>



<p>I was also able to discuss the work they are doing to help vulnerable people more broadly, including their cost-of-living helpline, fraud prevention and work to teach useful financial skills to young people.</p>



<p>I’ll continue to support maintaining access to bank branches and cash in our communities and town centres.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="636" height="791" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3375" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg 636w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-241x300.jpeg 241w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Nieper Foundation visit:</u></strong></p>



<p>In Alfreton I joined Robert Halfon, the Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education, in a visit related to the Christopher Nieper Education Trust. The Trust was set up to allow David Nieper Ltd to invest in local education and help young people into long-term, rewarding employment.</p>



<p>We visited David Nieper Ltd and met with Dr Hobbs, the Headteacher of David Nieper Academy, others who are supporting the work of the Trust and met with a student to do an interview for the Spirit of Alfreton. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684233937.JPG" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong><u>Local primary school visits:</u></strong></p>



<p>I have also able to visit both Mundy Junior School and Heage Primary School to speak to teachers and school leaders about funding.</p>



<p>With schools also being hit with high energy bills, there was concern that planned increases to teacher’s salaries and additional provisions for students would not be fully funded if prices for heating stay high. I was able to talk to teachers about the worry this is causing.</p>



<p>It is only right that any increases to staff pay are properly covered by increased investment into schools and it is important that the Government has contingency plans and funding in place to reassure schools that they will be supported should energy bills stay high.</p>



<p><strong><u>Windows for Ukraine:</u></strong></p>



<p>I also took part in a visit to CPR Manufacturing in Alfreton, who are supporting a project called Windows for Ukraine. Cromwell Polythene is manufacturing polyethylene film used to make effective temporary windows as part of a project called Insulate Ukraine. The company have donated some of the film being used, which is an alternative to glass and insulates homes better than double-glazing. The local business usually manufactures bin liner products.</p>



<p><strong><u>Collis engineering visit &amp; 5G masts:</u></strong></p>



<p>To look at their new 5G masts I&#8217;ve also been to see Collis Engineering Ltd. They&#8217;re manufacturing a new mast and tower system to support the rollout of 5G and which has a high headload capacity, meaning several operators can share the same structure and system. Collis are an important local employer and it was good to learn more about this innovation that is being manufactured right here in the heart of Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that access to telephone and broadband signal remains an issue for many residents, so hopefully this innovation will help with that, and I&#8217;ll continue to pursue solutions for areas where there are concerns or problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684234142.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Street Watch:</h1>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Social Security Health Assessments System <span style="color:#06396a;">Has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>The cross party Work and Pensions Select Committee responsible for scrutinising the Department for Work and Pensions’ (DWP) policies, has published a damning report on the Government’s health assessments system which is used to screen whether sick and disabled people should have access to vital social security payments.</p>
<p>These payments provide financial support to a working age person who is unable to work because of their health condition or disability; the assessment for this is the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) and is for either Employment Support Allowance or Universal Credit Limited Capability to Work. In addition there is also the Personal Independence Payment (PIP) assessment process to access support to cover the extra costs disabled people face because of their disability which are estimated at over £580 a month on average; this is for the Personal Independence Payment.</p>
<p>The report exposed the detrimental impact of the assessment process itself on the health and well being of claimants.</p>
<p>Giving evidence to the Committee, Professor Ben Barr, from the University of Liverpool, was asked about research he carried out in 2015 which looked at the impacts of the WCA as claimants were reassessed to move onto Employment Support Allowance. His analysis estimated that across England, the WCA had caused an additional 600 suicides, 300,000 additional cases of mental health problems and a large rise in the prescribing of antidepressants over a nine-year period.</p>
<p>“We looked at whether it could be explained by other factors or other economic trends, but there was quite a unique pattern in the increase in mental health problems, and the most likely explanation was that it was due to the reassessment process”, he told the committee. He said it is difficult to assess improvements since this study as “there are no systems in place” to monitor the impact of the health assessments and the potential adverse outcomes.</p>
<p>A survey by the University of Kent last year found half of claimants who have been through the WCA process said it made their mental health worse. Dr Ben Baumberg Geiger, who led the research, told the committee: “It is not sufficient to say that this is a historical problem and that everything is fine now. If there was more transparency, it would be easier to know a bit more about it, but the evidence suggests that there are still major problems with the WCA that could lead to an increased risk of poor mental health.”</p>
<p>Debbie Abrahams the Member of Parliament for Oldham East and Saddleworth and a Member of the Work and Pensions Select Committee said:</p>
<p><em>“The evidence is clear – the current system is not fit for purpose. The DWP’s own figures show that <strong><u>274 people a month</u></strong> <strong><u>die 6 months after being found fit for work </u></strong>and <strong><u>60 people a month die 3 months after having PIP refused. </u></strong>These are poorly people not the shirkers and scroungers that some Conservatives refer to when discussing social security claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“We heard evidence during the inquiry that when people were being reassessed between 2010 and 2013, there were 600 additional suicides. In 2020, National Audit Office has said that the claimant deaths that the DWP had investigated were the tip of the iceberg. The current approach is contributing, directly and indirectly, to the physical and mental health harm of claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“Last year the Equality Watchdog, The Equality and Human Rights Commission, issued a Section 23 order against the Department of Work and Pensions over their discriminatory treatment of disabled claimants.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Government itself has effectively acknowledged a different approach is needed when they announced that they would abolition the Work Capability Assessments, something I have been calling for years, but the detail of the future process is too opaque and doesn’t provide reassurance. Given it will take place several years to replace, what happens until then?</em></p>
<p><em>“I remain deeply concerned about these health assessments but also about the punitive nature of the sanctions regime, introduced in 2012 and, once again, on the rise. </em></p>
<p><em>“I believe it is these social security policies, as well as the inadequacy of the social security support especially for working age people, and the dehumanising culture that claimants too often experience that collectively contribute to the adverse health effects is the It is so detrimental to vulnerable people especially, but to all people as well.</em></p>
<p><em>“Given the failure of the Government to make many of the changes recommended in our predecessor Committee in 2018, I hold little hope in them taking on board the improvements set out in the report.”</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7098</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
    <category term="Department for Work and Pensions"/>
    <category term="Health Assessment"/>
    <category term="Social Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>St Helens Mobile Pantry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2023/04/18/st-helens-mobile-pantry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7624</id>
    <published>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes school debaters to Downing Street</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/03/29/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-school-debaters-to-downing-street/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament before their visit to Number Ten. The day was rounded off by a Q&amp;amp;A session with Matt and the competition judges as well as guests from Parliament including House of Commons Library Director of Research Edward Wood. The panel passed on their careers advice as well as explaining some of the opportunities available in politics besides being an MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4189 aligncenter" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the visit &lt;strong&gt;Matt Warman MP commented&lt;/strong&gt; ‘I was keen to establish a debating competition to encourage students to think deeply about some of the issues facing our society and, crucially, to equip them with the skills to consider both sides of a complex argument. Today’s visit to the home of modern democracy was an excellent opportunity to see those skills in action with students having the chance to observe opposition MPs challenging Ministers at the despatch box. I look forward to next year’s programme and on a broader note, am always happy to welcome schools in my constituency to Parliament.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chair of Governors at Boston High School Lisa Smith&lt;/strong&gt; who accompanied the visit said ‘This was a wonderful opportunity for our students to see democracy in action – and to be inspired by the opportunities for careers in parliament. We are grateful to Matt for arranging the debate competition and the visit and look forward to defending our winner’s trophy next year!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4187 alignnone" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-768x576.png 768w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4188 alignright" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4186</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="pbs-main-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="//blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgPGr6SMD45ood6qhiuu4blT62kHviIBP6ckpE65JIBe6BV4lwfD_ljqSW6Yfh3INMQ01Hq2IglXwA8RYJBvaG3TNP9bm646Qr4SeQjTadGOm9f0ATEqV7u3pFvBanBHg/s220/Labour+4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=ROJpTLyg" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-64904aa207c93" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-64904aa207c93').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"64904aa207c93","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-64904aa207c93" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-64904aa207c93" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="64904aa207c93" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_64904aa207c93" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_64904aa207c93" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_64904aa207c93" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_64904aa207c93" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_64904aa207c93" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_64904aa207c93" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_64904aa207c93_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-64904aa207c93 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxzqm9JrJkHwEKp_DVLm3qjBM7-kDhPcmSW03XVvVVfN4XKxC9-iEBsIsMDzoff2LtjOMorAmtGalVlfePVlA' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhgWOtViNTWZUKIZ7kYL0nvU_TB1vTIlyfy6c2hOYUjDUWjHn0fS4lV3RKEy0FbSs1Op_wlbHJMkd1fsc3GmRYy7ZLdcf7NII9s64Dg9e1WaE3Gssj9jjosABrXEBz2Kg/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>2</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
