<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-01-26T18:32:16Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Birmingham&#8217;s Bids Binned]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/26/birminghams-bids-binned/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6691</id>
		<updated>2023-01-26T15:40:17Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-26T15:40:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="austerity"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Levelling up"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="midlands"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="tories"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="west midlands"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Tories have been in charge for thirteen years. During that time we’ve seen the NHS driven to the verge of collapse, our schools are falling apart, the police and justice system is in turmoil, and homelessness has reached crisis point. Still this government denies responsibility and looks elsewhere for scapegoats. At the 2019 election<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/26/birminghams-bids-binned/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Birmingham&#8217;s Bids Binned</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/26/birminghams-bids-binned/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>The Tories have been in charge for thirteen years. During that time we’ve seen the NHS driven to the verge of collapse, our schools are falling apart, the police and justice system is in turmoil, and homelessness has reached crisis point. Still this government denies responsibility and looks elsewhere for scapegoats.</p>



<p>At the 2019 election the Tories promised to fix things by levelling up. Last week, in Birmingham, we saw the reality of those promises. Bids to regenerate Druids Heath in my constituency, one of the poorest parts of the country, Erdington and Northfield high streets didn’t get a penny, while the PM’s wealthy rural constituency was rewarded with an astonishing £19 million. Over £350 million went to projects which have nothing to do with levelling up, like the £45 million allocated to improve roads to Dover.</p>



<p>In Birmingham 42% of children are growing up in poverty, there’s a 10 year gap in life expectancy between the richest and poorest areas, and our unemployment rate is double the national average. Even Tory Mayor Andy Street, who we’re normally told has a hotline to Downing Street, has been driven to complain about the ‘begging bowl culture’. It leaves those places most in need to fend for themselves, while those with less call for public funds but a large number of Tory marginal seats have hit the jackpot.</p>



<p>After 13 years it’s hard not to come to the conclusion that the only people doing well under the Tories are those who evade their taxes and donors who get seats in the House of Lords or cushy roles in public bodies. Not only has this government failed to level up, it’s done the opposite through acts of vandalism which have destroyed our public services.</p>



<p>The British people who are properly paying their taxes are paying at the highest levels for 70 years. Our growth rates are at their lowest levels since the 1700s. The deficit, which the Tories used as an excuse to cut public expenditure, is now a permanent feature and public debt is at its highest level for 40 years.</p>



<p>We can’t afford the Tories any longer.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/26/birminghams-bids-binned/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/26/birminghams-bids-binned/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby joins campaign to shut down the UK fur trade</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/26/toby-joins-campaign-to-shut-down-the-uk-fur-trade/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/26/toby-joins-campaign-to-shut-down-the-uk-fur-trade/">Toby joins campaign to shut down the UK fur trade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/26/toby-joins-campaign-to-shut-down-the-uk-fur-trade/">Toby joins campaign to shut down the UK fur trade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5175</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T14:44:43Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T14:44:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local organisations encouraged to share in £8.76 million available across Boston and East Lindsey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/01/26/uk-shared-prosperity-fund/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boston Borough and East Lindsey District Councils have invited local organisations to submit expressions of interest for the funding.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK Shared Prosperity fund and the Rural England Prosperity Fund have awarded £6.14 million and £2.62 million to East Lindsey and Boston respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcoming the announcement, MP for Boston and Skegness Matt Warman said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This £8.76 million Shared Prosperity funding to Boston and East Lindsey comes on top of the £70.3 million Town Deals and £22.8 million in Levelling Up Funding and shows the Government&amp;#8217;s commitment to Levelling Up Boston, East Lindsey and Lincolnshire as a whole. It represents a huge vote of confidence in the vision for regeneration and growth put forward by Boston and East Lindsey Councils and the Town Deal boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The request for expressions of interest for projects meeting the three priorities of this latest fund is a great opportunity for even more local organisations to join in driving innovation, growth and community in our area.'&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full bidding guide for the funding and the expression of interest form is available on the Council&amp;#8217;s website at&lt;a href="http://www.e-lindsey.gov.uk/UKSPF"&gt;http://www.e-lindsey.gov.uk/UKSPF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.boston.gov.uk/UKSPF"&gt;www.boston.gov.uk/UKSPF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the full details here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Lindsey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/eastlindseydistrictcouncil/posts/pfbid0QVp5pXNH9zacbgmZeBot7kkTpzSEXmTnpSnEjBWygbW2UWFbGHak5X5LYkBWBanxl"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/eastlindseydistrictcouncil/posts/pfbid0QVp5pXNH9zacbgmZeBot7kkTpzSEXmTnpSnEjBWygbW2UWFbGHak5X5LYkBWBanxl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boston&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/BostonBoroughCouncil/posts/pfbid03wtoKqq6ma4Fya4rEw8mvPksQ3Ti5GqQxPWQtyDQA9wCicsFuzhMjh6H9DezhygPl"&gt;https://www.facebook.com/BostonBoroughCouncil/posts/pfbid03wtoKqq6ma4Fya4rEw8mvPksQ3Ti5GqQxPWQtyDQA9wCicsFuzhMjh6H9DezhygPl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Boston Borough and East Lindsey District Councils have invited local organisations to submit expressions of interest for the funding. The UK Shared Prosperity fund and the Rural England Prosperity Fund have awarded £6.14 million and £2.62 million to East Lindsey and Boston respectively. Welcoming the announcement, MP for Boston and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4151</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T14:21:52Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T14:21:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More likely to be hit by lightning twice than be the victim of voter fraud!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/01/more-likely-to-be-hit-by-lightning-twice-than-be-the-victim-of-voter-fraud/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;You&amp;#39;re more likely to be hit by lightning *twice* than be the victim of voter fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the Tories want to spend £180m on forcing &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/VoterID?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#VoterID&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f5f3.png" alt="🗳" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2705.png" alt="✅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;Protect your vote ahead of the local elections by applying for a postal vote: &lt;a href="https://t.co/iytSUerARk"&gt;https://t.co/iytSUerARk&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/HEbGj4U867"&gt;pic.twitter.com/HEbGj4U867&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f499.png" alt="💙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1618547707282620416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 26, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apply from a Postal Vote to avoid ID issues at the Poling Station:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.newcastle.gov.uk/services/postal-and-proxy-voting"&gt;https://www.newcastle.gov.uk/services/postal-and-proxy-voting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">You're more likely to be hit by lightning *twice* than be the victim of voter fraud. Yet the Tories want to spend £180m on forcing #VoterID. 🗳️✅Protect your vote ahead of the local elections by applying for a postal vote:… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13179</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T13:57:45Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T13:57:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HOLOCAUST MEMORIAL DAY 2023 MARKED IN PARLIAMENT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/01/26/holocaust-memorial-day-2023-marked-in-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has marked Holocaust Memorial Day 2023 in parliament by signing the Holocaust Educational Trust’s Book of Commitment.</p>



<p>Local MP Docherty-Hughes pledged his commitment to Holocaust Memorial Day and honouring those who were murdered during the Holocaust. The parliamentarian also paid tribute to the extraordinary Holocaust survivors who work tirelessly to educate young people today.</p>



<p>Holocaust Memorial Day falls on 27th January every year, the anniversary of the liberation of the infamous former Nazi concentration and death camp, Auschwitz-Birkenau, in 1945. Across the UK – and world – people will come together to remember the horrors of the past.</p>



<p>In the lead up to and on Holocaust Memorial Day, thousands of commemorative events are arranged by schools, faith groups and community organisations across the country, remembering all the victims of the Holocaust and subsequent genocides. The theme for this year’s commemorations is ‘Ordinary People’.</p>



<p>On Holocaust Memorial Day we also remember and pay tribute to all of those persecuted by the Nazis, including Roma and Sinti people, disabled people, gay men, political opponents to the Nazis and others. We also remember all of those affected by genocide since, in Cambodia, Rwanda, Bosnia and Darfur.</p>



<p><strong>Commenting, Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:</strong></p>



<p>“Holocaust Memorial Day is an important opportunity for people in West Dunbartonshire and across the country to reflect on the darkest times of European history.</p>



<p>“Through my work in parliament I have been privileged to meet survivors of the Holocaust. Their testimonies serve as a powerful reminder of the horrors of the past; and for the sake of future generations they must never be forgotten.</p>



<p>“Today, I pledge to remember the six million Jewish men, women and children who were murdered in Holocaust, as well as the millions of others persecuted by the Nazis including Roma and Sinti people, black people, gay people, mentally and physically disabled people.</p>



<p>“We cannot ever be complacent in standing up to hatred, discrimination and intolerance.”</p>



<p><strong>Karen Pollock CBE, Chief Executive of the Holocaust Educational Trust, said:</strong></p>



<p>“On Holocaust Memorial Day we remember the 6 million men, women and children who were murdered by the Nazis and their collaborators, simply for being Jewish, and we pay tribute to the incredible survivors, many of whom still share their testimony day in and day out to ensure that future generations never forget the horrors of the past.</p>



<p>“We also remember that antisemitism did not start or end with the Holocaust, we must all be vigilant, and speak out whenever it is found.”</p>



<p><strong><em>Further information on Holocaust Memorial Day 2023 is available at: <a href="https://www.het.org.uk/hmd-2023">https://www.het.org.uk/hmd-2023</a></em></strong></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has marked Holocaust Memorial Day 2023 in parliament by signing the Holocaust Educational Trust’s Book of Commitment. Local MP Docherty-Hughes pledged his commitment to Holocaust Memorial Day and honouring those who were murdered during the Holocaust. The parliamentarian also paid tribute to the extraordinary Holocaust survivors who work tirelessly to ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="HOLOCAUST MEMORIAL DAY 2023 MARKED IN PARLIAMENT" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/01/26/holocaust-memorial-day-2023-marked-in-parliament/#more-1821527" aria-label="More on HOLOCAUST MEMORIAL DAY 2023 MARKED IN PARLIAMENT">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821527</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T12:11:14Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T12:11:14Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Holocaust Memorial Day"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex responds to DEFRA crustacean die-offs report]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/alex-responds-to-defra-crustacean-die-offs-report/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14628</id>
		<updated>2023-01-26T12:11:03Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-26T12:11:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Today the government have been found out – but it is the people of Teesside who have paid the price. For over fifteen months I and others across Teesside, North Yorkshire and County Durham have been calling for answers on the mass crustacean die-offs that have blighted our environment and have had a detrimental impact [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/alex-responds-to-defra-crustacean-die-offs-report/">Alex responds to DEFRA crustacean die-offs report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP statement ahead of proposed teachers strikes </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-statement-ahead-proposed-teachers-strikes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP says,  
‘’Whilst any decision to close schools will be for individual headteachers and their governing bodies, I know that schools in Basingstoke will be doing everything possible to ensure that strike action does not affect young people’s education. This is particularly pressing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-statement-ahead-proposed-teachers-strikes</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brendan Clarke-Smith MP - Business Questions to the Leader of the House</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-business-questions-leader-house" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">3G Pitches - One issue I have been approached about is access to local public sports facilities, especially with all-weather surfaces. Today I raised this issue in the House of Commons.
“I very much welcome this Government’s commitment to sport and its many benefits, particularly those linked to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-business-questions-leader-house</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My View on the Strikes (Minimum Service Levels) Bill </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/my-view-strikes-minimum-service-levels-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to share my thoughts on the new Strikes (Minimum Service Levels) Bill that the Government has introduced.
As many of you know, this bill will make sure that important public services like healthcare, education, fire and rescue, transportation, and more, maintain a basic level of function…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/my-view-strikes-minimum-service-levels-bill</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP votes against plans to let water companies dump sewage into lakes and rivers until 2038</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439613/mp-votes-against-plans-to-let-water-companies-dump-sewage-into-lakes-and-rivers-until-2038"/>
  <updated>2023-01-26T11:37:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439613/mp-votes-against-plans-to-let-water-companies-dump-sewage-into-lakes-and-rivers-until-2038</id>
  <summary type="text">Last night in Parliament, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron voted against controversial Government plans to let water companies continue to discharge sewage into lakes and rivers for the next 15 years.
Under the Environment Act, the Government is obliged to bring forward new binding environmental targets.
The new legilsation set a target of an 80% reduction in phosphates in rivers by 2038. Phosphates are naturally occurring minerals found in human waste and can lead to a dramatic growth in algae and deplete oxygen levels when they are dumped in rivers.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last night in Parliament, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron voted against controversial Government plans to let water companies continue to discharge sewage into lakes and rivers for the next 15 years.</p>
<p>Under the Environment Act, the Government is obliged to bring forward new binding environmental targets.</p>
<p>The new legilsation set a target of an 80% reduction in phosphates in rivers by 2038. Phosphates are naturally occurring minerals found in human waste and can lead to a dramatic growth in algae and deplete oxygen levels when they are dumped in rivers.</p>
<p>However, the regulation was approved by Conservative MPs, by 300 votes to 170.</p>
<p>According to the Rivers Trust. water companies dumped sewage more than 2,800 times in South Lakeland in 2021 for a duration of 36,265 hours.</p>
<p>This included:</p>
<p>- 1172 hours at Staveley wastewater treatment works into the River Kent</p>
<p>- 1348 hours at Grasmere wastewater treatment works into Grasmere Lake</p>
<p>- 1372 hours at Hawkshead wastewater treatment works into Black Beck</p>
<p>- 1809 hours at Milnthorpe sewage treatment plant into the River Bela</p>
<p>- 2710 hours at Coniston wastewater treatment works into Church Beck</p>
<p>Speaking after the vote, Tim said: <em>"This is a pathetic target which allows water companies to get away with a staggering 15 more years of shameful sewage dumping. This is a betrayal of the British public who rightly want tougher action against water companies.</em></p>
<p><em>"The water companies that are responsible for dumping sewage into our rivers, lakes and coastal waters every day, now have 15 years to clean up their act. Meanwhile their top execs have paid themselves £51 million, including £30.6 million in bonuses over the last two years.</em></p>
<p><em>"Conservative MPs should be ashamed of themselves. It will be swimmers and treasured wildlife which pay the price for today's flimsy target. Water company execs will be cheering this through parliament. I am proud the Liberal Democrats voted against these unacceptable targets."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surgeries February 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/01/26/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>My next constituency surgery will take place on <strong>Friday 3rd February</strong> in Troon.</p>



<p>Please note, however, in order to comply with both Covid and security protocol, these will not be drop-in surgeries – <strong>appointments must be made in advance</strong>.</p>



<p>To book, please call 01294 311 160 or email philippa.whitford.mp@parliament.uk </p>



<p>For scheduled dates and times, please see below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/MP-SURGERY.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2683" srcset="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/MP-SURGERY.png 940w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/MP-SURGERY-300x251.png 300w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/MP-SURGERY-768x644.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px"/></figure>



<p/>



<p><em><strong>Please note that all surgery dates are subject to change dependent upon Covid guidelines and Parliamentary business. </strong></em></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202023" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202023" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202023" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202023" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202023" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F01%2F26%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2%2F&amp;title=Surgeries%20February%202023" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/01/26/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2/" data-a2a-title="Surgeries February 2023"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/01/26/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2/">Surgeries February 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My next constituency surgery will take place on Friday 3rd February in Troon. Please note, ... <a title="Surgeries February 2023" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/01/26/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/01/26/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2/">Surgeries February 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2682</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T10:56:43Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T10:56:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Surgeries"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit wins</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/01/26/brexit-wins-3/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We voted for Brexit because we once again wanted to live in an independent country. We want our laws and taxes settled in Parliament by MPs that we can vote out of office if they do not please. Elections empower voters to get change. A sovereign Parliament can do what it takes to promote the freedoms and prosperity of the British people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In 2019 we had to vote again to get Brexit through owing to the obstructions of all too many MPs. The voters showed they knew the way to get their will done by removing many of the MPs who were thwarting Brexit. Now we are legally out of the EU the government needs to do more to exercise the Brexit freedoms we have gained.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There have already been some good wins from exit. We  no longer have to make large contributions to the EU. As promised NHS spending has increased, by  more than the savings from Brexit so far. We no longer have to accept the accumulating debts and liabilities of the EU. Since we left the EU has started to borrow large sums in its own name to spend mainly in the financially stressed  countries of the Union. All that debt becomes a burden on the taxpayers of all  the member states, the only source of money to pay for it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out of the EU we were able to pursue our own vaccine and covid strategy, getting to a vaccine earlier than the EU and allowing us to get out of lockdown before many continental countries. We are pressing ahead with different approaches to the regulation of science and medical advance, to assist in the development of UK excellence in those fields like gene editing. Faced with a shortage of drivers over lockdowns, we were able to flex our regulations temporarily  to help solve the problems. We cancelled VAT on female hygiene products and suspended it on green investments for five years.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wild pessimism of Remain forecasts for the economy did not come true when we voted to leave. We did not see a rise in unemployment, a fall in house prices, a rise in interest rates in 2016 on the vote nor in 2020 on departing. Our trade with non EU countries is expanding, and we have completed a series of new trade deals with non EU countries. We may well soon join the  very large Trans Pacific Trade Partnership,something we could not do as members of the EU.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We have been able to rebuild old valued friendships and alliances. The UK damaged important ties with Australia, New Zealand and Canada on joining the EEC. Today we are building a wider relationship on the back of our 5 Eyes Intelligence grouping and with new trade and investment links  possible.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many of us are far happier now we are out. We are impatient to show more Brexit wins by changing laws and repealing taxes the EU imposed. Our happiness resides in the knowledge that our Parliament can  now make the right decisions and laws for us if it wishes, and we can change the Parliament if it refuses. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We voted for Brexit because we once again wanted to live in an independent country. We want our laws and taxes settled in Parliament by MPs that we can vote out of office if they do not please. Elections empower voters to get change. A sovereign Parliament can do what it takes to promote the…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=34324</id>
    <published>2023-01-26T05:09:27Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-26T05:09:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>We've recruited extra 196 Police Officers in Herts</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2162-we-ve-recruited-extra-196-police-officers-in-herts"/>
		<published>2023-01-25T20:43:13+00:00</published>
		<updated>2023-01-25T20:43:13+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2162-we-ve-recruited-extra-196-police-officers-in-herts</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’ve recruited an extra 196 Police Officers in Hertfordshire, as part of 16,753 officers we’ve recruited so far since 2019. We have more Police than ever before locally cracking down on crime &amp;amp; tackling violence against women &lt;a href="https://t.co/Nb7yc5CxZJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Nb7yc5CxZJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1618328092937691146?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 25, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We’ve recruited an extra 196 Police Officers in Hertfordshire, as part of 16,753 officers we’ve recruited so far since 2019. We have more Police than ever before locally cracking down on crime &amp;amp; tackling violence against women &lt;a href="https://t.co/Nb7yc5CxZJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Nb7yc5CxZJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1618328092937691146?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 25, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE MARKS HOLOCAUST MEMORIAL DAY</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/hmd2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Newcastle North MP and Co-Chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group Against Antisemitism this week signed the Holocaust Educational Trust’s Book of Commitment in Parliament, pledging to honour those who were murdered during the Holocaust as well as paying tribute to the extraordinary Holocaust survivors who work tirelessly to educate young people today.  Holocaust Memorial … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/hmd2023/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE MARKS HOLOCAUST MEMORIAL DAY</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7830</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T12:02:59Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T12:02:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="laest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: The Worst is Yet to Come</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-the-worst-is-yet-to-come/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-the-worst-is-yet-to-come" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content"&gt;&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"&gt;&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Sometimes a week in Westminster can be momentous, some days even infamous &amp;#8211; last week was something else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On Monday, the Tories passed a bill that was nothing short of an attack on workers&amp;#8217; rights, specifically the basic right to withdraw labour in disputes. They were happy to clap nurses, but now they want to make it easier to sack them. Families in every community are struggling to put food on the table or heat their home because of the direct actions of this UK Government&amp;#8217;s handling of the economy but instead of apology and support, they are looking for scapegoats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Tuesday came, and with it, an attack on democracy and devolution. The UK Government chose to weaponise legislation passed by two-thirds of MSPs to flex its muscles over Scotland&amp;#8217;s Parliament and seek to create a diversionary culture war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It seemed things couldn&amp;#8217;t get much worse by Wednesday, but we still had the Retained EU Law bill to debate. Hundreds of you wrote to me to share your dismay at the contents of the bill, and these are concerns I very much share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The sunset clause in this bill means that fundamental rights will be scrapped automatically if not first identified and replaced by the end of the year. Do you trust this Government firstly to have the competence to review thousands of pieces of legislation by the deadline and secondly to make decisions in the interest of the public rather than their donors, cronies and chums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;This UK Government seems intent on destroying hard-fought rights and legislation that protects those who need it most. They also seem determined to undermine devolution at every turn as they attempt to impose more and more direct rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It&amp;#8217;s easy to forget how different decisions taken by the Scottish Parliament impact us every day. Just imagine if Westminster made all the choices?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;We&amp;#8217;d be paying for every prescription, you&amp;#8217;d be paying bedroom tax, we&amp;#8217;d have fewer doctors, nurses, and police officers. Untreated sewage would be allowed to run into our rivers and coastline, just for a start. The list goes on, and it is long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Make to mistake, this UK government is only getting started – they know they&amp;#8217;ve lost voters because of the mess they have made and so are doubling down on their right-wing credentials to stoke division, and it is the most vulnerable who are left paying the highest price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-the-worst-is-yet-to-come/"&gt;ARTICLE: The Worst is Yet to Come&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Sometimes a week in Westminster can be momentous, some days even infamous – last week was something else! On Monday, the Tories passed a bill that was nothing short of an attack on workers’ rights, specifically the basic right to withdraw labour in disputes. They were happy to clap nurses, but now they want to …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-the-worst-is-yet-to-come/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: The Worst is Yet to Come</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-the-worst-is-yet-to-come/">ARTICLE: The Worst is Yet to Come</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7378</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T12:00:13Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T12:00:13Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin signs Holocaust Educational Trust Book of Commitment  </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-signs-holocaust-educational-trust-book-commitment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week Robin signed the Holocaust Educational Trust’s Book of Commitment, in doing so pledging his commitment to Holocaust Memorial Day and honouring those who were murdered during the Holocaust as well as paying tribute to the extraordinary Holocaust survivors who work tirelessly to educate…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-signs-holocaust-educational-trust-book-commitment</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>582 extra local police</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/582-extra-local-police" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A key election commitment in 2019 was to recruit 20,000 extra police officers across the country. New figures today show that 16,573 officers have now been recruited since 2019, with an additional 582 in our local Thames Valley police force.
Significantly, this now brings the total number of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/582-extra-local-police</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Council Leaders Meeting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/council-leaders-meeting" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2597" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">25 January 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Council Leaders Meeting</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Our local councils are on the frontline of the big issues of the day, from housing and social care to transport and business support.</p>

<p>That’s why I appreciated the chance to join my Mid Norfolk councils, Breckland District Council and South Norfolk District Council, for one of our regular catch ups last night.</p>

<p>Together we discussed:</p>

<p>- The Warm Homes initiative</p>

<p>- Local support for Ukrainian refugees</p>

<p>- The Cambridge-Norwich Tech Corridor</p>

<p>- A Norfolk Devolution Deal</p>

<p>As ever, I took the chance to thank our local council leaders and officials for all the work they do for our communities on a daily basis, and I committed to helping them follow up with ministers and officials on a variety of actions.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-01/george_freeman_council_leader_call.png" width="602" height="338" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2597 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T11:35:13Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T11:35:13Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne blasts Tory levelling up ‘scam’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-blasts-tory-levelling-up-scam/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-blasts-tory-levelling-up-scam" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236022" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/tlevelling.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has labelled the Government’s levelling-up agenda a ‘total scam’, after a new report laid bare the scale of regional inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/uk-levelling-up/rishi-sunak-relaunch-government-funding-pledge-2023.html"&gt;Bloomberg’s 2023 Levelling Up Scorecard&lt;/a&gt;, it was highlighted that since 2019 – when the Tories promised to ‘level-up’ neglected regions across the UK – inequalities have widened and key prosperity indicators have fallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across Denton and Reddish, it was revealed that local people have seen their salaries, access to affordable housing, life expectancy and broadband coverage all fall or remain the same since 2019. The report also shows that overall Government spending has declined in the local area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, &lt;a href="https://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/news/greater-manchester-news/levelling-up-fund-slammed-final-26017588"&gt;Gwynne slammed the Government&lt;/a&gt; after Tameside Council’s levelling up bid to transform Denton Town Centre was rejected. Rishi Sunak’s own constituency was awarded funding, leading to accusations of favouritism being levelled at the Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Andrew Gwynne said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These findings reinforce what we’ve long suspected, that Tory levelling up is a total scam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Government explicitly promised that they would level up swathes of neglected regions across the UK, but instead they’ve actively made things worse – it’s shameful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Conservatives have been in power for 13 years, and we’ve nothing to show for it except lower salaries, worse living standards and skyrocketing bills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We need a General Election, and a Labour Government that works in the interests of local people”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/uk-levelling-up/rishi-sunak-relaunch-government-funding-pledge-2023.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full Bloomberg report. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter  wp-image-236023" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" width="713" height="713" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1-300x300.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1-150x150.jpg 150w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1-768x768.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Conservative-Levelling-Down-1.jpg 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 713px) 100vw, 713px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-blasts-tory-levelling-up-scam/"&gt;Gwynne blasts Tory levelling up &amp;#8216;scam&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has labelled the Government’s levelling-up agenda a ‘total scam’, after a new report laid bare the scale of regional inequality. In Bloomberg’s 2023 Levelling Up Scorecard, it was highlighted that since 2019 – when the Tories promised to ‘level-up’ neglected regions across the UK – inequalities have widened […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-blasts-tory-levelling-up-scam/">Gwynne blasts Tory levelling up ‘scam’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236018</id>
    <published>2023-01-25T11:29:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-25T11:29:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Herefordshire and Worcestershire to receive £1,509,000 for mental health services</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/01/24/herefordshire-and-worcestershire-to-receive-1509000-for-mental-health-services/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Government has announced that a £150 million fund will be used to build 150 new facilities to support mental health urgent and emergency care services and up to 100 new specialist mental health ambulances.  £1,509,000 of this fund will... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/01/24/herefordshire-and-worcestershire-to-receive-1509000-for-mental-health-services/#more-4589">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4589</id>
    <published>2023-01-24T17:35:16Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-24T17:35:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz calls for a plan to provide care in the community and clear NHS backlogs]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-plan-to-tackle-waits-for-social-care/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=12044</id>
		<updated>2023-01-24T16:59:44Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-24T16:57:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ministers will never deal with the record waits for NHS treatment until they stop older people being stuck in hospital because they cannot get decent social care in the community or at home.<br />
Yet after 13 years of the Conservative Government there are now 540k people waiting to have their social care needs assessed &#38; reviewed. Ministers haven’t got a plan to sort this crisis and to stop people ending up in hospital when they don’t need to be there.<br />
I called on the Government to put this right today in Parliament.&#160;&#160;<br />
You ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-plan-to-tackle-waits-for-social-care/">Liz calls for a plan to provide care in the community and clear NHS backlogs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-plan-to-tackle-waits-for-social-care/"><![CDATA[<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-12044-1" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/HEALTH-QS-2-JAN.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/HEALTH-QS-2-JAN.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/HEALTH-QS-2-JAN.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Ministers will never deal with the record waits for NHS treatment until they stop older people being stuck in hospital because they cannot get decent social care in the community or at home.</p>
<p>Yet after 13 years of the Conservative Government there are now 540k people waiting to have their social care needs assessed &amp; reviewed. Ministers haven’t got a plan to sort this crisis and to stop people ending up in hospital when they don’t need to be there.</p>
<p>I called on the Government to put this right today in Parliament.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can see my question to the Minister in the clip above or read it<a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-01-24/debates/08886250-29D0-470C-9799-F185E4F9261C/Covid-19BacklogElectiveCare#contribution-BA2747C7-C82B-418B-B3E4-262A8E386D50"> here</a></p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-7888" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/taking-on-ukip-over-the-eu-2/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/SpectatorEUdebate_24-150x150.jpg" alt="Taking on UKIP over the EU" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/taking-on-ukip-over-the-eu-2/" class="wp_rp_title">Taking on UKIP over the EU</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-6677" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-stands-firmly-on-the-side-of-older-workers-and-family-carers/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/20.jpg" alt="Labour stands firmly on the side of older workers and family carers" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-stands-firmly-on-the-side-of-older-workers-and-family-carers/" class="wp_rp_title">Labour stands firmly on the side of older workers and family carers</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-9628" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-backs-cancer-awareness-campaign/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Liz-with-Cancer-Research-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz backs cancer awareness campaign" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-backs-cancer-awareness-campaign/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz backs cancer awareness campaign</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-2113" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tory-liberal-budget-will-hit-poorest-hardest/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/15.jpg" alt="Tory-Liberal Budget will hit poorest hardest" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tory-liberal-budget-will-hit-poorest-hardest/" class="wp_rp_title">Tory-Liberal Budget will hit poorest hardest</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-2868" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/1-3bn-care-cuts-for-vulnerable-elderly/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/1.jpg" alt="£1.3bn care cuts for vulnerable elderly" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/1-3bn-care-cuts-for-vulnerable-elderly/" class="wp_rp_title">£1.3bn care cuts for vulnerable elderly</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-plan-to-tackle-waits-for-social-care/">Liz calls for a plan to provide care in the community and clear NHS backlogs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/HEALTH-QS-2-JAN.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="0" type=""/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Levelling Up Fund &amp; Local Jobs Fair</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/levelling-up-fund-local-jobs-fair/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Folkestone last week received a multi-million pound regeneration boost from the government’s Levelling Up fund. Following a successful bid from Folkestone and Hythe District Council, we will receive an over £19million grant from the government which will be invested in improving the town centre. Over the past decade we have seen a tremendous regeneration of […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6237</id>
    <published>2023-01-24T14:25:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-24T14:25:17Z</updated>
    <category term="My Articles"/>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Backs Calls to Re-Open Well-Used Beverley Rail Crossing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-backs-calls-re-open-well-used-beverley-rail-crossing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart MP has backed calls to re-open the England Springs Level Crossing, closed last month without prior notice.
 
Network Rail has closed the popular pedestrian crossing, used by over a hundred people on an average day.
 
Minster and Woodmansey Councillors Kerri Harold and David Elvidge…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-backs-calls-re-open-well-used-beverley-rail-crossing</id>
    <published>2023-01-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-188" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">With yet more strikes last week, legislation to tackle the unfair disruption to people’s lives caused by strike action had its second reading last week.
The Strike (Minimum Service Levels) Bill will ensure that the necessary number of workers in the public sector are given work notices on the day…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-188</id>
    <published>2023-01-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>City Art Centre Reveals Exhibitions Programme for 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13634/city-art-centre-reveals-exhibitions-programme-for-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The City Art Centre, Edinburgh, dedicated to championing historic and contemporary Scottish visual arts and crafts, announces an exciting range of exhibitions for 2023.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13634/city-art-centre-reveals-exhibitions-programme-for-2023</id>
    <published>2023-01-23T12:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-23T12:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>£150 Million to Support Mental Health Services </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/ps150-million-support-mental-health-services" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the Government has announced investment of £150 million in NHS mental health urgent and emergency care services.
£143 million will fund 150 new facilities centred on improving mental health crisis response infrastructure across the country. This includes over 30 schemes providing crisis cafes…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/ps150-million-support-mental-health-services</id>
    <published>2023-01-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Question to the DWP Ministers on Supporting People into Work</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-dwp-ministers-supporting-people-work" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The best solution for low-income families is not increases in universal credit but access to better-paid employment, so will the Minister join me in encouraging the 1,130 universal credit claimants in Broadland to come to my jobs fair on 10 March at Taverham High School?</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-dwp-ministers-supporting-people-work</id>
    <published>2023-01-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Barking and Dagenham Talking Therapies</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/barking-and-dagenham-talking-therapies" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Barking and Dagenham Talking Therapies</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-01-23T10:16:00+00:00">Mon, 01/23/2023 - 10:16</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1179 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-23T10:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-23T10:16:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A local plea to detoxify comment on my social media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/01/a-local-plea-to-detoxify-comment-on-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">After receiving the following email from a constituent – which I publish by permission – I decided to take new steps to detoxify comment on my social media: I am writing to you after having spoken to [XXX] about how horrified and upset I get when I go to your FB account. I love seeing the posts and photos of the various places you go in my town and the local organisations you visit and then promote.  What I hate […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18618</id>
    <published>2023-01-23T10:05:21Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-23T10:05:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Democracy"/>
    <category term="Social media"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up :: 20 January 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/20/weekly-round-up-20-january-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-20-january-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>I started the week celebrating the Samaritans Brew Monday. This was a chance to enjoy a cuppa and a catch up with friends and colleagues in Parliament. It was excellent to meet with Samaritans volunteers to hear about the work they have been doing and to learn so much more about how people often just call them to talk and share. Please remember how important it is to share with someone.</p>
<p>It’s important that we take the time to pause, put the kettle on, and have a chat with those around us. It’s too easy to ask, “How are you?”, receive the answer, “Fine, thanks,” and to move on. Sometimes we need to ask more and make it clear that we have the time and the willingness to listen and care. Saving lives cannot wait – the Government have to take action now. As a society, we need to start listening.</p>
<p>The news that serving Met police officer David Carrick commited dozens of rape and sexual offences has shocked society and caused anger at vetting procedures and code of practice. I have previously taken part in the police service parliamentary scheme with both the Metropolitan police and the Avon and Somerset police. During that scheme, I joined police officers going into the homes and situations of the country’s most vulnerable people, overwhelmingly women. That women cannot be confident about police officers is abhorrent. In some of the worst situations that you can imagine, women must be able to trust police enough to reach out for help. The Home Office needs to get a grip, ensure that proper vetting procedures are in place, and that the culture within the police changes so that monsters like Carrick cannot get away with committing such heinous crimes.</p>
<p>This week the UK Tory Government triggered Section 35 of the Scotland Act following the passing of the Gender Recognition Reform Act by the Scottish Parliament. I’m proud that the last Labour Government secured devolution via the Scotland Act, and also passed the Gender Recognition Act and the Equality Act. It’s vital that these laws work with each other in harmony. This means we need to have a grown-up discussion on how we achieve this. This is now looks set to be debated in the courts.</p>
<p>The second issue that is related to the above is that this serious and complicated debate is not being held in the respectful and calm way the issues warrant. It is not acceptable for people who stand up for women’s rights and who raise legitimate concerns about the fears of women to have their safe spaces removed to be constantly badgered, attacked, and treated as bigots. We, of course, have to ensure that transgender people are supported and protected in law. This is a complete mess created by the UK Tory Government and SNP Scottish Government playing party politics over the rights of individuals. We must ensure that rights are balanced and not made enemies of each other.</p>
<p>Parliament also focussed on two important laws this week. The first is technically known as the EU (Retained Law) Bill. But would better be described as a Whitehall power grab. All laws passed by British MPs, whilst we were members of the EU to ensure everything was compatible, will be scrapped in one fell swoop under this Bill. Not only is this unworkable – many public bodies have said as much – it will see the biggest move of power from you to the Government. I can see this causing so much chaos and confusion for Bristolian businesses and individuals. What’s being advertised as a bonfire of red tape is likely going to spread and set fire to things we desperately need to keep. </p>
<p>The second Bill Parliament focused on this week was the Online Safety Bill. It’s clear for all to see that social media has become a Wild West when it comes to bullying, discrimination and harassment. There are very few levers of accountability and this must change. The Bill is a missed opportunity to right many wrongs. It has achieved the seemingly impossible of both letting social media giants mark their own homework and grant the UK Government unprecedented powers to determine what you can and can’t see. The ‘legal but harmful’ clause is so vague it will allow a minister to determine content not acceptable in the UK when it’s perfectly fine. Freedom of expression campaigners are seriously concerned and so we should. </p>
<p>It’s great to hear that Filwood Broadway has received over £14.5 million in funding. It will be used to build more homes, community and business spaces in the heart of Knowle West. Our high streets and local areas outside the centre are the beating heart of our cities – they are where we raise our families, where we spend time with friends, where we shop and eat. Levelling up areas like this is vital for improving outcomes across the city and for helping everyone raise their families in safe and pleasant environments. </p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/20/weekly-round-up-20-january-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 20 January 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I started the week celebrating the Samaritans Brew Monday. This was a chance to enjoy a cuppa and a catch […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/20/weekly-round-up-20-january-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 20 January 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3435</id>
    <published>2023-01-20T15:13:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-20T15:13:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-9/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you concerning a couple of local issues.</p>
<h2>ULEZ</h2>
<p>Firstly many of you will be aware that the Mayor of London has decided to widen London’s ultra low emission zone from later this year. This has significant implications for our area.</p>
<p>I won’t get into the politics of this now, except to say that I am strongly opposed to the change at this time because of its impact on our area, on pensioners and people on low incomes with older cars and most significantly those seeking treatment at St Helier or the Marsden. I have asked him to reconsider this aspect of the scheme in particular.</p>
<p>But I thought that I should give you a picture of what the change means for us locally.</p>
<p>The first thing to say is that the plan does not include extending the zone right to the London boundary everywhere. For us the outline ULEZ map says it will not cover the route from Epsom to the M25 via Malden Rushett or from Ewell to Tolworth and the A3 going southwards. There has been some confusion over the status of Rushett Lane and I am checking that with TfL.</p>
<p>It will also not include the north end of Stoneleigh and parts of Worcester Park.</p>
<p>Full details of the plan and what cars are included are here, together with Transport for London’s map of the new extension.</p>
<p><a href="https://tfl.gov.uk/modes/driving/ultra-low-emission-zone/ulez-expansion-2023"><strong>https://tfl.gov.uk/modes/driving/ultra-low-emission-zone/ulez-expansion-2023</strong></a></p>
<p>The target date for the launch is August 29th, though that may slip as some councils are refusing to work with the Mayor to install the cameras that will be needed to make it operational.</p>
<h2>Epsom &amp; Mole Valley Local Plans</h2>
<p>There have been two new developments on the Local Plans which shape the future of housing development in our area – in Epsom and Ewell and Mole Valley.</p>
<p>Epsom and Ewell Borough Council is due to publish its draft plan in the next few days, and this will show the degree to which it has decided to push for development on local green belt land. I very much hope they have chosen to focus on brown field sites and particularly on the potential for the Kiln Lane and Longmead areas.</p>
<p>If you have not previously seen my proposal for the area, you can find it on my website page <strong><a href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/shaping-the-right-plan-for-epsom-and-ewell-a-proposal-from-chris-grayling/">here</a></strong>.</p>
<p>I will include links on my site to the Council’s local plan documents when they are published. Please do take part in the public consultation. This will affect us all.</p>
<p>Meanwhile in Mole Valley, the Council has asked the Planning Inspector to delay consideration of their plans, following the Government’s revision of its national planning policies. It is too early to know if this may affect the plans for Ashtead, but I will keep you posted.</p>
<h2>Energy Support Scheme</h2>
<p>Many thanks to everyone who donated to the Energy Support Scheme. In total we have raised about £45,000 and this is being used by the Good Company, which runs the food bank, and Citizens Advice, to help people struggling with high bills this winter to deal with short term problems with their bills and to buy low energy appliances. I am really grateful to all who have contributed.</p>
<p>If you would still like to help, details are at <a href="http://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme"><strong>www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme</strong></a></p>
<h2>Epsom Citizens Advice</h2>
<p>Finally a word of congratulation to Epsom and Ewell’s Citizens Advice team for putting together a very good financial awareness training programme for local sixth formers, which has been trialled initially at Epsom and Ewell High School. This is a really important area, and hopefully other schools locally will be able to benefit soon as well. Details can be viewed <strong><a href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/work/citizens-advice-delivers-new-financial-literacy-project-to-epsom-ewell-high-school-students/">here</a></strong>.</p>
<p>Best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-9/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you concerning a couple of local issues. ULEZ Firstly many of you will be aware that the Mayor of London has decided to widen London’s ultra low emission zone from later this year. This has significant implications for our area. I won’t get into the politics of this now, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-9/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6376</id>
    <published>2023-01-20T13:12:04Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-20T13:12:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Shropshire discharge funding to help this Winter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/update-shropshire-discharge-funding-help-winter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7338" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">20 January 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Update on Shropshire discharge funding to help this Winter</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Dunne welcomes Health Secretary, Steve Barclay’s announcement that over £200m will be invested in supporting discharge of patients from hospitals across the UK. This will relieve pressure this winter and has been provided to integrated care boards for immediate use.</p>

<p>A further £50m has been allocated for the creation of modular units in hospitals which will help free up bed spaces – meaning ambulances can get back onto the road sooner to deal with emergency one calls and enabling faster response times.</p>

<p>The announcement means £1.7m has been provided to Shropshire NHS Integrated Care Board to help facilitate the new national discharge process to reduce risk and improve patient safety. This in turn will increase capacity to discharge patients and create improved flow in acute hospitals in Shropshire and Telford.</p>

<p>Funding for Adult Social Care will contribute towards four weeks of a new extended care package following discharge for patients who no longer meet in-patient criteria. Additionally, clinical advice or therapeutic will be available where appropriate in step-down facility to help patients with recovery, reconditioning and rehabilitation.</p>

<p>The Government is running a national campaign to recruit extra staff needed to support more packages of care. The £500m social care discharge fund announced last September can be used for the recruitment and retention of the care workforce. A further £15m was set aside to further boost overseas recruitment opportunities.</p>

<p>Commenting on the update, Philip Dunne said:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“The Government recognises current winter pressures on the NHS and is helping the NHS deal with discharge some 10,000 elderly patients who occupy beds, while medically fit for discharge. Fixing the link between discharge and after care, whether in social care settings or at home, is imperative.</p>

<p>“I am glad the Department for Health is using medical advances like virtual beds, artificial intelligence, and better analytics to better understand the use of time between admittance and discharge.</p>

<p>“This should help with the delays to ambulance response times and patient handovers as it will improve patient flow through our acute hospitals”.</p>
</blockquote></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7338 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-01-20T12:02:57Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-20T12:02:57Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair play?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Independent analysis of the largest cities and towns in England identified Bradford as the UK’s number one Levelling Up opportunity – given that none of the four Bradford bids were successful in this round – does the Minister believe that the people of Bradford will think this is a fair outcome, or indeed that this process stinks?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Lucy Frazer MP, Minister for Housing and Planning said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As I mentioned earlier, as somebody who grew up in Leeds, I understand how important that area of the country is, and how much more we can do. We were only able to allocate in this round £2.1 billion, but there is further funding available and Levelling Up Round 3 will be coming in due course.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking afterwards, Judith said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This is yet another example of this Government leaving Bradford and West Yorkshire behind.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is hugely disappointing that Bradford&amp;#8217;s ambitious £50m levelling up bid to regenerate the Osdal area has not been successful. The transformative plan would have brought significant investment and hundreds of jobs in to Bradford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is a damning indictment of this Government&amp;#8217;s lack of vision and support for Bradford when not one of the city&amp;#8217;s submitted bids in this round was successful.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith added: “This is not the government levelling up, it is the government messing up. The government needs to fix the process to ensure fairness, so that public funds are targeted to places that would benefit the most like Bradford.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, levelling, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;87&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;87&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" alt="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, minister, bradford, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked: “Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair play? “Independent analysis of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2698</id>
    <published>2023-01-19T15:42:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-19T15:42:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour Levelling up bid statement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/01/19/nottingham-labour-levelling-up-bid-statement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour is disappointed that Nottingham City Council has not been successful in three bids for funding from the Government’s Levelling Up Fund. These bids were for:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The £20m Broad Marsh bid&amp;nbsp;to prepare the frame of the derelict shopping centre to be retained and reimagined as a unique space for play, performance and food.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The £20m Bulwell town centre bid&amp;nbsp;was to create a&amp;nbsp; Bulwell Promenade with enhancements of green space and public realm alongside the River Leen. It also included improvements to the marketplace and the restoration of heritage buildings and easier access and better connectivity between Bulwell Bogs, the tram stop, bus station, the market place and high streets.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The £17m Island Quarter bid,&amp;nbsp;submitted on behalf of developers Conygar, focused on renovating three heritage warehouse buildings at the heart of the 36-acre site near to Nottingham Station as well as improving access for pedestrians, cyclists and vehicle users with an upgraded junction connecting the site to the Sneinton community.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All three bids put forward a strong case for national funding to help regenerate areas of the city in a way that was progressive, clean, green and sustainable. Nottingham City Council officers worked hard on putting forward these bids, which clearly fell under the scope of the Levelling Up Fund.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Levelling Up Fund is about making the country more equal, giving increased amounts of funding to areas that have been overlooked or not received their fair share in the past. Cities like Nottingham should be the prime targets for the fund. Under the current Government, this is not the case.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The rejection of all three bids does not make any clear economic sense. Cities are the drivers of the economy, they draw in people from suburbs and towns to work, to study and to relax. The Broadmarsh and Island Quarter bids would have created jobs, built new homes and revived the city centre. Not only that, but they would have helped the transformation of one of the entrances to the city, into a green and welcoming area, an area that would be modern and innovative. The Bulwell bid would have helped regenerate one of the more economically-deprived areas of the city, enhancing and improving the marketplace and area alongside the River Leen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nottingham needed this funding, but instead it went to places like Rutland, somewhere that would be difficult to describe as deprived or needing more money for improvements. Indeed, it seems as though economic sense was not the key driver of the decisions around which bids were successful. When looking at the areas that received funding, more often than not the local MP is Conservative. This is one more example of the Government making decisions based on political benefit instead of what will benefit people who need help the most. The most damning evidence of this is that of the 80 successful bids in England only half are in the 100 most deprived parts of the country.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is made even more obvious by the fact that Prime Minister Sunak’s own constituency of Richmond in Yorkshire had a £19 million successful bid, while the nearby city of Leeds was unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is clear then that the decisions for funding were political decisions. Despite this disappointment, work will still be able to start on the Green Heart, and the first phase will be completed. The new Central Library will be completed this year, improvements are currently ongoing to Bulwell Bus Station and Conyger is continuing work on the Island Quarter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour will continue to work and push for improvements and funding for Nottingham City. More Levelling Up funding will become available and bids will be submitted. Nottingham Labour is committed to seeking all available funding to help Nottingham residents and to help improve and grow our city.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour is disappointed that Nottingham City Council has not been successful in three bids for funding from the Government’s Levelling Up Fund</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2962</id>
    <published>2023-01-19T14:59:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-19T14:59:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Bulwell"/>
    <category term="Economic Regeneration"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="Broadmarsh"/>
    <category term="Conservatives"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="levelling up"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Disappointment for Na h-Eileanan an Iar as the UK Government Levelling Up Fund proves to be a hollow promise</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/01/19/disappointment-for-na-h-eileanan-an-iar-as-the-uk-government-levelling-up-fund-proves-to-be-a-hollow-promise/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says Scotland has been utterly conned by the UK Government as Levelling Up Funding is announced today (Thursday).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil has been informed by the UK Government that local applications to the Levelling Up Fund &amp;#8211; which was marketed as the replacement to EU funding lost through Brexit &amp;#8211; have been unsuccessful.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The applications submitted by Comhairle nan Eilean Siar were for ‘Eilean Siar Spinal Route &amp;amp; Connecting Infrastructure’ and the ‘Eilean Siar Cultural Heritage and Regeneration Project’. Both projects would have brought major benefits to Na h-Eileanan an Iar through transport upgrades and cultural projects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil said: “It is a huge blow for Na h-Eileanan an Iar to miss out on funding for these two projects. I know this has involved a huge amount of work from Comhairle staff.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; “Since Brexit, we have lost EU funding which contributed a lot to development over decades. EU structural funding was about £3.5m a year &amp;#8211; Tory Brexit is short-changing the islands with less than a third of the money.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The UK Government gave assurances that Brexit would not lead to a loss of money to rural areas. &amp;nbsp;However, now we see the magnitude of that lie with today’s announcement that the Comhairle’s bids to the Levelling Up Fund have been unsuccessful.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Scotland’s share of the Levelling Up funding is just £177 million out of £2 billion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Around £1.1 billion out of the £1.6 billion total levelling up funding in England has been given to areas with a Conservative MP.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil he added: “People have been utterly conned by the UK Government and their Brexit. If ever there was a time for Independence, it is now.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="3882" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/angus-lochs-4-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg" data-orig-size="772,579" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="angus lochs 4" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=772" alt="" class="wp-image-3882" width="840" height="630" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg 772w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/08/angus-lochs-4-edited.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 840px) 100vw, 840px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says Scotland has been utterly conned by the UK Government as Levelling …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/01/19/disappointment-for-na-h-eileanan-an-iar-as-the-uk-government-levelling-up-fund-proves-to-be-a-hollow-promise/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4080</id>
    <published>2023-01-19T14:11:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-19T14:11:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP delighted with successes of levelling up bid for new Blackpool Multiversity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/local-mp-delighted-successes-levelling-bid-new-blackpool-multiversity" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scott Benton MP is delighted to welcome Michael Gove, the Secretary Of State for Levelling Up to Blackpool
Mr Gove is here to today (19.01.2023) to announce the latest allocations from the £4.8 billion allocated in levelling up funding, of which Blackpool will be receiving £40 million.
Blackpool…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/local-mp-delighted-successes-levelling-bid-new-blackpool-multiversity</id>
    <published>2023-01-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Letter to the Prime Minister on Fulfilling Dementia Commitments</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/our-letter-to-the-prime-minister-on-dementia/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">We Demand that the Government <span style="color:#06396a;">Fulfils its Commitments on Dementia</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>Today I joined Alzheimer’s Society Ambassadors Vicky McClure and Dame Arlene Phillips as well as Elliot Colburn MP and Ananga Moonesinghe, who lives with dementia, to deliver an open letter to PM Rishi Sunak at Downing Street, demanding the Government urgently fulfil their promises on dementia.</p>
<p>Launched by leading dementia charity Alzheimer’s Society, the open letter has been signed by over 36,000 members of the public and famous names including Choreographer Dame Arlene Philips and actor Vicky McClure. We were joined at the hand-in by my colleague on the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Dementia, Vice-Chair Elliot Colburn MP, showing cross-party support. It urges Rishi Sunak to deliver on previous Conservative Party commitments to dementia and not let the UK’s biggest killer fall down the political agenda.</p>
<p>Previous Conservative Prime Ministers have actively committed to improving the lives of people affected by dementia. Now Rishi Sunak must deliver on promises to reform social care, double dementia research funding and release a ten-year plan for dementia which gives the condition the priority it deserves. The 36,000 people who signed the open letter are making themselves clear – they don’t just want to hear empty promises, they want to see action. People with dementia can’t and won’t wait any longer.</p>
<p>With diagnosis rates still sitting below pre-pandemic levels, national figures reveal people are waiting up to two years in some areas for a diagnosis, thereby missing out on vital treatment and support. Alzheimer’s Society research also shows three in five people affected by dementia struggled to get social care in the past year, with half of family carers revealing they ended up in crisis, such as rushing their loved one to A&amp;E due to lack of support</p>
<p>The charity is concerned the deepening workforce crisis in social care – with vacancies sitting at 165,000 – risks leaving people with dementia desperate for help while living costs soar. Alzheimer’s Society say it’s more important now than ever for the Government to prioritise dementia.</p>
<p>In the past year, the Government has made many commitments on dementia, promising to deliver a ‘visionary ten-year plan’ for dementia, to reform the social care system and double spending on dementia research by 2024.  Alzheimer’s Society says the delivery of these will be transformational for the lives of the 900,000 people living with dementia but calls on the Government to urgently make these a reality to prevent a deepening crisis in dementia care.</p>
<p>This follows the news last year that a new drug, lecanemab, was shown to slow cognitive decline in people living with Alzheimer’s disease. Unfortunately, this breakthrough will mean little if diagnosis rates remain stagnant and often inaccurate. This treatment works best for people with early Alzheimer’s disease. Without early and accurate diagnosis, we risk hopeful advancements like this having minimal effect.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/our-letter-to-the-prime-minister-on-dementia/">Our Letter to the Prime Minister on Fulfilling Dementia Commitments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/our-letter-to-the-prime-minister-on-dementia/">Our Letter to the Prime Minister on Fulfilling Dementia Commitments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7088</id>
    <published>2023-01-19T11:06:54Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-19T11:06:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Dementia"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="alzheimer's society"/>
    <category term="Downing Street"/>
    <category term="Petition"/>
    <category term="Prime Minister"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John celebrates town&#8217;s success in £20Million Levelling-Up Fund bid for Government cash]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/19/john-celebrates-towns-success-in-20million-levelling-up-fund-bid-for-government-cash/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5642</id>
		<updated>2023-01-19T07:27:53Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-19T07:27:53Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Local Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Regenerating Weston"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose is celebrating today&#8217;s announcement that Ministers have approved the town&#8217;s multi-million pound Levelling Up Fund bid for Government cash. In summer last year, John supported North Somerset&#8217;s Levelling-Up Fund bid to turn Weston into a year-round destination by upgrading underused and vulnerable local heritage sites into “must visit” destinations; reinventing the town [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/19/john-celebrates-towns-success-in-20million-levelling-up-fund-bid-for-government-cash/"><![CDATA[
<p>Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose is celebrating today&#8217;s announcement that Ministers have approved the town&#8217;s multi-million pound Levelling Up Fund bid for Government cash.</p>



<p><br>In summer last year, John supported North Somerset&#8217;s Levelling-Up Fund bid to turn Weston into a year-round destination by upgrading underused and vulnerable local heritage sites into “must visit” destinations; reinventing the town centre and high street; creating more attractive routes within the town; improving the visitor experience; and encouraging footfall and spending.</p>



<p><br>John said: &#8220;This is brilliant for Weston. The cash should boost investment in local jobs and growth, create opportunities for people who never had them before, and make our town look better for local residents and visitors alike.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Less Survivable Cancers Awareness Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/01/18/less-survivable-cancers-awareness-day/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Less Survivable Cancer Taskforce (LSCT) have been working hard to increase awareness and research of brain, liver, lung, oesophagus, pancreas, and stomach cancers. I was pleased to meet with them on #LessSurvivableCancersAwarenessDay where we discussed how important their work is. Unfortunately, awareness of less survivable cancers remains very low, and it is important that [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/01/18/less-survivable-cancers-awareness-day/">Less Survivable Cancers Awareness Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5091</id>
    <published>2023-01-18T16:21:06Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-18T16:21:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We Cannot Afford To Lose The British Steel Industry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/we-cannot-afford-to-lose-the-british-steel-industry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3285</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T15:46:06Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T15:46:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Strengthening the Online Safety Bill is essential</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/01/strengthening-the-online-safety-bill-is-essential/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8703" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/01/strengthening-the-online-safety-bill-is-essential/230117-online-safety-bill-campaign/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,768" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="230117 Online Safety Bill campaign" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=790%2C593&amp;ssl=1"/>
<p>I have long campaigned for stronger protections for children and the public online. </p>



<p>The Government have made a mess of the Online Safety Bill. Rishi Sunak is so out of touch he’s completely misread the room. There’s a parliamentary majority to strengthen the Bill and ensure company directors are liable for their failures to protect children.</p>



<p>I will be voting today to: </p>



<ul><li>strengthen criminal sanctions for senior managers who fail to make their platforms safe.  </li><li>allow Ofcom to set minimum standards for platforms’ terms and conditions on online harms and hold them to account for changing them on a whim. </li><li>introduce an ombudsman, for better redress for individuals when a platform fails to deal with their complaint. </li></ul>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8703" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/01/strengthening-the-online-safety-bill-is-essential/230117-online-safety-bill-campaign/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,768" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="230117 Online Safety Bill campaign" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/230117-Online-Safety-Bill-campaign.jpg?fit=790%2C593&amp;ssl=1"/>I have long campaigned for stronger protections for children and the public online. The Government have made a mess of the Online Safety Bill. Rishi Sunak is so out of touch he’s completely misread the room. There’s a parliamentary majority to strengthen the Bill and ensure company directors are liable for their failures to protect […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8702</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T14:39:53Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T14:39:53Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-7774544376901163283</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T15:38:00.001+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T15:38:28.065+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Mr Grant, one Chestnut Grove, Clayton-le-Moors, Valuation Office, revaluation of property.</title>
    <summary type="text">Open my shared note:Mr GrantNotesSent from my iPhone</summary>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/7774544376901163283"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/7774544376901163283"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2023/01/mr-grant-one-chestnut-grove-clayton-le.html" title="Mr Grant, one Chestnut Grove, Clayton-le-Moors, Valuation Office, revaluation of property."/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-43" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I started this week with a visit to the Taste sandwich shop in Kirkby. Meeting hardworking businessowners like Fiona is exactly what makes me proud to be the MP for this great area. 15 years ago, Fiona was a single parent to twins and was struggling to make ends meet. Rather than feeling sorry for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-43</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Endoscopy Unit for PRU Granted Planning Permission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/new-endoscopy-unit-pru-granted-planning-permission" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">At a meeting of Bromley Council’s Development Control Committee in January, Councillors voted to allow planning permission for a new Endoscopy Unit at the Princess Royal University (PRU) hospital.
 
The new unit will help to reduce wait times for local cancer patients, speed up diagnostic time and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/new-endoscopy-unit-pru-granted-planning-permission</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - The 2021 Census &amp; Ashford </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-2021-census-ashford" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The exam question this morning is how much do we know about our local community? The data from the 2021 Census is becoming available, and it shows how the constituency of Ashford is not only growing but changing.
To start with the basics, there are 51,400 households, with a population of 127,300.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-2021-census-ashford</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Payments – Spring 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/cost-of-living-payments-spring-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Details for the next round of cost-of-living payments were announced by The Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) last week, with low-income houses set to receive new Cost of Living Payments from Spring 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These payments, initially unveiled in the Chancellor’s Autumn Statement, could provide low-income households with up to £1,350 from the Government in 2023/4 to help with the cost of living. I’m pleased that this extra cash will be available to support the most vulnerable across Aldridge-Brownhills, including extra support for disabled people and the elderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the link to find out more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/millions-of-low-income-households-to-get-new-cost-of-living-payments-from-spring-2023?fbclid=IwAR1gogmHWtm0_sFw-i4k0TXHhxD7zY6KGFklNbYYctLQqMipuxCjT9JLAFY"&gt;Millions of low-income households to get new Cost of Living Payments from Spring 2023 &amp;#8211; GOV.UK (www.gov.uk)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Details for the next round of cost-of-living payments were announced by The Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) last week, with low-income houses set to receive new Cost of Living […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4481</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T09:51:23Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T09:51:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[January 2023 Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/01/10/january-2023-newsletter/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10686</id>
		<updated>2023-01-10T11:12:36Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-10T10:15:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/><category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="Newsletter"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope that everybody had an enjoyable and relaxing Christmas and New Year Period. Please find below my most recent newsletter, with information on what I have been busy doing both in the constituency and in Parliament throughout the past couple of months. There are also details of my upcoming advice surgeries contained within the ... <a title="January 2023 Newsletter" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/01/10/january-2023-newsletter/" aria-label="More on January 2023 Newsletter">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scottish Borders MP visits local ice rink</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-visits-local-ice-rink" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">John Lamont MP has encouraged local people to get involved in curling and skating in 2023 after visiting the Border Ice Rink in Kelso.
The Scottish Borders MP said the Kelso centre was a “fantastic day out” and the local curling club was a “brilliant fun activity for people of all ages.”
The rink …</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-visits-local-ice-rink</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>December 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/december-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/fe0ab0e4662f/tulip-siddiq-mp-december-2022-enewsletter-5372294"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5607" width="291" height="152" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews-300x157.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews-768x402.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews-105x55.png 105w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews-669x350.png 669w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/decnews-630x330.png 630w" sizes="(max-width: 291px) 100vw, 291px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/fe0ab0e4662f/tulip-siddiq-mp-december-2022-enewsletter-5372294">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for December 2022</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for December 2022</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5605</id>
    <published>2022-12-31T16:01:04Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-31T16:01:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="December"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-85/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted to meet their daughter Catherine, Acting Principal of NPT College Group, chair of Welsh Netball, and their son-in-law Mark Dacey (married to another daughter, Alison), Principal of Neath College, in 2014 and we have become close friends. Crid was a pillar of the local community wherever they lived all over the world. A socialist, feminist, Alan’s office manager, member of Cefn Hengoed Ladies Choir (who sang at her funeral) and so much more. Gelligaer Church was full of Crid’s family, friends, and members of community organisations. RIP my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;As part of the Stonegate Group’s annual investment programme, it has invested £174,000 into the Castell-Nedd Arms in Neath town centre. I was delighted to take my staff to visit and see the improvements. We met with the operator of the pub Kayleigh Strinati, the Group’s area manager Danny Cross, and the bar staff. Kayleigh told us that she had worked in the pub trade for a number of years, and she felt that it was time to take that step up to managing the Castell-Nedd. She completed the training requirements, and then Covid struck. But when the pub re-opened again, the customers gradually came back to what had become a social hub for many people who live in Neath. The new challenge is the “cost of living crisis”, but Kayleigh is providing a very warm welcome for people to gather, talk, listen, watch TV, use the Wi-Fi, as well as great refreshments. The refurbishment includes new windows and seating area overlooking Angel Street, a pool and darts section, and many more facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2712"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2712" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1D2F4A81-ED7E-449E-8944-5797D4A54227-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I visited the Churches Together Nativity Scene which this year is displayed in the Greyhound Trust Charity Shop Window, instead of in the Town Square. It is secure and able to be seen by all passers by. Massive thanks to the charity shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I met with Mark Fisher, NPT Council Unison Representative, to discuss Fair Funding for the council. Mark has always done a fantastic job representing Unison members, and although it was announced this week that NPT has received a better than anticipated settlement of 7.1% from Welsh Government, he shared his concerns about pressure on future budgets, and the continuing “cost of living” challenges faced everyday by every one of his members. Mark will be holding a Fair Funding Event at NPT Council for local elected representatives and his Unison members on Friday 13th January 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;After the meeting, Mark and I joined the Royal Mail workers who are striking for a fair pay settlement and no diminishing of their terms and conditions, on their Picket Line which was outside the Royal Mail Sorting Office in Neath. There was a great turnout, and many passers-by supported the strike. People were dropping off food to keep the workers going in the freezing, sub-zero temperatures. In solidarity, I bought all the strikers coffee from our superb local coffee shop, Brew &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2713"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2713" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/71AD8D08-F334-4B81-ADF0-2D1614C1BD81-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Mynydd Fforch Dwm Windfarm is a proposal by &lt;a href="https://mfdwindfarm.co.uk/about-us/"&gt;Naturalis Energy&lt;/a&gt; to provide clean, carbon free energy to homes and businesses across South Wales, including a renewable energy park near Tonmawr. Naturalis is a joint venture between Falck Renewables and REG Windpower energy companies. A number of constituents have contacted me regarding the proposal, asking me to call into the one of the Naturalis public consultation sessions. I dropped into the one held at Neath Little Theatre to view the plans and listen to a presentation by Naturalis staff. As part of the Development of National Significance (DNS) planning process Naturalis are required to undertake a comprehensive programme of pre-application engagement consultations. As an MP I have no remit over Welsh Government or Local Authority Planning applications. My role is to pass on the views and concerns of all my constituents to the stakeholders involved in a particular planning application. Please email me and I shall make sure that your questions are passed onto the stakeholders involved in this application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;My brother James was suddenly taken seriously ill and was rushed to Basingstoke Hospital. My daughter Angharad and I visited him in hospital, but James died following his fight against his illness which turned into pneumonia. My big brother was always there to look after me, after the death of my father, when I was seventeen. James was an industrial pharmacist, worked all over the world, and had many friends and colleagues. James was brought up by my grandparents who owned the Walnut Tree Pub in Kenfig Hill. He was a product of Bridgend Grammar School, Loughborough and Cardiff Universities. James organised the old boys network for former pupils of his old school. My grandfather was a founder of Kenfig Hill RFC, and my parents managed the bar. Rugby was part of James’ life, and he was proud to play number 8 at schoolboy rugby for Wales. I have lived with my brother all over the world at various times during my life. He was my mentor, my hero, my rock. I am devastated at the passing of my beloved brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Being a member of the congregation of St David’s Church Neath has been a great source of comfort to me. The people who go to my church are genuine, caring, supportive, never forget that life is very challenging, and we are always there to help each other through the good and the not-so-good times. It was so good to see my friends at the Choir Coffee Morning at St David’s Church, Neath. Many thanks to everyone who came to help and support. Coffee, cake, festive music with loyal friends in the beautifully Christmas decorated church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It’s an honour to be a patron of YMCA Neath and I really enjoyed the Christmas Fayre. There were stalls, arts and crafts, jewellery, face painting, glitter tattoos, pottery painting, tombola, lucky dip, raffle prizes, and refreshments. It was so good to catch up with Centre Manager Claire Hicks, and Admin Officer Jessica Kennedy. As a lifelong vegan, it was good to meet YMCA staffer Rhys Oliver who has recently started her delivery business “Vegan Kitchen – Food with a conscience – Made in Wales”. Rhys was selling a taste of her produce, vegan sausages, pasties, and chocolate cakes. Her menus are changed weekly and are made freshly on the day of delivery. And all packaging is environmentally friendly. Please email Rhys on DaffodilBach@gmail.com or telephone 07947715435 to place your orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I dropped into The Haven to meet my dear friend Major Mary Wolfe, her successor Major Neil Duquemin, and Skills Coordinator Christina Davies. On the day of my visit, The Haven had provided 48 Christmas lunches to their regular clients, but their door is always open to anyone who wants to call in and have a substantial breakfast for 50 pence, and a choice of lunch for a pound. On Wednesdays, agencies are based in The Haven for the day to offer help and advice, including Citizens Advice, the Wallich, Medical Staff, and Jobcentre Plus. Christina delivers skills courses including “budgeting on benefits”, and “cooking on a limited income”. My heartfelt thanks to Mary, Neil, Christina and all the volunteers who give up their time everyday for the homeless and people in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2714"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2714" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/F5AD216A-2D09-4C5D-A382-D5F671130946-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It was an absolute delight to meet the winner of my Christmas Card 2022 Competition Caitlin Vaughan, aged 6, and her mother Hannah. Thank you to all the children who sent in their designs. It is always a very difficult task to select a winner, but Caitlin’s card was exceptional for one so young. Special mention for Gorazd Trajkovski from Skopje, Macedonia, aged 10 who won the International Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2715"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2715" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/8E3138C3-FA2C-4191-A3BE-698499C533AB-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On the last day in the Neath Office, I took my wonderful Neath Office staff for Christmas lunch. This is our first Christmas lunch since the onset of the pandemic in 2020. My I take this opportunity to wish all my constituents a very merry Christmas and a happy, healthy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2716"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2716" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/BB5F61DE-C53B-4E60-98D7-9EC5CC5EE178-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2711</id>
    <published>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</updated>
    <category term="My Weekly Round-up"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Southfield School leads the way in their teaching of over 80 pupils with learning difficulties via the priority they give to communication, self-regulation and independence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps had the pleasure of meeting both teachers and pupils to see the achievements of the school and thank the staff for their tireless and crucial work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I am very grateful for all the work the staff do for the school and their pupils” Mr Shapps commented, “and I know that my gratitude is shared both by parents and the wider community”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The teachers thanked Mr Shapps for his visit and expressed their gratitude to him for his support with the headteacher, Angela O’Rourke, saying:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The pupils and the staff very much enjoyed having Mr Shapps on the site and were thrilled to be able to share with him the incredible role that Team Southfield play in the lives of our children. We are very grateful for Mr Shapps making the time for us”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/"&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/">&lt;strong&gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&lt;/strong&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=46138</id>
    <published>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP celebrates Christmas in Fulmer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Always love stopping by the Black Horse at Christmas time.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer</id>
    <published>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Heart Hero awards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/12/07/green-heart-hero-awards/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7576</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Surgery Waiting List]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1716</id>
		<updated>2022-12-07T14:48:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-12T14:44:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bolton Hospital"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="cancer"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="healthcare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="NHS"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Surgery"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett continues campaign against Southeastern timetable changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford, is continuing to campaign for changes to the new Southeastern railway timetable, which will be implemented from Sunday 11 December.
To date, Sir David has held meetings with Southeastern Managing Director, Steve White, the Rail Minister,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[GIVING TUESDAY]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=469</id>
		<updated>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3358</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:46:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Constituent, Welcome to my November&#160;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&#160; Autumn Statement: Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my November&nbsp;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Autumn Statement:</h1>



<p>Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. In which he detailed how the Government intends to restore economic stability and tackle inflation.</p>



<p>Like many countries around the world, the UK is facing profound economic challenges. Supply disruption caused by the world’s economies emerging from lockdown has been compounded by Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine and deliberate interference with Europe’s energy supply to create massive increases in the cost of energy. This has led to high inflation and high interest rates across many of the world’s major economies, and the UK is no different.</p>



<p>I welcome the proposals in the Autumn Statement. To achieve long-term, sustainable growth we need to grip inflation, balance the books, and get debt falling as a share of GDP. The plan presented by the Chancellor yesterday takes the tough decisions to face up to this situation without passing the buck onto future generations. What’s more, it protects the hard-working majority by enacting no headline tax increases, and protects the most vulnerable by maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation – something I have personally been campaigning for. All while protecting and maintaining public spending for the next two years at the levels set out in 2021.</p>



<p>The plan involves a roughly equal split between tax rises and spending cuts, with the greatest burden falling on those who can afford it most. Specifically, the plan:</p>



<p><strong>Increases taxpayer funding for our NHS and schools by an extra £11 billion over the next two years.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Government will provide £4 billion in additional funding to schools and £7.7 billion in additional funding to the NHS and social care sector over the next two years. Prioritising the public services that matter most.</p>



<p>&#8211; £2–3 billion in additional funding for the NHS in each of the next two years so we can bring down ambulance waiting times, tackle the Covid backlog, and improve access to GPs. Also providing £2.8 billion next year and £4.7 billion the year after for adult social care, which aims to double the number of people leaving hospitals on time and into care by 2024, addressing unmet needs and boosting low pay in the sector.</p>



<p>&#8211; £4 billion in additional funding for schools over the next two years. We are increasing the schools budget by £2 billion this year and £2 billion next year to help schools with rising costs as a result of inflation. Which is more than Labour has pledged to give schools.</p>



<p><strong>Introduces no headline tax increases.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Autumn Statement raises £25 billion in additional taxes over the forecast period but there are no increases in the headline rates of tax. By targeting tax rises toward businesses, wealthier households, and the oil and gas industry, the Government has ensured that it can honour its manifesto commitment not to increase Income Tax, National Insurance, or VAT.</p>



<p>&#8211; Instead of raising rates, the Government is freezing personal tax thresholds for a further two years. There are also reforms to the Additional Rate threshold, so that a taxpayer who earns more than £150,000 will pay £1,200 more in tax per year.</p>



<p>&#8211; It is only fair that companies who have made genuine windfall profits as a result of the war in Ukraine make an additional contribution to pay for the support we have outlined. So from 2023, the Energy Profits Levy rate will rise from 25per cent to 35per cent and will continue until the end of March 2028. A 45per cent Levy will be applied to extraordinary returns made by electricity generators. In total these windfall taxes will raise £52 billion over six years. This is more ambitious than Labour’s proposal.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting and maintaining public spending.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; For the next two years public spending will remain at the levels set out in 2021 and then increase by one per cent in real terms each year until 2027–28.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting every household with their energy bills.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Energy Price Guarantee will continue to support everyone for another year. This winter, the price households pay for the energy they use will be capped, so that a typical household will pay £2,500. From April 2023, the price cap will rise so that a typical household will pay £3,000. The Energy Price Guarantee will then end in April 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting the most vulnerable through maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; I have been publicly campaigning for benefits and pensions to be increased in line with inflation for some time now, and so was very pleased to see the Chancellor yesterday confirm that this would be part of the Government’s plan.</p>



<p>&#8211; To protect the most vulnerable, benefits will now be increased in line with inflation for 2023–24. More than 10 million households in receipt of working-age and disability benefits will see an increase in their benefit payments.</p>



<p>&#8211; The pensions triple lock will also be protected. Because of the difficult but necessary decisions the Government has taken elsewhere, the triple lock for pensions will be protected in full. This means that in April, the State Pension will increase in line with inflation, which is the biggest cash increase in the State Pension ever.</p>



<p><strong>Additional support for the most vulnerable.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Over £12 billion of additional targeted support is assigned to help the most vulnerable households. The Government will continue providing this year’s cost of living payments and next year it will provide extra one-off payments of £900 for the 8 million households on means-tested benefits, £300 to pensioners, and £150 for disability benefit recipients. The Government is also providing £1 billion of extra funding by extending the Household Support Fund for another year.</p>



<p>The OBR has confirmed that these plans will restore the public finances to a sustainable position and help reduce inflation and unemployment. And I look forward to engaging with my ministerial colleagues as these policies are rolled out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Remembrance Sunday:</h1>



<p>This year for Remembrance Sunday on 13th November, I was honoured to lay wreaths in Ripley and Kilburn in memory of those who have served our county, and in honour of those who are still serving. There are a multitude of remembrance services held across our constituency every year, so it is unfortunately impossible for me to attend all of them. However, every year I try to rotate which services I attend. This year it was a memorial service at Ripley War Memorial in the morning and another in Kilburn in the afternoon.</p>



<p>This has been a particularly important period of remembrance as we mark 40 years since the end of the Falkland’s war, and we commemorate the 255 British personnel who lost their lives in defence of the islands. Their courage and sacrifice must never be forgotten. Thank you to everyone who organised or supported the remembrance services and parades across Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Alfreton Solar Farm Update:</h1>



<p>On 21st October, I spoke at the public inquiry into plans from Kronos Solar to build a 50-megawatt solar farm between Alfreton and Oakerthorpe. Many of you will remember that Amber Valley Borough Council’s (AVBC) planning authorities rejected the proposal last December, stating that the project’s scale and impact on the landscape outweighed any environmental benefits the site would provide. However, Kronos Solar have since filed an appeal to overturn the decision of AVBC and get the site approved, resulting in this enquiry.</p>



<p>I have been opposing the project on behalf of local residents and businesses throughout the process, a great many of whom have contacted me about the proposals. I very much support the expansion of our clean energy network, and in the right place a solar farm would be an asset. However, there are good reasons why this site was refused planning permission. We all want renewable energy expansion but not at any cost.</p>



<p>To begin with, much of the land is north facing, which means the site would need to be overly large. The impact on the amenity of local residents, the impact on the countryside area, and the impact on the various heritage assets is just too great. And that is before we consider Alfreton Park and Alfreton Park Community School, which looks after children with the very highest level of need, very close in the vicinity.</p>



<p>It is clear to me that this is a totally unsuitable site for this intensity of development. Frankly, I believe this proposal was not based on a thorough search for suitable land for a solar farm, instead, it looks to me to be based on a search for a suitable sub-station, with the proposal then trying to force some land to suit.</p>



<p>I will continue to keep residents updated on any developments. And at present, a decision is expected at some point in the next few months.</p>



<h1>Pollution and our waterways:</h1>



<p>I have recently welcomed the Department for Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs’ (DEFRA) plans to raise the civil penalty for water companies who pollute our environment by one thousand times, from £250,000 up to £250 million. I am hopeful that increasing the penalties the Environment Agency can enforce without a lengthy and costly court process will enable swifter and stronger action to be taken against water companies that illegally pollute our environment.</p>



<p>Many residents have contacted me about pollution and the use of storm drains in our sewage system. There has also been a great deal of misinformation circulating on social media regarding the Government’s campaign to address these issues.</p>



<p>Last year, the Government introduced the Environment Act 2021 which was a bill designed to tackle this problem and reduce sewage pollution ignored by previous Governments. When the Environment Act was going through Parliament the Duke of Wellington, a hereditary peer, introduced an amendment that would legislate the complete elimination of storm drains and therefore of storm overflow sewage into our waterways. This of course sounds admirable, and indeed is something I support in principle. However, this amendment came without a plan for how it could be delivered and how such a vast project could be funded.</p>



<p>Initial assessments suggested elimination would cost between £150 &#8211; £650 billion. To put those figures in perspective, £150 billion was more than the entire schools, policing, and defence budgets put together. Therefore, the Government did not support the amendment, and I did not vote for it. In my view, the last thing people wanted was for their water bill to go through the roof.</p>



<p>Twitter mis-informers seized this opportunity and claimed we had all voted in favour of water companies dumping raw sewage into our rivers. Which was totally false, and ironically punished the Government for actually trying to do something about the problem ignored by previous Governments.</p>



<p>With this most recent announcement by DEFRA, I am glad to see the Government continuing the campaign to improve the quality of our waterways. To hold water companies to account, and ensure any polluter pays for the environmental harm they cause, the Environment Agency must take advantage of these new powers.</p>



<h1>Illegal crossings over the Channel:</h1>



<p>Many of you have contacted me about the number of small boats illegally crossing the English Channel in recent months. I appreciate the strength of feeling on this alarming issue and want to outline my position to you and explain some of the challenges we face in tackling this problem.</p>



<p>The number of illegal entries into the United Kingdom via small boats crossing the English Channel is too high. It endangers the lives of those making the journey, puts money into the pockets of ruthless and brutal people smuggling gangs, and puts undue pressure on our existing asylum system as well as our public services. I remain committed to an immigration policy that welcomes people to the UK through safe and legal routes, and an immigration policy that allows us to provide asylum to those in genuine need. However, it is clear many of those arriving in small boats are not here in genuine need of asylum, and as a result, the current situation cannot go on.</p>



<p>One reason for small boat crossings increasing in frequency is the success the Government has had in tackling other forms of illegal immigration. Such as increased checks and security for lorries and freight crossing the channel, effectively reducing the number of illegal entries into the UK through these means, and increasing the number of people turning to small boats as a way to enter the UK. The problem that now presents itself is how to police and secure hundreds of miles of coastline 24/7.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Parliament passed the Nationality and Borders Act which overhauled our approach to asylum and illegal migration. The legislation includes fairness towards those who need our help, and in welcoming people through safe and legal routes, but firmness in tackling abuse of the system and expediting the removal of those who have no legitimate claim for protection. It is worth noting that Labour opposed this Act designed to toughen our immigration system.</p>



<p>Further to changing the law in this country, the Government has recently signed a joint UK-France arrangement on tackling small boat crossings in the Channel which includes a 40% increase in the number of UK-funded officers patrolling French beaches. The new agreement lays the foundations for deeper UK-French co-operation to tackle illegal migration. The arrangement means, for the first time, specialist UK officers will be able to observe French officials at work in control rooms and on the ground patrolling the coastline.</p>



<p>It is clear, however, that big challenges still lie ahead, and that the number of small boats currently crossing the channel is unacceptable. The Prime Minister speaking recently on GB News said that tackling illegal immigration was a huge priority for his Government, and that while the recent joint UK -France arrangement was a big step in the right direction there was more that needs to be done. I share the Prime Minister’s view, and will continue engaging with my ministerial and Parliamentary colleagues to make the case for further measures to reduce cross channel migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on why Iran should be removed from UN commission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=Z4qpEver" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-63d2c67bbcbed" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-63d2c67bbcbed').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"63d2c67bbcbed","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-63d2c67bbcbed" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-63d2c67bbcbed" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="63d2c67bbcbed" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_63d2c67bbcbed" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_63d2c67bbcbed" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_63d2c67bbcbed" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_63d2c67bbcbed" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_63d2c67bbcbed" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_63d2c67bbcbed" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_63d2c67bbcbed_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-63d2c67bbcbed script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dw_YmSSxh78fjvxp-vXbxcMJOsvnX_j-c3hhnMxNXO2ZBKi9Bd93aa3z9R9EXx6IUkC3cFwuSYQowmY43Wu2A' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
