<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-06-22T06:28:52Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Philip Dunne MP meeting South Shropshire NFU farmers at Burwarton</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/gallery/philip-dunne-mp-meeting-south-shropshire-nfu-farmers-burwarton" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7431" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-node-title field--type-ds field--label-hidden field--item"><h2>
  Philip Dunne MP meeting South Shropshire NFU farmers at Burwarton
</h2>
</div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-gallery-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.philipdunne.com/sites/philipdunne.com/files/styles/feature_box_525x325_/public/2023-06/philip_dunne_nfu_farmers_burwarton.jpg?itok=3WlBPOcl" width="540" height="325" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7431 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-06-22T05:03:34Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-22T05:03:34Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Too much inflation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/06/22/too-much-inflation/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Prices rise when too much money chases too few goods and services. As economists would say, when potential demand outstrips supply, prices rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bank of England has presided over a big expansion of the amount of money and credit available from March 2020 to 2022. There have been supply shortages of energy, food and much else, with a rush to import. We import LNG gas instead of producing more of our own, losing tax revenue and causing more CO2 worldwide as a result. We import too much food, giving grants to farmers  not to grow more instead of boosting our home output. We make it difficult to produce steel, make ceramics and stay in other high energy using businesses, only to import the products we need with more CO 2 produced by the foreign factories as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government needs to take action to get inflation down. Short term measures include taking VAT off fuel, and raising the VAT threshold for small business  to allow them to expand more quickly. Longer term measures must entail regulatory and tax changes to make and grow more at home, and to produce more domestic energy. Lifting the IR 35 tax on the self employed could regain some of the lost 700,000 self employed of recent years. They will serve us well and generate more taxes of other kinds as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK has too few producers.  Now is a good time to flex rules and lower tax rates to free the makers and service providers to do more. Government must help get prices down. The Bank must be careful not to lurch from far too much  money and credit to too little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Prices rise when too much money chases too few goods and services. As economists would say, when potential demand outstrips supply, prices rise. The Bank of England has presided over a big expansion of the amount of money and credit available from March 2020 to 2022. There have been supply shortages of energy, food and…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=35417</id>
    <published>2023-06-22T04:00:34Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-22T04:00:34Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Leicester West takes over the Space Centre!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/13047-2/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=13047</id>
		<updated>2023-06-21T14:15:27Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-21T14:13:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Helping young people get the high skill, high wage jobs of the future is a top priority for me as a local MP. That is why I am campaigning to ensure children in Leicester West benefit from the jobs being created in our city’s growing space sector. Our fantastic Space [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/13047-2/">Leicester West takes over the Space Centre!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/13047-2/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13048" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-540x405.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-540x405.jpg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-260x195.jpg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-184x138.jpg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2-800x600.jpg 800w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-event-2.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></a>Helping young people get the high skill, high wage jobs of the future is a top priority for me as a local MP. That is why I am campaigning to ensure children in Leicester West benefit from the jobs being created in our city’s growing space sector.</p>
<p>Our fantastic Space Park is bringing together our world leading university research with business and industry in state of the art facilities. It aims to create 2,500 high skill, high paid jobs and generate £750m for the wider East Midlands economy.</p>
<p>Last week I helped host a “Leicester West Secondary School Takeover” day. &nbsp;We put on a series of events and talks to inspire students from Babington, Beaumont Leys, Castlemead and New College to think about pursuing a career in the space sector including in engineering, science, IT, data and design.</p>
<p>It was an absolutely amazing day and I am so grateful to the Space Centre for helping to put it on!</p>
<p><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13050" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-540x405.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-540x405.jpg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-260x195.jpg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-184x138.jpg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3-800x600.jpg 800w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-3.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13049" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4-405x540.jpg" alt="" width="405" height="540" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4-405x540.jpg 405w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4-195x260.jpg 195w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4-138x184.jpg 138w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Space-Centre-4.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 405px) 100vw, 405px" /></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/13047-2/">Leicester West takes over the Space Centre!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[“The fishing industry deserve answers” says Alex as he demands “overdue” response from Fisheries Minister on ocean monitoring]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/the-fishing-industry-deserve-answers-says-alex-as-he-demands-overdue-response-from-fisheries-minister-on-ocean-monitoring/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14684</id>
		<updated>2023-06-21T13:36:55Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-21T13:36:53Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A demand for an “overdue” response to questions about ongoing ocean monitoring and sample archiving has been made by Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham to Fisheries Minister, Mark Spencer MP. Writing to the Minister on 12 May Alex, who met with scientists who were part of the independent panel into crustacean die-offs across the Teesside [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/the-fishing-industry-deserve-answers-says-alex-as-he-demands-overdue-response-from-fisheries-minister-on-ocean-monitoring/">“The fishing industry deserve answers” says Alex as he demands “overdue” response from Fisheries Minister on ocean monitoring</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We want to hear your views on Community Payback Orders</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13759/we-want-to-hear-your-views-on-community-payback-orders" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Edinburgh residents are being asked for their views on Community Payback Orders (CPO) which are given by the Court to people to pay for their crimes as an alternative to a prison sentence.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13759/we-want-to-hear-your-views-on-community-payback-orders</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T14:27:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T14:27:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP presents Parliamentary Bill to give outdoor education experience to all young people</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442450/mp-presents-parliamentary-bill-to-give-outdoor-education-experience-to-all-young-people"/>
  <updated>2023-06-21T13:18:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442450/mp-presents-parliamentary-bill-to-give-outdoor-education-experience-to-all-young-people</id>
  <summary type="text">In Parliament yesterday, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron presented a Bill to give every child from every school in the country an opportunity to visit an outdoor education centre.
Last week, Tim tabled an Early Day Motion in the House of Commons on the same subject which has received cross party support from MPs from Labour, the Liberal Democrats, the Democratic Unionist Party and the Green Party.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In Parliament yesterday, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron presented a Bill to give every child from every school in the country an opportunity to visit an outdoor education centre.</p>
<p>Last week, Tim tabled an Early Day Motion in the House of Commons on the same subject which has received cross party support from MPs from Labour, the Liberal Democrats, the Democratic Unionist Party and the Green Party.</p>
<p>The idea for the Bill came after Tim visited the Outward Bound Trust at Ullswater.</p>
<p>Tim, who is the co-chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Outdoor Learning said: "<em>It's been a delight to visit some of our amazing local outdoor education centres here in Cumbria recently such as the Outward Bound Trust in Ullswater.</em></p>
<p><em>"They all do an incredible job of providing a life changing experience for young people, which can improve their confidence, build mental health resilience and help them rediscover a love of learning and the outdoors.</em></p>
<p><em>"However this should be an experience that is available to every young person from every school in our country.</em></p>
<p><em>"That's why I've tabled this Bill to get the ball rolling on a campaign for the Government to provide the funding to allow all schools to give their pupils this lifechanging opportunity."</em></p>
<p>Martin Davidson, Chief Executive of the Outward Bound Trust said: <em>"Every young person should have the opportunity to benefit from an outdoor residential experience, which is why this motion is a huge step forward for the sector.</em></p>
<p><em>"Thousands of young people miss out on these experiences each year, and this bill represents an opportunity to correct that and kickstart a conversation around equity and access."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Fight to Safeguard Essential Banking and Postal Services in Rural Communities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/rural-services-bill/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=rural-services-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p>As you may know, <a href="https://youtu.be/mR7-0byx8CI">I have presented the Banking and Postal Services (Rural Areas) Bill</a>, an essential piece of legislation designed to protect the services that our communities across Badenoch and Strathspey so vitally rely on, to the House of Commons.</p>
<p>Your voices have been instrumental in driving this process forward. From listening to those on community council groups to those of you I’ve had the pleasure of speaking with on your doorsteps, and to those who have shared their experiences online – I want to extend my heartfelt thanks for making your voices heard.</p>
<p>The concerns you have raised and the stories you have shared underscore the urgent need for us to address service cuts, particularly their impact on our older residents, which are simply unacceptable. These services are more than financial transactions or mail delivery points; they are community lifelines that connect individuals to the wider social and economic network.</p>
<p>The Bill is not simply just legislation; it represents our communal fight to ensure that all of our communities have access to essential banking and postal services. It proposes the implementation of a minimum number of physical branches per population, ensuring rural communities have access to these vital services.</p>
<p>However, our fight is far from over. This is about more than just preventing the last High Street bank in a single community from closing its doors. We must continue to advocate for a framework that works for our rural postmasters and for our communities. We must ensure that our march towards progress doesn’t sideline these vital communities. While digital infrastructure and digital literacy programmes are important, the physical presence of these services is indispensable.</p>
<p>Our rural communities form the bedrock of Scotland. They are responsible for preserving our environment, ensuring food security, and maintaining our cultural heritage. Yet, these communities are often sidelined, left grappling with dwindling essential services. The UK Government’s inaction in addressing these issues has left our rural communities floundering. It is imperative that we take proactive steps to tackle this issue.</p>
<p>The ongoing withdrawal of essential services from our rural communities is not just an issue; it is a crisis. We must ensure that our digital transition is inclusive, compassionate, and considerate of all our citizens, regardless of their location.</p>
<p>Your continued support is crucial in this endeavour. Your experiences, your stories, and your voices matter more than ever. Please continue to share them. You can do so by <a href="https://us13.list-manage.com/survey?u=79400f257882be15026d47c7a&amp;id=aaae50e454&amp;attribution=false">clicking here</a> to share your thoughts and experiences.</p>
<p>Together, we can make our case stronger and ensure that everyone’s voice is heard. Let’s continue to work together for a better future for our rural communities.</p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/rural-services-bill/">The Fight to Safeguard Essential Banking and Postal Services in Rural Communities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>As you may know, I have presented the Banking and Postal Services (Rural Areas) Bill, an essential piece of legislation designed to protect the services that our communities across Badenoch and Strathspey so vitally rely on, to the House of Commons. Your voices have been instrumental in driving this process forward. From listening to those …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/rural-services-bill/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">The Fight to Safeguard Essential Banking and Postal Services in Rural Communities</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/rural-services-bill/">The Fight to Safeguard Essential Banking and Postal Services in Rural Communities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7555</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T12:50:25Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T12:50:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="In Parliament"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maria Miller's Response to the Government AI Consultation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-millers-response-government-ai-consultation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maria Miller responded to the Government's AI consultation to highlight the threats faced by women and girls from rapidly developing AI technologies. Read the full response here:
AI Regulation: A Pro-Innovation Approach - Consultation Response
Overview
AI presents a real and credible threat to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-millers-response-government-ai-consultation</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Supporting Global Motor Neurone Disease Awareness 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/supporting-global-motor-neurone-disease-awareness-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Motor Neurone Disease Association has hosted its event marking Global MND Awareness Day 2023. Within the United Kingdom, MND has affected more than 5,000 adults; Motor Neurone Disease is a fatal, rapidly advancing neurological condition. 
Support is needed for research within the field of MND. It…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/supporting-global-motor-neurone-disease-awareness-2023</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart welcomes £270,360 to fund new farming equipment </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-welcomes-ps270360-fund-new-farming-equipment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness, is pleased that farmers across Beverley and Holderness have been rewarded £270,260 to upgrade their farming equipment from the Farming Equipment and Technology Fund. 
 
Announced in Autumn 2021, the Farming Equipment and Investment Fund helps farmers…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-welcomes-ps270360-fund-new-farming-equipment</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg challenges Rail Minister over HS2 failures on community engagement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-challenges-rail-minister-over-hs2-failures-community-engagement" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">At the Transport Select Committee this morning, Greg Smith MP once more raised serious concerns with the Rail Minister about the behaviour of HS2 Ltd and their contractors when it comes to their lack of consideration towards everyone who is so badly affected by the construction of this monstrous…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-challenges-rail-minister-over-hs2-failures-community-engagement</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>BIGYN WARD ADVICE SURGERY – CANCELLED</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/06/bigyn-ward-advice-surgery-cancelled/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BIGYN WARD ADVICE SURGERY &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday, 23rd June 2023 – Selwyn Samuel Centre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Please note that the above surgery has now been cancelled.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Residents in the Bigyn Ward area who had planned to attend for an advice session appointment should instead contact my office in the usual way.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">BIGYN WARD ADVICE SURGERY Friday, 23rd June 2023 – Selwyn Samuel Centre Please note that the above surgery has now been cancelled.  Residents in the Bigyn Ward area who had planned to attend for an advice session appointment should instead contact my office in the usual way.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8871</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T10:53:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T10:53:19Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Award Winning Company Celebrates 60 Years in Welwyn Hatfield</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/award-winning-company-celebrates-60-years-in-welwyn-hatfield/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=award-winning-company-celebrates-60-years-in-welwyn-hatfield" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, was invited to KANE International in his constituency to celebrate their 60&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; year in Welwyn Hatfield.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;KANE International is a local family business that designs analysers which help heating engineers install and service heat pumps, hydrogen, gas and oil boilers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps was shown KANE’s latest model – the KANE 460 Heating and Cooling Analyser as well as taking him on a tour around their new building. Mr Shapps was shown all elements of the business from design to construction to sales and was told all about how the company supports the University of Hertfordshire and Oaklands College students into well-paid jobs in their many areas.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The CEO, Jonathan, thanked Mr Shapps for taking the time to visit:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;We really appreciate Grant&amp;#8217;s support. His business, parliamentary and ministerial experience is invaluable in helping our Welwyn Hatfield constituents make KANE become the UK&amp;#8217;s best analyser company.&amp;#8221;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps was very happy to have been invited to celebrate their 60th year in the constituency:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I am thrilled to see that KANE is doing so well and it was a joy to take a tour around their excellent new building to see how the business all fits together. It was a pleasure to join them to celebrate their 60th year in Welwyn Hatfield as KANE provides such fantastic job opportunities for the local community. I thank them for having me to visit”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps wishes the team at KANE the best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/award-winning-company-celebrates-60-years-in-welwyn-hatfield/"&gt;Award Winning Company Celebrates 60 Years in Welwyn Hatfield&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, was invited to KANE International in his constituency to celebrate their 60th year in Welwyn Hatfield. KANE International is a local family business that designs analysers which help heating engineers install and service heat pumps, hydrogen, gas and oil boilers. Mr Shapps was shown KANE’s latest model […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/award-winning-company-celebrates-60-years-in-welwyn-hatfield/">Award Winning Company Celebrates 60 Years in Welwyn Hatfield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Yarwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=48647</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T10:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T10:30:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support for Local Community Groups!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/support-for-local-community-groups/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="margin: 0cm; line-height: 10.8pt;"><span style="font-size: 9.0pt; color: black;">I am encouraging local community groups across Aldridge-Brownhills to apply for funding from the latest round of the £150 million Community Ownership Fund. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm; line-height: 10.8pt;"><span style="font-size: 9.0pt; color: black;">The Government has announced that even more community projects will be able to apply for funding to take over invaluable community assets and run them as businesses – by the community, for the community.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm; line-height: 10.8pt;"><span style="font-size: 9.0pt; color: black;">Many pubs, clubs, and community shops across the UK are already benefiting from our flagship £150 million Community Ownership Fund. I would urge interested groups across our local area to apply for the funding and take part to protect and preserve as many locally prized assets as possible.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 0cm; line-height: 10.8pt;"><span style="font-size: 9.0pt; color: black;">Fort further details go to: –  <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/community-ownership-fund-prospectus"><span class="s11"><span style="color: #0563c1; text-decoration: none; text-underline: none;">Community Ownership Fund: prospectus – GOV.UK (www.gov.uk)</span></span></a></span></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am encouraging local community groups across Aldridge-Brownhills to apply for funding from the latest round of the £150 million Community Ownership Fund.  The Government has announced that even more […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4771</id>
    <published>2023-06-21T09:09:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-21T09:09:47Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why standards in public life matter – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-standards-in-public-life-matter-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-standards-in-public-life-matter-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236640" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/STANDARDSPUB.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>There’s been an awful lot of political noise over the past week or so. Boris Johnson’s honours list; his resignation; the findings of the Privileges Committee that he did deliberately mislead parliament; all have all meant that we are once again furiously debating the importance of standards in public life.</p>
<p>Over the last few days, the point has been made by some that this Conservative psychodrama doesn’t matter to the general public – it’s a ‘Westminster Bubble’ story that doesn’t affect people’s day to day lives.</p>
<p>I couldn’t disagree more, and I think it’s important to set out why. When I was elected by the people of <span class="markenymmpg09" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span>, I was chosen to represent them in Parliament. But democratic representation only works if we have functioning democratic institutions, where debates are held with the correct information and politicians are held to account.</p>
<p>What Boris Johnson did was give incorrect information to the House of Commons. He did so knowingly and repeatedly chose not to correct the record. If we let this slide and dismissed it as ‘Boris being Boris’, we would be setting a dangerous precedent that lying in Parliament doesn’t matter.</p>
<p>The similar is true of the honours system. Boris Johnson has handed out various peerages to his friends, some of whom are under 30-years-old and others who boasted about getting away with breaching Covid restrictions in Number 10. A peerage is not just a flashy title, it means that for the rest of your life you are given a seat in the House of Lords, making and scrutinising laws directly effecting ordinary people. That this privilege should be given out to the pals of a disgraced former Prime Minister makes me incredibly angry, and I suspect I am not alone.</p>
<p>So yes, there is an enormous amount to focus on across the country at the moment, but if we let someone ride roughshod over our democratic institutions then we all suffer. I sincerely hope that the current Prime Minister takes a stand against this kind of behaviour, and sends a message that integrity, honesty and accountability are absolutely essential to modern political life in Britain.</p>
<p>If he is too weak to do so, then he should do the decent thing and call a General Election so that the British people can put an end to this Conservative soap opera once and for all.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-standards-in-public-life-matter-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why standards in public life matter – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>There’s been an awful lot of political noise over the past week or so. Boris Johnson’s honours list; his resignation; the findings of the Privileges Committee that he did deliberately mislead parliament; all have all meant that we are once again furiously debating the importance of standards in public life. Over the last few days, […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-standards-in-public-life-matter-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why standards in public life matter – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236639</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T14:22:22Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T14:22:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins MP joins representatives from Chesterfield’s armed forces community to Labour’s reception to mark Armed Forces Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/20/toby-perkins-mp-joins-representatives-from-chesterfields-armed-forces-community-to-labours-reception-to-mark-armed-forces-day/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/20/toby-perkins-mp-joins-representatives-from-chesterfields-armed-forces-community-to-labours-reception-to-mark-armed-forces-day/">Toby Perkins MP joins representatives from Chesterfield’s armed forces community to Labour’s reception to mark Armed Forces Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/20/toby-perkins-mp-joins-representatives-from-chesterfields-armed-forces-community-to-labours-reception-to-mark-armed-forces-day/">Toby Perkins MP joins representatives from Chesterfield’s armed forces community to Labour’s reception to mark Armed Forces Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5231</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T14:10:30Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T14:10:30Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surgeries June 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/20/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>My next constituency surgery will take place on <strong>Friday 3oth June</strong> in Boutreehill, Irvine.</p>



<p>Please note, however, in order to comply with both Covid and security protocol, these will not be drop-in surgeries – <strong>appointments must be made in advance</strong>.</p>



<p>To book, please call 01294 311 160 or email philippa.whitford.mp@parliament.uk </p>



<p>For scheduled dates and times, please see below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/1-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2765" srcset="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/1-1.png 940w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/1-1-300x251.png 300w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/1-1-768x644.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 940px) 100vw, 940px"/></figure>



<p>Link to the venue location: <a href="https://www.google.co.uk/maps/place/Towerlands+Community+Centre/@55.6190673,-4.6297278,18z/data=!4m6!3m5!1s0x4889cdc90e5c5361:0xb32619d7098a1bee!8m2!3d55.6190673!4d-4.6288266!16s%2Fg%2F1tflxgw1?entry=ttu" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">Towerlands Farm Road, Bourtreehill  KA11 1PY</a></p>



<p><em><strong>Please note that all surgery dates are subject to change dependent upon  Parliamentary business. </strong></em></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20June%202023" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20June%202023" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20June%202023" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20June%202023" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20June%202023" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F20%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2%2F&amp;title=Surgeries%20June%202023" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/20/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2/" data-a2a-title="Surgeries June 2023"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/20/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2/">Surgeries June 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My next constituency surgery will take place on Friday 3oth June in Boutreehill, Irvine. Please ... <a title="Surgeries June 2023" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/20/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/20/surgeries-may-2022-3-2-2-2-2-2/">Surgeries June 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2760</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T13:28:43Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T13:28:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Surgeries"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin pays tribute to local hospices and calls for greater financial support</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-pays-tribute-local-hospices-and-calls-greater-financial-support" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">During a debate on support for hospices last week in Parliament, Aberconwy MP Robin Millar paid tribute to the clinical staff and volunteers of Tŷ Gobaith Children's Hospice and St David’s Hospice.
Robin opened his speech by saying:
“I would like to pay tribute briefly to two hospices in my…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-pays-tribute-local-hospices-and-calls-greater-financial-support</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Armed Forces Day 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/armed-forces-day-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was pleased to attend Banbury’s Armed Forces Day on Saturday in support of our serving troops, veterans, cadets and Service families.
This celebration is a really important annual event locally given our town’s strong links with our Armed Forces community. It was lovely to see so many people come…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/armed-forces-day-2023</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Privileges Committee report into Boris Johnson</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/privileges-committee-report-boris-johnson" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday I voted against the Privileges Committee report and recommendations into Boris Johnson.  I want to set out clearly and unambiguously, for my constituents in Beaconsfield, why I believed this vote mattered and I could not, in all conscience, support it or abstain from it.
 
I believe the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/privileges-committee-report-boris-johnson</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Universal Credit Deductions – impacting on 120,000 children in the North East</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/06/universal-credit-deductions-impacting-on-120000-children-in-the-north-east/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;120,000 children in the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NorthEast?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NorthEast&lt;/a&gt; are impacted by Universal Credit deductions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the Minister if deducting funds from my constituent, a Mother of two young children, who were then forced to use a food bank, is evidence of a working system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He didn&amp;#39;t answer the question. &lt;a href="https://t.co/2yNYDEzZJO"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2yNYDEzZJO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah ???? (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1671070187557212161?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 20, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">120,000 children in the #NorthEast are impacted by Universal Credit deductions. I asked the Minister if deducting funds from my constituent, a Mother of two young children, who were then forced to use a food bank, is evidence of a… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13649</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T10:30:36Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T10:30:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SPEECH: PRIVILEGES COMMITTEE REPORT ON BORIS JOHNSON</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/20/speech-privileges-committee-report-on-boris-johnson/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martin spoke in the House of Commons Debate on the Privileges Committee report into the conduct of ex-Prime Minister Boris Johnson. Here is an extract of his speech transcribed via&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-19/debates/E15A1DF8-31A1-4FEF-B007-3CBF444BAA11/details#contribution-72D44187-9F19-42CB-A6C8-0F10FE824E0E"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hansard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): &lt;/strong&gt;Yesterday I spent some time with my dad, who is about to enter his 90th year, but too many people across Clydebank, Dumbarton and the Vale of Leven did not get time to spend with their dad yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am sure there will be many people in this House who took that opportunity and who have constituents whose fathers, mothers, brothers or sisters are not around because of covid-19. How many disabled people were locked in their homes because they listened to what the Government had to say? My nephew, in a wheelchair in his own home, was unable to go out because of covid-19 and a British Prime Minister who told him what to do but broke the rules himself. My sister, who is a constituent and a kidney transplant patient, sat in her own room unable to go about the house with the rest of her family, just like other constituents across Clydebank, Dumbarton and the Vale of Leven.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is personal. It is personal for every constituent that I represent, and I am sure it is personal for every other constituent represented by Members of this House. But I am afraid the House has to take a lesson. While I commend the report and all the members of the Committee, including the Chair, and I commend all the Clerks who helped, the report does not answer some fundamental questions that the House will need to consider in the long term. How is it possible that Boris Johnson walks out the door and earns millions within days and all we can say—I will quote from the report—is:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In view of the fact that Mr Johnson is no longer a Member, we recommend that he should not be granted a former Member’s pass”?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How ridiculous we look, yet the Committee is hamstrung by the very regulations of this place.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report is not a panacea for democratic practice in the House of Commons for the British state. It is not an answer, but it does contain evidence about the former Member for Uxbridge, who lied through their teeth and partied on while our constituents were dying. As the hon. Member for Weaver Vale (Mike Amesbury) talked about, there were people in working-class communities the length and breadth of these islands—ambulance drivers, paramedics, orderlies in hospitals—who could not get personal protective equipment, even though we have seen it dumped in fields in the shires of England in the last couple of days. How ridiculous that communities like mine had to suffer the indignity of that buffoon sitting in Downing Street while our families were dying.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Some Conservative Members said they saw no evidence. Well guess what? Here’s the evidence! It is in the report. They might as well read it for a change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Another former Prime Minister, David Cameron, said at the covid inquiry today that&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“from all my experience of chairing COBRs…the system works…but the system works better when the Prime Minister is in the chair”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Conservative party removed the right hon. Member for Maidenhead (Mrs May). While we may disagree, I have every confidence that she would have been at every Cobra meeting during covid-19, unlike the person they replaced her with. That is the ridiculous proposition that David Cameron came up with today. He agrees that that idiot—if that is not parliamentary, I will retract it, but I think it is—missed five covid-19 Cobra meetings. People were dying, it was the greatest tragedy since the blitz, and he could not be bothered to turn up. My constituents turned up. They had to go to work; they drove ambulances; they were working as porters in hospitals. What do they get told? I will say it again: that the former Member for Uxbridge gets his pass taken off him. That actually sounds quite pathetic, but those are the limitations that have been given to us in this report. They are the limitations placed on the Privileges Committee itself.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Back on 9 December 2021—because we had heard about Christmas parties in 2020; you might remember that, Mr Speaker—I asked whether the then Paymaster General, the right hon. and learned Member for Northampton North (Sir Michael Ellis), agreed&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“that if something looks like a duck, walks like a duck, quacks like a duck and it is at a Christmas party, it is usually a duck.”—[&lt;/em&gt;Official Report, 9 December 2021; Vol. 705, c. 563.]&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It seems that the duck was also a liar, and that liar said that those parties never took place. On the issue that my hon. Friend the Member for Glasgow East (David Linden) talked about, that of the rights and privileges of the former Member for Uxbridge now that they have left, do not give him a damn thing. Do not allow a single honour that he has sought the monarch’s approval for to go through. I am no monarchist, but I believe that the monarch—the Head of State—or the advisers to the monarchy have the ability to say that the person is not befitting the honour. That whole goddamn list is not befitting any honour. Every single one of them should be withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But that brings us back to the crux of the whole issue: the limitations on the House. We are giving out honours left, right and centre to people who sit as legislators who broke the law. The report expunges them: they are lawbreakers, but through privilege, we are allowing them to sit in the other place. We are forcing the Head of State, the monarch—through the Prime Minister, in practice—to make sure that those people go to the other place to dictate law to us and our constituents. What an absolute laughing stock!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is the issue of those who see the report as some sort of panacea that will allow the House of Commons, this mother of Parliaments, to move forward. Democracy is imperfect, and I think the hon. Member for Brighton, Pavilion (Caroline Lucas) was the first Member to talk about the issue of truth in our politics and how far it goes back. I am afraid that this report will not answer why Boris Johnson came about. It will not answer the questions about the dark money that funded his campaign for Brexit. It will not answer the issues around Scottish limited partnerships that funnel money—issues that so many Members know about and that we have talked about consistently, but which the Government do nothing about. That is why this report exists: we have allowed it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I hope to God—I am a doubting Thomas when it comes to that; I am an imperfect Christian—that Members on all sides of the House will go through the Lobby tonight to support the report, with all its limitations. However, it does not answer the question that my constituents want answered as to why Boris Johnson is not at the Bar, being held in contempt as a stranger. Some people may say that that is a bit of an arcane process, but he was the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland. It is the first time that a Prime Minister has been held in contempt of the House, and this is all we have got to say to him. How ridiculous this place must seem to our constituents; how ridiculous it must seem to the people of Clydebank, Dumbarton and the Vale that this ex-Prime Minister swans off while they are living in the traumas of the modern age. What an absolute parcel of rogues in a nation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch the debate in full &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://parliamentlive.tv/event/index/3df2f5d0-f842-4ad5-bbb4-1706499f1e1f?in=21:15:20"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://martindocherty.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/House_of_Commons_19_06_23_21_15_23-1.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Martin spoke in the House of Commons Debate on the Privileges Committee report into the conduct of ex-Prime Minister Boris Johnson. Here is an extract of his speech transcribed via Hansard: Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): Yesterday I spent some time with my dad, who is about to enter his 90th year, but too many ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="SPEECH: PRIVILEGES COMMITTEE REPORT ON BORIS JOHNSON" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/20/speech-privileges-committee-report-on-boris-johnson/#more-1821778" aria-label="More on SPEECH: PRIVILEGES COMMITTEE REPORT ON BORIS JOHNSON">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821778</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T10:14:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T10:14:44Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Boris Johnson"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Partygate"/>
    <category term="Privileges Committee report"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“DOING NOTHING IS NOT AN OPTION” – COST OF LIVING CRISIS FOR NEW PARENTS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/new-parents-cost-of-living/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine as Chair of the House of Commons Petitions Committee  led a debate in parliament highlighting the impact of the cost of living crisis on new parents.  The debate comes after a petition calling on the Government to raise statutory maternity pay in line with the cost of living. Opening the debate, Catherine said: “the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/new-parents-cost-of-living/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">“DOING NOTHING IS NOT AN OPTION” – COST OF LIVING CRISIS FOR NEW PARENTS</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7957</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T09:28:38Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T09:28:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Children and Young People"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Families"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="childcare"/>
    <category term="cost of living"/>
    <category term="economy"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
    <category term="petitions"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-95/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">My week began celebrating Women in Cricket. The All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Cricket, chaired by James Daly MP, England and Wales Cricket Board, and Lord’s Taverners hosted the event and we had the opportunity to meet some wonderful famous women cricketers. There was a panel discussion involving the stars and grassroots heroes which focused on the upcoming Ashes, growth of elite women’s cricket, and how to build and grow the game towards the 2026 World Cup.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a vice-chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) on Coalfield Communities I was delighted to attend our Parliamentary launch of the report entitled “<a href="https://www.appgcoalfields.co.uk/levelling-up-the-coalfields">Next Steps in Levelling Up the Former Coalfields</a>” which we published on Monday 12th June. The report is the culmination of evidence gathering sessions, and I thank all contributors. The launch was very well attended by representatives from all over the UK – MPs from all parties, local councillors and officers, trade unions, voluntary organisations, and former miners and their families. The chair Alex Davies-Jones MP (Pontypridd) welcomed everyone and introduced the speakers. Secretariat of the APPG, Chris Whitwood of the Industrial Communities Alliance, presented the report and went through its contents and recommendations. Special thanks to Steve Fothergill, who has been leading on the inquiry and all our previous inquiries. Gary Ellis, CEO, Coalfields Regeneration Trust; Aaron Bell MP; and Owen Thompson MP, responded to the report. The meeting was then opened up for questions from the attendees. I spoke about Thatcher closing down the mines over forty years ago and that she had no plans to replace the livelihoods of the many miners and their families who were left devastated and destitute, and that Neath was a prime example, but that the development of the <a href="https://www.gcre.wales/">Global Centre of Rail Excellence</a> (GCRE) in Onllwyn provided the first real opportunity to bring jobs and apprenticeships to my constituency, so that youngsters will not have to leave to look for employment.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The business in the Chamber was a debate on the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-12/debates/2D29C249-E67F-4787-B72A-A6269147A8FF/RetainedEULaw(RevocationAndReform)Bill">Lords Amendments to the Retained EU Law (Revoke and Reform) Bill</a>. At the end of the Transition Period the EU Withdrawal Act 2018 incorporated most EU Law as applied on December 31st 2020 onto the statute book as “retained EU law”.  There is need to resolve the future status and relevance of retained EU law, how applicable it is and where it should be placed in a hierarchy relative to UK primary legislation. There are over 2,400 pieces of retained EU law to which this Bill will apply covering nearly all Government departments. The Government u-turned on a fundamental aspect of the Bill removing a sunset clause that would have removed all EU retained law from the statute book at the end of 2023. Whilst this is a relief, removing a cliff edge, there are questions about scrutiny and excessive power transfer to the Executive. There were two votes. Lords Amendment 15B which provides that any future regulations restating, revoking or updating retained EU law cannot reduce environmental protection in the UK. The UK Government voted to disagree with this Lords Amendment and won the vote by 269 to 204 votes. Lords Amendment 42B provided for a Commons Committee to examine any plans to revoke or replace retained EU law before being voted on by both Houses before they can be used. The UK Government voted to disagree with this Lords Amendment and won the vote by 269 to 202 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I met Nicky Ryan and Steve Treharne at the <a href="https://www.polfed.org/">Police Federation of England and Wales</a> (PFEW) parliamentary drop-in session for Welsh MPs to support their key campaigns: #Pay #SimplifyDG6 and the Elizabeth Medal. In March 2023, PFEW called for a 17% pay increase after a Social Market Foundation study showed police pay has fallen nearly 20% behind inflation between 2000 and 2022, whilst other protective services pay has increased by 1-1.4%, and police pay has risen at barely half the rate of an average UK employee. #SimplifyDG6 asks the UK Government to issue New Supporting Guidelines and Updated FAQs so that police officers can safely share information with prosecutors (CPS) without the gratuitous obligations on officers to redact evidence. On January 10th 2023, my friend Peter Aldous MP, asked Ed Argar MP (Minister for State and Victims Sentencing) to amend the Data Protection Act to end this bureaucratic burden on policing and speed up administration of justice. On 21st February 2023, the Justice Select Committee asked the then Solicitor General whether the UK Government are considering this amendment.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a vice-chair of the APPG for Rare Diseases, I attended the drop-in event hosted by <a href="https://catapult.org.uk/">Catapult</a>, and the <a href="https://geneticalliance.org.uk/">Genetic Alliance UK</a>, to receive an update about how advanced therapies can transform lives and healthcare, and meet patients who are receiving lifelong treatments which impact severely on their lives, when they could receive a one-time treatment allowing patients and their carers to become or to continue being economically active. Cell and gene therapies can transform people’s lives by addressing the root causes of diseases leading to long-term disease modification. Cell therapy uses living cells to replace missing cells in the body, and gene therapy uses technologies that enable genes to be introduced into the body which modify a genetic information that is the root cause of a disease. They would substantially reduce health care costs, address healthcare inequalities, and create high value jobs, but it needs a changed approach. With coherent and concerted action, the UK can take the lead in demonstrating how to harness the potential of Advanced Therapies to transform health care systems. If fully embraced by the UK’s interrelated health, wellness, and research and innovation structure, Advanced Therapies will keep many more people healthy and fitter for longer, delivering substantially greater value from public expenditure.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dolly Parton created the <a href="https://dollywoodfoundation.org/">Dollywood Foundation</a> and I supported the Parliamentary event to celebrate Dolly’s Imagination Library in the UK and to look to the next chapter. Dolly’s Imagination Library has gifted over 5 million books to under-fives in the UK. That’s 5 million moments that have inspired a lifelong love of books and reading in our youngest children.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The business in the Chamber was a debate on the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-13/debates/5F35C5A7-83E8-4E16-A1DF-0E56E4CDF48D/ProcurementBill(Lords)">Procurement Bill (Lords) Report Stage</a>. The Official Opposition had tabled Amendments to strengthen the Bill, because Labour do recognise the need for this Bill to consolidate the patchwork of former EU rules and create a more straightforward procurement regime, but the Bill is unambitious and fails to take advantage of post Brexit opportunities to promote local businesses and outlaw VIP lanes. The Bill hands more powers to Ministers over direct awards. Amendment 2 would prevent VIP lanes by ensuring that any contract awarded under emergency provisions or direct awards should include transparency declarations and is a recommendation by the independent NAO. The amendment was defeated by 230 to 280 votes. New Clause 10 would clamp down on taxpayer’s money going to tax havens by introducing transparency into the system requiring multinational organisations bidding for large contracts to produce transparent tax reports. The amendment was defeated by 231 to 282 votes. My dear friend Marie Rimmer MP has been campaigning against forced organ harvesting, and Marie tabled an amendment which received cross-party support which is designed to give a discretionary power to exclude suppliers from being awarded a public contract who have participated in forced organ harvesting or unethical activities relating to human tissue including where they are involved in providing a service or goods relating to such activities. Unfortunately, the amendment was defeated by 229 to 280 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">John McNally MP and myself as vice-chair and chair of the APPG for Hairdressing, Barbering and Cosmetology, met with Rob Smith co-founder at <a href="https://www.getslick.com/">Slick</a> to learn about his services to the sector. Rob told us that Slick is committed to helping business owners grow and build the business of their dreams and that he is optimistic for the sustainability of the UK sector because “the lipstick effect” is as true today as it was over 20 years ago – men and women continue to prioritise spending money on life’s little luxuries, blow dries, manicures, lipstick, rather than costlier purchases such as eating out, holidays, and shopping sprees. Rob gathers anonymous data from his clients to build a picture of what UK hair and beauty businesses are experiencing, which show the following trends: salons are busy, with over two thirds of appointments being filled; smaller businesses are busier but have trouble attracting staff; average salon bills and client prices are increasing, especially in larger salons; client habits are changing and they prefer booking online, and salons that offer online booking are thriving; cancellations and no shows are still an issue; with the cost of living crisis, and clients are shopping around for the best prices and value, which influences whether they remain at a particular salon. Rob offered to work with the APPG to tackle these challenges that Rob has identified as the trends that remain problematical for the hair and beauty sector.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Every year, I join the <a href="https://readingagency.org.uk/children/quick-guides/summer-reading-challenge/">Summer Reading Challenge</a>. In 2022-23 The Reading Agency reached over 2.17 million people, including 1.12 million children. People read over 13.5 million books, e-books, and audiobooks, and borrowed over 12.9 million books from libraries. The Reading Agency gifted 256,825 books, e-books, audiobooks and reading resources to people who experience barriers to reading. By taking part in the reading challenge, 3-in-4 children, young people, and adults enjoyed reading 77% more, and increased reading confidence by 71%.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">To celebrate International Domestic Workers Day, I attended the Parliamentary event organised by <a href="https://www.thevoiceofdomesticworkers.com/">The Voice of Domestic Workers</a>, to call on the UK Government to ratify the Domestic Workers Convention, which promotes decent work for domestic workers and recognises their invaluable contribution to the global economy. Its key provisions are: minimum wage; equal treatment re hours, overtime, compensation, daily and weekly rest of at least #24 hours; paid annual leave; access to tribunals and courts; social security, protection from abuse, harassment and violence; labour inspection, enforcement and penalties. Estimates from the International Labour Organisation ILO in 2019 put the numbers of domestic workers at 75.6 million globally, of whom 76.2% are women. They work long hours for low wages and are often excluded from Labour and social protections. They suffer abuse, forced Labour, domestic servitude, and failure to be paid the minimum wage. The Voice of Domestic Workers (formerly Justice 4 Domestic Workers) is an education and campaigning group, calling for justice and rights for the UKs thousands of foreign domestic workers.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I took part in Flavour Perception Testing, which is an early screening process for Alzheimer’s disease being developed by The University of Warwick and University Hospitals for Coventry and Warwickshire. It was a pleasure to meet Professor Alan Chalmers of <a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/wmg/">Warwick Manufacturing Group</a> (WMG) at University of Warwick, who explained that the profile of the ability to taste and smell as a means of early detecting the possibility of Alzheimer’s so that the person can be referred quickly for the tests that will actually confirm diagnosis. The inability to distinguish flavours is an early sign of Alzheimer’s. Every 5 seconds someone is affected by Alzheimer’s, but there is no current means of early and widespread screening. The new drugs that are coming onto the market which can reverse Alzheimer’s but only when it is in its earliest stages, means that early detection is absolutely vital. Parliamentarians were given 2 drinks to taste and had to decide which was the sweetest, and if you correctly identified the sweetest flavour, it was a sign that they were symptom-free for Alzheimer’s.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I have been a supporter of <a href="https://www.guidedogs.org.uk/">Guide Dogs UK</a> for many years, and it was a pleasure to meet my friends from <a href="https://www.guidedogs.org.uk/guide-dogs-cymru/">Guide Dogs Cymru</a> who are blind or partially sighted and who had made the long train journey from Wales to Westminster on a very hot June day. It was so hot that they had to leave their support dogs at home, but the wonderful staff and volunteers from Guide Dogs Cymru travelled with them to look after them, and make sure that they arrived safely. It is so important that adults, young people, and children who have lost their sight or are partially sighted, do not lose their freedom as well. I repledged my support to Guide Dogs UK in its campaign to stop people who are blind or partially sighted being refused access to premises, services and some modes of transport when they are accompanied by their support dogs.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was proud to meet representatives from <a href="https://www.akt.org.uk/">Akt</a>, which is a charity that works with 16-25 year olds in the UK who identify as LGBTQ+ and are experiencing homelessness or struggling with their housing situation. Akt believe that there are 5 important reasons for raising awareness of LGBTQ+ youth homelessness: over 24% of young people experiencing homelessness identify as LGBTQ+; 77% of young people Akt support cited family rejection and abuse after coming out or being outed; they will often be asked to “evidence” that they have been kicked out, but they cannot, or ask to return to abusive relationships; nearly 25% are not aware of available support services, and only 33% sought support from their local authority whilst homeless; only 44% of local authorities and housing associations have received training on LGBTQ+ inclusion and LGBTQ+ homelessness. Akt is calling for the UK Government to implement a national cross-department strategy to end youth homelessness including: prevention, focusing on schools, families and councils; housing; and financing. Improve monitoring of gender identity and sexuality in housing and homelessness services. Build safe and inclusive housing and homelessness services.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the <a href="https://www.tsb.co.uk/fraud-prevention-centre/fraud-refund-guarantee/">TSB Fraud Guarantee Refund</a> event again this year to listen to the progress that TSB has made since it implemented its refund policy to all victims of fraud cases at TSB in 2019. It was positive to hear that TSB has refunded 97% of all claims, but concerning that Meta companies account for 80% of fraud cases at TSB within the three most common fraud categories – investment, impersonation, and purchase fraud. TSB are campaigning for media companies to protect its customers and take financial liability when their safeguards fail.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">It was an honour to meet the Ukraine Diplomat, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vasyl_Filipchuk">Dr Vasyl Filipchuk</a>, for a confidential briefing on the current situation in Ukraine and for an overview of the short-term and long-term challenges plus the strategic issues facing Ukraine during Putin’s attacks, and rebuilding infrastructure when the war is over. Dr Filipchuk is a foreign and security expert at Ukraine’s oldest think tank – the <a href="https://www.icps.com.ua/en/">International Centre for Policy Studies</a> (ICPS). Vasyl has worked in many previous roles, including the Ukraine Government’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs, the Cabinet Ministry of Ukraine, and was spokesperson, political director, EU director general in the Foreign Ministry of Ukraine, and the EU director at the Secretariat of the Ukraine Government. In 2014, Vasyl founded his own media holding – Apostrophe – which included TV, internet media, and social platforms, as well as consulting companies which specialise in communication media, business intelligence, and crisis management.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My week began celebrating Women in Cricket. The All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Cricket, chaired by James Daly MP, England and Wales Cricket Board, and Lord’s Taverners hosted the event and we had the opportunity to meet some wonderful famous women cricketers. There was a panel discussion involving the stars and grassroots heroes which focused […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2748</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T20:16:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T20:16:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on gender-based violence and its impact on trade</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_article_on_gender-based_violence_and_trade" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_article_on_gender-based_violence_and_trade</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T14:14:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T14:14:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-53" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I would like to start this week’s column by paying tribute to the victims of the attack that occurred in Nottingham. Three horrific murders took place and several families have lost their loved ones. It was an incredibly dark day for our city, and I don’t think the people of Nottinghamshire will…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-53</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What steps are the Government taking to cut out the paperwork and free up frontline time to keep our communities safe?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/what-steps-are-government-taking-cut-out-paperwork-and-free-frontline-time-keep-our" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Despite the Government’s efforts to free up the time of frontline police officers by reducing the amount of bureaucracy and paperwork, which takes up more and more of their time, officers often say to me that this increases year on year and so reduces the amount of time they can spend on the beat.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/what-steps-are-government-taking-cut-out-paperwork-and-free-frontline-time-keep-our</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-204" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Procurement Bill completed its remaining stages in the House of Commons on Tuesday before the Bill was sent back to the Lords for consideration of the changes that the House of Commons has made. The Bill will establish a set of transformative new rules which rip up bureaucratic EU regulations…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-204</id>
    <published>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-19T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Welcomes Government Funding to Boost Skills Training</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-welcomes-government-funding-boost-skills-training" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has welcomed the Government’s £48 million investment through the Skills Investment Fund, boosting the rollout of Higher Technical Qualifications (HTQs) and equipping students from all backgrounds with the high-quality, higher-level skills needed to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-welcomes-government-funding-boost-skills-training</id>
    <published>2023-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Barnehurst Ward Coffee Morning</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/barnehurst-ward-coffee-morning" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Saturday 17th June, Barnehurst Ward held a Coffee Morning at Anne Rawlings House. 
The event was attended by Rt Hon Sir David Evennett and Ward Councillors Brian Bishop and Howard Jackson.
 
 </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/barnehurst-ward-coffee-morning</id>
    <published>2023-06-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>I was pleased to speak to Ben Wright on Radio 4’s Westminster Hour on Sunday night about Keir Starmer’s call for a General Election following the resignations of the former Prime Minister and two of his supporters. There will now be at least 2 by-elections in July and potentially and third later this year all about the same issues but all taking place in very different parts of the country. We also have the issue of Margaret Ferrier’s seat in Scotland potentially coming vacant in the summer.</p>
<p>We cannot continue over the next 6 or 12 months with a government more focussed on party management than addressing the needs of the country. Who knows if there will be more by-elections in the coming months, causing yet more disruption and distraction from the issues that really matter to people.</p>
<p>I joined a debate in Westminster Hall on the new hospital programmes, predominantly in London, however the issue of hospitals is not a localised issue. We quickly learned that the Government’s promise of a new hospital programme was not a promise of 40 new hospitals. They are not all hospitals and there certainly are not 40 of them.</p>
<p>According to the National Audit Office, the NHS estate does not meet the demands of a modern health service. The growth in backlog maintenance risks harm to patients, and the need for capital is being consistently underestimated. Billions of pounds of capital spending have been diverted to cover inadequate revenue funding, and yet some restrictive ringfencing on some capital budgets means there are huge underspends even though the NHS estate is crying out for investment.</p>
<p>In July 2020, the Public Accounts Committee recommended a capital strategy and guidance, including expectations on how backlog maintenance costs will be addressed alongside other priorities.<br/>
In October 2021, the NHS Confederation stated that NHS leaders had concerns about safety standards because they cannot sufficiently maintain their estate, enable positive digital innovations and reduce the elective backlog without further worsening health inequalities. It described a disjointed and opaque allocation system and unresolved issues about how integrated care systems will allocate and prioritise capital spend. Where is the Government action on any of this?</p>
<p>I saw the impact of the cuts to the health service during a visit to Hull with Wes Streeting MP and the Shadow Health team. We went to see Bransholme Health Centre, the Urgent Treatment Centre, the Jean Bishop Integrated Care Centre and Hull Royal Infirmary Emergency Department. The incredible work that the doctors, nurses, healthcare assistants and all the other hospital staff are doing in very difficult circumstances is always inspiring. We saw some fantastic services for frail patients to help keep them from falls and maintain independence, but the staff are so clearly at breaking point. Our health service needs support – it deserves our support, because I do not know where we would be without them and their care and dedication.</p>
<p>In Bristol, it was wonderful to visit New Oak Primary and meet with staff and see the work being done with some exceptional young people. This is a fantastic, nurturing environment for our young people. The teachers, teaching assistants, and SEND staff have created a great atmosphere for learning and there is support for every student and their needs. I got to speak to some of the students and they quizzed me on my job as an MP. It’s great to spend time with some inquiring minds and those who have such bright ideas about the future!  And to all the year 11’s moving on, good luck for whatever comes next.</p>
<p>This week we marked the anniversary of the Grenfell Tower fire, which took the lives of 72 people. We remember the victims, and stand with their loved ones and the Grenfell community as they pursue justice and campaign for change.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575.</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/">Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to speak to Ben Wright on Radio 4’s Westminster Hour on Sunday night about Keir Starmer’s call […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/16/weekly-round-up-16th-june-2023/">Weekly Round Up :: 16th June 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3549</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T15:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T15:00:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill Holds Adjournment Debate on Heating Rural Homes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/16/sir-bill-holds-adjournment-debate-on-heating-rural-homes/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Tuesday evening, Sir Bill Wiggin, Member of Parliament for North Herefordshire, held an Adjournment Debate on Heating Rural Homes. Sir Bill called on the Government to rethink its 2026 oil-fired boiler ban and recognise that rural homes were not... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/16/sir-bill-holds-adjournment-debate-on-heating-rural-homes/#more-4776">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4776</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T14:26:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T14:26:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne-Marie on ITV Tyne Tees Around the House</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-itv-tyne-tees-around-house" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday I discussed several of the important issues facing our local area with ITV News Tyne Tees.
You can catch up on the broadcast of their ‘Around The House’ programme online at:
https://www.itv.com/news/tyne-tees/2023-06-16/around-the-house-watch-june-2023-programme
 </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-itv-tyne-tees-around-house</id>
    <published>2023-06-16T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-16T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John calls on Government to enable Britain&#8217;s world-leading Open Banking success in other sectors too]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/16/john-calls-on-government-to-enable-britains-world-leading-open-banking-success-in-other-sectors-too/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5758</id>
		<updated>2023-06-16T10:39:15Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-16T10:39:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/16/john-calls-on-government-to-enable-britains-world-leading-open-banking-success-in-other-sectors-too/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/06/16/snp-opposition-day-debate-on-the-need-for-a-dedicated-cost-of-living-committee/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10882</id>
		<updated>2023-06-16T09:23:37Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-16T09:20:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[During an SNP Opposition Day Debate in Westminster on Wednesday 14th June, my colleagues and I called for the UK Government to set up a dedicated Cost Of Living Committee &#8211; to better understand the impact of Brexit and the cost-of-living crisis and to explore possible solutions to these matters. In rural constituencies like Argyll ... <a title="SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/06/16/snp-opposition-day-debate-on-the-need-for-a-dedicated-cost-of-living-committee/" aria-label="More on SNP Opposition Day Debate on the need for a dedicated Cost of Living Committee">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/House_of_Commons_14_06_23_15_30_03_V1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="13578289" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rat-Running Taskforce – Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/rat-running-taskforce-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2726" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">15 June 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Rat-Running Taskforce – Update</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span>As part of my ongoing campaign to support the South of the A47 Taskforce that I helped convene in order to address rat-running concerns in the Corridor between the Wood Lane/Berry’s Lane junction at Honingham and the A11 at Wymondham, I welcomed the chance to engage again with the Taskforce in recent days.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Although much progress has been made as the Taskforce have worked with Norfolk County Council Highways to develop a package of mitigation measures aimed at alleviating existing rat-running while also preparing in advance for any likely impacts of the A47 dualling between North Tuddenham and Easton (as well as the Norwich Western Link), I am conscious that there remain some local concerns about specific routes along this Corridor that appear to have been missed in the mitigation package.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>That’s why I have contacted NCC Highways again to suggest another rat-running meeting in the coming weeks to look at what more can be done for those one or two locations worried that they are not included in the proposals.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Rest assured, I am firmly committed to supporting these communities – and will continue to hold the key stakeholders to account in order to deliver the mitigation improvements we need to see.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Full details of my work with the Taskforce can be found on my website </span></span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/a47-rat-running-campaign-and-taskforce"><span>here</span></a>.</span></span></span></p>

<p> </p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2021-06/george_freeman_yaxham.jpg" width="540" height="325" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2726 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T15:46:29Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T15:46:29Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Critics Must Allow Debate]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=7054</id>
		<updated>2023-06-15T15:33:54Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-15T15:33:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="division"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="government"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="labour"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="politics"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="tory"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It&#8217;s become fashionable to claim our politics is broken and, given the recent behaviour of a few leaders, it’s easy to understand why, but are some of the loudest critics also breaking our politics? I’m talking about the intolerant activists, those who never stand for election to anything but assume they’re always right and know<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Critics Must Allow Debate</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6589" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-6/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6589" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>It&#8217;s become fashionable to claim our politics is broken and, given the recent behaviour of a few leaders, it’s easy to understand why, but are some of the loudest critics also breaking our politics?</p>



<p>I’m talking about the intolerant activists, those who never stand for election to anything but assume they’re always right and know what other people must give up. We see it in the cavalier behaviour of protestors like ‘Just Stop Oil’ and their contempt for the opinions of others. It’s also standard behaviour for ‘keyboard warriors’, who direct streams of social media abuse at anyone daring to question their views.</p>



<p>Birmingham is a large and diverse city. We need to accommodate conflicting pressures and different views. It isn’t always easy.</p>



<p>I acknowledge the needs of the transgender community but consider those with concerns or who want women’s only spaces also have a totally valid point. They can’t just be shouted down. Even on relatively simple issues like cycling, there are those obsessed with demonising all car drivers and attacking anyone not sharing their views. I doubt their behaviour wins many converts. Like a religious cult, it’s a politics based on closing down anyone with doubts. I see it drive normal people away from politics and other community groups.</p>



<p>I want politicians to up their game and treat the public with much more respect, but I also want a politics that allows debate and follows a process we can all understand. Small groups can’t have everything they want, no matter how much they disrupt or abuse. Practical politics requires consensus and efforts to balance the interests of all. As I often say, we might not always agree but it’s good to listen and show respect for others. It’s ironic that those who frequently denounce the behaviour of housing estate youths have no problem with the same antics when practised by their middle-class friends. Often, those who are most critical of our politics show the least respect for others. We need more reasoned arguments and less abuse, that would go a long way to mending the way we do our politics.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/06/15/critics-must-allow-debate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Ashford Jobs Fair Success</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-jobs-fair-success" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Everyone who has ever put on an event will know the feeling of worry beforehand. Will it work? Will anyone come?
I needed to have no such worries last week about my latest Jobs Fair in the Job Centre at County Square. Employers from the public, private and voluntary sectors filled the room with…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-jobs-fair-success</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MONTHLY CASEWORK SUMMARY</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/monthly-casework-summary" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
 Behind the scenes, MPs receive a significant number of emails from local residents asking for support with a variety of important personal issues.
Have a look, and see some of the things that I’ve been helping local residents with...
 If there’s anything I can do for you, please do get in touch.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/monthly-casework-summary</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Sadly today marks 6 years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower"/>
		<published>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</published>
		<updated>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WHIT FRIDAY FUN]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=498</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T09:11:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T09:10:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MacNeil calls for compensation for Uist businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses in Uist affected by the lack of Lochboisdale sailings in the month of June.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said: “People&amp;#8217;s jobs and livelihoods have been badly affected. The increased ferry traffic since RET has brought greater economic activity and as a result people have risen to meet the opportunities presented, and therefore cannot afford the financial hit when expected services don&amp;#8217;t materialise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given that practical alternatives to provide a ferry service, admittedly lesser than was timetabled, did not materialise, then the only other course of action is for businesses to be compensated for their loss.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Increased demand is placing greater strain on the ferry service with more people travelling in recent years, but that is not a fault the people in Uist should bear with a hit to their back pocket.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I do hope the Scottish Government will do the right, fair and decent thing, and compensate businesses.&amp;nbsp; It would be to their great credit if they did.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":29149039,"permalink":"https:\/\/angusmacneilsnp.com\/2023\/06\/12\/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses\/"}'  class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3780" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/angus/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png" data-orig-size="768,1024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="angus" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=529" data-id="3780" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-3780" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=113 113w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225 225w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4205</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sturgeon must be suspended from the SNP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following the arrest of Nicola Sturgeon on Sunday, and given the scale of the police investigation and the potential repercussions, the former First Minister should really be suspended from the SNP.
SNP MSP Michelle Thomson has said Sturgeon should lose the SNP whip, joining calls from the Scottish…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Consultation</h2>
<p>Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the County Council, Surrey has launched a consultation to seek views about three different potential options for the village.</p>
<p>The proposals are pretty wide-ranging, and it is important that everyone in Ewell gets the chance to give their views about the options, and indeed can suggest things that might be done as well or instead. You can find details of the consultation by following this link.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled">https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled</a>.</p>
<p>I am afraid that I am a little late to alert you about the drop in events, but you have the whole of June to make your views known.</p>
<h2>Charities Fair – Friday 23rd June</h2>
<p>For those of you who are looking for an opportunity to volunteer for a local charity, a reminder that my latest Charity Volunteers Fair is being held at St Paul’s Church, Howell Hill, between 4pm and 6pm on Friday June 23<sup>rd</sup>. For those of you who do not know the church, it is beyond Ewell East station on the road to Cheam.</p>
<p>Please do come along. There will be a wide range of local charities presenting what they do and looking for help.</p>
<h2>The Horton Arts Centre</h2>
<p>The Horton Arts Centre – Epsom’s beautifully renovated former chapel – has asked me to tell you that it is celebrating being open for one year. The award-winning heritage venue is planning a wide range of performances, courses and events this summer and the café-bar is open all day Tuesday to Saturday plus every Friday night.</p>
<p>A free photography exhibition by Epsom Camera Club is now running until 17 June and highlights coming up include a series of authentic Spanish classical music and dance concerts, performed in the round, 18-19 July.</p>
<p>See their website for more details: thehortonepsom.org or call 01372 747662.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Day</h2>
<p>And one more date for your diary. The organisers have asked me to let you know that Ewell Village Fair this year is on the 15<sup>th</sup>. It’s always a good day out. And many thanks and congratulations to everyone involved in Ashtead Rotary for organising another really good Ashtead Village Day on Saturday.</p>
<p>I hope you are well and have a good summer.</p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters. Ewell Village Consultation Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6430</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It is with a with a heavy heart and after much consideration, that I announce my decision not to stand again as your Member of Parliament at the next election. Serving as your representative has been an honour and a privilege, especially as it allowed me to serve the city in which I was born, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/">Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5157</id>
    <published>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed Closure of Girlguiding Activity Centres]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1785</id>
		<updated>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Update on Small Boat Crossings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/an-update-on-small-boat-crossings/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Prime Minister Rishi Sunak visited the Kent coast to meet with members of the Border Force team at Dover. Stopping illegal migration from small boat crossings in the Channel is one of the top priorities for the government. We must bring to an end these dangerous journeys that have led to loss […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6306</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/data-reveals-long-mental-health-waiting-lists-dagenham-rainham" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;span property="schema:name"&gt;Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span rel="schema:author"&gt;&lt;span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang=""&gt;Andrew&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-06-07T10:19:00+00:00"&gt;Wed, 06/07/2023 - 11:19&lt;/span&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1208 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To save lives, the Government must set new targets to tackle the ‘silent disease’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/to-save-lives-the-government-must-set-new-targets-to-tackle-the-silent-disease/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith has been vocal on the issue of Osteoporosis, which affects half of all women and a fifth of all men over 50. It is characterised by a loss of bone density, leaving people vulnerable to breaks and fractures. Because symptoms often aren’t noticed until a serious break, osteoporosis has been called the ‘silent disease’.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Raising the issue in Parliament, Judith highlighted the shocking reality of the condition:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Many of these will be serious hip fractures, and as many people will die from these fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Questioning the Minister, Judith asked why such a serious condition is so often overlooked in healthcare:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Can the Minister explain why not even one of the 63 key performance indicators set by NHS England for Integrated Care Boards sets a target for fracture prevention?’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Maria Caulfield MP, Minister for Women’s Health Strategy, thanked Judith for her longstanding work on bone health. The Minister also highlighted measures the Government is undertaking to tackle Osteoporosis:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘NHS England is expanding fracture services for higher risk women who do have Osteoporosis to prevent falls in the first place.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the Government’s claims to be stepping up fracture services, the limits of the current services mean that 74,000 preventable fractures will occur over the next five years, costing the NHS £665 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making fracture prevention a key performance target could lead to stronger delivery of these services, preventing unnecessary pain, giving patients the level of care they deserve, and saving vital NHS resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Following the exchange, Judith said that Government support for fracture prevention was still inadequate:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Whilst Bradford offers a trailblazing service for those with Osteoporosis, this is not always the case nationally.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘The argument for investing in the prevention of fractures is clear: To save money and save lives, we need a government with the sense to invest in the future of women’s health in this country.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;???? As many people die from hip fractures as from lung disease or diabetes &amp;#8211; but osteoporosis is often overlooked in healthcare.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; While Bradford &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BTHFT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BTHFT&lt;/a&gt; has a trailblazing service, this isn&amp;#39;t the case nationally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;????This needs to improve. &lt;a href="https://t.co/c4MTw9LtoB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/c4MTw9LtoB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1666090988975321088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/FLS-Report-2022-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" alt="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith Cummins MP on Tuesday called for the government to step up and provide 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services in England.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Osteoporosis is a long-term health condition characterised by weak bones prone to breaking or fracture. It affects 3.5m people across the UK: a fifth of men and half&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: fracture, people, services, judith, england, fractures, nhs, health, osteoporosis, will&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SDP3245-0810-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" alt="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked: “Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, government, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" alt="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, minister, health, bradford, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;Government has 'lots of words - but very little action'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/SDP3245-0255-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" alt="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In her latest editorial in the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus, Judith talks about her recent work on a range of important local and national issues: I hope that people have managed to get a break during the summer. Over the summer months we saw terrible events unfold in Afghanistan. Afghanistan is&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, will, care, people, issue, local, bradford, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed. Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives. Judith has been vocal on the issue […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2741</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Asylum Backlog &amp; Small Boats on Channel 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/asylum-backlog-small-boats-on-channel-4/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>joshuatuck</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3459</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My statement on the continued closure of the High Wycombe driving test centre</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/06/my-statement-on-the-continued-closure-of-the-high-wycombe-driving-test-centre/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I understand the frustration the continued closure of the driving test centre is causing. I share that frustration. Constituents are routinely writing to me requesting an update on its planned reopening, illustrating the reasons I believe it is essential we have a functional driving test centre in High Wycombe. As many of my constituents know, we have, of course, been here before. Twice now, I have worked with key stakeholders in our area to save the driving test centre in […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18663</id>
    <published>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#DrivingTestCentre"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Driving Test Centre"/>
    <category term="High Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The new Executive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/22/the-new-executive/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor David Mellen will remain as Leader of the council, continuing the hard work of continuing the hard work of himself, Cllr Adele Williams, Cllr Sally Longford and all previous and current executive and backbench members. He is responsible for continuing devolution, strategic regeneration, development and work on the city’s ambitious plan to be carbon neutral by 2028, as well as promoting the vision of the council and supporting all of his Portfolio Holders in their work. There is much work to be done over the next term and the new executive will be key in achieving the goals Nottingham Labour want for the city.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Audra Wynter has been confirmed as the new Deputy Leader and she will have responsibility for the finance and HR portfolios. With a background in finance work, Councillor Wynter will ensure the council remains on track in delivering a balanced budget and sticking to the Medium-Term Financial Plan, while delivering high-quality services for residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-small-font-size"&gt;Councillor Corall Jenkins will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Energy, Environment and Waste Services and Parks. She will have responsibility for key services such as bin collection and disposal, keeping our city’s streets clean and maintaining all of our wonderful parks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Cheryl Barnard will remain as Portfolio Holder for Children, Young People and Education. She will continue to be responsible for leading our children’s services, working with Ofsted to improve it where necessary, ensuring children’s safeguarding and working with academy trusts across the city on schools, ensuring attendance and working to reduce exclusions, so that all children get the best start in life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Steve Battlemuch will be taking up the reins as Portfolio Holder for Skills, Growth, Economic Development and Property. He will lead on skills and employment, ensuring that the workforce in the city is prepared for any changes in the way we work, and that the people of this city have the right opportunities. He will also oversee the management of the city centre, attracting investment and helping to ensure that Nottingham is promoted nationally and internationally to business and tourism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Jay Hayes has been confirmed as the new Portfolio Holder for Housing. He will lead on managing the council housing service, student housing, private rented properties and areas such as selective licensing and homelessness. Housing is incredibly important, all those who live in the city deserve to have a property that is safe, secure and that can be called home, whether they rent in the private sector or have social housing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sajid Mohammed will lead as Portfolio Holder for Neighbourhoods, Safety and Inclusion. This covers areas such as community protection, domestic violence work, licensing, taxi strategy and more. It is so important that Nottingham is a safe place to work and live in. Councillor Mohammed with many years of experience of community work and as director of Himmah will bring the required expertise to lead in these vital areas, and he will also lead on refugee and asylum seeker work, to ensure that Nottingham is a welcoming city for all, and that those vulnerable refugees and asylum seekers can integrate and make new lives in Nottingham.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Pavlos Kotsonis will continue as Portfolio Holder for Leisure and Culture. He will ensure that we continue to offer an outstanding events programme. He will also oversee the reopening and flourishing of the Castle, the continued running of Wollaton Hall and Newstead Abbey as well as leisure centres, markets, libraries and community centres across the city. Access to cultural events and key things like libraries and leisure centres is so important for allowing the people of the city to thrive and create.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Linda Woodings will also remain as Portfolio Holder for Adult Social Care and Health. She will continue to work on Public Health and Wellbeing, tackling health inequalities and working to reduce smoking prevalence, working on mental health and generally improving the health of residents in the city. She will also lead on independent living. All of these will help to improve the quality and length of life for residents in the city for years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, Councillor Angela Kandola will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Highways, Transport and Planning. She will oversee public transport such as buses and the tram. She will also lead on greener transport such as cycling and cycling links in the city, ensure highways are correctly managed and repaired as well as the Workplace Parking Levy to help increase public transport usage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is just a short summary of the responsibilities that the Executive will have for the next year. They will bring both their expertise and new views to help ensure that there is strong and effective political leadership at the council. This will continue both our journey with the Improvement and Assurance Board but also enable us to bring in the pledges that we made to the residents of the city in our manifesto in the May local elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=3074</id>
    <published>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Arboretum"/>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="Berridge"/>
    <category term="Bestwood"/>
    <category term="Bilborough"/>
    <category term="Bulwell"/>
    <category term="Bulwell Forest"/>
    <category term="Castle"/>
    <category term="Dales"/>
    <category term="election"/>
    <category term="Housing"/>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/2023/05/17/april-newsletter-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>liamtaggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=333</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3374</id>
		<updated>2023-05-16T11:22:21Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-16T11:22:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; Dear Constituent, Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve been on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Illegal migration bill update:</u></strong></p>



<p>The main piece of legislation that has been going through the House of Commons in the last few weeks is the Illegal Migration Bill. I’ve heard from a number of constituents with a diverse range of views on this topic. On the 26<sup>th</sup> of April the bill completed its remaining stages in the Commons and is now moving through the House of Lords, before it will return to the Commons for a final review.</p>



<p>This Bill is set to enhance the powers of the Government to tackle illegal migration, including the ability to remove illegal migrants from the UK to safe countries, new ways to determine ages of migrants without formal identification, additional protections for child migrants, and tougher sentences for those found guilty of people smuggling. The Bill was also amended during its remaining stages to include the Government’s commitment to review the safe and legal routes that are available.</p>



<p>It is clear that we need an asylum system that does work for those families truly in need, but is also tough on those who are trying to exploit the process to gain entry to the UK and on human traffickers who are exploiting vulnerable people and worsening the crisis. The new bill tackles the latter problems, while leaving open safe and legal routes for those in need.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sewage &amp; storm overflows update:</u></strong></p>



<p>Another key development in Parliament was new plans to further increase water quality targets and reduce sewage being released into our waterways.</p>



<p>The Government has announced its plan to enshrine the Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published last August, into law through the Environment Act. This will make its target to reduce storm overflows legally binding. The Government’s Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published in August 2022, set out stringent targets to protect people and the environment and is backed up by up to £56 billion capital investment, which is the largest infrastructure programme in water company history.</p>



<p>Further, the Government is now consulting on proposals for unlimited fines to be imposed on water companies that break the rules. More than £142 million has already been levied in fines since 2015 and I am aware that money from fines and penalties will now be channelled back into the environment.</p>



<p><strong><u>East Midlands APPG:</u></strong></p>



<p>Outside the Chamber, the focus seemed to be local issues over the last few weeks, and we had another meeting of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on the East Midlands. This group brings together MPs from across the Chamber to discuss issues that are especially important to our region.</p>



<p>The most recent meeting was on the future of Infrastructure in the East Midlands. We heard from the East Midlands Chamber of Commerce and East Midlands Councils on infrastructure in our area and the need for infrastructure investment to fulfil our environmental commitments, to make it easier for people living here to travel and get to work, and to encourage businesses to move here.</p>



<p>Moving forward, we will continue to push for our region to receive funding in the future, by collecting evidence on the wider benefits of infrastructure projects to the local economy and local businesses and use this in future proposals for funding.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ferrero sustainable palm oil event:</u></strong></p>



<p>I was also able to welcome Ferrero, who own the Thornton’s factory in Somercotes, to Parliament. They hosted an event alongside Chester Zoo and the Orangutan Land Trust on Sustainable Palm Oil, where they discussed the damage palm oil farming has inflicted on jungles and local habitats of orangutans around the world. While many food producers have moved away from palm oil for these reasons, the same problems of deforestation and habitat destruction continue to persist regardless of the plant used.</p>



<p>Because of this, Ferrero highlighted the use of certified sustainable palm-oil to that avoids these poor practices by working with local wildlife experts, stopping further deforestation for farming land, and reducing the impact on the environment.</p>



<p>It was great to hear from a business that operates locally in our area that is tackling global issues and to talk to the charitable organisations that were supporting these efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="667" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3376" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg 1000w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Amber Valley Borough Council elections 4th May 2023 &amp; Parish/Town Council elections:</u></strong></p>



<p>On the 4th May 2023, elections were held for Amber Valley Borough Council. For the first time in a long time, elections were held for all 42 councillors over 18 wards (rather than the previous recent system of electing a third of councillors each year).</p>



<p>As a result of the election, the Labour Group took control of the Council and have 26 councillors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all who were elected and I look forward to working with the new Borough Council where needed and holding them to account where necessary too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find your borough councillor <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All the parish and town councils in Amber Valley were also up for election. You can find the results of these <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections/parish-and-town-councils/">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Access to Cash &#8211; Nationwide Heanor:</u></strong></p>



<p>I know for many constituents a key concern has been the closures of bank branches in our area.</p>



<p>Although banking is increasingly moving online, in-person branches are still relied upon by many in our communities and are staples in our high streets. People need access to bank branches so that they can speak to someone in person about their accounts and finances.</p>



<p>I was able to visit Nationwide in Heanor to discuss this issue and was reassured that they understood the important role they play on our high streets and intend to stay open for the foreseeable future.</p>



<p>I was also able to discuss the work they are doing to help vulnerable people more broadly, including their cost-of-living helpline, fraud prevention and work to teach useful financial skills to young people.</p>



<p>I’ll continue to support maintaining access to bank branches and cash in our communities and town centres.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="636" height="791" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3375" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg 636w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-241x300.jpeg 241w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Nieper Foundation visit:</u></strong></p>



<p>In Alfreton I joined Robert Halfon, the Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education, in a visit related to the Christopher Nieper Education Trust. The Trust was set up to allow David Nieper Ltd to invest in local education and help young people into long-term, rewarding employment.</p>



<p>We visited David Nieper Ltd and met with Dr Hobbs, the Headteacher of David Nieper Academy, others who are supporting the work of the Trust and met with a student to do an interview for the Spirit of Alfreton. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684233937.JPG" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong><u>Local primary school visits:</u></strong></p>



<p>I have also able to visit both Mundy Junior School and Heage Primary School to speak to teachers and school leaders about funding.</p>



<p>With schools also being hit with high energy bills, there was concern that planned increases to teacher’s salaries and additional provisions for students would not be fully funded if prices for heating stay high. I was able to talk to teachers about the worry this is causing.</p>



<p>It is only right that any increases to staff pay are properly covered by increased investment into schools and it is important that the Government has contingency plans and funding in place to reassure schools that they will be supported should energy bills stay high.</p>



<p><strong><u>Windows for Ukraine:</u></strong></p>



<p>I also took part in a visit to CPR Manufacturing in Alfreton, who are supporting a project called Windows for Ukraine. Cromwell Polythene is manufacturing polyethylene film used to make effective temporary windows as part of a project called Insulate Ukraine. The company have donated some of the film being used, which is an alternative to glass and insulates homes better than double-glazing. The local business usually manufactures bin liner products.</p>



<p><strong><u>Collis engineering visit &amp; 5G masts:</u></strong></p>



<p>To look at their new 5G masts I&#8217;ve also been to see Collis Engineering Ltd. They&#8217;re manufacturing a new mast and tower system to support the rollout of 5G and which has a high headload capacity, meaning several operators can share the same structure and system. Collis are an important local employer and it was good to learn more about this innovation that is being manufactured right here in the heart of Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that access to telephone and broadband signal remains an issue for many residents, so hopefully this innovation will help with that, and I&#8217;ll continue to pursue solutions for areas where there are concerns or problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684234142.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Street Watch:</h1>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Social Security Health Assessments System <span style="color:#06396a;">Has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>The cross party Work and Pensions Select Committee responsible for scrutinising the Department for Work and Pensions’ (DWP) policies, has published a damning report on the Government’s health assessments system which is used to screen whether sick and disabled people should have access to vital social security payments.</p>
<p>These payments provide financial support to a working age person who is unable to work because of their health condition or disability; the assessment for this is the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) and is for either Employment Support Allowance or Universal Credit Limited Capability to Work. In addition there is also the Personal Independence Payment (PIP) assessment process to access support to cover the extra costs disabled people face because of their disability which are estimated at over £580 a month on average; this is for the Personal Independence Payment.</p>
<p>The report exposed the detrimental impact of the assessment process itself on the health and well being of claimants.</p>
<p>Giving evidence to the Committee, Professor Ben Barr, from the University of Liverpool, was asked about research he carried out in 2015 which looked at the impacts of the WCA as claimants were reassessed to move onto Employment Support Allowance. His analysis estimated that across England, the WCA had caused an additional 600 suicides, 300,000 additional cases of mental health problems and a large rise in the prescribing of antidepressants over a nine-year period.</p>
<p>“We looked at whether it could be explained by other factors or other economic trends, but there was quite a unique pattern in the increase in mental health problems, and the most likely explanation was that it was due to the reassessment process”, he told the committee. He said it is difficult to assess improvements since this study as “there are no systems in place” to monitor the impact of the health assessments and the potential adverse outcomes.</p>
<p>A survey by the University of Kent last year found half of claimants who have been through the WCA process said it made their mental health worse. Dr Ben Baumberg Geiger, who led the research, told the committee: “It is not sufficient to say that this is a historical problem and that everything is fine now. If there was more transparency, it would be easier to know a bit more about it, but the evidence suggests that there are still major problems with the WCA that could lead to an increased risk of poor mental health.”</p>
<p>Debbie Abrahams the Member of Parliament for Oldham East and Saddleworth and a Member of the Work and Pensions Select Committee said:</p>
<p><em>“The evidence is clear – the current system is not fit for purpose. The DWP’s own figures show that <strong><u>274 people a month</u></strong> <strong><u>die 6 months after being found fit for work </u></strong>and <strong><u>60 people a month die 3 months after having PIP refused. </u></strong>These are poorly people not the shirkers and scroungers that some Conservatives refer to when discussing social security claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“We heard evidence during the inquiry that when people were being reassessed between 2010 and 2013, there were 600 additional suicides. In 2020, National Audit Office has said that the claimant deaths that the DWP had investigated were the tip of the iceberg. The current approach is contributing, directly and indirectly, to the physical and mental health harm of claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“Last year the Equality Watchdog, The Equality and Human Rights Commission, issued a Section 23 order against the Department of Work and Pensions over their discriminatory treatment of disabled claimants.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Government itself has effectively acknowledged a different approach is needed when they announced that they would abolition the Work Capability Assessments, something I have been calling for years, but the detail of the future process is too opaque and doesn’t provide reassurance. Given it will take place several years to replace, what happens until then?</em></p>
<p><em>“I remain deeply concerned about these health assessments but also about the punitive nature of the sanctions regime, introduced in 2012 and, once again, on the rise. </em></p>
<p><em>“I believe it is these social security policies, as well as the inadequacy of the social security support especially for working age people, and the dehumanising culture that claimants too often experience that collectively contribute to the adverse health effects is the It is so detrimental to vulnerable people especially, but to all people as well.</em></p>
<p><em>“Given the failure of the Government to make many of the changes recommended in our predecessor Committee in 2018, I hold little hope in them taking on board the improvements set out in the report.”</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7098</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
    <category term="Department for Work and Pensions"/>
    <category term="Health Assessment"/>
    <category term="Social Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>St Helens Mobile Pantry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2023/04/18/st-helens-mobile-pantry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7624</id>
    <published>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes school debaters to Downing Street</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/03/29/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-school-debaters-to-downing-street/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament before their visit to Number Ten. The day was rounded off by a Q&amp;amp;A session with Matt and the competition judges as well as guests from Parliament including House of Commons Library Director of Research Edward Wood. The panel passed on their careers advice as well as explaining some of the opportunities available in politics besides being an MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4189 aligncenter" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the visit &lt;strong&gt;Matt Warman MP commented&lt;/strong&gt; ‘I was keen to establish a debating competition to encourage students to think deeply about some of the issues facing our society and, crucially, to equip them with the skills to consider both sides of a complex argument. Today’s visit to the home of modern democracy was an excellent opportunity to see those skills in action with students having the chance to observe opposition MPs challenging Ministers at the despatch box. I look forward to next year’s programme and on a broader note, am always happy to welcome schools in my constituency to Parliament.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chair of Governors at Boston High School Lisa Smith&lt;/strong&gt; who accompanied the visit said ‘This was a wonderful opportunity for our students to see democracy in action – and to be inspired by the opportunities for careers in parliament. We are grateful to Matt for arranging the debate competition and the visit and look forward to defending our winner’s trophy next year!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4187 alignnone" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-768x576.png 768w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4188 alignright" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4186</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="pbs-main-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="//blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgPGr6SMD45ood6qhiuu4blT62kHviIBP6ckpE65JIBe6BV4lwfD_ljqSW6Yfh3INMQ01Hq2IglXwA8RYJBvaG3TNP9bm646Qr4SeQjTadGOm9f0ATEqV7u3pFvBanBHg/s220/Labour+4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=ROJpTLyg" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6493ea074d219" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6493ea074d219').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6493ea074d219","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6493ea074d219" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6493ea074d219" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6493ea074d219" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6493ea074d219" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6493ea074d219" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6493ea074d219" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6493ea074d219" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6493ea074d219" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6493ea074d219" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6493ea074d219_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6493ea074d219 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dz0gjuBoHOE9ZnwIC0hiko-8K9TUhUTgM0HNL4n8VPPE612zk2LXFAlPP5bp_VlrNtI1rlYpkWMsjMK02QHsA' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhgWOtViNTWZUKIZ7kYL0nvU_TB1vTIlyfy6c2hOYUjDUWjHn0fS4lV3RKEy0FbSs1Op_wlbHJMkd1fsc3GmRYy7ZLdcf7NII9s64Dg9e1WaE3Gssj9jjosABrXEBz2Kg/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>2</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
