<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-01-09T06:06:49Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>University challenge</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/01/09/university-challenge/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The pandemic lockdowns have posed a series of difficult questions to universities. Today we live in a world where they have been told to go over to remote learning for all but a few courses like medicine and some other scientific areas that require laboratory and practical  work in a specialist location. </p>



<p>There is first the issue of accommodation. Many  students with or without help from parents  have signed on for a year’s rental in student accommodation. The students will not be able to use this and some are asking for rental reductions or cancellations of the agreements.  Private landlords say they have to provide the facility whether the student uses it or not, pay any debt interest on the borrowings to own it, and meet service and utility charges to keep the building going. Some of the private landlords depend on the income from the letting to buy the basics  and are not rich. Other private landlords are richer individuals or better financed companies or charities.</p>



<p>Some of the landlords are the Universities themselves, providing student accommodation on the main campus or owning properties nearby. They too may have taken on debts to build and own the housing and need revenue to pay the maintenance and utility bills.</p>



<p>The  second  issue is  payments for tuition. Some students think there should be a discount or rebate for remote teaching. They argue that they agreed to tuition fees on the assumption of face to face teaching and lectures which are no longer available. The Universities reply that they still have the same staff on the same salaries and are providing teaching on line so the full tuition fee should still apply. </p>



<p>In a situation like this there is a tussle between the student, the University, the landlord and the state over should pay the bills.  Where both students and university unite to say the state should subsidise, they are saying all taxpayers should make a contribution. This will include people who did not have the benefit of going to a  university and people earning less than the student hopes to earn following graduation. The same may be true of smaller landlords, if they were expected to take some of the hit.</p>



<p>In many cases students are being told they have to pay for full tuition fees and accommodation even though they are living at home and learning on line. Do you think this is the right answer?</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The pandemic lockdowns have posed a series of difficult questions to universities. Today we live in a world where they have been told to go over to remote learning for all but a few courses like medicine and some other scientific areas that require laboratory and practical work in a specialist location. There is first […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29389</id>
    <published>2021-01-09T05:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-09T05:30:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update following discussions regarding vaccinations in Chesterfield and Derbyshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/94H1vQroyDU/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4761</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T18:30:29Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T18:30:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Havering Libraries Close Their Doors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/havering-libraries-close-their-doors" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/Rainham-Library.jpg?itok=ghlQMGjN" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p> </p>
              <p>Today (Friday 8 January) Havering Council have announced the closure of all libraries within the borough until at least mid-February as an additional measure in the fight against Covid-19. After an initial closure period which lasted until November 2020, libraries have been open for the collection and return of books and pre-booked essential computer/internet access.</p>
              <p>Late fees are to remain suspended.</p>
              <p><strong>Jon Cruddas MP said:</strong> “I think in light of the current situation across east London this is the right move. Every necessary step should be taken to combat the virus until vaccines can be effectively delivered on mass. Many of the library services that are cherished by residents can still be accessed online through ebooks, audiobooks and events.”</p>
              <p>The library service is still delivering a number of online events to keep communities connected throughout the national lockdown, and details can be found on the website here: <strong><a href="https://www.havering.gov.uk/events/20039/libraries">https://www.havering.gov.uk/events/20039/libraries</a></strong></p>
              <p>Residents can also find out more details about services via email: <a href="mailto:alexis.wainwright@havering.gov.uk">alexis.wainwright@havering.gov.uk</a></p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/rainham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Rainham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/libraries" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Libraries</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/services" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Services</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/covid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Covid</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1444 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T16:20:50Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T16:20:50Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New year, new hope – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/new-year-new-hope-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-year-new-hope-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233208" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/New-year-new-hope.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Some years fly by. 2020 most certainly did not. It was an extremely difficult year for all of us and one that most of us will be very glad to see the back of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Obviously things won’t magically be better just because it’s no longer 2020. In fact, we are now facing a strict national lockdown as COVID cases surge across the country, thanks largely to a new strain of the virus. This is going to be a very difficult time, particularly for us here in Greater Manchester where we’ve been under stricter restrictions since July. We’ve been moved up tiers and in and out of lockdown, every few weeks but restrictions have never really loosened for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;But this lockdown is different from previous ones in two key respects. Firstly, this new variant of COVID spreads more quickly and easily than the original strain. This makes it even more important to take precautions to avoid spreading it. As difficult as it will be, we have to go back to staying at home to protect our NHS from getting overwhelmed and save lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;The other – much happier – difference this time around is that we can begin to see light at the end of the tunnel, in the form of the vaccine. It has always been the vaccine that would see this crisis brought to an end and it is finally here and being rolled out. I went with my dad to the Hyde drive-in centre to get his vaccine and it was a very efficient and impressive process – yet more evidence of how fantastic our NHS is. There is also a vaccination centre at Denton Festival Hall and I would encourage anybody eligible in the most vulnerable groups to make sure they get an appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;It is essential that the Government uses the (at least) 7 weeks of lockdown to get the vaccination programme firing on all cylinders. We can’t afford another fiasco like the one we saw on Test and Trace or PPE. The more efficient the roll-out is, the more people get vaccinated, the quicker we can finally get back to something like normality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;So I’d like to finish off by saying Happy New Year! 2021 will be difficult, but if we all pull together and look out for each other for the next few months, I hope that it will be a much happier and healthier year than the one we’ve just left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/new-year-new-hope-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/"&gt;New year, new hope &amp;#8211; my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Some years fly by. 2020 most certainly did not. It was an extremely difficult year for all of us and one that most of us will be very glad to see the back of. Obviously things won’t magically be better just because it’s no longer 2020. In fact, we are now facing a strict national […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/new-year-new-hope-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">New year, new hope – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233207</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T16:15:11Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T16:15:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Environment Agency plan Tenbury scheme phone briefing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/environment-agency-plan-tenbury-scheme-phone-briefing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tenbury residents will be able to take part in a phone briefing session as the Environment Agency continues its consultation on the new flood defence scheme. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/environment-agency-plan-tenbury-scheme-phone-briefing" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5021 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T16:01:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T16:01:15Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 8 January 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/8jan21" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>From this week, the Government are introducing new national lockdown measures<span><strong>. </strong>I know how frustrating and disheartening this news will be after an incredibly challenging year, b</span>ut these restrictions are necessary to save lives and to prevent our NHS from becoming overwhelmed. We’ve seen alarming increases in cases in recent weeks, with rates of infection and hospitalisation now rising extremely quickly in every region of the UK. The new variant of the virus is 50% to 70% more infectious and transmissible. Hundreds of people are losing their lives on a daily basis. Every day without decisive action means more will die and our hospitals will be unable to care for those who are desperately ill. It’s devastating for families and businesses to start the New Year with tighter restrictions – but this is the only way we will save lives; protect our NHS; and get through the toughest winter we have ever faced.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/8jan21</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T15:36:24Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T15:36:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>*Attention Schools and Parents*</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/attention-schools-and-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=attention-schools-and-parents" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>While they are sadly closed during lockdown, schools can use this link to request free increases in mobile data allowances for families who don’t have broadband and can’t afford it themselves, so that the kids can access online education. Three, Smarty, Virgin Mobile, EE, Tesco Mobile &amp; Sky Mobile are all taking part in the scheme.<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://get-help-with-tech.education.gov.uk/about-increasing-mobile-data?fbclid=IwAR1cM8ld8nwRpR4xOVhFHQhntqoOx1rbzlfIl0BQB4v7ORB4AAHZ0nlPsY8" target="_blank">https://get-help-with-tech.education.gov.uk/about…</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Information for parents on home learning.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2827</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T14:25:27Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T14:25:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>The light at the end of the tunnel just got that little bit brighter – MP welcomes UK approval of third COVID-19 vaccine</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389231/the-light-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel-just-got-that-little-bit-brighter-mp-welcomes-uk-approval-of-third-covid-19-vaccine"/>
  <updated>2021-01-08T14:16:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389231/the-light-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel-just-got-that-little-bit-brighter-mp-welcomes-uk-approval-of-third-covid-19-vaccine</id>
  <summary type="text">Commenting on the breaking news that the UK's medicines regulators have approved the Moderna vaccine, local MP Tim Farron said: "This is absolutely fantastic and heart-warming news.
"I want to say a big thank you to everyone involved and to those on the front-line in our NHS who are working so hard to roll out the vaccines to protect the lives of our loved ones.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Commenting on the breaking news that the UK's medicines regulators have approved the Moderna vaccine, local MP Tim Farron said: <em>"This is absolutely fantastic and heart-warming news.</em></p>
<p><em>"I want to say a big thank you to everyone involved and to those on the front-line in our NHS who are working so hard to roll out the vaccines to protect the lives of our loved ones.</em></p>
<p><em>"The light at the end of the tunnel just got that little bit brighter."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This week I participated in the Public Health debate concerning the implementation of new Covid restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the third wave of Covid intensifies and we are back under lockdown, it is critical the UK Government agree to a &amp;#8216;Zero Tolerance&amp;#8217; approach to community transmission, as sought last summer by the three Devolved Governments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also crucial that the UK Government restrict international travel both too and from the UK.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only by following such a strict approach will our domestic economy and society eventually be able to open up fully and safely as we have seen in countries like New Zealand, Singapore and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The impact of new restrictions will be tough on families and businesses who will need financial support to get through it and so it was hugely disappointing to hear that the £375 million of support for businesses in Scotland promised by the Chancellor has since been rescinded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the public health debate here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Qx8FeTZmkk"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Qx8FeTZmkk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="06/02 Public Health Debate" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Qx8FeTZmkk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford MP&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, when the SARS-Cov-2 virus emerged, there was no handbook on covid. All Governments had to feel their way, but there is little excuse for repeating the same mistakes a year on. “Go early and go hard” has been public health experts’ consistent advice. Michael Ryan of the World Health Organisation said at the start of the pandemic:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The virus will always get you if you don’t move quickly”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet just last week, the Health Secretary still refused to put England into tier 4, despite surging case numbers and the devolved nations already being under tight restrictions since Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the late lockdown in March and rushed reopening in May, the Government allowed rates of infection in England to run seven times higher than in Scotland or Northern Ireland over the summer, and at the time, chose not to agree a zero-tolerance covid policy to eliminate community spread of the virus on a UK-wide basis. The gains of lockdown were gradually lost, as eat out to help out drove up cases in August and September, thus beginning the second wave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK is one of the few countries that never closed its borders and many new strains of covid were imported by people travelling to Europe on summer holidays.&amp;nbsp;Even now, in the middle of the second wave, the UK does not have strict testing and residential or monitored quarantine for arrivals. On the contrary, the Government have sought to grant further exemptions from quarantine rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September, the Prime Minister ignored the tenfold rise in covid cases and his own advisory group to listen yet again to the proponents of disease-driven rather than vaccine-based herd immunity, leading to a six-week delay in instigating the autumn lockdown. Herd immunity can be safely achieved only through the use of a vaccine, and even then, only if the vaccine prevents transmission of the virus and thus also protects the unvaccinated. That is the hope, but we do not yet know if either of the vaccines used in the UK will achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is understandable that Governments are wary about the use of tight covid restrictions and their impact on our economy and society, but it is a false dichotomy to set public health against the economy and lives against livelihoods. People simply choose not to endanger themselves or their families and need to have confidence that the risk of catching the virus is very low. Allowing increased levels of spread—and, therefore, high rates of viral replication—also contributes to more frequent mutations, and increases the risk of generating yet more problematic new variants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;With cases growing exponentially, it simply is not possible to vaccinate our way out of the current surge so I welcome the decision for this lockdown, but it is tough on everyone, and both individuals and businesses will need support to get through it. That is why it is bitterly disappointing to hear that the £375 million of support for businesses in Scotland promised by the Chancellor just yesterday has now been rescinded, leaving Scotland with no new funding to deal with the economic impact of the current shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Government must also consider what strategy they will follow at the end of the lockdown. It should be maintained long enough to achieve suppression of community transmission and to establish a more systematic approach to test, trace and isolate. It is critical to provide both financial and practical support to those who need to isolate, as it is only isolation that actually breaks the chains of infection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strict controls at external borders would avoid importing more covid cases and new variants. Such a covid-secure approach would allow the domestic UK economy to reopen fully, with the Government then able to target financial support at the industries associated with international travel, such as aviation and aerospace, which have been so badly impacted by the pandemic. Countries such as New Zealand, Singapore and Korea, which have tight travel restrictions and quarantines, have eliminated community transmission and been able fully to open up their economies and societies, including schools, hospitality and domestic tourism. We only have to look at their Christmas and new year celebrations to see what could be on offer to us here if we get things right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;#038;title=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/" data-a2a-title="Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/"&gt;Public Health Debate &amp;#8211; Covid Restrictions 06/01/21&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week I participated in the Public Health debate concerning the implementation of new Covid ... <a title="Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/">Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2023</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T14:06:10Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T14:06:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Health, Wellbeing, &amp; Social Justice"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="Financial-Support"/>
    <category term="Health &amp; Social Care"/>
    <category term="Public Health"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apprenticeships with the National Grid </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/apprenticeships-national-grid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Calling on those in Aberconwy looking for a graduate role or apprenticeship. The National Grid is recruiting the next generation of problem solvers and creative thinkers to help transform the energy sector to meet net zero.
National Grid owns and operates the electricity and gas transmission…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/apprenticeships-national-grid</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[BASF decision to close Seal Sands plant shows real need a Tees Valley Industrial Plan, says Alex]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/basf-decision-to-close-seal-sands-plant-shows-real-need-a-tees-valley-industrial-plan-says-alex/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13862</id>
		<updated>2021-01-07T17:08:04Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-07T17:08:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The decision by BASF to close its hexamethylene diamine (HMD) plant at Seal shows there is a real need for a Tees Valley Industrial Plan, says Stockton North MP, Alex Cunningham. From 12 February 2021 the maintenance and operation of&#160; the plant will transfer to BASF following the termination of an agreement between them and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/basf-decision-to-close-seal-sands-plant-shows-real-need-a-tees-valley-industrial-plan-says-alex/">BASF decision to close Seal Sands plant shows real need a Tees Valley Industrial Plan, says Alex</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Delivering essential services throughout temporary lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13076/delivering-essential-services-throughout-temporary-lockdown" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Council is working to minimise the impact of new temporary lockdown measures on services.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13076/delivering-essential-services-throughout-temporary-lockdown</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:53:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Committee fishing for wildlife photographer to capture the beauty of British nature </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/committee-fishing-wildlife-photographer-capture-beauty-british-nature" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="6865" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">7 January 2021</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Committee fishing for wildlife photographer to capture the beauty of British nature </span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span>Environmental Audit Committee (EAC) Chairman, Philip Dunne MP, is urging members of the public to send in photos that capture British nature. The winning photo will be used as the front cover of the Committee’s report to Government, due to be published in the Spring, on how to secure the health of Biodiversity and Ecosystems. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>Biodiversity is continuing to decline faster now than at any time in human history, with an estimated 1 million animal and plant species threatened with extinction around the world. The fragile state of biodiversity has been brought into sharper focus in recent months with the recent documentaries by Sir David Attenborough and fears that the UK will fail to meet biodiversity targets.  </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>The EAC is keen to maintain this public interest and to invite members of the public to submit their own photographs of what they feel symbolises British nature. The competition may encourage some to undertake a new photography expedition when restrictions ease over the coming months, or a submission may be a photo that has been sitting in a camera roll for some time.   </span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--quote paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
<div class="text">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span>We have some fantastic wildlife photographers in South Shropshire. I really hope they will come forward with some of their amazing photographs to help illustrate this important report into Biodiversity in the UK.</span></span></span></p></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-quote-attribution field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item">Philip Dunne MP</div>
      
  </div>

      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span>Environmental Audit Committee Chairman, Rt Hon Philip Dunne MP, said: </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>“We are incredibly fortunate in the UK that we have unique wildlife on our doorsteps – and it doesn’t matter where in the UK you are or what season we’re in. But our British wildlife faces a very uncertain future, with many species threatened with extinction. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>“It’s not only a very sad state of affairs – some of the animals and plants that I remember seeing regularly when I was a child are now scarce – but there are severe repercussions for humans if we do not address declining biodiversity. The food we eat and the air we breathe depends on it. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>“We heard during evidence sessions of the importance of healthy ecosystems, and we are in a time of reckoning where we must adapt and put nature in recovery. With the Government setting bold environmental ambitions, we are hoping our report will be very carefully considered by Ministers. Our report will be incomplete without photographs to illustrate just how wonderful British nature is.</span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>“We have some fantastic wildlife photographers in South Shropshire. I really hope they will come forward with some of their amazing photographs to help illustrate this important report into Biodiversity in the UK.” </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>The competition closes on 12<span>th</span> March, before the finalists are selected by the Committee and winner chosen by Chairman Philip Dunne. Runners up will have their photographs featured within the report alongside the Committee’s recommendations for how to best protect the future of biodiversity in the UK. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>The launch of the competition comes ahead of the Ministerial evidence session for the Biodiversity and Ecosystems inquiry on Wednesday 13<span>th</span> January. The EAC will be hearing from Environment Secretary George Eustice, MHCLG Minister Chris Pincher and DEFRA Minister Zac Goldsmith. The evidence session offers the opportunity for the Committee to put some of the key findings during the inquiry to Government ahead of the report. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>Terms and conditions for the competition: </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>You must follow <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus"><span>current covid-19 guidelines and restrictions</span></a> when taking your photo. You can submit a photo you have taken previously so long as you are the photographer and hold the copyright to the image. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>What you need to know: </span></span></span></p>

<ol><li><span><span><span><span>Between 5<span>th</span> January and 12<span>th</span> March 2021 post your photo on Twitter, tagging #EACBiodiversity so that the committee can see your submissions, or e-mail it to us at <a href="mailto:eacom@parliament.uk"><span>eacom@parliament.uk</span></a>  </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>We may request a high-resolution copy of the photo </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>Photos should not contain violent or explicit content </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>No person under 18 should be visible or identifiable in the photo </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>Anyone visible in the photo must have consented to their likeness being used </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>No slogans or obvious logos should be visible in the photo   </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>Please do not submit a photo that might give away your personal address </span></span></span></span></li>
</ol><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>Please consider: </span></span></span></p>

<ol><li><span><span><span><span>If we retweet your photo, it will be publicised on the Environmental Audit Committee Twitter feed and potentially on other House of Commons and UK Parliament channels. It might be seen by thousands of people. </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>If you e-mail your photo to us or tag us on Twitter, you have given your consent for us to use the image in Committee publications </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>The decision to contribute is your own. The Committee does not have means to support you to create your photograph. </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>Photo editing is allowed to enhance the image but not substantially edit the photo’s content  </span></span></span></span></li>
	<li><span><span><span><span>The risk of contributing a photograph is your own. The Committee does not have means to support contributors through any consequence of photographs being published. The Committee has no means to help or respond to any negative repercussions. </span></span></span></span></li>
</ol><p><span><span><span> </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>More information can be found in our privacy notice for the public: <a href="https://www.parliament.uk/globalassets/documents/data-protection/public-privacy-notice-25-may.pdf"><span>https://www.parliament.uk/globalassets/documents/data-protection/public-privacy-notice-25-may.pdf</span></a>. </span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6865 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T13:23:38Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T13:23:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SNP not lifting a finger in hopes of fishing failure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/snp-not-lifting-finger-hopes-fishing-failure" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The SNP are not lifting a finger to help Scottish fishing exports in the hopes of a failure they can blame on Brexit, the Scottish Conservatives have said.
In recent days there have been delays to Scottish fishing exports for two reasons - as a result of hold-ups in Scotland that have not been…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/snp-not-lifting-finger-hopes-fishing-failure</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Is your MP on this list backing my amendment to the Fire Safety Bill? If not email them, so leaseholders do not have to pay for historic fire safety defects</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1739-is-your-mp-on-this-list-backing-my-amendment-to-the-fire-safety-bill-if-not-email-them-so-leaseholders-do-not-have-to-pay-for-historic-fire-safety-defects"/>
		<published>2021-01-07T11:04:19+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-07T11:04:19+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1739-is-your-mp-on-this-list-backing-my-amendment-to-the-fire-safety-bill-if-not-email-them-so-leaseholders-do-not-have-to-pay-for-historic-fire-safety-defects</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Is your MP on this list and backing my and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s amendment to the Fire Safety Bill? If not email them and ask them to support our campaign so leaseholders do not have to pay for historic fire safety defects. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ukcag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ukcag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EOCS_Official?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@EOCS_Official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndOurCladdingScandal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndOurCladdingScandal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/7IW8bHXr8i"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7IW8bHXr8i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1347135785343062018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Is your MP on this list and backing my and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s amendment to the Fire Safety Bill? If not email them and ask them to support our campaign so leaseholders do not have to pay for historic fire safety defects. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ukcag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ukcag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EOCS_Official?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@EOCS_Official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndOurCladdingScandal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndOurCladdingScandal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/7IW8bHXr8i"&gt;pic.twitter.com/7IW8bHXr8i&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1347135785343062018?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 7, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>BTEC, vocational and technical exams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/01/07/btec-vocational-and-technical-exams/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6410</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T09:52:52Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T09:52:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on New National Lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/statement-on-new-national-lockdown/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Parliament was recalled today for a vote on the Government’s new lockdown measures and a statement on education. I put myself forward to speak in the proceedings but unfortunately did not get selected, therefore I wanted to update constituents on what is happening. The situation is clearly incredibly serious. Covid-19 is spreading rapidly across the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/statement-on-new-national-lockdown/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Statement on New National Lockdown</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7039</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T15:47:54Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T15:47:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Summary of lockdown restrictions for parents with children</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/summary-lockdown-restrictions-parents-children" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following the national lockdown, Coronavirus restrictions for parents and children have been updated. Parents and carers can continue to access childcare through early years settings (including nurseries and childminders) , which remain open. Childminders should continue to allow children to attend…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/summary-lockdown-restrictions-parents-children</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lockdown 3</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/lockdown-3/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is not the Happy New Year we were hoping for. Before Christmas the daily data produced by the Government, showing the numbers of new cases of coronavirus in Kent, was starting to look more positive. In Folkestone and Hythe there had been a sustained fall in the rolling seven-day average of new cases, from […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5489</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T05:26:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T05:26:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Local MP, Karin Smyth, is encouraging all constituents to follow the rules laid down by the Government this week in order to protect those vulnerable to this virus and to support the work of NHS staff. This comes after the UK Government finally acted upon the SAGE documents published before Christmas.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Government has now implemented a national lockdown in England, and everyone must now stay at home to try to slow the spread of the virus; that means, working from home where possible and only go out for essential reasons: to shop for basic necessities, to exercise, to seek or provide medical assistance, and to attend education for those eligible. Most children and university students will now learn remotely until February half term.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">For greater detail on the rules and exceptions, check the UK Government website at: <a href="http://gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFLiV7obsfUO_K8WoTzkvmzXLrfJQ">gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home</a>.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Karin Smyth MP said:</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“2020 was an incredibly difficult year for many and this was not the start we wanted to the New Year, but the third lockdown announced this week is vital to prevent the NHS from being overwhelmed and to protect those most at risk from this virus. It’s important that we all act quickly on Government advice as we need to make up for time lost through dither and delay.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“The vaccine is being rolled out, but until sufficient numbers have been vaccinated, we need to continue to pull together and protect our family and friends, and all those we come into contact with. I know it’s difficult, that we all miss seeing those we love, and that we are weary of the frequently changing rules, but there is light at the end of the tunnel, and we must not stop now.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Support for constituents can be found on the Bristol Council website at <a href="https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnuP4YCjbRT0MAvCOYX50KuJjtJw">https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know</a> and from the local Citizens Advice Bureau at <a href="http://bristolcab.org.uk/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://bristolcab.org.uk&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGKa93gq4aVSLQZwsamnHRlO8xtHQ">bristolcab.org.uk</a> or on the phone at 0808 278 7957.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In accordance with the lockdown rules and public health guidance, Karin’s office is working remotely but are still available for constituents to contact via email at <a href="mailto:Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk">Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk</a> or on the phone at 0117 953 3575.</p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/" target="_blank">“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/" target="_blank">“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2833</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T15:43:59Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T15:43:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coronavirus (COVID-19)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-27/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituents</p>
<p>I am writing to you with a further update on the coronavirus pandemic. You will be aware that the Prime Minister last night announced a further lockdown across England.</p>
<p>The main thing that is changing for us locally is that schools are to close for all except the children of key workers. In addition, shielding is to be reintroduced for the most vulnerable. Most other rules, and particularly for local businesses, remain unchanged from what they were under the Tier 4 regime.</p>
<p>All the details about school, colleges and university closures can be found <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home#going-to-school-college-and-university"><strong>here</strong></a>.</p>
<h3><strong>Surrey Covid-19 Cases</strong></h3>
<p>The new measures have been prompted by a continued increase in the rate of infections locally and around the country and continuing increases in pressure on hospitals. The number of patients with the virus in Epsom and St Helier Hospitals continues to rise sharply.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.surreycc.gov.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0006/249378/Daily-Dashboard_0501.pdf"><strong>Here</strong></a> are the latest infection figures that I have for Surrey. You will see just how much of an increase there has been.</p>
<h3><strong>Business Support</strong></h3>
<p>For those of you in business who have been affected by the requirement to close, the Government has this morning announced additional grant support.</p>
<p>The first details of these are <strong><a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/46-billion-in-new-lockdown-grants-to-support-businesses-and-protect-jobs">here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>These are in addition to the previous grants announced before Christmas.</p>
<h3><strong>Vaccination Programme</strong></h3>
<p>Many of you have sent me further questions about the vaccination programme.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/files.royalfree.nhs.uk/Patient_resources/COVID-19/(External_leaflet)_PHE_11843_Covid-19_why_do_I_have_to_wait_leaflet_download.pdf">Here</a> </strong>is the official NHS leaflet about the programme. I hope it answers many of your questions.</p>
<p>I know that the local NHS is ready to administer vaccines as soon as each delivery arrives in our area.</p>
<h3><strong>Shielding</strong></h3>
<p>With the return of shielding and the lockdown, if you have any difficulties getting access to support or to get essential things like food shopping done, please contact me and I will point you to where you can get help.</p>
<p>I will give you any more information as I get it.</p>
<p>Best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-27/">Coronavirus (COVID-19)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituents I am writing to you with a further update on the coronavirus pandemic. You will be aware that the Prime Minister last night announced a further lockdown across England. The main thing that is changing for us locally is that schools are to close for all except the children of key workers. In [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-27/">Coronavirus (COVID-19)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6070</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T14:44:12Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T14:44:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus (COVID19)"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UPDATE: SCOTLAND IN LOCKDOWN</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On 4th January 2021 the Scottish Government announced a new national lockdown in mainland Scotland to prevent the spread of the new, highly contagious strain of coronavirus (Covid-19). The new measures make it a legal requirement to stay at home … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/">UPDATE: SCOTLAND IN LOCKDOWN</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1490424</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:24:28Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:24:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign Emails"/>
    <category term="Latest Issues"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>National Lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/national-lockdown" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Please see below the Prime Minister's address to the nation from yesterday evening.  The full guidance is below and HERE.
The key differences to the March lockdown is that support and childcare bubbles remain in place, and early years childcare remains open.  Please do all you can to limit your…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/national-lockdown</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New National Lockdown Restrictions – Stay At Home</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/new-national-lockdown-restrictions-stay-at-home/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Prime Minister has announced this evening new national lockdown restrictions which will come into force tonight. As back in March this year, everyone must stay at home.  I know even tougher restrictions than under Tier 4 are disappointing. All schools which haven’t already will move to online learning from tomorrow, except for vulnerable [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/new-national-lockdown-restrictions-stay-at-home/">New National Lockdown Restrictions – Stay At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3029</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T20:57:11Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T20:57:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The UK’s future relationship with the EU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/the-uks-future-relationship-with-the-eu/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p class="xmsonormal">On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister heralded the deal his negotiators had struck with European Union counterparts concerning our future relationship with our nearest neighbours and the largest trading bloc in the world. After running a General Election over a year ago to ‘Get Brexit Done’ and boasting he had an ‘oven-ready deal’, he seemed incapable of delivering this ‘gas mark 4, 20 minutes’ deal for the country until the last possible moment. Why is that?</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">Well some, including the Government, have blamed the European Union. But I believe, this is all about the Government playing politics. It was clear where they were heading several weeks ago, and I predicted that just before Christmas, the Prime Minister would strike a deal and claim to have saved the day.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">The theatrics, posturing and even the insincerity in how some politicians and their acolytes chose to behave is, for me, the worst aspect of what should be a noble profession. Instead this disingenuous, calculated game-playing demeans the role of MPs, and certainly discredits the title of honourable, let alone right honourable, members.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">The fact that the Prime Minister had already signed the EU-UK Trade and Co-operation Agreement before the EU (Future Relationship) Bill had been voted on by MPs, makes an absolute mockery of Brexit being about taking back control and Parliamentary sovereignty. It is an appalling charade.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">But what about the Agreement itself? I think describing this deal as ‘thin’ is being kind to say the least. It is true it is better than no deal but there are many omissions, for example, on financial services which accounts for 80% of the UK economy, and there are many shortfalls, not least the aspect of the deal on fisheries.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">The Agreement consists of three pillars: a trade agreement, collaboration on security and governance arrangements. The trade agreement provides for zero tariffs and zero quotas on goods as long as UK goods have the same standards as the EU; however, that does not mean there are no costs to businesses.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">There will be costs associated with SPS checks, customs formalities and in establishing the rules of origin of UK goods. As mentioned above there is no financial services passport and professional qualifications from the UK will not be recognised. And although we no longer have access to most EU programmes, our experience this year with managing the Covid pandemic has made some in the Government realise the importance of co-operation with EU countries in life sciences research; as such the deal retains participation in Horizon Europe for the next few years, subject to the UK’s financial contribution.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">There are new security arrangements with the EU as we lose access to the European Arrest Warrant, but these are subject to the retention and implementation of the European Convention on Human Rights. And where either the UK or EU disagree with the interpretation or implementation of this new Agreement a soon-to-be-established (at what costs one wonders) Joint Partnership Council will seek to pass judgement on the dispute.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">But fear not! Our post-Covid holiday plans to Europe won’t be affected. We will be able to travel to EU countries for up to 90 days without a visa, but unfortunately our pets won’t. And there’s no protection from mobile phone roaming charges being re-introduced.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">The reciprocal rights of EU and UK citizens, and peace and stability on the island of Ireland are still protected under the Withdrawal Agreement, and the Protocol on Ireland and Northern Ireland within this.</p>
<p><span style="color: black;">The new EU-UK Trade and Cooperation Agreement took effect on 1<sup>st</sup> January 2021. And as the European Commission states:</span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt;"><em><span style="color: black;">‘On that date, the UK will leave the EU Single Market and Customs Union, as well as all EU policies and international agreements. The free movement of persons, goods, services and capital between the UK and the EU will end.</span></em></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36.0pt;"><em><span style="color: black;">The EU and the UK will form two separate markets; two distinct regulatory and legal spaces. This will create barriers to trade in goods and services and to cross-border mobility and exchanges that do not exist today.’</span></em></p>
<p><span style="color: black;">It is difficult to do justice to the tens of thousands of pages that have been written about Brexit and what will happen now in a few hundred words. This deal is the result of what most British people said they voted for back in 2016, and what many people told me that they wanted last year when I campaigned during the General Election. I hope they’re right. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: black;">But I fear that there will be many detrimental impacts resulting from this appalling deal, some of which may not emerge for months or even years. I hope I am wrong. So, I am putting you on notice, Mr Johnson, I will hold you to account for every empty promise that you have made, for the inequality that you say you can now vanquish and the ‘levelling up’ across our country that you claim can only now happen. I’m not going to let you get away with any more lies.   </span></p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/the-uks-future-relationship-with-the-eu/">The UK’s future relationship with the EU</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/the-uks-future-relationship-with-the-eu/">The UK’s future relationship with the EU</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6714</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T13:27:52Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T13:27:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-101" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It’s a free trade deal!
Is this now - finally - Brexit - and a trade deal? Just to be clear, we left the EU at the beginning of 2020, but subject to a transition arrangement under the Withdrawal Agreement which expired on 31 December 2020. This agreement finally delivered our sovereignty, our…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-101</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Axing the Tampon Tax – I am glad to set the record straight</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/01/axing-the-tampon-tax/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My letter to constituents on my role in axing the Tampon Tax follows below. Thank you for writing to me about the abolition of the “Tampon Tax”.  Having fought for it, I am very pleased a zero rate of VAT now applies to women’s sanitary products.  This is part of wider action by this Conservative Government to end period poverty, which includes free sanitary products in schools, colleges and hospitals.  You can find the Government’s announcement here: https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tampon-tax-abolished-from-today In particular, “The Chancellor […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18340</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T09:57:11Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T09:57:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Tampon Tax"/>
    <category term="Tax"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Jack Gebhard</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Walker proud to vote for PM’s deal to deliver Brexit with a deal and a zero tariff free trade agreement]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-proud-to-vote-for-pms-deal-to-deliver-brexit-with-a-deal-and-a-zero-tariff-free-trade-agreement/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2122</id>
		<updated>2021-01-02T13:39:13Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-24T13:36:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Christmas Eve the Prime Minister announced that after intense negotiations the British government has reached a trade deal with the European Union, concluding the process of our EU exit. Last night the House of Commons voted by a decisive majority to support that deal. Four and a half years on from the biggest democratic [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-proud-to-vote-for-pms-deal-to-deliver-brexit-with-a-deal-and-a-zero-tariff-free-trade-agreement/"><![CDATA[<p>On Christmas Eve the Prime Minister announced that after intense negotiations the British government has reached a trade deal with the European Union, concluding the process of our EU exit. Last night the House of Commons voted by a decisive majority to support that deal. Four and a half years on from the biggest democratic exercise in our country’s history we now have a deal that takes back control, while maintaining a friendly relationship based on free trade with our nearest friends and neighbours. This delivers on all the manifesto commitments on which the Conservative Party was re-elected in 2019 and on my long-standing ambition to ensure we secured a deal with the European Union based on full restoration of U.K. sovereignty and free trade.</p>
<p>I always believed that a full and fair referendum on EU membership was the only right thing to do as I saw our relationship with our neighbours changed and like many people felt that too many decisions were being taken over the heads of the British electorate. I campaigned for a referendum even before it was my party’s policy, I campaigned for reform of that relationship and although I campaigned to remain during the Brexit referendum campaign as I believed that remaining was the right pragmatic choice to make at that time, I always respected the fact that the electorate would decide.  When the British people spoke and people in Worcester voted decisively to leave the EU I immediately accepted  that it was incumbent on the government to deliver on the will of the British people.</p>
<p>After the referendum I was appointed one of the first Ministers in the Department for Exiting the European Union and over two and half years in that department, as it’s longest serving Minister I worked to secure the Withdrawal Agreement including the protection of rights for four million U.K. and EU citizens living in each other’s territories, the transition period and to set up our approach to the future relationship negotiations. There I set out the preferred future partnership of a relationship with a strong security partnership, an economic deal without tariffs on all goods and services; reduction of trade barriers without being bound by European rules; personal data protections; and associate membership of the Horizon programme so that our academic institutions can continue to work together to ensure we’re at the cutting edge of science and technology. All of these ambitions are achieved by the deal on which the House of Commons voted yesterday. Also at DExEU I prioritised protecting our citizens in Gibraltar by enabling them to have visa-free access to the Spanish mainland. Gibraltarians will have full access to the Schengen free travel area, protecting both their sovereignty and their ability to trade and travel.</p>
<p>The deal we have reached is a good deal for the United Kingdom and one that I am proud to have voted for. There will be no tariffs or quotas, meaning that many businesses will be able to continue to trade within Europe without extra baggage or cost and that British consumers will be protected from the negative impact of tariffs.   Security cooperation can continue in a way that benefits the safety and security of our people and there will continue to be a basis for the free exchange of data between the U.K. and the EU as well as recognition for our world leading standards for food and farming. Northern Ireland’s place in the U.K. customers territory and our internal market is protected but so is the absence of a border with the Republic of Ireland which has proved so important to the working of the Good Friday Agreement and the Peace Process.</p>
<p>A truly sovereign British Parliament will regain full control of British law, ending the jurisdiction of the European Court of Justice. As promised we will continue to maintain the highest labour, environmental and climate standards. But we will do so because it is the right thing to do and it will be our elected MPs who set and are held accountable for these rules.</p>
<p>Fish featured heavily in the Brexit negotiations and I’m glad that this deal will take back control of our waters. Fishing communities will benefit from a boost of £100 million to expand and update their fleet of vessels. A five year period will help ease the transition, after which we will have full control of our waters. Crucially we continue to be able to export fish tariff free to our biggest market in Europe but our fisherman shall immediately begin to see the benefits of an increased share of catch.</p>
<p>In leaving the European Union and bringing and end to the transition period we are delivering on a solemn promise made to the British people, one which was reconfirmed in both the 2017 and 2019 elections. In December 2019 I was re-elected to represent Worcester with an increased majority and over 50 per cent of the vote after promising to get Brexit done. Within weeks we had passed the Withdrawal Agreement and now, one year later, we have a trade deal that will allow us to show what Global Britain means to the world. We can strike our own trade deals and set our own laws. We have control over our borders and our waters and we can thrive as an independent nation.</p>
<p>The people of Worcester 54:46 in favour of voting to leave the EU and this deal delivers on that outcome. Respecting the fact that the majority voted to leave but also that a significant minority wanted to protect our trading relationship with European neighbours. It protects the interests of businesses and consumers by ensuring no quotas or tariffs are introduced that would hinder trade with the EU.</p>
<p>This deal allows us to close this particular chapter and get on with the priority of British people which is combatting Covid, getting the country back to some kind of normality and then building back better and levelling up our economy. With this deal marking the largest and most comprehensive trade deal ever reached by the European Union it shows that we can get off to a new start as friendly neighbours and with over 60 other trade deals already signed this year it is a great jumping off point for our ambitions for Global Britain. I hope that after so many debates and arguments over the last few years this deal settles the issue of our departure from the EU and avoids the unacceptable extremes of either reversing the referendum result or leaving on bad terms and in dispute with our neighbours. Now is a time for the whole country to come together and make a success of our new position and it is time to look to the future with confidence.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-proud-to-vote-for-pms-deal-to-deliver-brexit-with-a-deal-and-a-zero-tariff-free-trade-agreement/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-proud-to-vote-for-pms-deal-to-deliver-brexit-with-a-deal-and-a-zero-tariff-free-trade-agreement/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 vaccines update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/covid-19-vaccines-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Good news but please be patient.</p>



<p>Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. </p>



<p>Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect to get 4,000 Pfizer and 2,800 Oxford by next week, but understand that the main roll-out of the vaccine to our 45,000 over 80s and health / care workers will be from 11th January. Then it will be all systems go ……. </p>



<p>Please make sure you are registered with  GP, and you will get your invitation. But also please remember the vaccine takes time to be effective and gives no guarantee you will not pass the disease on to others. </p>



<p>In the meantime, please stay at home unless you have to go out. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Good news but please be patient. Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7941</id>
    <published>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job Vacancy: Chi Seeks to Appoint New Caseworker for Newcastle Central</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/job-chi-seeks-to-appoint-new-caseworker-for-newcastle-central/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below:</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Job Title</strong>: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31 March 2021</p>
<p><strong>Working For</strong>: Chi Onwurah MP</p>
<p><strong>Location</strong>: Internet</p>
<p><strong>Salary</strong>: £21,529- 24,000</p>
<p><strong>Job Details: </strong></p>
<p>Chi Onwurah MP (Newcastle Central) has a vacancy for a caseworker/admin officer. The most important factor is a willingness to learn and work together with the senior caseworker. Training will be provided.</p>
<p>(This post is currently until March 31st 2021, potential for extension dependant on IPSA funding)</p>
<p>The successful candidate will be well-organised with excellent IT and communication skills and attention to detail. Ideally s/he will have some knowledge of welfare benefits and public services including Universal Credit and experience of managing casework, confidential and sensitive information; and of drafting complex letters.</p>
<p>Experience of a similar role and CaseworkerMP would be beneficial. A good understanding of the political environment is advantageous, and a knowledge of local issues in the constituency is desirable. The successful candidate will demonstrate their enthusiasm to play a key role in a small team supporting Chi in her constituency work.</p>
<p><strong>Key Tasks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Provide advice and support to constituents on a range of financial, health, housing and other issues variety of issues through liaison with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve matters.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Responsibilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deal with queries by phone/in person, taking appropriate action to resolve, by gathering information or evidence; then document or escalate their concerns or enquiries in order to progress or close the case.</li>
<li>Manage own caseload and progress of casework, prioritising, logging and updating any actions taken and following up any outstanding queries; with urgent cases reported to the Member.</li>
<li>Draft responses or respond to constituents on any issues raised on behalf of the Member.</li>
<li>Maintain an up-to-date knowledge of relevant guidelines/legislation as appropriate in dealing with casework.</li>
<li>Analyse patterns of enquiries and produce reports.</li>
<li>Ensure records are kept adhering to the Data Protection Act principles Undertake general administrative tasks.</li>
<li>Assist with the work of other colleagues as required and communicate appropriately with internal and external contacts.</li>
<li>Competent use of IT including casework management systems, Microsoft Of ce package, email and internet to support the above.</li>
<li>Attending surgeries and meetings as appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Chi values inclusivity and diversity, and welcomes applications from candidates of all backgrounds.</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Interview/Start Dates: </strong></p>
<p>Closing time for applications 5pm.</p>
<p>Interviews scheduled via zoom Monday 18th January 2021</p>
<p>Start date Monday 25th January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Application Details: </strong></p>
<p>Please send an email with the subject line “Caseworker application – YOURNAME” to <strong>Anthony.bone@parliament.uk</strong> Please attach a CV, a covering letter and a report (max 2 sides A4) which presents a complex situation you have dealt with.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong>: 0191 233 5838</p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="http://chionwurahmp.com/">http://chionwurahmp.com</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below: Closing Date: 15 January 2021 Job Title: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10769</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK-EU Trade deal press release</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">‘I am currently reading through the 1246 pages of the new UK-EU Trade Deal, announced by the Prime Minister on Christmas Eve. I believe this deal makes good on the promises that were made, by the Prime Minister, myself and... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/#more-3749">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3749</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EU (Future Relationship) Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was sorry, along with scores of other MPs, not to be called to speak on this vital but all too short debate. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5019 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Brexit to coronavirus and everything in between - Ashfield MP reflects on eventful first year in office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From sending Boris Johnson into isolation, to being trolled on social media, dealing with coronavirus and Brexit, it’s been a busy year for former miner Lee Anderson who has clocked up one year representing his home turf as Ashfield MP.
The married dad of two, raised in Huthwaite, is the area’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s December Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3047</id>
		<updated>2020-12-30T11:33:26Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-30T11:32:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters here</p>
<p></p>
<p>Dear Constituent,</p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" /></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. Under these challenging circumstances, I nevertheless wish you a very safe and happy new year in 2021.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Heanor Future High Streets Fund bid success &#8211; £8.5 million:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following Heanor&#8217;s bid towards the Government&#8217;s £830 million Future High Streets Fund, I&#8217;m delighted that Heanor has been successful and has been awarded over £8.5 million to help transform its town centre and recover from the pandemic. You can find the full details of the Borough Council&#8217;s bid <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/">here</a>, which focuses on plans to regenerate the Market Place and Grammar School site. The Council now have a few months to confirm the final version of their plans, and I look forward to continuing to support and work with them to ensure we can maximise this funding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit deal latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister reached a deal with the EU regarding our future relationship after the end of the transition period, from the 1st January 2021. Parliament has been recalled today, on the 30th December, to consider the deal and vote on it. You can read the deal <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union">here</a> and the legislation enabling it <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf" data-cke-saved-href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf">here</a>. The select committee on the Future Relationship with the EU on which I serve has published a report on the deal this morning, which you can read <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/">here</a>.</p>
<p>I can confirm I will be supporting the deal when it comes to a vote later.</p>
<p>Many constituents have contacted me throughout the negotiation period, and I think this deal delivers on the key areas whilst also providing certainty and security for businesses and residents already impacted by Covid-19.</p>
<p>This deal delivers on Brexit, the referendum and last year&#8217;s election result by taking back control of our laws, borders, money, trade and fisheries.</p>
<p>&#8211; there is no role for the European Court of Justice and no requirement for the UK to follow EU law, so <strong>regaining parliamentary sovereignty</strong>;</p>
<p>&#8211; we will <strong>trade with the EU on the basis of zero tariffs and zero quotas</strong>, which will allow businesses to be able to trade smoothly and continue to access EU markets;</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Allows us to introduce our own modern subsidy system. </strong>This new subsidies system will operate in a that best suits the interests of UK industries &#8211; outside the EU State Aid regime.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> offers streamlined <strong>co-operation on law enforcement</strong>, ensuring we continue to effectively tackle serious organised crime and counter terrorism, protecting the public, and bringing criminals to justice. It also provides for future cooperation between the UK and EU on emerging security challenges, such as cyber and health security, including continuing to work together on tackling the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p><strong>- Recognises UK sovereignty over our fishing waters and puts us in a position to rebuild our fishing fleet and increase quotas, overturning the inequity that British fishermen have faced for over four decades. </strong>By the end of the five year transition we will have full control of our waters and the amount of fish available to UK fishermen will have risen from half to two-thirds.</p>
<p><strong><strong>- Provides for the UK’s participation in certain EU programmes, furthering our commitment to making the UK a science and research superpower. </strong></strong>This deal will fulfil our manifesto commitment to participate in the Horizon Europe programme, but also the Euratom Research and Training programme, and the space programme, Copernicus.</p>
<p>The deal also includes arrangements for airlines and hauliers that provides them with certainty, and gives people the ability to travel to and from the EU easily for work and holidays; a social security agreement that has practical benefits for UK citizens including accessing healthcare when travelling in the EU; and agreements on energy which will benefit consumers by helping to keep prices down.</p>
<p>As I set out in previous newsletters, compromises were necessary to achieve a deal, especially on fishing and the level playing field. Having been through the deal I am satisfied that these compromises are acceptable in the context of the importance of tariff free access to the EU market. This is a good deal achieved at great speed and gives us the best possible platform to make a success of Brexit.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus guidance latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following the last review of the tier restrictions on 16 December, Amber Valley and all of Derbyshire remained in the tier 3 restrictions. The next review takes place today. Amber Valley currently has a high case rate, of 332 cases per 100k, which is one of the highest in Derbyshire, and up 44% on the previous week. This is a very concerning situation and may lead to further restrictions being out in place locally.</p>
<p>On the positive side, mass testing has started in Swadlincote in the south of the County and will spread further in the county, including to Amber Valley early in the new year. This programme, along with similar roll outs in health, care and school settings will help identify cases earlier and slow the spread.</p>
<p>Vaccines are also now starting to be rolled out across the County, and I&#8217;m pleased that Ripley is one of the first primary care centres to begin rolling out the vaccine, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/">here</a>. Now that the Oxford vaccine has been approved for us, the roll out of vaccination should increase rapidly at dedicated centres as well as local GPs and pharmacies. Please do wait to be contacted about the vaccine though rather than asking your GP.</p>
<p>We are now at a critical point in this pandemic with cases rising rapidly and the problems of 2 new variants. But the end is in sight now we can rapidly vaccinate the most vulnerable. At this time we all need to show as much caution as possible to reduce the number of cases and minimise the new restrictions needed. We’ve got this far, let’s not ease off now.</p>
<p>I will continue to engage with ministers, the public health team and the local NHS to ensure that this area sees the full roll out of the vaccines and mass testing as soon as possible and that support is in place for those who can’t work and those businesses forced to close as a result of the tier measures.</p>
<p>You can read my contributions in Parliament here including on highlighting the need to roll out the vaccine to people who are unable to leave their homes as soon as logistics allow <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4">here</a> and about consideration of more localised geography for tier restrictions <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As always, you can find the latest Covid-19 guidance, and support available, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus &#8211; support for local businesses &amp; high streets:</span></strong></p>
<p>In Parliament, I&#8217;ve continued to highlight the difficulties faces by our local businesses, such as the events industry and conference centres (you can read my question to the Secretary of State for Business on this <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4">here</a>), and supporting local high streets (which you can read more on <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4">here</a>).</p>
<p>I welcome the Chancellor&#8217;s announcement of the extension of the furlough scheme until the end of April 2021, and the extension of the business loan schemes until the end of March. You can find more information on the support and grants available for you or your business <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></span></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills" data-cke-saved-href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like me on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" /></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Johnson’s deal ‘social and economic disaster’ for Argyll &amp; Bute</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/12/29/johnsons-deal-social-and-economic-disaster-for-argyll-bute/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I can’t vote for a ‘deal’ that undermines our farmers, fishermen and future opportunities for young people Tomorrow (Wednesday) I will vote against Boris Johnson’s post-Brexit EU trade deal. I will do so because the deal we are being asked to support is woefully deficient, as it undermines our farmers, our fishing communities and the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9118</id>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Trade Deal Secured</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/trade-deal-secured/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In June 2016 residents from across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency voted to take back control of our money, our laws, our borders and our waters.</p>
<p>On 31st January this year we honoured our commitment to leave the European Union and next week we will leave the transition period.</p>
<p>We will leave with the confidence of having secured a free trade deal with our friends and partners in the European Union.</p>
<p>A trade deal that respects what people voted for in the referendum whilst prioritising frictionless access to European markets without quotas and tarrifs protecting jobs and livelihoods across the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>When Parliament is asked to ratify the trade deal I will be supporting the Prime Minister as this new deal will allow us to flourish as a nation by forging new friendships with old friends and new allies alike as an independent global trading nation.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In June 2016 residents from across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency voted to take back control of our money, our laws, our borders and our waters. On 31st January this year we honoured our commitment to leave the European Union and next week we will leave the transition period. We will leave with the confidence of having […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3490</id>
    <published>2020-12-24T15:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T15:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Losses due to UK Government induced panic must be repaired, says Isles MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/24/losses-due-to-uk-government-induced-panic-must-be-repaired-says-isles-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;img src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/a1b5c66c-64cd-4de6-8cc5-d2cd48c1794c.jpeg?w=864" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to Chancellor of the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, urging him to repair the losses faced by the shellfish and fish operators in the Hebrides due to UK Government induced panic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr MacNeil said: “There will be many losses suffered by operators, shellfish producers and shellfish sellers who can ill-afford this. This is particularly felt in the Christmas market which is often a make or break market for companies. To have that snatched away from them at the last minute because of UK Government induced panic is doubly sickening.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The UK Government caused the population of London to flee, caused the French to close the border.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The UK Government has been printing money left right and centre for bankers and handing out contracts worth billions to their friends.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“They must not walk away from the problems they have created for fishermen, fish producers and fish processors here in the islands and the West Highlands.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I have therefore written to the Chancellor to make good any losses sustained to shellfish and fish operators in the Hebrides and west coast of Scotland. Our communities, which are going to be the hardest hit in all of Europe by the coming Brexit, can ill afford this.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to Chancellor of the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, urging him to …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/24/losses-due-to-uk-government-induced-panic-must-be-repaired-says-isles-mp/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3291</id>
    <published>2020-12-24T09:21:10Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-24T09:21:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas cheer for the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/christmas-cheer-for-the-friends-of-neath-abbey-iron-company/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Hard-working volunteers with the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have pulled another iron from the fund-raising fire – a £9,300 grant from the National Lottery Heritage Fund to take the project to a new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Part of the cash will be used to create a digital guide to the history of Neath Abbey – including not only the world-famous ironworks but the impressive remains of the Cistercian monastery close by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;And with open days, guided tours and personal presentations all off-limits while the corona virus pandemic continues, digital outreach has become an essential tool in raising awareness of the project by allowing people to visualise the ironworks at its world-beating peak – when it powered the industrial revolution of the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Data will be posted on Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and People’s Collection Wales, creating a virtual guided tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;In addition, new interpretive panels at the ironworks will explain the history and function of the various structures and buildings on site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;The remainder of the money will be used to renovate an old BT telephone kiosk – which cost £1 – and convert it into a heritage centre at the nearby Longford housing estate where local people can, via a display book and works of art, discover the area’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;The artworks will be created by children of the local Dwr y Felin Comprehensive School. Other community groups such as Bryncoch Environment Group, Dyffryn Clydach Community Council, Dyffryn Clydach and Bryncoch Historic Group will also display community news, events and information in the kiosk.&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2344"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2344" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8DCDF1DF-42F0-4CD0-97E0-3676E4E7186B-560x297.png" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hard-working volunteers with the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have pulled another iron from the fund-raising fire – a £9,300 grant from the National Lottery Heritage Fund to take the project to a new level. Part of the cash will be used to create a digital guide to the history of Neath Abbey – […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2343</id>
    <published>2020-12-23T08:53:03Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T08:53:03Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Speaks Up for Traveling Showmen and Women</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-speaks-up-for-traveling-showmen-and-women/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2969" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-980x653.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled &lt;strong&gt;Future of fairs and Showgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and showmen community and steps in to provide vital support before it is too late. As a longstanding supporter and advocate for show people and a member of the All Party Parliamentary Group for Fairs and Showgrounds, I will continue to be a voice for this community and press the Government at every opportunity for better support and recognition. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the outset of the pandemic, many fairs were either cancelled or postponed – from summer fetes to Christmas Markets. As a result of the closures and postponing of fairs, many show people suffered huge financial loss, plunging them into financial insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The heart of the issue is that the financial support offered to the tourism industry during COVID-19 continually excluded the fairground community. Showmen and women also did not qualify for the assistance announced in the recent budget for retail, leisure and hospitality firms relating to business rates in the coming year, due to the way that the Show people operate, which falls outside the scope of static leisure providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Show people across the UK and particularly those here in South Shields, now face losing their businesses and livelihoods if the UK Government does not step in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read my speech by clicking &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2020-12-17/debates/3B335883-D800-426D-ACAD-2204734ED4F7/FairsAndShowgrounds#contribution-374A337C-9576-467B-95F1-505F40A37FE0"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled Future of fairs and Showgrounds. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2971</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>David Evennett and Bexley Conservatives supporting local pubs, sports and social clubs this winter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bexley Council with funding support from the government has announced further Covid-19 support packages for local businesses across Bexleyheath and Crayford. 
These new grant schemes include a special winter support package of just under £1 million being made available for local independent pubs,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Weston&#8217;s MP Welcomes Cuts To Housing Targets &#038; Commitment to Building Up, Not Out]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/21/westons-mp-welcomes-cuts-to-housing-targets-commitment-to-building-up-not-out/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4537</id>
		<updated>2020-12-21T10:18:02Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-21T10:18:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose has welcomed news the Government will drop proposals to increase North Somerset’s housebuilding targets from 1,365 to 1,708 a year. This announcement comes just months after John wrote to Ministers raising concerns that the proposed new housebuilding targets were unrealistic and weeks after John and Liam Fox raised the issue in [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/21/westons-mp-welcomes-cuts-to-housing-targets-commitment-to-building-up-not-out/"><![CDATA[
<p>Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose has welcomed news the Government will drop proposals to increase North Somerset’s housebuilding targets from 1,365 to 1,708 a year.</p>



<p>This announcement comes just months after John wrote to Ministers raising concerns that the proposed new housebuilding targets were unrealistic and weeks after John and Liam Fox raised the issue in a debate on housebuilding in North Somerset. John made the point that the algorithm being used&nbsp;encouraged environmentally damaging housebuilding over green fields rather than investment and regeneration in urban areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>John said: &#8220;It&#8217;s great that the Government has listened to what I, Liam Fox, North Somerset Council and others have been saying. This is a big step in the right direction, although the existing building targets are still pretty high. But if we Build Up Not Out in urban areas like central Weston or Bristol, and use local Council-approved Design Codes so the new builds match the best of what’s already here, we can build a lot more green, good-looking homes that local people can afford, that are close to work, transport-links, shops, schools and GP surgeries, and which revive our town centres and High Streets too.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chippenham High Street Closure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19.</p>



<p>High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market Place. Alternative route: via Market Place – The Causeway – A4 – Bath Road and vice versa.</p>



<p>The closure and diversion route will be clearly indicated by traffic signs and access will be maintained for residents and businesses where possible throughout the works period.</p>



<p>These works will commence on 21 December 2020 and are anticipated to be required for one day. This Notice will have a maximum duration of 21 days. </p>



<p>For further information regarding these works please contact Tracy Howell on behalf of Chippenham Town Council on 01249446699. Sustainable Transport Group, County Hall, Bythesea Road, Trowbridge BA14 8JN Ref: SH/DEC2020</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="722" src="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33865" srcset="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg 1024w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-300x212.jpg 300w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-768x542.jpg 768w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-710x501.jpg 710w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1030x726.jpg 1030w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg 1316w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19. High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33864</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Chippenham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=loneliness-and-our-communities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="5663" class="elementor elementor-5663" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-27b274df elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="27b274df" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-71d5ac96" data-id="71d5ac96" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3b39d78c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3b39d78c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"><p><!-- wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p>
<p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances none of us would have imagined. As we look to the light provided by new vaccines and as we approach a new year, there is yet another nasty legacy sting in the tail of 2020 – a rise in feelings of loneliness.</p>
<p>Research from Age UK has shown that this Christmas is set to be the loneliest yet for older people. Over 160,000 people over the age of 65 will suffer from feeling lonely this festive season, with nearly 60% of them fearing that they won’t see any family and friends. Those are heartbreaking numbers, even one person feeling like this is one too many.</p>
<p>Our communities can carry another more positive legacy from 2020. The Age UK research also highlighted that over 100,000 older people were helped to get through the pandemic by the kindness of strangers. The simple act of checking on people made a life-enhancing difference for so many, we can never know for sure, but it’s probably safe to assume that in some instances, it was life-saving.</p>
<p>Of course, loneliness and isolation don’t discriminate; young people are also affected. The Office of National statistics were able to point out that, during the first month of the pandemic, 7. 4 million people, across the nations of the UK said that their wellbeing was affected through feeling isolated.</p>
<p>We all knew that these restrictions were essential to protect lives, but the collateral effect was, as predicted, substantial. Recently, we have become more aware of a problem that has existed for some time but rarely brought into public debate. Work undertaken for the charities MIND and Mental Health UK confirmed that young people are particularly affected by loneliness.</p>
<p>During the pandemic almost half of 18-24-year-olds experienced, and those aged 25-34 are twice – yes twice – as likely to be lonely at Christmas than older people. That’s a lot of lonely people out there feeling isolated.</p>
<p>While we cannot visit indoors, there are many other ways we can help people feel less isolated. Given that a third of people are too embarrassed to admit that they are lonely, it is small acts that make a difference; it might be a note through the door or a phone call to someone you haven’t spoken to in a while. Simple offers of contact, help with shopping, a chat a few steps back from the doorstep could mean a big deal to reassure folk that they are valued and to feel a little less alone.</p>
<p>If you need to talk to someone over the festive period, or any other time, the below contacts offer free and non-judgemental help;</p>
<p>MikeysLine 01463 729000</p>
<p>Breathing Space 0800 83 85 87</p>
<p>Samaritans 116 123</p>
<p>Mind 0300 123 3393</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
<p><!-- /wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5663</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Over 100 Parliamentarians urge the UK Government to take action to protect the Rohingya against genocide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p style="background: white;">
          <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: black;">104 Parliamentarians from across parties are calling on the UK Government to take urgent action to protect the Rohingya Muslim minority from persecution from the Myanmar Government and military. </span>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP welcomes Covid-19 vaccine hub in his constituency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-covid-19-vaccine-hub-in-his-constituency/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/10869/eovtwrvwmaegtuk/" rel="attachment wp-att-10870"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-10870" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-740x416.jpg" alt="" width="740" height="416" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-740x416.jpg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"/></a></p>
<p>The MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, has welcomed that Holderness Health in his constituency is one of the first GP practices to offer the Pfizer-BioNTech vaccination against Covid-19 to their most vulnerable patients.</p>
<p>The UK became the first country in the world to approve the vaccine on 2nd December, when the independent Medicines &amp; Healthcare products Regulatory Agency gave it the go-ahead. The NHS is now in the process of delivering the largest programme of immunisation in the country’s history, and subsequently announced that Castle Hill Hospital would act as a vaccine hub to protect the most vulnerable patients and healthcare staff in the region.</p>
<p>Now, GP practices are being added to the list of sites approved to administer the vaccine, despite health bosses having to contend with the practicalities of storing and transporting the vaccine, which must be stored between -80°C and -60°C and given to patients within six hours of being thawed.</p>
<p>As a result, Holderness Health has been chosen as one of four local Covid-19 vaccination centres in Hull and the East Riding, with more practices joining on a phased basis over the course of the coming months. The first GP-led vaccinations were carried out at Holderness Health yesterday afternoon (14th December).</p>
<p>Patients over the age of 80 with the greatest clinical risk are being offered appointments first, with priority groups determined by the Joint Committee on Vaccination &amp; Immunisation. Eventually, mass vaccinations will be offered in sports venues and conference centres once further vaccine supplies become available.</p>
<p>Graham commented, “This is fantastic news for vulnerable constituents in Beverley and Holderness, who will be among the first to be offered this vaccination by their family GPs.</p>
<p>“I know Holderness Health have plenty of experience in delivering safe and effective vaccination programmes, as they do every year with the flu jab, so I have every confidence that they will rise to the challenge despite its scale and complexity.</p>
<p>“The public can really help with this by not contacting the surgery to ask for a jab, because eligible people will be proactively contacted by phone, letter, or the national booking system.”</p>
<p>For it to be effective, people are required to have two doses of the vaccine 3 weeks apart and the NHS is urging people to ensure that they book their jabs when contacted and are emphasising the importance of attending both appointments: Dr Craig Dobson, medical advisor to the East Riding CCG (Clinical Commissioning Group) said, “The vaccine has been shown to be effective and it is fantastic news that in our local area we can start to vaccinate our more vulnerable residents, who need it most.</p>
<p>“If you are in one of the priority groups, I would urge that when your GP Practice contacts you, please make sure you book and attend your appointments when you arrange them.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, has welcomed that Holderness Health in his constituency is one of the first GP practices to offer...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10869</id>
    <published>2020-12-15T16:59:12Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T16:59:12Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="Covid-19"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Holderness"/>
    <category term="Holderness Health"/>
    <category term="Hospital"/>
    <category term="NHS"/>
    <category term="Vaccine"/>
    <category term="Withernsea"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meeting Father Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I met Father Christmas in Marks and Spencers' Car Park on Sunday 13 December. He had been invited there by the Beckenham Roatary Club of which I an also a member. It was the first time I have seen him this year and he said would be delivering presents to children as normal what ever happened over…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas</id>
    <published>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/23/lambed/07/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - Brexit </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we approach the end of this terrible year I suspect I will not cheer anyone up by reminding them that the end of the Brexit transition period is very close. It is a matter of huge interest to the whole country but is of course of particular concern to us in Kent because of the possibility of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0</id>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WGC Becomes Location for First Ever Green Number Plate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Transport Secretary Grant Shapps recently visited Halfords autocentres in Welwyn Garden City to have the first ever ‘green number plate’ fitted. This comes as the country prepares for the mass adoption of electric vehicles ahead of the UK ending its contribution to climate change by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number plate consists of a green coloured flash on the left-hand side of the plate to designate the vehicle as having zero emissions at tailpipe. The plates are now available to the general public and will be included with all new zero-emissions-vehicles unless customers choose to opt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said the move “Underlined the Government’s commitment to tackling poor air quality in the UK’s towns and cities. It builds on last month’s announcement to end the sale of new petrol and diesel cars and vans in the UK by 2030, putting the UK on course to be the fastest G7 country to decarbonise these vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the new plates on UK roads will raise awareness of the growing number of zero emission vehicles, as well as helping motorists benefit from possible local initiatives such as special parking spaces and cost-free entry into zero-emission zones such as the one in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said: “A green recovery is key to helping us achieve our net zero carbon commitments while also promoting economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Green number plates could unlock a number of incentives for drivers and increase awareness of cleaner vehicles on our roads, showing people that a greener transport future is within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re supporting small businesses to develop the transport tech of the future through a multi-million-pound investment, ensuring that&amp;nbsp;UK&amp;nbsp;businesses remain at the forefront of low carbon innovation and research.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video was produced during the visit, which can be viewed below:&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0  et_pb_text_align_center"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F719013365401804%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=476" width="476" height="476" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30910</id>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Green Number Plates"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Garden City"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[HAVE YOUR SAY ON THE FUTURE OF BUSES]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=341</id>
		<updated>2020-12-09T13:20:32Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-09T13:18:48Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated
announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce
the spread of Covid-19 in England.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed
once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to
ensure we keep people safe and well. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is vital that careful consideration is given
to ensuring the right areas are placed in the right tiers. While we welcome the
way the three tiers recognise that different areas require different approaches
to managing the virus, we believe that Nottingham City Council is uniquely
placed to understand the best interests of its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last month, Nottingham was placed in tier 2 before being
stepped up to tier 3, alongside our partners in the neighbouring
Nottinghamshire County Council. At that time, we had one of the highest rates
of Covid-19 in the country. Since then, we have seen a significant and
sustained reduction in the rate of Covid-19 in Nottingham City, with 40
consecutive days of falling Covid cases and counting. We now sit below the
national average for rates per 100,000 population and are ranked 121&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;
Lower Tier Local Authority nationally. I’m sure you would agree this is a
dramatic and impressive turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our rate is now 50 per cent lower than when we were last
placed into tier 3. We believe our sustained lower rate of Covid-19 should be
reflected in the way Nottingham is allocated a tier this time around.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our fall in cases of Covid-19 is a reflection of the hard
work which has taken place, along with neighbouring councils, the police,
businesses and our city’s two universities – as well as with the local NHS. All
organisations have united in a shared response to reducing the spread of the
virus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also, of course, attributable to the efforts of our
local communities, and their support in adhering to the guidelines and
restrictions in place. We feel that people in Nottingham have worked hard to
bring down the rate of Covid-19 in our communities and among our older
population – and that our position in the tier system should reflect this
decrease.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We know that ongoing restrictions will continue to have a
significant impact on our businesses, our hospitality sector and our
communities. It is vital the right decisions are made for our city.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We would like the opportunity to build on Nottingham’s
successful partnership work in a way that allows us more freedom to reopen key
parts of our economy: to keep restaurants and indoor entertainment venues open
and to ensure our city can begin to reopen in a way that is safe, supported and
protected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would welcome the opportunity to discuss this further.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;br&gt;Cllr David Mellen&lt;br&gt;Leader, Nottingham City Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/"&gt;Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Prime Minister, I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce the spread of Covid-19 in England. It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2569</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith tells Government ‘the people of the north will hold you to account’ on rebalancing the economy.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning I took part in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanJarvisMP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DanJarvisMP&lt;/a&gt; debate on support for the economy in the North. We need a fundamental rebalancing of our economy after Covid. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this Government to account for their promises and their actions. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iCcp6jNBhp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iCcp6jNBhp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the
economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was
fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s handling of the Covid crisis, and in
particular their approach to local restrictions and regional packages of
financial support, has shown that too often the needs of the North are still an
after-thought or, worse, ignored altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Instead of
establishing a clear and transparent framework of support, proportionate to
need, the Government has employed a strategy of divide and rule.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are now in a national lockdown of course, and the
furlough scheme has been extended until March, but the Government must set out
exactly what will happen at the end of this period. They have indicated we will
go back into the tiered system, but many businesses in Bradford will simply not
survive if we go straight back into tier 2 or 3 with the current level of
support.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the short term, the Government must ensure that whatever
the restrictions are after December 2nd, there is a fair set of financial
support that takes into account how long an area has been under local
restrictions. For each measure, the Government should produce an impact
assessment by region, which includes the impact on regional inequality and the
regional economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the longer term, we need a fundamental rebalancing of our
economy. Levelling up rhetoric and the odd project here and there will not be
enough. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this
Government to account for their promises and their actions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith also called for reform of the Treasury’s ‘Green Book’
which is used to make decisions on Government investment, as it currently
“skews investment and therefore growth into where it already happens, rather
than where it needs to happen”. In response, the Government announced they
would be publishing the revised Green Book at this year’s spending review on
the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, support, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;90&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" alt="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has welcomed the latest proposals for tougher sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving and urges the government to act on them without delay Responding in Parliament, Leader of the House Jacob-Rees Mogg said: " “I thank the hon. Lady for the campaigning she's done on this very&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, judith, will, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/imgID149097243-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" alt="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A version of this article was first published in The Times Ever since I heard Matt Hancock, in a recent interview, extol the virtues of getting seven hours sleep a night through this pandemic, I’ve been thinking about what keeps me awake at night. At the top of my list&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: local, government, support, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;67&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: restrictions, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2359</id>
    <published>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
