<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-01-10T06:32:46Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>A Health package</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/01/10/a-health-package/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>At last Ministers had something to say about getting waiting lists for treatment down and waiting times at A and E reduced. The fundamental principle of the NHS is free access to health care based on need. Rationing by delay is not part of the deal to taxpayers who are now paying  very large sums for the service.</p>
<p>The NHS needs more medical capacity. It needs more GP surgery slots, more hospital beds and more operations performed. The backlogs are unacceptable. This is why I and others have been calling for a Manpower Plan. This needs to set out expectations of manageable workloads per employee and realistic targets for staff  numbers needed to cope with likely demand. They also need extra to get rid of the oversized waiting lists.</p>
<p>This raises various questions over training, recruitment and retention. Could we introduce high standards of training in specific areas that take less time than a full doctor’s qualification to staff specialist centres for cataracts, knee surgery and the other high volume standard procedures for elective surgery? Can nurses and pharmacists have more authority  over prescribing and providing medicines? Can medical tests be streamlined and  be more efficient?</p>
<p>When it comes to retaining doctors that does highlight the general tax issue where people get taxed at 60% in the £100,000 to £125,000 range, and where the allowed level of savings for pension has bee cut  back substantially. It would be good to ease these tax issues for all as doctors tell us they lead more to retire early when we still need their skills.</p>
<p>The Secretary of State yesterday announced more money to buy bedspaces in care homes to allow earlier discharge from hospital for some elderly patients. He also announced the equivalent of 7000 extra beds in the form of virtual wards where people are clinically supervised remotely by professionals whilst be in bed at home. he also announced some increase in capacity through adding modular units to allow more day care in A and E. He also proposed more work for pharmacies to cut the demands on GPs.</p>
<p>There is still no full workforce plan,  nor stated plans to add beds with relevant staff to hospitals. As the population keeps on growing, and as an ageing population needs more hospital care the NHS does need to expand its core bed capacity.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">At last Ministers had something to say about getting waiting lists for treatment down and waiting times at A and E reduced. The fundamental principle of the NHS is free access to health care based on need. Rationing by delay is not part of the deal to taxpayers who are now paying  very large sums…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=34211</id>
    <published>2023-01-10T05:06:43Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-10T05:06:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby highlights Tory inaction on college building project investment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/09/toby-highlights-tory-inaction-on-college-building-project-investment/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/09/toby-highlights-tory-inaction-on-college-building-project-investment/">Toby highlights Tory inaction on college building project investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/09/toby-highlights-tory-inaction-on-college-building-project-investment/">Toby highlights Tory inaction on college building project investment</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5161</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T20:03:29Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T20:03:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP challenges Health Secretary to tackle Cumbria’s cancer crisis</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439243/mp-challenges-health-secretary-to-tackle-cumbria-s-cancer-crisis"/>
  <updated>2023-01-09T18:53:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439243/mp-challenges-health-secretary-to-tackle-cumbria-s-cancer-crisis</id>
  <summary type="text">In Parliament this evening, South Lakes MP Tim Farron pleaded with the Health Secretary to intervene over waiting times for cancer treatment in Cumbria.
Speaking during a Health Statement in the House of Commons, Tim said: "Patients living with cancer and their families and the outstanding cancer workforce will be staggered, as am I, that we just had a statement on NHS pressures with no serious plan being put forward for tackling the deadly cancer backlog.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In Parliament this evening, South Lakes MP Tim Farron pleaded with the Health Secretary to intervene over waiting times for cancer treatment in Cumbria.</p>
<p>Speaking during a Health Statement in the House of Commons, Tim said: <em>"Patients living with cancer and their families and the outstanding cancer workforce will be staggered, as am I, that we just had a statement on NHS pressures with no serious plan being put forward for tackling the deadly cancer backlog.</em></p>
<p><em>"17,000 cancer patients in the last three months had their targets for cancer treatment delayed and missed. 43% of people diagnosed with cancer in South Cumbria waited more than two months for their first lifesaving treatment.</em></p>
<p><em>"In North Cumbria, 63% of those people diagnosed with cancer waited more than two months for their first treatment. So where is the urgent plan to tackle the cancer backlog?</em></p>
<p><em>"And on a very practical and cross-party level, will he attend or one of his ministers attend the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Radiotherapy's Inquiry on the 18th of January, so we can work together to come up with some quick technical solutions that will actually save lives?"</em></p>
<p>Responding, the Secretary of State for Health, Steven Barclay said: "<em>So firstly, it's worth just pointing out to the House that 92% of new patients are starting their cancer treatment within four weeks, but also to the substance of his point, that is exactly why we're rolling out the programme of community diagnostic centres.</em></p>
<p><em>"It's why we've got the surgical hubs programme in order to prioritise those cancer treatments and also, given that it was a central part of the statement today, it is rather surprising that the major investment bringing the potential of cancer world-leading cancer vaccines from our life science strategy, which could be absolutely transformational for cancer patients, wasn't even referenced there.</em></p>
<p><em>"And it's something I hope he does support because it has the potential to be a game changer."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The NHS is in crisis, so where is the Government? – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-nhs-is-in-crisis-so-where-is-the-government-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-nhs-is-in-crisis-so-where-is-the-government-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235983" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/hhh.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>Like many people across Tameside, I’ve been watching the crisis in the NHS unfold with a mixture of horror and disbelief. Waiting times have reached historic highs, patients are unable to be discharged because of collapsing social care provision and the images of backed-up ambulances outside A&amp;E are plastered across news channels on a daily basis.</p>
<p>Here in Tameside, NHS staff are working around the clock for patients, but the truth is they have been failed by 13 years of Government neglect and mismanagement. When the last Labour Government left office, we had the highest patient satisfaction, historically low waiting times, and handed over a successful and efficient NHS. It is beyond depressing, then, to see how quickly that golden legacy has been obliterated by the Conservatives.</p>
<p>It isn’t just A&amp;E suffering, but Primary Care too. In December, new data was released which revealed that over 1,500 people across Denton and Reddish faced a wait of 28 days or more to see a GP in October. Figures like these would have felt unimaginable 13 years ago, but sadly have become all too common.</p>
<p>So how do we address this crisis? Well, it requires a combination of short-term and long-term thinking. Labour would scrap the non-dom tax status and using the cash to implement the biggest expansion of the NHS workforce in modern history. This radical investment would come alongside reform to make sure that patients received the very best care possible.</p>
<p>But we also need to see short-term action taken immediately to plug the gaps and stop the NHS from totally sinking. This means doing things like utilising spare capacity in the private sector, fixing doctors pension rules to improve staff retention, getting funds into adult social care, and boosting flu and covid vaccination efforts. Steps like these could be taken today, but the Government is failing to take the decisive action which is so desperately needed.</p>
<p>It might be a strange thing to say, but I genuinely hope the Government steals Labour’s NHS strategy. We can’t afford to wait for the next General Election. The problems are too acute, too widespread, and too life-threatening. I want the Government to nab our fully-costed long term workforce strategy and start implementing the necessary short-term fixes immediately.</p>
<p>Things should never have got to this stage, but now that they have, we need to see some leadership. NHS Patients deserve better, NHS staff deserve better, and the people of Tameside deserve better.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-nhs-is-in-crisis-so-where-is-the-government-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">The NHS is in crisis, so where is the Government? – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Like many people across Tameside, I’ve been watching the crisis in the NHS unfold with a mixture of horror and disbelief. Waiting times have reached historic highs, patients are unable to be discharged because of collapsing social care provision and the images of backed-up ambulances outside A&amp;E are plastered across news channels on a daily […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-nhs-is-in-crisis-so-where-is-the-government-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">The NHS is in crisis, so where is the Government? – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235982</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T18:32:51Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T18:32:51Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour proposes to keep all local libraries open</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/01/09/nottingham-labour-proposes-to-keep-all-local-libraries-open/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o.jpg"&gt;&lt;img width="1024" height="575" src="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o-1024x575.jpg" alt="water, building, sky, paving" class="wp-image-2627" srcset="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o-1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o-300x169.jpg 300w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o-768x432.jpg 768w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/17038977_1381868608549923_8939392318586755908_o.jpg 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Revised proposals to transform local library services and achieve savings for the City Council are being recommended for approval by the authority’s Executive Board ( 17 January).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Initial plans involved among other things the closure of three libraries, with Aspley being turned into a distribution hub for the library service but closing to the public. Some savings have already been achieved through a staffing restructure in the libraries service. The decision to put forward the closure of the libraries was not one that was proposed lightly, but was due to pressure to balance the council budget from the Government’s austere economic measures. The laws around local government and the requirements made from the Tories for all councils around the country are not fit for purpose leading to a situation whereby the closure of the three libraries had to be considered. No Labour politician would ever want to bring such proposals forward, but the budget is an ongoing challenge and so it will remain until the Conservatives are removed from office.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposals now due to be considered by members of the Executive Board involve keeping all existing libraries open, with some shortened opening times across the library network, and retaining Aspley as a publicly accessible library, whilst fitting in it a stock distribution centre for Nottingham Performing Arts Library. Different libraries currently have different opening times and the proposal is to align them to an updated core, satisfying communities’ use. This proposal protects the library buildings if slightly altering opening times and delivers the required saving at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a response to strong feedback from residents against the closure proposals, coupled with emerging factors such as the integral role that libraries continue to perform during the ongoing cost-of-living crisis, for example as warm hubs. The conditions of people living in our city and around the country have worsened significantly as a result of the Government’s inadequacy to bring inflation under control and to support public services at all levels over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report to Executive Board states: “The transformation principles and revised recommendations provides a positive response to the views and concerns raised by individuals and communities and the strong opposition to closures. The recommendations still enable the transformation to create a modern library service that remains relevant, whilst still responding to financial pressures facing the local authority and the specific delivery of the savings requirement.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cllr Pavlos Kotsonis, Portfolio Holder for Leisure, Culture and Planning, said: “Our ability to bring forward proposals to protect all three libraries constitutes a positive response to the needs of people in Nottingham including the most vulnerable in our communities. Their voices from the extensive consultation have been heard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“No matter how much the Government threatens our public services we need to continue doing all we can to fight for them, and even though we still have to operate under a Conservative Government that has created a difficult financial environment &amp;#8211; and we will still be asked to make disproportionate amounts of savings in the future &amp;#8211; we still need to keep doing all we can to mitigate the impact to all our communities.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report to the Executive Board can be read here: &lt;a href="https://committee.nottinghamcity.gov.uk/ieListDocuments.aspx?CId=177&amp;amp;MId=9491"&gt;Agenda for Executive Board on Tuesday, 17th January, 2023, 2.00 pm &amp;#8211; Nottingham City Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Revised proposals to transform local library services and achieve savings for the City Council are being recommended for approval by the authority’s Executive Board ( 17 January). Initial plans involved among other things the closure of three libraries, with Aspley being turned into a distribution hub for the library service but closing to the public.… <a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/01/09/nottingham-labour-proposes-to-keep-all-local-libraries-open/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More »<span class="screen-reader-text">Nottingham Labour proposes to keep all local libraries open</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2955</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T16:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T16:16:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Libraries"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="Radford"/>
    <category term="Wollaton East &amp; Lenton Abbey Labour Team"/>
    <category term="aspley"/>
    <category term="basford"/>
    <category term="libraries"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Annual Report Back to Constituents 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/annual-report-back-constituents-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2587" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Annual Report Back to Constituents 2022</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Being an active local constituency MP means working to help find solutions to some of the biggest local problems we face here in Mid Norfolk.</p>

<p>I think it also means being accountable to YOU – the people I am here to represent and serve. As I have pledged on each of the four election nights on which I’ve been honoured to be elected, I will always do my best to represent EVERYONE in Mid Norfolk – not just the people that voted for me.</p>

<p>To read my annual report to constituents, please click the link below.</p>

<p> </p>
<a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2022-12/reporting_back_2022.pdf"><img alt="Reporting Back" data-entity-type="file" data-entity-uuid="b8c68ee0-b8b4-4c6e-b8bb-88c5973cc533" src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/inline-images/reporting_back_0.jpg" class="align-center" width="590" height="833" loading="lazy"/></a>

<p> </p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2587 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T16:02:55Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T16:02:55Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy New Year!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/happy-new-year-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Happy New Year – it’s been lovely throughout the festive period to be out and about across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency and join you at so many of your events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s back to Parliament today in which we have a packed week of business to ensure that we continue to work on your priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to being back in the constituency at the weekend and joining the Aldridge Youth Theatre for their annual Pantomime – Oh Yes I am!!!!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy New Year – it’s been lovely throughout the festive period to be out and about across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency and join you at so many of your events. It’s […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4471</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T14:48:58Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T14:48:58Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Individual Issues raised by constituents NOVEMBER 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/01/individual-issues-raised-by-constituents-november-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img data-attachment-id="13115" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/01/individual-issues-raised-by-constituents-november-2022/individual-issues-november-2022/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?fit=1028%2C1242&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1028,1242" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Individual issues NOVEMBER 2022" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?fit=248%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?fit=700%2C845&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13115 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?resize=700%2C845&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="845" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?resize=848%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 848w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?resize=248%2C300&amp;ssl=1 248w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?resize=768%2C928&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Individual-issues-NOVEMBER-2022.png?w=1028&amp;ssl=1 1028w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13114</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T13:59:09Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T13:59:09Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Aberconwy MP welcomes Project Gigabit coming to Nant Bwlch yr Haern in Eryri</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/aberconwy-mp-welcomes-project-gigabit-coming-nant-bwlch-yr-haern-eryri" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">After years of enduring slow internet speeds Nant Bwlch yr Haern, a popular residential education centre in the Gwydir Forest near Llanrwst for children from throughout North Wales, now has lightning-fast, reliable gigabit broadband thanks to the UK Government’s Project Gigabit.
Speaking about the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/aberconwy-mp-welcomes-project-gigabit-coming-nant-bwlch-yr-haern-eryri</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Increasing Hospital Capacity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/increasing-hospital-capacity" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We’re investing up to £250 million to free up hospital beds for those who need it the most.
Thousands of medically fit patients will be discharged safely from hospitals into community care homes over the coming weeks to reduce pressure on the NHS.
The £200 million will be used to buy care…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/increasing-hospital-capacity</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Channel 4's liberal metropolitan bias almost makes the BBC look impartial</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/channel-4s-liberal-metropolitan-bias-almost-makes-bbc-look-impartial" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I raised my concerns about the way the state owned channel is operated and the concerns I hear from many of my constituents over its direction.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/channel-4s-liberal-metropolitan-bias-almost-makes-bbc-look-impartial</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg questions Treasury Minister on energy support for businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-questions-treasury-minister-energy-support-businesses" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This afternoon the Government announced further support on energy bills for businesses.
The Government have already provided £18 billion of business support through 2022/23. This is equivalent to 40% of defence spending or c.3 pence on people’s income tax. However, the immediate burden on…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-questions-treasury-minister-energy-support-businesses</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Telegraph: John says PM should not drop plans for war on Whitehall red tape]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/09/telegraph-john-says-pm-should-not-drop-plans-for-war-on-whitehall-red-tape/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5632</id>
		<updated>2023-01-09T10:01:16Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-09T10:01:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Press Cuttings"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article was written by Nick Gutteridge, POLITICAL CORRESPONDENT, and Christopher Hope, ASSOCIATE EDITOR, and originally published by The Telegraph. Rishi Sunak has dropped plans to rein in Whitehall bureaucracy by setting Government departments “red tape budgets’’. Ministers would have been handed binding annual targets limiting the total regulatory cost they could impose on businesses. [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/09/telegraph-john-says-pm-should-not-drop-plans-for-war-on-whitehall-red-tape/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong><em>This article was written by Nick Gutteridge, POLITICAL CORRESPONDENT, and Christopher Hope, ASSOCIATE EDITOR, and originally published by The Telegraph.</em></strong></p>



<p>Rishi Sunak has dropped plans to rein in Whitehall bureaucracy by setting Government departments “<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/politics/2022/09/24/planning-red-tape-cut-effort-turbocharge-home-building/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">red tape budgets</a>’’.</p>



<p>Ministers would have been handed binding annual targets limiting the total regulatory cost they could impose on businesses.</p>



<p>The proposals were part of efforts under Liz Truss to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2022/08/08/seize-brexit-opportunity-revamp-red-tape/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ease the burden on the economy</a>&nbsp;from civil servants’ excessive lawmaking.</p>



<p>But they will not be taken forward by Mr Sunak, The Telegraph has been told.</p>



<p>Jacob Rees-Mogg, the former business secretary,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2022/11/13/bank-england-dragging-feet-cutting-eu-red-tape/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">drew up detailed plans</a>&nbsp;for putting the new system into action.</p>



<p>An annual review would have set each department a ceiling for the overall cost of regulation it could impose on firms.</p>



<p>They could have chosen how to &#8220;spend&#8221; their red tape budget but would have faced sanctions for exceeding it.</p>



<p>There would have been no exemptions, with the rules covering all public bodies that churn out red tape including quangos.</p>



<h2>&#8216;Worst possible time&#8217;</h2>



<p>Mr Rees-Mogg warned the decision to drop the plan was “bad for the British economy at the worst possible time”.</p>



<p>“One of the most important jobs of any minister is to keep their department&#8217;s regulatory instincts at bay and cut the cost of government on businesses,” he said.</p>



<p>“An overarching policy of regulatory budgets would force officials to prioritise and would revolutionise accountability.</p>



<p>“Without them these burdens will only continue to grow, harming the country&#8217;s growth and competitiveness.”</p>



<p>The introduction of red tape budgets was one of the key recommendations of a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/politics/2021/12/07/bureaucratic-britain-has-become-addicted-permanent-failure/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">bureaucracy review</a>&nbsp;recently handed to No 10.</p>



<p>John Penrose, a senior Tory MP, was commissioned by Mr Sunak when he was chancellor to produce a report on potential reforms.</p>



<p>“The whole system in Westminster and in Whitehall is set up to create new rules,” he said.</p>



<p>“It&#8217;s how politicians, civil servants and regulators make their names, so the political and cultural direction of travel is always pro-regulatory unless we stop it.”</p>



<p>Mr Sunak has also ruled out bringing back the &#8220;one-in-two-out&#8221; rule for red tape.</p>



<p>It states that for every pound of new regulatory burden departments create they must scrap two pounds worth.</p>



<p>The rule was introduced by David Cameron but then quietly dropped by Theresa May.</p>



<p>Sir Iain Duncan Smith, the former Conservative leader, said the Prime Minister should reinstate it to bring bureaucracy back under control.</p>



<p>“Civil servants oppose it, but it&#8217;s the only way to change the culture of bad regulation. The Government should hold their nerve and do it,” he said.</p>



<p>Boris Johnson considered reinstating the rule, but decided against doing so over fears it would hamper efforts to meet his Net Zero target.</p>



<h4>MPs plan to fight against delay to scrap redundant EU regulations</h4>



<p>Brexiteer Tory MPs are separately planning to fight any attempt by the Government to delay&nbsp;<a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2022/09/23/remaining-eu-laws-scrapped-replaced-end-next-year/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">scrapping redundant EU regulations</a>&nbsp;from the end of this year.</p>



<p>A decision on each of the 4,000 pieces of legislation inherited from Brussels during the UK’s membership must be made this year under a planned law.</p>



<p>However, officials have written into the Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill an allowance for ministers to delay some of the sunsetting of regulations until June 2026.</p>



<p>Mark Francois, the European Research Group chairman, said ministers should ink firm timelines on the face of the Bill to force them to stick to the end-2023 deadline, and have to have a vote in the Commons to sign off on any delay.</p>



<p>He said: “Given the history of all the Parliamentary shenanigans surrounding Brexit, it would be far better to include firm timelines on the face of the REUL Bill, rather than leaving this vital issue to secondary legislation &#8211; and thus passing Ministerial whim.</p>



<p>“This process needs to be seen through, which will require firm Government resolve, which I hope and believe will still be forthcoming.”</p>



<p>Downing Street said “there are no plans to change” the deadline.</p>



<p>A Government spokesman also insisted the Prime Minister “remains fully committed to reducing red tape”.</p>



<p>“The Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill will help meet our target to cut £1 billion of business costs from retained EU red tape,” he added.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-5211053597166584393</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T09:09:00.001+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T09:09:51.838+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Businessfore donation to Ms Britcliffe</title>
    <summary type="text">Businessfore donation to Ms Britcliffe

'Businessfore' is a company that is not registered at Companies House and has no evidence of any trading or being a genuine business. 

It operates out of at least three forwarding addresses.

Sara Britcliffe MP received £5,000 from Businessfore.

There are no details about its owners, business interests or where the money came from. 

As listed on the </summary>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/5211053597166584393"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/5211053597166584393"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2023/01/businessfore-donation-to-ms-britcliffe.html" title="Businessfore donation to Ms Britcliffe"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Amazing result for Stevenage FC</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2154-amazing-result-for-stevenage-fc"/>
		<published>2023-01-08T21:29:33+00:00</published>
		<updated>2023-01-08T21:29:33+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2154-amazing-result-for-stevenage-fc</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Respect 👏 Amazing result for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StevenageFC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@StevenageFC&lt;/a&gt; - wonderful history of taking on premier league sides in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FACup?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FACup&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; always believing 🤩 &lt;a href="https://t.co/mVG02N7CIW"&gt;https://t.co/mVG02N7CIW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1612165711228542977?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 8, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Respect 👏 Amazing result for &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/StevenageFC?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@StevenageFC&lt;/a&gt; - wonderful history of taking on premier league sides in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FACup?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#FACup&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; always believing 🤩 &lt;a href="https://t.co/mVG02N7CIW"&gt;https://t.co/mVG02N7CIW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1612165711228542977?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 8, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Hits out at Falling Wages in Dagenham and Rainham</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/mp-hits-out-falling-wages-dagenham-and-rainham" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">MP Hits out at Falling Wages in Dagenham and Rainham</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/index.php/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-01-06T15:43:00+00:00">Fri, 01/06/2023 - 15:43</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1174 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-06T15:43:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-06T15:43:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy New Year]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/05/happy-new-year/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6648</id>
		<updated>2023-01-05T15:30:14Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-05T15:30:14Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="2023"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="future"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="hope"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="king charles"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="New year"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I liked the tone of the first Christmas message from King Charles. His emphasis on service and consideration for others, values too many in public life ignore these days, appealed to me. He credited his mother, our late Queen, for encouraging his beliefs. As he talked of light from darkness, a concept common to most<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/05/happy-new-year/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Happy New Year</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/05/happy-new-year/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I liked the tone of the first Christmas message from King Charles. His emphasis on service and consideration for others, values too many in public life ignore these days, appealed to me. He credited his mother, our late Queen, for encouraging his beliefs. As he talked of light from darkness, a concept common to most religions, it was obvious he’s been reflecting on his loss as he takes on his new role without her.</p>



<p>Many of us will have suffered loss of different kinds over the past 12 months and life at its darkest can seem pointless. Loss is a time for reflection, whether it be loved ones, the death of idols or other events. We should value our pleasures but not just for ourselves. What we do for others matters.</p>



<p>I’ve been thinking about some celebrities lost in 2022, people who gave me joy and pleasure. Pelé, probably the world’s greatest footballer and such a contrast to many of the overpaid petulant &#8220;stars&#8221; of today; Christine McVie of Fleetwood Mac; Sidney Poitier, a fine actor with a range from Detective Virgil Tibbs to Mark Thackeray in To Sir with Love; Mikhail Gorbachev, so different from Putin with his quest for peace and an end to the Cold War; Nichelle Nichols, Star Trek’s Lt Uhura, whose ground breaking role attracted attention from Nelson Mandela; Olivia Newton John, how many of you were tempted to buy a pair of leather pants after watching her and John Travolta?</p>



<p>As we head into 2023, life will change and we’ll lose people we love, those we’ve admired and those whose performances brought joy. We won’t always be happy and just like light and darkness there’s always good and bad. Those we love and trust may let us down and some derive pleasure from giving pain not joy, but most people aren’t like that. The majority want to do right by their family, loved ones, friends, neighbours and even those they barely know. By doing what we feel and know to be right, we can find light and a bright future. All the best for 2023 folks!</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/05/happy-new-year/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/05/happy-new-year/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Uncertain Future for Community Sutton Café as Lease Negotiations Grind to a Halt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/uncertain-future-community-sutton-cafe-lease-negotiations-grind-halt" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rumbles Community Café faces closure after negotiations with Ashfield District Council to extend their lease fail to make any significant progress.
Ashfield District Council, the landlords, entered negotiations with the directors of Rumbles Community Café on Sutton Lawn amidst local pressure after…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/uncertain-future-community-sutton-cafe-lease-negotiations-grind-halt</id>
    <published>2023-01-05T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Tories are short-changing working people, says Alex, as it emerges that wages in Stockton North are worth 7.4% less than when Conservatives came to power]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/tories-are-short-changing-working-people-says-alex-as-it-emerges-that-wages-in-stockton-north-are-worth-7-4-less-than-when-conservatives-came-to-power/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14604</id>
		<updated>2023-01-04T12:10:28Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-04T12:10:27Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham has accused the Conservative Government of short-changing working people as new analysis reveals that the value of wages in Stockton North constituency has fallen by £2,276, or 7.4%, since 2010. Across the country as a whole, real wages are down by an average of 5%, leaving people £1,600 a year [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/tories-are-short-changing-working-people-says-alex-as-it-emerges-that-wages-in-stockton-north-are-worth-7-4-less-than-when-conservatives-came-to-power/">Tories are short-changing working people, says Alex, as it emerges that wages in Stockton North are worth 7.4% less than when Conservatives came to power</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government's New Plan For Maths</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/governments-new-plan-maths" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the Prime Minister will set out his priorities for the year ahead and ambition for a better Britain, including his goal for all school pupils in England to study some form of maths to the age of 18.
Around eight million adults in England have primary school-level numeracy skills, so we must…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/governments-new-plan-maths</id>
    <published>2023-01-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-185" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we enter the New Year, what we see happening will very much depend on how the global energy crisis unfolds. It also depends on the effectiveness of the measures the Chancellor set out in his Autumn Statement last year. The Office for Budget Responsibility has forecast that both inflation and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-185</id>
    <published>2023-01-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Basingstoke MP meets with Basingstoke Police District Commander</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-meets-basingstoke-police-district-commander" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maria Miller recently met with District Commander Scott Johnson of Basingstoke Police to discuss police activities in Basingstoke including what is being done to deter dangerous driving and car meets. 
Maria commented, “Noisy car meets, and urban racing have caused a huge amount of noise and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-meets-basingstoke-police-district-commander</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Standard Column – Happy New Year!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/01/llanelli-standard-column-happy-new-year/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!  I hope 2023 proves to be better for many than 2022 did.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The last 12
months have been remarkable in many ways.&amp;nbsp;
Three Prime Ministers, 4 Chancellors, the UK economy crashed by a
Government in permanent disarray and a cost of living crisis with inflation at
a 40 year high are just a few examples of how ordinary people are now paying
the price for twelve years of arrogant Tory unfairness and incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I see on a
regular basis families across Llanelli who are struggling to make ends
meet.&amp;nbsp; Life can be pretty tough for some,
even in the good times, but things have got undoubtedly worse for many over the
last year or so.&amp;nbsp; The impact of a
Conservative Party more interested in themselves than in the difficulties faced
by the British public is very real indeed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A general
election and the hope this country need from a change of government can’t come
soon enough but it looks like that will have to wait until 2024.&amp;nbsp; Until then, along with other Labour MPs, I
will continue to press the UK Government to change tack and make more decisions
that help the most vulnerable and not just those that are already comfortable
and well off.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we enter the
New Year, the Government really needs to up its game across the board.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They need to get
around the table and take a more constructive approach to ending the strike
disputes we have seen across many public services.&amp;nbsp; Frontline workers really deserve to have
their efforts recognised and supported during these difficult times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They also need
to concentrate on delivering an economy based on fairness.&amp;nbsp; One that achieves a level of growth that they
have failed to get anywhere near for more than a decade and one that create
jobs and helps businesses, big and small.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Massive backlogs
that have accumulated, from driving tests to asylum applications, court cases
bringing criminals to justice to passports, need time, energy and resources to
be cleared.&amp;nbsp; So far, the Government has
shown little sign of providing the investment in our public services that they
require.&amp;nbsp; Their record of complete and
utter failure is letting people down and holding our country back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only time will
tell whether any of this will happen under the current government. Whilst I
remain optimistic about the future, I am also in no doubt that the next twelve
months may well turn out to be as difficult as the last.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As always, I am
keen to help people in my Llanelli constituency and to meet as many businesses,
local organisations and community groups as I possibly can.&amp;nbsp; If you have any problems or issues that you
think I can assist with and would like to discuss them with me then please do
not hesitate to get in touch either by email on &lt;a href="mailto:nia.griffith.mp@parliament.uk"&gt;nia.griffith.mp@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt; or by calling my office at 43 Pottery
Street on 01554 756374.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy New Year!  I hope 2023 proves to be better for many than 2022 did. The last 12 months have been remarkable in many ways.  Three Prime Ministers, 4 Chancellors, the UK economy crashed by a Government in permanent disarray and a cost of living crisis with inflation at a 40 year high are just […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8697</id>
    <published>2023-01-02T11:44:07Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-02T11:44:07Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Westminster - January 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/letter-westminster-january-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7323" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">1 January 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Letter from Westminster - January 2023</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span>As I wrote my Letter from Westminster this time last year, we were a nation still deep in the throes of the Covid pandemic. Twelve months later, the darkest days of the pandemic are behind us but for those who lost loved ones, life will never be quite the same again. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>It will take many months for our health service to recover from the treatment backlog due to the pandemic, but the Government recognises this. More investment in our health and social care sector announced by the new Chancellor Jeremy Hunt in his Autumn Statement, incidentally, bringing weekly spending on the NHS to over £1 billion more than at the time of the EU referendum. Here in Shropshire, the Hospitals Transformation Plan which local clinicians believe essential to improve quality of care is moving forward with renewed impetus. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Looking back, 2022 was a tumultuous year in Westminster, but good progress was achieved in many areas. For several years I have campaigned for improvements to water quality of our rivers and waterways. On this front the Government have gone further than ever before. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Progress began with the Environment Act, passed in 2021, introducing measures to tackle sewage pollution for the first time. Working with many campaigning organisations I helped secure a new legal duty on water companies to reduce the impact of sewage discharges. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>There is no quick fix for six decades of underinvestment in our Victorian sewerage infrastructure, now bursting at the seams, but it is welcome that </span></span>the Government announced <span><span>increased investment focussed on storm overflows. £56bn of capital investment in water treatment was announced over the next 25 years, more than double what has been spent annually since privatisation of the water sector, and quadruple what was spent each year when in public ownership.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span>In November, I was pleased that the Government accepted a further recommendation made by myself and others to ensure that millions of pounds raised by the Treasury from fines on water companies for polluting in breach of permits will in future be redirected to the catchment affected by the pollution to improve water quality. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>The sum of these measures represents enormous progress towards cleaning up our rivers, but <span>this is not the end of sewage pollution, and I will continue to do all I can to keep up the fight in the years ahead.</span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Looking to 2023, the Government are rightly focussed on the urgent challenges we face; from bringing down inflation and supporting the vulnerable through the cost of living and energy prices, to doing all we can to ensure that Putin’s war in Ukraine does not succeed. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>The UK has led the way in providing military and humanitarian aid to Ukraine and we should be proud of our warm welcome to those fleeing war who have found safety in our communities, including 550 here in Shropshire. We must not conflate the genuine sanctuary Ukrainian refugees seek with the many thousands of migrants who have landed on our shores via illegal routes driven by inhumane people traffickers in France. The Home Secretary will need to go further to put an end to this dreadful trade. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>Action is also needed to deliver economic growth and opportunity across the whole of our United Kingdom and I look forward to working with Shropshire Council in the coming months as they continue to bid for Government Levelling Up Funds to unlock the potential of towns like Craven Arms. </span></span></p>

<p><span><span>As ever, there is much to do, but with Rishi Sunak at the helm, I feel positive for the year ahead. Happy New Year.</span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7323 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-01-01T10:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-01T10:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lord Provost offers his condolences on death of Pope Emeritus Benedict XVI</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13625/lord-provost-offers-his-condolences-on-death-of-pope-emeritus-benedict-xvi" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Right Honourable Lord Lieutenant and Lord Provost of the City of Edinburgh, Robert Aldridge, has expressed condolences on behalf of the city.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13625/lord-provost-offers-his-condolences-on-death-of-pope-emeritus-benedict-xvi</id>
    <published>2022-12-31T10:10:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-31T10:10:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Homes for Ukraine Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/homes-ukraine-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was overwhelmed by the generosity of people in North Oxfordshire who welcomed Ukrainian guests into their homes earlier this year. The scheme was designed to help to quickly bring as many Ukrainians as possible to safety and so far more than 100,000 have been welcomed.
I am delighted that the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/homes-ukraine-update</id>
    <published>2022-12-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Christmas Message from Graham Stuart MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/christmas-message-graham-stuart-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What an incredible year it's been for people in Beverley and Holderness.
It's hard to remember that a year ago we were facing the omicron variant.
Now, for the first time since 2019, we can look forward to a normal Christmas once again.
That's because of the amazing effort by everyone who took up…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/christmas-message-graham-stuart-mp</id>
    <published>2022-12-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR HOLIDAYS 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/12/22/christmas-and-new-year-holidays-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>My constituency office will be closed from 3pm Thursday 22nd December 2022 and reopen on Monday 9th January 2023.</p>



<p>The office answer phone will take messages on 0141 952 2988 and emails received at martin.docherty.mp@parliament.uk. However, these will not be routinely monitored and may not be actioned until the office reopens.</p>



<p>My next advice surgeries will be published in early January on my website here: <a href="https://martindocherty.scot/surgeries/">https://martindocherty.scot/surgeries/</a></p>



<p>West Dunbartonshire Council has produced a helpful guide to emergency contact information and out of hours services during the festive period, available online at: <a href="http://www.west-dunbarton.gov.uk/council/christmas-holiday-service-availability/">www.west-dunbarton.gov.uk/council/christmas-holiday-service-availability/</a></p>



<p>I’d like to wish all my constituents across Clydebank, Dumbarton and the Vale of Leven a Merry Christmas and a Guid New Year.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My constituency office will be closed from 3pm Thursday 22nd December 2022 and reopen on Monday 9th January 2023. The office answer phone will take messages on 0141 952 2988 and emails received at martin.docherty.mp@parliament.uk. However, these will not be routinely monitored and may not be actioned until the office reopens. My next advice surgeries ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR HOLIDAYS 2022" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/12/22/christmas-and-new-year-holidays-2022/#more-1821503" aria-label="More on CHRISTMAS AND NEW YEAR HOLIDAYS 2022">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821503</id>
    <published>2022-12-22T14:04:14Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-22T14:04:14Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Christmas!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/happy-christmas/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11993</id>
		<updated>2022-12-22T11:53:38Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-22T11:53:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My office is now closed for the Christmas and New Year break.<br />
The team will continue to monitor emails and voicemail remotely during this period.<br />
If you are a constituent of Leicester West and require urgent assistance over the Christmas period, I’ve put together a list of emergency contacts which may be helpful: see the list here.<br />
I hope everyone has a safe and restful Christmas, and a happy New Year!</p>
<p>Related postsIn The House: Liz Kendall wants you to give your views on Waterside development (Leicester Mercury, 20th February)Liz calls on Government to ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/happy-christmas/">Happy Christmas!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/happy-christmas/"><![CDATA[<p>My office is now closed for the Christmas and New Year break.</p>
<p>The team will continue to monitor emails and voicemail remotely during this period.</p>
<p>If you are a constituent of Leicester West and require <strong>urgent assistance</strong> over the Christmas period, I’ve put together a list of emergency contacts which may be helpful: <a href="https://lizkendall.org/urgent-contacts-christmas/">see the list here.</a></p>
<p>I hope everyone has a safe and restful Christmas, and a happy New Year!</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-7195" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/in-the-house-liz-kendall-wants-you-to-give-your-views-on-waterside-development-leicester-mercury-20th-february/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/8.jpg" alt="In The House: Liz Kendall wants you to give your views on Waterside development (Leicester Mercury, 20th February)" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/in-the-house-liz-kendall-wants-you-to-give-your-views-on-waterside-development-leicester-mercury-20th-february/" class="wp_rp_title">In The House: Liz Kendall wants you to give your views on Waterside development (Leicester Mercury, 20th February)</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-10142" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-on-government-to-do-more-for-social-care-during-coronavirus/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/22.jpg" alt="Liz calls on Government to do more for social care during coronavirus" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-on-government-to-do-more-for-social-care-during-coronavirus/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz calls on Government to do more for social care during coronavirus</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-6905" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/voting-for-equal-pay/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Equal-Pay-150x150.png" alt="Voting for Equal Pay" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/voting-for-equal-pay/" class="wp_rp_title">Voting for Equal Pay</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-3771" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/we-must-fight-on-for-vulnerable/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/6.jpg" alt="We must fight on for vulnerable" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/we-must-fight-on-for-vulnerable/" class="wp_rp_title">We must fight on for vulnerable</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-5060" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/supporting-our-armed-forces/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/22.jpg" alt="Supporting our armed forces" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/supporting-our-armed-forces/" class="wp_rp_title">Supporting our armed forces</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/happy-christmas/">Happy Christmas!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-85/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted to meet their daughter Catherine, Acting Principal of NPT College Group, chair of Welsh Netball, and their son-in-law Mark Dacey (married to another daughter, Alison), Principal of Neath College, in 2014 and we have become close friends. Crid was a pillar of the local community wherever they lived all over the world. A socialist, feminist, Alan’s office manager, member of Cefn Hengoed Ladies Choir (who sang at her funeral) and so much more. Gelligaer Church was full of Crid’s family, friends, and members of community organisations. RIP my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;As part of the Stonegate Group’s annual investment programme, it has invested £174,000 into the Castell-Nedd Arms in Neath town centre. I was delighted to take my staff to visit and see the improvements. We met with the operator of the pub Kayleigh Strinati, the Group’s area manager Danny Cross, and the bar staff. Kayleigh told us that she had worked in the pub trade for a number of years, and she felt that it was time to take that step up to managing the Castell-Nedd. She completed the training requirements, and then Covid struck. But when the pub re-opened again, the customers gradually came back to what had become a social hub for many people who live in Neath. The new challenge is the “cost of living crisis”, but Kayleigh is providing a very warm welcome for people to gather, talk, listen, watch TV, use the Wi-Fi, as well as great refreshments. The refurbishment includes new windows and seating area overlooking Angel Street, a pool and darts section, and many more facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2712"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2712" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1D2F4A81-ED7E-449E-8944-5797D4A54227-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I visited the Churches Together Nativity Scene which this year is displayed in the Greyhound Trust Charity Shop Window, instead of in the Town Square. It is secure and able to be seen by all passers by. Massive thanks to the charity shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I met with Mark Fisher, NPT Council Unison Representative, to discuss Fair Funding for the council. Mark has always done a fantastic job representing Unison members, and although it was announced this week that NPT has received a better than anticipated settlement of 7.1% from Welsh Government, he shared his concerns about pressure on future budgets, and the continuing “cost of living” challenges faced everyday by every one of his members. Mark will be holding a Fair Funding Event at NPT Council for local elected representatives and his Unison members on Friday 13th January 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;After the meeting, Mark and I joined the Royal Mail workers who are striking for a fair pay settlement and no diminishing of their terms and conditions, on their Picket Line which was outside the Royal Mail Sorting Office in Neath. There was a great turnout, and many passers-by supported the strike. People were dropping off food to keep the workers going in the freezing, sub-zero temperatures. In solidarity, I bought all the strikers coffee from our superb local coffee shop, Brew &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2713"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2713" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/71AD8D08-F334-4B81-ADF0-2D1614C1BD81-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Mynydd Fforch Dwm Windfarm is a proposal by &lt;a href="https://mfdwindfarm.co.uk/about-us/"&gt;Naturalis Energy&lt;/a&gt; to provide clean, carbon free energy to homes and businesses across South Wales, including a renewable energy park near Tonmawr. Naturalis is a joint venture between Falck Renewables and REG Windpower energy companies. A number of constituents have contacted me regarding the proposal, asking me to call into the one of the Naturalis public consultation sessions. I dropped into the one held at Neath Little Theatre to view the plans and listen to a presentation by Naturalis staff. As part of the Development of National Significance (DNS) planning process Naturalis are required to undertake a comprehensive programme of pre-application engagement consultations. As an MP I have no remit over Welsh Government or Local Authority Planning applications. My role is to pass on the views and concerns of all my constituents to the stakeholders involved in a particular planning application. Please email me and I shall make sure that your questions are passed onto the stakeholders involved in this application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;My brother James was suddenly taken seriously ill and was rushed to Basingstoke Hospital. My daughter Angharad and I visited him in hospital, but James died following his fight against his illness which turned into pneumonia. My big brother was always there to look after me, after the death of my father, when I was seventeen. James was an industrial pharmacist, worked all over the world, and had many friends and colleagues. James was brought up by my grandparents who owned the Walnut Tree Pub in Kenfig Hill. He was a product of Bridgend Grammar School, Loughborough and Cardiff Universities. James organised the old boys network for former pupils of his old school. My grandfather was a founder of Kenfig Hill RFC, and my parents managed the bar. Rugby was part of James’ life, and he was proud to play number 8 at schoolboy rugby for Wales. I have lived with my brother all over the world at various times during my life. He was my mentor, my hero, my rock. I am devastated at the passing of my beloved brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Being a member of the congregation of St David’s Church Neath has been a great source of comfort to me. The people who go to my church are genuine, caring, supportive, never forget that life is very challenging, and we are always there to help each other through the good and the not-so-good times. It was so good to see my friends at the Choir Coffee Morning at St David’s Church, Neath. Many thanks to everyone who came to help and support. Coffee, cake, festive music with loyal friends in the beautifully Christmas decorated church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It’s an honour to be a patron of YMCA Neath and I really enjoyed the Christmas Fayre. There were stalls, arts and crafts, jewellery, face painting, glitter tattoos, pottery painting, tombola, lucky dip, raffle prizes, and refreshments. It was so good to catch up with Centre Manager Claire Hicks, and Admin Officer Jessica Kennedy. As a lifelong vegan, it was good to meet YMCA staffer Rhys Oliver who has recently started her delivery business “Vegan Kitchen – Food with a conscience – Made in Wales”. Rhys was selling a taste of her produce, vegan sausages, pasties, and chocolate cakes. Her menus are changed weekly and are made freshly on the day of delivery. And all packaging is environmentally friendly. Please email Rhys on DaffodilBach@gmail.com or telephone 07947715435 to place your orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I dropped into The Haven to meet my dear friend Major Mary Wolfe, her successor Major Neil Duquemin, and Skills Coordinator Christina Davies. On the day of my visit, The Haven had provided 48 Christmas lunches to their regular clients, but their door is always open to anyone who wants to call in and have a substantial breakfast for 50 pence, and a choice of lunch for a pound. On Wednesdays, agencies are based in The Haven for the day to offer help and advice, including Citizens Advice, the Wallich, Medical Staff, and Jobcentre Plus. Christina delivers skills courses including “budgeting on benefits”, and “cooking on a limited income”. My heartfelt thanks to Mary, Neil, Christina and all the volunteers who give up their time everyday for the homeless and people in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2714"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2714" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/F5AD216A-2D09-4C5D-A382-D5F671130946-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It was an absolute delight to meet the winner of my Christmas Card 2022 Competition Caitlin Vaughan, aged 6, and her mother Hannah. Thank you to all the children who sent in their designs. It is always a very difficult task to select a winner, but Caitlin’s card was exceptional for one so young. Special mention for Gorazd Trajkovski from Skopje, Macedonia, aged 10 who won the International Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2715"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2715" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/8E3138C3-FA2C-4191-A3BE-698499C533AB-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On the last day in the Neath Office, I took my wonderful Neath Office staff for Christmas lunch. This is our first Christmas lunch since the onset of the pandemic in 2020. My I take this opportunity to wish all my constituents a very merry Christmas and a happy, healthy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2716"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2716" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/BB5F61DE-C53B-4E60-98D7-9EC5CC5EE178-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2711</id>
    <published>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</updated>
    <category term="My Weekly Round-up"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Royal British Legion Christmas Support Line</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/21/royal-british-legion-christmas-support-line/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Royal British Legion are keen for members of the Armed Forces community to know that they are here for them over Christmas. Pressures of life are often exacerbated during the festive season, with feelings of loneliness and isolation and financial worries increased. The Royal British Legion are here to offer assistance, companionship, and a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/21/royal-british-legion-christmas-support-line/">Royal British Legion Christmas Support Line</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5086</id>
    <published>2022-12-21T13:44:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T13:44:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-up :: 22 December 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/21/weekly-round-up-22-december-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-22-december-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>In the immortal words of Noddy Holder, “it’s Christmas!” or at least it nearly is. This is a special time of year for many as people come together to celebrate with family, friends and even the odd works party. </p>
<p>But before we wrap up this year’s round-up it would be a good time to look back on the year that was. To say that 2022 has been able to cram in more happenings than many would be an understatement. As the saying goes, you wait for a Prime Minister and three come along at once… or is that buses?</p>
<p>So where better to start that with the disastrous tenure of Liz Truss – Britain’s shortest serving Prime Minister of all time. During her term in office, she achieved a run on the pound, your mortgages to increase by over £500 a year and inflation ramping up to levels not seen since the Winter of Discontent in the 1970s. I took part in debates around the Mini-Budget, the Tory trigger for this chaos, pointing out how you cannot have something for nothing. I also raised the spectre of a Winter Crisis in the NHS never seen before. Sadly, this also has come to pass.</p>
<p>Rewind a few more months and we can see where the foundations for this government that refuses to govern was laid: Boris Johnson. The former Prime Minister’s erosion of rules and principles that governed the UK Government left the country rudderless and open to further political corruption. The Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee, of which I’m a member, has been undertaking many investigations into this issue. Indeed, one of our meetings hauled the then Prime Minister’s ‘independent’ advisors on ethics before us. Only a couple of days later did he resign when it became clear that his position was untenable.</p>
<p>As a former NHS employee, I have spent this year raising my deep concern that the failures we are seeing in the health service were set before the pandemic struck. If retention rates had been maintained at even 2011 levels, we would have had 10,000 more staff than we do currently. This issue is worsened by a social care system that is on its knees. The Government promised social care reform earlier this year, but then u-turned during the financial statement designed to mop up the fallout of the Mini-Budget. More families have been put in precarious positions because of this inability to lead.</p>
<p>The cost-of-living crisis is really starting to bite but we must also spare a thought for Ukrainians who have now experienced their 300th day of Russia’s war on their country. The shocking military assault that began in February has not played out the way President Putin would have liked nor how many of us would have predicted. Ukrainians have shown determination and courage in their staunch defence of their country that is inspiring to see. We must continue to support their efforts with training, military equipment, and humanitarian aid for as long as it will be necessary. For the security of the rest of Europe, Putin cannot be allowed to prevail and we must support a Ukrainian victory. I know some families in Bristol have taken in refugee families and this was also an incredible effort to witness. Slava Ukraini! </p>
<p>As much as the Tories in Westminster are hellbent on undermining everything that is good about our country there are some glimmers of light locally. We held another amazing Apprenticeship Fair in the constituency that matched young and not so young to exciting new careers. This was the first full in-person fair since the pandemic and it was brilliant to see so many people and businesses working together to deliver for Bristol.</p>
<p>I was also able to spend this year providing Maternity Leave cover for my colleague Liz Kendal MP as Shadow Health minister. This allowed me to meet many wonderful people in the care sector and to speak up on their behalf in Parliament. I’m determined to see fundamental reform taken with social care to ensure families don’t face the misery of not knowing where their loved one will be supported. We can achieve so much more if we focus on the workforce and training routes into this wonderful career.</p>
<p>This will be the last weekly round-up of 2022. My next round-up will start when Parliament sits in the New Year.  Whatever you are doing over this festive period I wish you and yours a wonderful time.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/21/weekly-round-up-22-december-2022/">Weekly Round-up :: 22 December 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In the immortal words of Noddy Holder, “it’s Christmas!” or at least it nearly is. This is a special time […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/21/weekly-round-up-22-december-2022/">Weekly Round-up :: 22 December 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3401</id>
    <published>2022-12-21T12:22:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T12:22:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PM ACCUSED OF ‘IGNORING THE WARNINGS’ ON £6.7B WASTED ON COVID FRAUD</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/pm-accused-of-ignoring-the-warnings-on-6-7b-wasted-on-covid-fraud/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine questioned the Prime Minister over the failure to prevent and tackle Covid fraud, during his time as Chancellor and Prime Minister. Catherine questioned the Prime Minister during the Liaison Committee hearing on Tuesday 20th December, the exchange is below. Catherine McKinnell: I appreciate that you cannot comment on ongoing legal proceedings, but do you … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/pm-accused-of-ignoring-the-warnings-on-6-7b-wasted-on-covid-fraud/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">PM ACCUSED OF ‘IGNORING THE WARNINGS’ ON £6.7B WASTED ON COVID FRAUD</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7823</id>
    <published>2022-12-21T12:14:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T12:14:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="Covid"/>
    <category term="economy"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Southfield School leads the way in their teaching of over 80 pupils with learning difficulties via the priority they give to communication, self-regulation and independence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps had the pleasure of meeting both teachers and pupils to see the achievements of the school and thank the staff for their tireless and crucial work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I am very grateful for all the work the staff do for the school and their pupils” Mr Shapps commented, “and I know that my gratitude is shared both by parents and the wider community”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The teachers thanked Mr Shapps for his visit and expressed their gratitude to him for his support with the headteacher, Angela O’Rourke, saying:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The pupils and the staff very much enjoyed having Mr Shapps on the site and were thrilled to be able to share with him the incredible role that Team Southfield play in the lives of our children. We are very grateful for Mr Shapps making the time for us”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/"&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/">&lt;strong&gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&lt;/strong&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=46138</id>
    <published>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP celebrates Christmas in Fulmer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Always love stopping by the Black Horse at Christmas time.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer</id>
    <published>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Card Competition 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/christmas-card-competition-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> Following on from the success of my last two Christmas Card Competitions, I wrote to the Headteachers of all of our primary schools in Broadland to ask them to help me find the best young artists, again!
 There were lots of great entries but I eventually came to settle on a winner and a runner up…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/christmas-card-competition-2022</id>
    <published>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Go With The FLOW</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/go-with-the-flow/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3235</id>
    <published>2022-12-19T11:26:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-19T11:26:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="FLOW"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Article on Space in Scotland</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I was recently invited to write an article showcasing the space sector in Prestwick and Scotland for <em>House</em> magazine. </p>



<p>You can read the article <a href="https://library.myebook.com/thehouse/destination-space/4526/#page/8" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;title=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/" data-a2a-title="Article on Space in Scotland"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Article on Space in Scotland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was recently invited to write an article showcasing the space sector in Prestwick and ... <a title="Article on Space in Scotland" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Article on Space in Scotland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2667</id>
    <published>2022-12-16T11:52:14Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-16T11:52:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Central Ayrshire at Westminster"/>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="space sector; SpacePort"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Upate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update on the support being provided locally for those struggling with energy bills this winter, particularly now that things have turned colder.</p>
<h2>Epsom &amp; Ewell Energy Support Scheme</h2>
<p>Firstly, the Epsom and Ewell Energy Support scheme has been making great progress. I am grateful to all of you who have supported the appeal, which is to help those who are struggling with bills to make their homes more energy efficient. The scheme is in operation across the whole of the constituency, including Epsom and Ewell Borough, plus the Nork and Tattenhams area on Epsom Downs and in Ashtead and Leatherhead.</p>
<p>So far the appeal has raised around £36,000 and the money is already making a huge difference. The money is being used by the Good Company, which runs local food banks, and Citizens Advice in Epsom to help people reduce their bills.</p>
<p>The Good Company has been running a package of support for those needing help, including free energy advice – delivered by an expert adviser from Surrey Community Action – and energy saving appliances to help reduce their energy usage, as well as a gas/electricity top-up to help relieve the immediate financial pressure on them. All of the money you have contributed has been used to provide the top-up and energy saving appliances like air fryers, heated drying racks and LED light bulbs. In total they have helped around 250 people so far.</p>
<p>The response from those being helped has been really positive. This is one example:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>“The workshop was so helpful and we would definitely want to come to any more you have, so useful, and you’re all so nice! The electric drying rail would be amazing, thank you so much. And the hooded blankets sound great. Really appreciate all the support you guys are giving out.”</em><br/>
<em>(Maria, group workshop)</em></p>
<p>Citizens Advice have also been providing top-ups for those struggling with bills, and then providing energy saving advice and lower cost appliances. They say that air fryers are by far the most popular option and have been their biggest means of help so far. One of the people they helped said he felt “stronger, more in control and more able to cope with future problems.”</p>
<p>I am again really grateful to those who have helped out. The scheme aims to get those people who do not need the £400 top up being provided for bills this winter by the Government to contribute it to the fund instead. If you are in that position and have not yet supported the scheme, please do consider doing so now.</p>
<p>You can donate via this Justgiving page, which also has more details about the scheme.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme">www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme</a></strong></p>
<h2>Warm Hubs</h2>
<p>Secondly there is now a county-wide network of warm hubs which provide people who are worried about their bills with a place to go during the day if they need one. Several of our local churches are taking part as well as some other organisations. I am really grateful to all those who are doing so.</p>
<p>There is a full list of all the venues and when they are open on the Surrey website, and you can access the detail via this link.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="www.surreycc.gov.uk/health-and-welfare/support/welfare-support/everyday-living/warm-hubs/list-of-warm-hubs-in-surrey">www.surreycc.gov.uk/health-and-welfare/support/welfare-support/everyday-living/warm-hubs/list-of-warm-hubs-in-surrey</a></strong></p>
<h2>Pension Credit</h2>
<p>If you are retired and living off the state pension alone or are on a low income you may be entitled to pension credit. The Government is running a campaign to help people understand more about what they may be entitled to. There is also an extra cost of living payment of £324 available for people entitled to pension credit, but you need to apply before December 18th. The details are here.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="gov.uk/pension-credit/how-to-claim">gov.uk/pension-credit/how-to-claim</a></strong></p>
<p>There is more information here available from the charity Independent Age.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.independentage.org/get-advice/advice-guides-factsheets-leaflets">https://www.independentage.org/get-advice/advice-guides-factsheets-leaflets</a></strong></p>
<h2>Citizens Advice Volunteers</h2>
<p>Finally thank you to all of those who came to my volunteer fair in October and particular to those who have signed up as volunteers.</p>
<p>Citizens Advice have asked me to advertise the fact that they are still looking for a retired lawyer to help them co-ordinate their work with local firms providing pro bono support for people in difficulties. They have also asked me to say that they are short of volunteers to help with the energy support scheme and a range of other roles, and if you would like to help there are details at <strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="www.caee.org.uk/volunteer/">www.caee.org.uk/volunteer/</a></strong></p>
<p>Best wishes</p>
<p>Chris Grayling</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/">Local Upate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update on the support being provided locally for those struggling with energy bills this winter, particularly now that things have turned colder. Epsom &amp; Ewell Energy Support Scheme Firstly, the Epsom and Ewell Energy Support scheme has been making great progress. I am grateful to all [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/">Local Upate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6366</id>
    <published>2022-12-15T15:03:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-15T15:03:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A major step forward to unlock islands renewables potential says Isles MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/15/a-major-step-forward-to-unlock-islands-renewables-potential-says-isles-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says today’s announcement that approval has been granted from energy regulator Ofgem for the need to build a 1.8GW interconnector to export renewable energy from the Western Isles to the mainland grid is a major step forward.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil has continually lobbied for the interconnector and today’s announcement is a long-awaited breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil said: “This has been the work of many years and is extremely welcome news for Na h-Eileanan an Iar. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This opens up the islands to fulfil its renewable energy potential bringing massive benefits to the islands’ economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For so long we wanted Ofgem to green light a 600MW connection and they were insisting on 450WM. &amp;nbsp;Now Ofgem have green lighted a 1.8GW connector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Years have been lost and things could be a lot better had this been built years ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As it is, construction is expected to be ongoing in 2025/26 with the project finished in 2030.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/20221125_115626-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="4078" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/20221125_115626-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,1362" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G780F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1669377386&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00091996320147194&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;58.189085452778&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-6.3795056&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="20221125_115626" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4078" width="904" height="616" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says today’s announcement that approval has been granted from energy regulator Ofgem …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/15/a-major-step-forward-to-unlock-islands-renewables-potential-says-isles-mp/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4075</id>
    <published>2022-12-15T12:00:04Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-15T12:00:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Investment in Ashford </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-investment-ashford" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is my last column before Christmas, so I am going to be resolutely cheerful, as we could all do with some cheer at the end of a year which has been difficult in so many different ways.
As it happens, despite the continuing problems on the roads in and around the town, there have been a number…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-investment-ashford</id>
    <published>2022-12-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tragic Incident in the English Channel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/tragic-incident-in-the-english-channel/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Wednesday this week we received the tragic news of deaths in the Channel after a small boat carrying migrants to the UK got into difficulties. This follows a similar incident just over a year ago when 27 people drowned in just one day. I would like to thank the Coastguard, RNLI Lifeboats, the police, […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kieran Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6195</id>
    <published>2022-12-14T14:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-14T14:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas 2022 Office Hours</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
	&lt;div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " &gt;
		&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Due to the festive break, my office will close from 23 December &amp;#8211;  3 January. From 3rd January, my team and I will be here to help you with any issue you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be periodically checking my email and voicemail over Christmas and the New Year, so if you have a very urgent query you can contact me as below. All other correspondence will be dealt with on our return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a very urgent query, please email details to &lt;a href="mailto:abrahamsd@parliament.uk"&gt;abrahamsd@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;. If you do not have access to emails, you can call &amp;amp; leave a voicemail regarding your urgent matter with details on 0161 624 4248 or 0207 219 1041&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other enquiries will be dealt with when the office re-opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team and I would like to wish you all a very Merry Christmas and a happy &amp;amp; healthy 2023!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debbie Abrahams MP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham East &amp;amp; Saddleworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful contacts/information for the festive period:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Cost of Living support &amp;#8211; &lt;em&gt;https://www.oldham.gov.uk/wecanhelp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Metropolitan Borough Council Helpline &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 7007&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welfare Support &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 6655&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(www.oldham.gov.uk/welfarerights)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizens Advice Oldham &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0808 278 7803&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Credit support &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0800 144 8444&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get Oldham Working &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 4674&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Foodbank &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 7007&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(www.oldham.foodbank.org.uk)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Credit Union &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 678 7245&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm Homes Scheme &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0800 019 1084&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Emergency 24 hour homelessness team: &lt;strong&gt;0800 988 7061&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social services (out of hours emergency only) –  &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 6936&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council First Response team – &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 2222&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police General Switchboard (24 hours) – &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police emergencies (24 hours) – &lt;strong&gt;999&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical emergencies:  visit your local &lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/service-search" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hospital&lt;/a&gt; or call 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-urgent medical advice – &lt;strong&gt;111&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas (24 hour emergency helpline) – &lt;strong&gt;0800 111 999&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity North West (24 hour emergency helpline) – &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Utilities website and details &lt;a href="https://www.unitedutilities.com/emergencies/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater Manchester Law Centre: &lt;strong&gt;0161 769 2244&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcho.co.uk/contact-us/ways-to-contact-us/"&gt;First Choice Homes Oldham &amp;#8211; Multiple contacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_empty_space"   style="height: 20px" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_empty_space_inner"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"&gt;&lt;h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;"&gt;Feel strongly about this article? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"&gt;&lt;a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact"&gt;Contact Debbie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/"&gt;Christmas 2022 Office Hours&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk"&gt;Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/">Christmas 2022 Office Hours</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7072</id>
    <published>2022-12-14T09:18:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-14T09:18:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Christmas"/>
    <category term="Office"/>
    <category term="Opening"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Human Rights Day 2022: Launch of the All-Party Parliamentary Group for International Law, Justice and Accountability]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/12/11/human-rights-day-2022-launch-of-the-all-party-parliamentary-group-for-international-law-justice-and-accountability/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10673</id>
		<updated>2022-12-11T11:23:41Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-11T11:22:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[December 10th marks the 74th anniversary of the adoption of one of the most important documents of our times, the United Nations’ universal declaration of human rights. Although it is the most translated document in the world, and is currently available in 500 languages, I sincerely wish more people had read it. The harsh and ... <a title="Human Rights Day 2022: Launch of the All-Party Parliamentary Group for International Law, Justice and Accountability" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/12/11/human-rights-day-2022-launch-of-the-all-party-parliamentary-group-for-international-law-justice-and-accountability/" aria-label="More on Human Rights Day 2022: Launch of the All-Party Parliamentary Group for International Law, Justice and Accountability">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Heart Hero awards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/12/07/green-heart-hero-awards/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7576</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Surgery Waiting List]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1716</id>
		<updated>2022-12-07T14:48:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-12T14:44:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bolton Hospital"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="cancer"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="healthcare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="NHS"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Surgery"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett continues campaign against Southeastern timetable changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford, is continuing to campaign for changes to the new Southeastern railway timetable, which will be implemented from Sunday 11 December.
To date, Sir David has held meetings with Southeastern Managing Director, Steve White, the Rail Minister,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Card Competition 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over the last few weeks, schools across the Scottish Borders have been taking part in a Christmas Card Competition run by Rachael Hamilton MSP and I. Now it's your chance to pick the winner.
We received hundreds of fantastic designs and have now whittled them down to 12 finalists. You can see each…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/christmas</id>
    <published>2022-11-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[GIVING TUESDAY]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=469</id>
		<updated>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3358</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:46:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Constituent, Welcome to my November&#160;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&#160; Autumn Statement: Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my November&nbsp;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Autumn Statement:</h1>



<p>Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. In which he detailed how the Government intends to restore economic stability and tackle inflation.</p>



<p>Like many countries around the world, the UK is facing profound economic challenges. Supply disruption caused by the world’s economies emerging from lockdown has been compounded by Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine and deliberate interference with Europe’s energy supply to create massive increases in the cost of energy. This has led to high inflation and high interest rates across many of the world’s major economies, and the UK is no different.</p>



<p>I welcome the proposals in the Autumn Statement. To achieve long-term, sustainable growth we need to grip inflation, balance the books, and get debt falling as a share of GDP. The plan presented by the Chancellor yesterday takes the tough decisions to face up to this situation without passing the buck onto future generations. What’s more, it protects the hard-working majority by enacting no headline tax increases, and protects the most vulnerable by maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation – something I have personally been campaigning for. All while protecting and maintaining public spending for the next two years at the levels set out in 2021.</p>



<p>The plan involves a roughly equal split between tax rises and spending cuts, with the greatest burden falling on those who can afford it most. Specifically, the plan:</p>



<p><strong>Increases taxpayer funding for our NHS and schools by an extra £11 billion over the next two years.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Government will provide £4 billion in additional funding to schools and £7.7 billion in additional funding to the NHS and social care sector over the next two years. Prioritising the public services that matter most.</p>



<p>&#8211; £2–3 billion in additional funding for the NHS in each of the next two years so we can bring down ambulance waiting times, tackle the Covid backlog, and improve access to GPs. Also providing £2.8 billion next year and £4.7 billion the year after for adult social care, which aims to double the number of people leaving hospitals on time and into care by 2024, addressing unmet needs and boosting low pay in the sector.</p>



<p>&#8211; £4 billion in additional funding for schools over the next two years. We are increasing the schools budget by £2 billion this year and £2 billion next year to help schools with rising costs as a result of inflation. Which is more than Labour has pledged to give schools.</p>



<p><strong>Introduces no headline tax increases.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Autumn Statement raises £25 billion in additional taxes over the forecast period but there are no increases in the headline rates of tax. By targeting tax rises toward businesses, wealthier households, and the oil and gas industry, the Government has ensured that it can honour its manifesto commitment not to increase Income Tax, National Insurance, or VAT.</p>



<p>&#8211; Instead of raising rates, the Government is freezing personal tax thresholds for a further two years. There are also reforms to the Additional Rate threshold, so that a taxpayer who earns more than £150,000 will pay £1,200 more in tax per year.</p>



<p>&#8211; It is only fair that companies who have made genuine windfall profits as a result of the war in Ukraine make an additional contribution to pay for the support we have outlined. So from 2023, the Energy Profits Levy rate will rise from 25per cent to 35per cent and will continue until the end of March 2028. A 45per cent Levy will be applied to extraordinary returns made by electricity generators. In total these windfall taxes will raise £52 billion over six years. This is more ambitious than Labour’s proposal.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting and maintaining public spending.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; For the next two years public spending will remain at the levels set out in 2021 and then increase by one per cent in real terms each year until 2027–28.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting every household with their energy bills.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Energy Price Guarantee will continue to support everyone for another year. This winter, the price households pay for the energy they use will be capped, so that a typical household will pay £2,500. From April 2023, the price cap will rise so that a typical household will pay £3,000. The Energy Price Guarantee will then end in April 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting the most vulnerable through maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; I have been publicly campaigning for benefits and pensions to be increased in line with inflation for some time now, and so was very pleased to see the Chancellor yesterday confirm that this would be part of the Government’s plan.</p>



<p>&#8211; To protect the most vulnerable, benefits will now be increased in line with inflation for 2023–24. More than 10 million households in receipt of working-age and disability benefits will see an increase in their benefit payments.</p>



<p>&#8211; The pensions triple lock will also be protected. Because of the difficult but necessary decisions the Government has taken elsewhere, the triple lock for pensions will be protected in full. This means that in April, the State Pension will increase in line with inflation, which is the biggest cash increase in the State Pension ever.</p>



<p><strong>Additional support for the most vulnerable.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Over £12 billion of additional targeted support is assigned to help the most vulnerable households. The Government will continue providing this year’s cost of living payments and next year it will provide extra one-off payments of £900 for the 8 million households on means-tested benefits, £300 to pensioners, and £150 for disability benefit recipients. The Government is also providing £1 billion of extra funding by extending the Household Support Fund for another year.</p>



<p>The OBR has confirmed that these plans will restore the public finances to a sustainable position and help reduce inflation and unemployment. And I look forward to engaging with my ministerial colleagues as these policies are rolled out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Remembrance Sunday:</h1>



<p>This year for Remembrance Sunday on 13th November, I was honoured to lay wreaths in Ripley and Kilburn in memory of those who have served our county, and in honour of those who are still serving. There are a multitude of remembrance services held across our constituency every year, so it is unfortunately impossible for me to attend all of them. However, every year I try to rotate which services I attend. This year it was a memorial service at Ripley War Memorial in the morning and another in Kilburn in the afternoon.</p>



<p>This has been a particularly important period of remembrance as we mark 40 years since the end of the Falkland’s war, and we commemorate the 255 British personnel who lost their lives in defence of the islands. Their courage and sacrifice must never be forgotten. Thank you to everyone who organised or supported the remembrance services and parades across Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Alfreton Solar Farm Update:</h1>



<p>On 21st October, I spoke at the public inquiry into plans from Kronos Solar to build a 50-megawatt solar farm between Alfreton and Oakerthorpe. Many of you will remember that Amber Valley Borough Council’s (AVBC) planning authorities rejected the proposal last December, stating that the project’s scale and impact on the landscape outweighed any environmental benefits the site would provide. However, Kronos Solar have since filed an appeal to overturn the decision of AVBC and get the site approved, resulting in this enquiry.</p>



<p>I have been opposing the project on behalf of local residents and businesses throughout the process, a great many of whom have contacted me about the proposals. I very much support the expansion of our clean energy network, and in the right place a solar farm would be an asset. However, there are good reasons why this site was refused planning permission. We all want renewable energy expansion but not at any cost.</p>



<p>To begin with, much of the land is north facing, which means the site would need to be overly large. The impact on the amenity of local residents, the impact on the countryside area, and the impact on the various heritage assets is just too great. And that is before we consider Alfreton Park and Alfreton Park Community School, which looks after children with the very highest level of need, very close in the vicinity.</p>



<p>It is clear to me that this is a totally unsuitable site for this intensity of development. Frankly, I believe this proposal was not based on a thorough search for suitable land for a solar farm, instead, it looks to me to be based on a search for a suitable sub-station, with the proposal then trying to force some land to suit.</p>



<p>I will continue to keep residents updated on any developments. And at present, a decision is expected at some point in the next few months.</p>



<h1>Pollution and our waterways:</h1>



<p>I have recently welcomed the Department for Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs’ (DEFRA) plans to raise the civil penalty for water companies who pollute our environment by one thousand times, from £250,000 up to £250 million. I am hopeful that increasing the penalties the Environment Agency can enforce without a lengthy and costly court process will enable swifter and stronger action to be taken against water companies that illegally pollute our environment.</p>



<p>Many residents have contacted me about pollution and the use of storm drains in our sewage system. There has also been a great deal of misinformation circulating on social media regarding the Government’s campaign to address these issues.</p>



<p>Last year, the Government introduced the Environment Act 2021 which was a bill designed to tackle this problem and reduce sewage pollution ignored by previous Governments. When the Environment Act was going through Parliament the Duke of Wellington, a hereditary peer, introduced an amendment that would legislate the complete elimination of storm drains and therefore of storm overflow sewage into our waterways. This of course sounds admirable, and indeed is something I support in principle. However, this amendment came without a plan for how it could be delivered and how such a vast project could be funded.</p>



<p>Initial assessments suggested elimination would cost between £150 &#8211; £650 billion. To put those figures in perspective, £150 billion was more than the entire schools, policing, and defence budgets put together. Therefore, the Government did not support the amendment, and I did not vote for it. In my view, the last thing people wanted was for their water bill to go through the roof.</p>



<p>Twitter mis-informers seized this opportunity and claimed we had all voted in favour of water companies dumping raw sewage into our rivers. Which was totally false, and ironically punished the Government for actually trying to do something about the problem ignored by previous Governments.</p>



<p>With this most recent announcement by DEFRA, I am glad to see the Government continuing the campaign to improve the quality of our waterways. To hold water companies to account, and ensure any polluter pays for the environmental harm they cause, the Environment Agency must take advantage of these new powers.</p>



<h1>Illegal crossings over the Channel:</h1>



<p>Many of you have contacted me about the number of small boats illegally crossing the English Channel in recent months. I appreciate the strength of feeling on this alarming issue and want to outline my position to you and explain some of the challenges we face in tackling this problem.</p>



<p>The number of illegal entries into the United Kingdom via small boats crossing the English Channel is too high. It endangers the lives of those making the journey, puts money into the pockets of ruthless and brutal people smuggling gangs, and puts undue pressure on our existing asylum system as well as our public services. I remain committed to an immigration policy that welcomes people to the UK through safe and legal routes, and an immigration policy that allows us to provide asylum to those in genuine need. However, it is clear many of those arriving in small boats are not here in genuine need of asylum, and as a result, the current situation cannot go on.</p>



<p>One reason for small boat crossings increasing in frequency is the success the Government has had in tackling other forms of illegal immigration. Such as increased checks and security for lorries and freight crossing the channel, effectively reducing the number of illegal entries into the UK through these means, and increasing the number of people turning to small boats as a way to enter the UK. The problem that now presents itself is how to police and secure hundreds of miles of coastline 24/7.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Parliament passed the Nationality and Borders Act which overhauled our approach to asylum and illegal migration. The legislation includes fairness towards those who need our help, and in welcoming people through safe and legal routes, but firmness in tackling abuse of the system and expediting the removal of those who have no legitimate claim for protection. It is worth noting that Labour opposed this Act designed to toughen our immigration system.</p>



<p>Further to changing the law in this country, the Government has recently signed a joint UK-France arrangement on tackling small boat crossings in the Channel which includes a 40% increase in the number of UK-funded officers patrolling French beaches. The new agreement lays the foundations for deeper UK-French co-operation to tackle illegal migration. The arrangement means, for the first time, specialist UK officers will be able to observe French officials at work in control rooms and on the ground patrolling the coastline.</p>



<p>It is clear, however, that big challenges still lie ahead, and that the number of small boats currently crossing the channel is unacceptable. The Prime Minister speaking recently on GB News said that tackling illegal immigration was a huge priority for his Government, and that while the recent joint UK -France arrangement was a big step in the right direction there was more that needs to be done. I share the Prime Minister’s view, and will continue engaging with my ministerial and Parliamentary colleagues to make the case for further measures to reduce cross channel migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on why Iran should be removed from UN commission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill plants a Remembrance stake in the Constituency Garden of Remembrance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday, Sir Bill Wiggin MP planted a wooden cross to pay tribute to service personnel from his constituency of North Herefordshire who have died in service to our country.  The Speaker of the House of Commons, Sir Lindsay Hoyle... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/#more-4548">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4548</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Network Rail Confirm Beckenham Junction Foot Bridge Repairs Timetable </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following pressure from Member of Parliament Bob Stewart, jointly with local Councillor Michael Tickner and London Assembly Member Peter Fortune; Network Rail have set out the timetable to replace the footbridge at Beckenham Junction. 
 
Bob, Michael and Peter wrote to Network Rail in October to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable</id>
    <published>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP secures key commitment on visas for international GPs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/11/04/matt-warman-mp-secures-key-commitment-on-visas-for-international-gps/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li>In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS.<br/>
• To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve this challenge’, for example working with the sector to explore umbrella sponsors for international GPs and holding meetings with the sector to encourage more GP surgeries to become visa sponsoring practices.</li>
</ul>
<p>On Wednesday (2nd November), a Westminster Hall debate took place in which the House<br/>
considered visas for international doctors.</p>
<p>Matt Warman MP raised the point that under current legislation, GPs who have come from abroad to train in the UK are in a position whereby it is difficult to obtain employment after they graduate. This is mainly because, in order for a General Practice to hire an international graduate, they must be registered as a ‘sponsoring practice’. This requires a large amount of complicated engagement with the Home Office, both on the international GP’s behalf and that of the practice hoping to sponsor them.</p>
<p>Following a discussion of members from different parties, the Minister for Immigration, Robert<br/>
Jenrick MP, acknowledged the issues raised and agreed to look at ways to make this process easier. The Minister assured that the Home Office will ‘reflect carefully on the points raised’ and stated that he will ‘task Home Office officials to work with stakeholders in the sector to give greater consideration to the central question of whether there is a simpler way in which GP practices can apply for relevant visas.’</p>
<p>The Minister for Immigration also pledged to ‘ask my officials to work with the sector to see whether there is a way forward to create umbrella bodies, if there is mutual support on both sides’, as well as agreeing to run further engagement events with the sector to discuss the process of becoming a sponsor.</p>
<p>Commenting on the positive outcome of this debate, Matt Warman said: <em>‘The Minister has </em><br/>
<em>demonstrated more progress on this important issue in the commitment that he has made to us </em><br/>
<em>today than we have seen in some years … I am immensely grateful to all Members who have brought the issue to life, and I look forward to continuing to work with the Minister on the outcome of the review, which will make a real difference to our constituents, and to doctors up and down the country.’</em></p>
<p>Matt will continue to liaise with the Home Office, the NHS and the Royal Colleges in order to turn this promise into action as quickly as possible.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS. • To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4133</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span class="searchHighlight">Halloween</span> is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for years, picking up speed in the past weeks and months as breathless newscasters break the news of more dark intrigue and betrayal. Make no mistake, this may look like a rollercoaster ride, but it is a dirty old carousel with the same old dangerously unfit horses going round and round in ever-decreasing circles.</p>
<p>Of course, seeing the first Asian Hindu take office is truly welcome, but this isn’t a new broom with Prime Minister Rishi Sunak. The Tories have been in office for over 12 years. He’s the ‘Party gate Chancellor” who broke his own laws. He isn’t going to make things better; he’s continuing their long-running austerity programme, degrading public services and growing food bank dependency. As a Brexiteer, he happily wedded us all to the deeply toxic Brexit ideology harming our businesses, starving them of vital staff and turbocharging inflation – especially basic food items, now running at up to 60% more.</p>
<p>Westminster’s hall of mirrors also shows Labour wedded to “make Brexit work”. It’s a nonsensical stance that, hand in hand with their stated belief that the Tories are not deporting enough people quickly enough is a chilling reflection.</p>
<p>And just when you thought that one of the most frightening apparitions had been removed, it is back where it was. Suella Braverman, the Home Secretary, whose dream is *not* of a brighter future for families, or a reduced skills shortage or even an end to people trafficking. No, it is her stated “dream and obsession” to see a flight take asylum seekers to Rwanda. Sacked only 6 days earlier having broken the ministerial code, she is back in the job tasked with upholding law and order and breached national security. She is back alongside colleagues at the helm of the ghostly pirate ship that is the Tory Government.</p>
<p>It’s a horror show we should be done with. The UK is substantially poorer than independent counties comparable to Scotland, with wider inequality, higher child and pensioner poverty and lower productivity. It is time for Scotland to choose a better path.</p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Halloween is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6525</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/september-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5588" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" data-type="URL" data-id="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for September 2022.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for September 2022.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5587</id>
    <published>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="September"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=V9wDfpUx" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-63bd05e24fd1a" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-63bd05e24fd1a').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"63bd05e24fd1a","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-63bd05e24fd1a" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-63bd05e24fd1a" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="63bd05e24fd1a" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_63bd05e24fd1a" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_63bd05e24fd1a" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_63bd05e24fd1a" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_63bd05e24fd1a" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_63bd05e24fd1a" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_63bd05e24fd1a" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_63bd05e24fd1a_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-63bd05e24fd1a script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dyQQ5cIJ3Otn3h49xaZy1PC02Zp0AOLUBEg8r0-iCawXNgevZXX0NiBzYKRd7t5EwrPjsCXPeM7G5J7wqBfng' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
