<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-03-06T21:33:09Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Central Banks are not independent and often get it wrong</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/03/06/32357/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Please see below the slides from my lecture at All Souls College, Oxford, titled ‘There is no Independent Central Bank’:</p>
<p><strong>Slide 1 – Three common propositions</strong></p>
<p>The main Central Banks are independent.</p>
<p>They are staffed and led by experts in economies and markets which means they will get it right.</p>
<p>Were the politicians and government departments to have more of a role in the conduct of monetary policy it would be badly run.</p>
<p>The last 30 years experience demonstrates all three of these propositions are false.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 2 –  Policy changes affecting the Bank of England</strong></p>
<p>1997 – The Bank of England is said to be made independent. It loses control of regulation of individual major banks to the FCA. It ceases to issue UK government debt which is given to the Treasury.</p>
<p>1998 – new Bank of England Act to confirm changes and keep Bank of England under Parliamentary control and supervision.</p>
<p>2003 – Chancellor of the Exchequer changes target for inflation from RPI at 2.5% to CPI at 2%, a looser target.</p>
<p>2008 – Chancellor of Exchequer overrides Bank of England interest rate setting, ordering a reduction in rates as part of a concerted G7 action to rescue collapsing markets.</p>
<p>2012 – New government legislates again through the Financial Service Act, confirming Treasury powers of direction over the Bank in Part 4.</p>
<p>Chancellor signs off successive programmes of Quantitative easing which are under joint control.</p>
<p>Treasury guarantees Bank of England balance sheet risks in bond portfolio.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 3</strong></p>
<p>The government plays politics with the Bank and the Bank plays politics for the government.</p>
<p>The government exercises its right to select a new Governor of the Bank when needed and uses the appointment process to employ someone compatible with their aims.</p>
<p>The Bank usually keeps its economic forecasts close to those of the Office of Budget Responsibility and Treasury, despite these often being wrong.</p>
<p>The Bank backed Remain heavily in the referendum campaign, producing forecasts that were so one sided it lost a lot of support from the majority Leave side.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 4 </strong></p>
<p>The Fed has a dual mandate to support employment and keep inflation below target.</p>
<p>The Fed Chairman has to report regularly to Congress and is therefore under pressure to respond to their priorities.</p>
<p>The Administration appoints the Board members, subject to ratification by Congress.</p>
<p>The Biden Administration is busily appointing Board members that reflect Democrat priorities.</p>
<p>President Trump took the Fed on in  public and forced a change of policy from monetary tightening to promotion of growth.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 5</strong></p>
<p>The ECB does not have a single country sovereign to report to, which could make it more independent.</p>
<p>However in practice it is very conscious that it is a major driver of European Union and therefore has to be  very political to assist integration.</p>
<p>ECB President Draghi’s ‘’Do whatever it takes’’ saved the Euro and Eurozone.</p>
<p>The ECB’s development of the Target 2 balances system has allowed the big cash transfers needed within the Eurozone without them going through a much bigger EU budget.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 6</strong></p>
<p>The Bank of Japan works closely with the Japanese government.</p>
<p>Its long standing QE programme and low rates has been part of the government’s 3 arrows policy to boost the economy.</p>
<p>It has continuously failed to get inflation up to 2%.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 7</strong></p>
<p>The Peoples Bank of China makes clear in all its policy statements it is an arm of government</p>
<p>It openly supports the thought and policies of President Xi</p>
<p>It takes direction from  the Communist party representative on its Board and fits into the successive government Plans.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 8</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gdp-1.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-32358" src="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gdp-1.png" alt="" width="452" height="320" srcset="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gdp-1.png 550w, https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/gdp-1-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 452px) 100vw, 452px"/></a></p>
<p><a href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GDP-2.png"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-32359" src="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GDP-2.png" alt="" width="455" height="321" srcset="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GDP-2.png 563w, https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/GDP-2-300x212.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 455px) 100vw, 455px"/></a></p>
<p><strong>Slide 9 – Current inflation rate against 2% target</strong></p>
<p>USA  – 7.5%</p>
<p>Eurozone – 5.8%</p>
<p>UK – 5.5%</p>
<p>Japan – 0.5%</p>
<p><strong>Slide 10 – Three major economic disasters inspired by Central Bank advice and thinking 1990-2021</strong></p>
<p>a) The Exchange Rate Mechanism collapse 1992</p>
<p>b) The Great Depression and banking collapse 2007-9</p>
<p>c) The Euro crises 2011-14</p>
<p>And now the Big inflation 2021-3</p>
<p><strong>Slide 11</strong></p>
<p>The consequences of political intervention have been mixed. Clearly Turkish override of the Central Bank and changes of Head have led directly to currency collapse and rapid inflation. Governments have debauched currencies in countries like Venezuela, Argentina, Zimbabwe where central Banks have not been able to exert more control.</p>
<p>In western societies the political intervention in the 2008 banking crash turned round the disastrous situation the Central Banks had created by deflating their bubble too quickly</p>
<p>President Trump was probably right that Quantitative tightening was too tough when he talked the Fed into a more neutral policy</p>
<p>Governments were right to encourage Central Banks to be very accommodative as an offset to lockdowns during the intense period of the pandemic</p>
<p>It is clearly true that governments are more likely to intervene helpfully when Central Banks are being too tough than when they are being too easy and risking too much inflation.</p>
<p><strong>Slide 12 – Why do Central Banks often get it wrong?</strong></p>
<p>The Western Banks base their work on a model of output and capacity. These concepts are flawed and difficult to measure in a complex globalised economy.</p>
<p>The Banks are too influenced by the consensus. The consensus rarely spots turning points.</p>
<p>The people on Bank Committees rarely have superior insights into markets.</p>
<p>Seeking judgements by Committees rarely gets it right, as Committees tend to an average or blended view. Often in markets you need to choose between two more extreme options to get it right.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Please see below the slides from my lecture at All Souls College, Oxford, titled ‘There is no Independent Central Bank’: Slide 1 – Three common propositions The main Central Banks are independent. They are staffed and led by experts in economies and markets which means they will get it right. Were the politicians and government…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=32357</id>
    <published>2022-03-06T05:00:01Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-06T05:00:01Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Edinburgh becomes a Queen’s Green Canopy 'Champion City'</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13434/edinburgh-becomes-a-queen-s-green-canopy-champion-city-" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">1270 trees have been planted in Stenhouse. </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13434/edinburgh-becomes-a-queen-s-green-canopy-champion-city-</id>
    <published>2022-03-05T17:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-05T17:30:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Really proud to see huge generosity from our community, as Stevenage Stands with Ukraine. Please donate support direct to the group</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1974-really-proud-to-see-huge-generosity-from-our-community-as-stevenage-stands-with-ukraine-please-donate-support-direct-to-the-group"/>
		<published>2022-03-05T15:14:24+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-05T15:14:24+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1974-really-proud-to-see-huge-generosity-from-our-community-as-stevenage-stands-with-ukraine-please-donate-support-direct-to-the-group</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Really proud to see huge generosity from our community, as Stevenage Stands with Ukraine. Amazing group set up to support our Ukrainian friends. Please donate &amp;amp; support directly to this group as we can get your donations to those who need them. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iHptTrVcFd"&gt;https://t.co/iHptTrVcFd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/RBFwaPzT9O"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RBFwaPzT9O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1500126015439392774?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 5, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Really proud to see huge generosity from our community, as Stevenage Stands with Ukraine. Amazing group set up to support our Ukrainian friends. Please donate &amp;amp; support directly to this group as we can get your donations to those who need them. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iHptTrVcFd"&gt;https://t.co/iHptTrVcFd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/RBFwaPzT9O"&gt;pic.twitter.com/RBFwaPzT9O&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1500126015439392774?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 5, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE BACKS FAIRTRADE FORTNIGHT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-fairtrade-fortnight/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Newcastle North MP Catherine McKinnell has reaffirmed her commitment to Fairtrade Fortnight during an event in Westminster. Catherine is a proud and passionate supporter of the fairtrade movement, as campaigning on this issue is how she first became involved in politics as a student. This year, Fairtrade Fortnight raises awareness of the need to protect … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-fairtrade-fortnight/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE BACKS FAIRTRADE FORTNIGHT</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7610</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T14:51:26Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T14:51:26Z</updated>
    <category term="Environment &amp; Animal Welfare"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="International Development"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mid Norfolk Ukraine appeal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/mid-norfolk-ukraine-appeal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2337" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">4 March 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Mid Norfolk Ukraine appeal</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>My thoughts are with the Ukraine people and their president, who’s defiance, courage, and patriotism in the face of foreign aggression is inspiring.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>That is why I was delighted to see and hear the constituents of Mid Norfolk have rallied round to support the people of Ukraine with their donations. <span><span>Hundreds of people have been donating essential supplies at collection points in the town, including at the Morrisons supermarket and the Railway Tavern on Yaxham Road.   </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>I look forward to supporting similar efforts moving forward.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p> </p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>To find out more please click:</span></span></span></span> <a href="https://www.derehamtimes.co.uk/news/dereham-response-to-ukraine-appeal-8726756">https://www.derehamtimes.co.uk/news/dereham-response-to-ukraine-appeal-8726756</a> </span></span></span></p>

<p> </p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2337 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T13:48:50Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T13:48:50Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/03/04/weekly-round-up-19/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-19" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="fb-root"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to join the British-Irish Parliamentary Assembly at the start of the week for one of our biannual plenary meetings. After the restrictions of Covid, it was good to meet with so many colleagues in person. Together we condemn Putin’s invasion of and war on Ukraine. A close working relationship is vitally important between Britain and Ireland and the UK and Ireland. We continue to stand together against violence and tyranny, and we continue to emphasise the importance of dialogue and debate over the common problems and challenges that we face. Whatever the headlines say about the Northern Ireland protocol, we in both parliaments will continue to discuss, debate, and ultimately work together to ensure peace and prosperity on both our islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to speak during questions on Health and Social care this week. The Government seem to think that there is some kind of magic staffing tree, but there is no increase in capacity, no elective recovery and no fixing of social care without an immediate and ambitious workforce plan. We have legislation in this place, and we have seen a tsunami of White Papers, but none of that includes a credible workforce plan. Given the estimated 93,000 NHS vacancies and more than 110,000 vacancies in social care, I asked the Health Secretary in Parliament this week when we could expect such a plan. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/feb/26/stressed-nhs-staff-quit-at-record-rate-of-400-a-week-fuelling-fears-over-care-quality"&gt;The Guardian have recently reported&lt;/a&gt; that around 400 workers are leaving the NHS every week in order to restore their work-life balance, with many complaining of burnout and PTSD following two years of battling with the Covid pandemic. This is completely unsustainable and we need a credible workforce plan that incorporates both hiring and retention of staff with acceptable and supportive conditions and pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of capacity and sustainability of the care system, I submitted a question to the Health and Social Care department on what recent assessments have been made of the impact on earning capacity and wellbeing of being an unpaid carer. Given the extremely challenging living crisis situation that we are facing in this country and the challenges facing the social care system, I find it unbelievable that the only assessment available is from BEIS from March 2020. The Health and Social Care Department should urgently address this issue and ensure that health plans for recovery include consideration of the role of unpaid carers and the ways in which they can be supported, financially and emotionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee questioned Michael Gove on the work of his Department for Levelling Up, Housing, and Communities. I was interested to hear from Michael Gove on the Strategy and Policy Statement for the Electoral Commission. We are concerned that the Government’s Statement could put at risk the full independence of the Electoral Commission. The Electoral Commission themselves have written to the Government to voice their concerns that such a Statement from the Government would be inconsistent with the role of an independent body and with maintaining public trust in the system. This is completely unacceptable and we must defend the role of the Electoral Commission to be entirely separate from Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleased to join a Cancer Drop In event in Parliament on the backlog that the NHS are facing with delivering diagnoses and providing treatment. The Covid pandemic hit at the worst time for the NHS: a decade of austerity had already depleted much of their resources to enable them to withstand the immense pressures and challenges that the pandemic brought. A decade of underfunding and understaffing has led to long waiting lists and a lack of investment in ageing equipment. We need an increase in treatment capacity that comes from more funding for staffing and more funding to replace equipment with the high-tech, cost-effective treatment of radiotherapy that is used in half of cancer treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know many constituents are concerned about the rise in eating disorders, indeed, in Bristol South we have seen a large increase in cases, so I visited a drop in event sponsored by Dr Agnes Ayton and Professor Gerome Breen to learn more. Dr Ayton has been leading vital research at the Oxford Health NHS Foundation Trust looking at the treatment of anorexia nervosa. One of the challenges is that people who are admitted to hospital when their condition becomes life-threatening and often involuntarily, are discharged when still malnourished. Readmission rates are as high as 50-60%. Her study suggests that providing uninterrupted care that includes integrated cognitive behaviour treatment improves outcomes and readmission rates. It’s clear that health isn’t something that is addressed in hospitals and GPs with our physical bodies; we have to take a greater holistic approach and recognise the importance of mental wellbeing in our treatments and health as a consideration across policy-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I supported Luke Pollard’s Ten Minute Rule Bill Keyham’s Law. On 12 August 2021 five people were murdered and two further people were injured in a shooting in Keyham and Ford in Plymouth. Keyham’s Law has three proposals: One, it would ban keeping pump-action weapons in homes (a pump-action weapon is fast to load and easy to use). Gun certificate holders who can demonstrate a legitimate reason for keeping these weapons in their homes who work in farming or pest control would be the only two permitted exemptions. Two, it would call for mental health concerns to be addressed by linking medical records to gun certificates. Under these proposals a person’s gun certificate would be linked to their medical records and if there were any concerns flagged about their mental health, the competent body for issuing the gun certificate would be required to review the person’s suitability for holding a gun certificate and possessing a gun. And three, it would make violent misogyny an aggravating offence. We have to do all we can to prevent such awful tragedies happening again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;The post &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/03/04/weekly-round-up-19/"&gt;Weekly Round-Up&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com"&gt;Karin Smyth&lt;/a&gt;.</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to join the British-Irish Parliamentary Assembly at the start of the week for one of our biannual […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/03/04/weekly-round-up-19/">Weekly Round-Up</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3161</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T12:44:18Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T12:44:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Weekly Round Up"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to help the people of Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/how-help-people-ukraine" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The United Kingdom stands with the people of Ukraine 
People across the country want to support those defending Ukraine and those fleeing their homes because of the invasion.
Here's how you can help: Ukraine: what you can do to help - GOV.UK (www.gov.uk)</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/how-help-people-ukraine</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ukraine: UK support</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/ukraine-uk-support" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">OUR RESPONSE TO THE SITUATION IN UKRAINE
Last updated: 15:00 Friday 4th March
The situation in Ukraine is changing constantly, but I am receiving questions from residents on how the UK is and can support Ukraine, so I thought it would be helpful to summarise actions to date.
Russia’s appalling and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/ukraine-uk-support</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Could you Support Ukrainian Refugees?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/could-you-support-ukrainian-refugees" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning I received an update from Norfolk County Council on what is being done locally to help those fleeing the tragic war in Ukraine.
The Council have stood up their Housing and People from Abroad Team using tried and tested methods to help those in need.
If you are able to offer…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/could-you-support-ukrainian-refugees</id>
    <published>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>CC</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[We must stop trading with all Russian banks]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=5741</id>
		<updated>2022-03-04T11:28:36Z</updated>
		<published>2022-03-04T11:28:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Bank"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Finance"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Putin"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Russia"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Ukraine"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the West responds to Vladimir Putin&#8217;s attack on Ukraine, he thinks he can intimidate us and avoid economic sanctions by threatening to put his forces on nuclear alert. His assault on Ukraine will fail in the end but tragically will result in the deaths of many innocent Ukrainians and young Russian conscripts, some of<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">We must stop trading with all Russian banks</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="5743" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/etienne-martin-2_k82gx9uk8-unsplash/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?fit=6000%2C4000&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="6000,4000" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?fit=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?fit=870%2C580&amp;ssl=1" width="870" height="580" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=870%2C580&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-5743" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=1024%2C683&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=1536%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=2048%2C1365&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?resize=1200%2C800&amp;ssl=1 1200w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?w=1740&amp;ssl=1 1740w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/etienne-martin-2_K82gx9Uk8-unsplash.jpg?w=2610&amp;ssl=1 2610w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>As the West responds to Vladimir Putin&#8217;s attack on Ukraine, he thinks he can intimidate us and avoid economic sanctions by threatening to put his forces on nuclear alert.</p>



<p>His assault on Ukraine will fail in the end but tragically will result in the deaths of many innocent Ukrainians and young Russian conscripts, some of whom think they&#8217;re on military manoeuvres rather than being sacrificed in a pointless war. There can only be one outcome to a nuclear exchange, mutually assured destruction (MAD).</p>



<p>Putin knows that. His generals know it and the Russian people, many of whom oppose him, know it. That&#8217;s why we must stand up to him just as John F Kennedy did with Khrushchev and the Cuban missiles back in 1962.</p>



<p>Perhaps if we&#8217;d taken a tougher line with Putin earlier, the people of Ukraine could have been spared some of the awful suffering he&#8217;s inflicting on them. We can&#8217;t acquiesce over his threats.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve got to show that we&#8217;re serious about bankrupting him, depriving Russia of all modern technology and isolating it from the civilised world.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve tolerated this dictator for too long. We&#8217;ve turned a blind eye to rigged elections in his own country and ignored attempts to undermine western democracies and interference in our elections.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve allowed London to become a playground for his rich Russian friends and our financial institutions, a haven for their dirty money.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time to call a halt. We must stop trading with all Russian banks, close our airspace, block all investment and freeze their assets.</p>



<p>This man must learn that we mean business and that his already fragile economy will collapse if he doesn&#8217;t stop this madness.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time to unite against this aggression and like Keir Starmer, I&#8217;ll back the government&#8217;s efforts to take the necessary steps. I ask one thing in return. We can&#8217;t destroy Putin and his cronies while still accepting their money.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time for the Tory party to give up its Russian donors. The interests of our country and defeating this dictator are far greater than the financial interests of any political party.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/03/04/we-must-stop-trading-with-all-russian-banks/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[EXPRESS: &#8220;Wake up or Blob will win!&#8221; John warns PM that EU red tape is holding back Brexit]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/03/03/express-wake-up-or-blob-will-win-john-warns-pm-that-eu-red-tape-is-holding-back-brexit/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5238</id>
		<updated>2022-03-03T21:51:40Z</updated>
		<published>2022-03-03T21:51:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[BREXIT needs to push the UK into pursuing a path into further deregulation to help British businesses become more competitive internationally, Tory MP John Penrose insisted. The Conservative MP insisted Boris Johnson needs to intervene to ensure one of the key benefits of Brexit is delivered. He said the UK must resume its reform scheme to remove [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/03/03/express-wake-up-or-blob-will-win-john-warns-pm-that-eu-red-tape-is-holding-back-brexit/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<p>BREXIT needs to push the UK into pursuing a path into further deregulation to help British businesses become more competitive internationally, Tory MP John Penrose insisted.</p>



<p>The Conservative MP insisted Boris Johnson needs to intervene to ensure one of the key benefits of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.express.co.uk/latest/brexit" target="_blank">Brexit</a> is delivered. He said the UK must resume its reform scheme to remove outdated regulation to ensure British businesses become more nimble and more competitive. He denounced the current Government&#8217;s strategy as threatening to leave business owners getting lost in a &#8220;blob&#8221; of <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.express.co.uk/latest/european-union" target="_blank">European Union</a>-inspired bureaucracy.</p>



<p>Mr Penrose told the Prime Minister: &#8220;In addition to the tragedy in Ukraine, I know the Prime Minister also wants to slash red tape to make Britain more internationally competitive.</p>



<p>&#8220;David Cameron succeeded but after he left, we abandoned his programmed one in, two-out regime and added billions in red tape costs instead.</p>



<p>&#8220;Last month&#8217;s Benefits of Brexit document repeats the mistake, vetoing one in, two out for another toothless regime.</p>



<p>&#8220;Can I urge the Prime Minister to step in before it&#8217;s too late?&#8221;</p>



<p>He added: &#8220;Otherwise the blob will win and we will fail to deliver a key benefit of Brexit.&#8221;</p>



<p>Mr Johnson insisted colleague Jacob Rees-Mogg, who was appointed as Minister of Brexit Opportunities last month, was already working on removing old EU-influenced regulations to help free businesses from added bureaucratic burdens.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister said: &#8220;I&#8217;m delighted to say that we have a new Secretary of State for post-Brexit freedoms and that he&#8217;s driving a campaign to reform, repeal and replace outdated legislation and regulation across the board.</p>



<p>&#8220;I don&#8217;t know about the blob, I can think of no more fearsome antagonist for the blob than my right honorable friend.&#8221;</p>



<p>The one in, two out approach was first adopted under David Cameron and meant ministers seeking to introduce a new regulation that would leave businesses facing added implementation costs need to remove or modify previous rules with double the cost to business.</p>



<p>Brexit has remained a hot topic in British politics despite the British Government striking a deal on future trading relations with the European Union in December 2020.</p>



<p>The Protocol relating to Northern Ireland is still a key point of contention between the bloc and the UK, with the DUP lamenting the impact the agreement has had on the nation&#8217;s role within the union.</p>



<p>Northern Ireland&#8217;s powersharing Executive collapsed earlier this month when the DUP&#8217;s Paul Givan resigned as first minister in protest at the protocol.</p>



<p>His party leader told the Bipa meeting: &#8220;Those who claim that the Northern Ireland Protocol is designed to protect the Good Friday Agreement and the political institutions that were created by it surely must now recognise that the three sets of relationships covered by the agreement have been damaged since the protocol was implemented.</p>



<p>&#8220;The continued imposition of the protocol upon Northern Ireland has cast its long shadow over our political arrangements at Stormont, as well as on a north-south and east-west basis and the everyday lives of our people.</p>



<p>&#8220;The genuine objections to it cannot be wished away, nor simply ignored.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conor shows support for #WorldBookDay2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/03/03/conor-shows-support-for-worldbookday2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7269</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T17:49:46Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T17:49:46Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>World Book Day 2022!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/world-book-day-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Happy 25th Birthday to World Book Day UK.</p>
<p>Millions of children across the UK over the past 25 years have discovered a love of reading and stories. It is great to support World Book Day again this year and I have enjoyed seeing children across Aldridge-Brownhills dress up as their favourite characters and share their favourite books.</p>
<p>The pleasure of reading is powerful for children and adults alike and this year its as important as ever to take some time out and read a good book, get lost in a good story and share the love of reading with those around us.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy 25th Birthday to World Book Day UK. Millions of children across the UK over the past 25 years have discovered a love of reading and stories. It is great to support World Book Day again this year and I have enjoyed seeing children across Aldridge-Brownhills dress up as their favourite characters and share their […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3994</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T17:02:30Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T17:02:30Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MacNeil calls for booking windows on ferry network this Summer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/03/03/macneil-calls-for-booking-windows-on-ferry-network-this-summer-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg"><img data-attachment-id="3724" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/ferry-1/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg" data-orig-size="2048,1152" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="ferry-1" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-3724" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg 2048w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/03/ferry-1.jpeg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>



<p>Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to Transport Scotland and Caledonian MacBrayne calling for the introduction of ‘booking-windows’ for the summer ferries to and from the islands.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil is suggesting a staggered release of vehicle bookings which will improve access to ferries for all, including islands residents who have to travel at short notice.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil said: “We have just come out of a winter period where many islanders have felt locked due to ferry breakdowns and inclement weather.</p>



<p>“As a result, we want to make sure that we plan now to avoid another difficult summer. We have seen disruption due to bad weather; we don’t want further difficulties due to the sheer volume of people.</p>



<p>“I am suggesting this year that, regardless of where people come from, there be a staggered release of space on car decks. 70% in the beginning, then 20% the month before and the last 10% in the week before the sailing. This gives different types of travellers, regardless of where people live, the ability to make these bookings. It gives businesses and people who need to travel at short notice or attend hospital, the hope of being able to travel.</p>



<p>“I would also suggest to Councillors and Community Councils to write to Calmac and the Transport Minister to ensure their voices are heard and that the strength of feeling is understood.</p>



<p>“We cannot have a situation where the winter weather is blocking island travel and the success of summer island tourism is also blocking island travel. Given the rising demand over the last couple of years, the only way to achieve this is to introduce ‘booking-windows’.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to Transport Scotland and Caledonian MacBrayne calling for the introduction …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/03/03/macneil-calls-for-booking-windows-on-ferry-network-this-summer-2/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3723</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T16:23:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T16:23:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An attack on Ukraine is an attack on democracy – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/an-attack-on-ukraine-is-an-attack-on-democracy-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=an-attack-on-ukraine-is-an-attack-on-democracy-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-234968" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/ukraine-graphic.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>Like everyone across the country, I have been watching events unfold in Ukraine with horror, shock and sadness. Vladimir Putin’s attack is an unprovoked, unjustifiable outrage, and a heinous violation of international law. Make no mistake, an attack on Ukraine is an attack on democracy. Everyone who believes in the triumph of democracy over dictatorship, good over evil and freedom over tyranny, must now support the Ukrainian people.</p>
<p>I was immensely proud to see Tameside Council flying the flag of Ukraine at Dukinfield Town Hall. This is a strong statement of solidarity to the people of Ukraine, and to Ukrainian friends living in the United Kingdom. I would like to echo the words of Tameside Council Leader Brenda Warrington, who last week urged any Ukrainians in Tameside, or those who have family in Ukraine and need support to come forward: We will do whatever we can to help you.</p>
<p>Ultimately, this is about standing up for what is right. The United Kingdom believes in the rule of law, in freedom and in democracy. We have a long tradition of staking up to dictators and tyrants, we must continue that tradition, and match our words with actions. That’s why I’ve advocated the hardest possible sanctions against all those linked to Putin and against the Russian government’s interests.</p>
<p>The sanctions announced so far by the Government have been good in principle, but we can, and we must go further. We must do everything we can to cut Putin’s rogue regime out of our financial system. That means widening export controls to include luxury goods, expanding the number of banks prevented from accessing sterling, and sanctioning more of Putin’s oligarchs and cronies who have assets here in the UK.</p>
<p>Alongside these tough measures, we must make sure that we urgently prepare to offer humanitarian support for Ukraine, and for our neighbours and partners on its borders. That means offering a simple sanctuary route to the UK for all who need it, and providing aid to the Ukrainian people at their hour of need.</p>
<p>These are dark and uncertain times, and I am sure I am not alone in feeling incredibly concerned at what the future holds. However, it is more important than ever that we stand up for what is right and send a message to the Ukrainian people that they have our full support as they bravely resist this assault.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/an-attack-on-ukraine-is-an-attack-on-democracy-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">An attack on Ukraine is an attack on democracy – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Like everyone across the country, I have been watching events unfold in Ukraine with horror, shock and sadness. Vladimir Putin’s attack is an unprovoked, unjustifiable outrage, and a heinous violation of international law. Make no mistake, an attack on Ukraine is an attack on democracy. Everyone who believes in the triumph of democracy over dictatorship, […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/an-attack-on-ukraine-is-an-attack-on-democracy-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">An attack on Ukraine is an attack on democracy – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=234967</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T15:21:05Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T15:21:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne supports World Book Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-supports-world-book-day" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7124" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">3 March 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne supports World Book Day</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Philip Dunne MP is supporting the 25th annual World Book Day today (Thursday 3rd March) to encourage children to develop a lifelong passion for reading.</p>

<p>Each year, World Book Day creates bespoke £1 books for children and young adults across the UK and Ireland, to promote the power of imagination and the importance of reading. In 2021, World Book Day gifted a further 110,000 £1 books in only five weeks.</p>

<p>Through World Book Day, every child in South Shropshire will be given a £1 book token, which they can take to a bookshop or supermarket to get their free World Book Day book.</p>

<p>Last year, 55% of primary children surveyed said they read more books as a result of World Book Day and 45% said they talk more about books with their family and friends.</p>

<p>Before entering Parliament, Mr Dunne co-founded the chain of high street bookshops, Ottakars, which was later merged with Waterstones.</p>

<p>Mr Dunne said:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“I am very pleased to support World Book Day today. As a former bookseller, it is perhaps not surprising I strongly support encouraging children to develop a lifelong passion for reading – which will not only give them access to a world of knowledge, but also the most moving, exciting and important stories.</p>

<p>“I hope schools, parents and children will get into the spirit of World Book Day and discover a great new read.”</p>
</blockquote></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.philipdunne.com/sites/philipdunne.com/files/2022-03/philip_dunne_world_book_day.jpg" width="540" height="809" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7124 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T15:09:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T15:09:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Minister Response to Hadrian’s Wall Campaign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/03/minister-response-to-hadrians-wall-campaign/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="12122" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/03/minister-response-to-hadrians-wall-campaign/hadrians/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?fit=719%2C1047&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="719,1047" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Hadrians" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?fit=206%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?fit=700%2C1020&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12122" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?resize=206%2C300&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="206" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?resize=206%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 206w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?resize=703%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 703w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Hadrians.jpg?w=719&amp;amp;ssl=1 719w" sizes="(max-width: 206px) 100vw, 206px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="12123" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/03/minister-response-to-hadrians-wall-campaign/hadrians2/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?fit=701%2C1031&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="701,1031" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="hadrians2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?fit=204%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?fit=696%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-12123" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?resize=204%2C300&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="204" height="300" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?resize=204%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 204w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?resize=696%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 696w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/hadrians2.jpg?w=701&amp;amp;ssl=1 701w" sizes="(max-width: 204px) 100vw, 204px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt; igel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nigel Huddleston, Minister for Sport, Tourism, Heritage and Civil Society, has responded to Chi&amp;#8217;s campaign for greater recognition of Hadrian&amp;#8217;s Wall in Newcastle, full letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/eCase-03126-Onwurah.pdf"&gt;eCase 03126 &amp;#8211; Onwurah&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">igel Nigel Huddleston, Minister for Sport, Tourism, Heritage and Civil Society, has responded to Chi’s campaign for greater recognition of Hadrian’s Wall in Newcastle, full letter: eCase 03126 – Onwurah  </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Gareth Fearn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12121</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:17:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:17:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Case for Fracking in the UK</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/Fracking" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mention the word ‘Fracking’ and some people will run a mile and as a rule its usually the same people who have never had to worry about paying a gas bill. No one disagrees with our Net Zero journey but Net Zero does not mean zero fossil fuels and its all well and good the local Green Party…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/Fracking</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>World Book Day 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/world-book-day-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today is World Book Day, an opportunity to celebrate storytelling and encourage children to read more.
Reading is so important for children. It helps improve levels of concentration, develops their creativity and boosts their social skills and interactions. Importantly, storytelling can help…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/world-book-day-2022</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beverley &amp; Holderness MP condemns Russia’s invasion of Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/beverley-holderness-mp-condemns-russias-invasion-ukraine" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, condemns Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and supports the Government’s severe sanctions against Russia.
Yesterday, Graham Stuart MP signed a book of solidarity in the Houses of Parliament to Ruslan Stefanchuk, Chairman of the Verkhovna Rada, Parliament of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/beverley-holderness-mp-condemns-russias-invasion-ukraine</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>​​​​​​​Scott Benton MP backs for the extension of bereavement leave and pay</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-backs-extension-bereavement-leave-and-pay" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MPs and Lords are supporting the extension of bereavement leave and pay to employees experiencing a close family bereavement
Scott Benton, MP for Blackpool South, attended a Parliamentary event on 2 March in support of extending bereavement leave and pay to employees experiencing a close family…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-backs-extension-bereavement-leave-and-pay</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg celebrates World Book Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-celebrates-world-book-day" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP for is supporting World Book Day’s 25th anniversary today (Thursday 3rd March 2022).
Each year, World Book Day creates bespoke £1 books for children and young adults across the UK and Ireland, to promote the power of imagination and the importance of reading. Through World Book Day,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-celebrates-world-book-day</id>
    <published>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[“An attack on workers’ rights”: Alex backs care workers’ in campaign against de-recognition of trade unions by Barchester Healthcare]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/03/an-attack-on-workers-rights-alex-backs-care-workers-in-campaign-against-de-recognition-of-trade-unions-by-barchester-healthcare/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14435</id>
		<updated>2022-03-03T10:35:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-03-03T10:35:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham has backed and local care workers as they campaign against a care home provider’s decision to refuse to negotiate agreements with their trade unions on pay and conditions. Barchester Healthcare, which operates Billingham Grange Independent Hospital in Billingham has moved to scrap trade union recognition agreements, which will see care [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/03/an-attack-on-workers-rights-alex-backs-care-workers-in-campaign-against-de-recognition-of-trade-unions-by-barchester-healthcare/">“An attack on workers’ rights”: Alex backs care workers’ in campaign against de-recognition of trade unions by Barchester Healthcare</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rainham Foodbank February Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/rainham-foodbank-february-newsletter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Rainham Foodbank February Newsletter</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-03-02T12:28:00+00:00">Wed, 03/02/2022 - 12:28</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1111 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-03-02T12:28:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-02T12:28:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[STANDING WITH UKRAINE]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/03/02/standing-with-ukraine/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=421</id>
		<updated>2022-03-02T10:59:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-03-02T10:59:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/03/02/standing-with-ukraine/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/03/02/standing-with-ukraine/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/03/02/standing-with-ukraine/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP AND CUMBRIA TOURISM JOIN FORCES AGAINST VAT RISE TO PROTECT LOCAL HOSPITALITY INDUSTRY</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1424943/mp-and-cumbria-tourism-join-forces-against-vat-rise-to-protect-local-hospitality-industry"/>
  <updated>2022-03-02T09:09:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1424943/mp-and-cumbria-tourism-join-forces-against-vat-rise-to-protect-local-hospitality-industry</id>
  <summary type="text">Tim Farron MP and Cumbria Tourism have joined forces against the proposed rise in VAT. The Chancellor, Rishi Sunak, lowered the rate to 12.5% to combat the effects of the pandemic but plans to return the rate to 20% in early April. Cumbria Tourism have discovered in a recent survey of their circa 2500 member businesses that the proposed VAT rise was the fourth biggest concern for members.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img class="content-edited" alt="Tim with Gill Haigh" title="Tim with Gill Haigh" src="/en/image/6q5pTB/360/270/tim-with-gill-haigh.png" style="width: 360px; height: 270px; float: right;"/>Tim Farron MP and Cumbria Tourism have joined forces against the proposed rise in VAT. The Chancellor, Rishi Sunak, lowered the rate to 12.5% to combat the effects of the pandemic but plans to return the rate to 20% in early April. Cumbria Tourism have discovered in a recent survey of their circa 2500 member businesses that the proposed VAT rise was the fourth biggest concern for members.</p>
<p>As the tourism and hospitality industries are one of the biggest employers within Cumbria the proposed rise is of particular concern following the COVID-19 pandemic and in the wake of the rising costs of living. In 2020 overseas residents flying to the UK fell by 96% and overall, the pandemic is estimated to have cost the UK tourism industry £2 Billion.</p>
<p>Tim Farron and Cumbria Tourism are calling on the Chancellor to not go ahead with the planned rise in VAT.</p>
<p>Tim has said, <em>"The tourism and hospitality industries are fundamental to Cumbrian life. The pandemic has been devastating on these industries and whilst the lowered VAT rate has helped boost the economy a little it is nowhere near recovered enough for the rates to return to 20%.</em></p>
<p><em>"We also need to keep people in employment and these local businesses will not be able to do that if they have to keep raising prices to keep up with VAT and other rising costs of living. Keeping VAT low is fundamental to keeping our local high streets thriving."</em></p>
<p>Gill Haigh, managing director of Cumbria Tourism, has added<em>, "The impact of COVID-19 had a catastrophic impact for the county's tourism industry in 2020, wiping £2billion off the value of our visitor economy. Whilst Government support has been hugely welcomed, significant challenges remain - not least around recruitment, which is now potentially holding back future growth. Combined with rising costs and supply issues, many tourism and hospitality businesses continue to struggle and we continue to urge Government to extend the discounted VAT rate.</em></p>
<p><em>"At the same time, there is also huge opportunity. Looking ahead, there is the chance to capitalise on the new 'staycation' experience, convert the 'new' visitors we have attracted over the past 18 months into repeat custom and increase short breaks out of season.</em></p>
<p><em>"Now is the time to seize the moment, invest and really take tourism seriously as an economic driver for the UK and extending the discounted VAT rate would be one way the Government can help make that happen."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>GUEST BLOG: Kady Weedop, who is studying A Level Politics, gives her views on the need to educate school children on government and politics</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/03/01/guest-blog-kady-weedop-who-is-studying-a-level-politics-gives-her-views-on-the-need-to-educate-school-children-on-government-and-politics/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/03/01/guest-blog-kady-weedop-who-is-studying-a-level-politics-gives-her-views-on-the-need-to-educate-school-children-on-government-and-politics/">GUEST BLOG: Kady Weedop, who is studying A Level Politics, gives her views on the need to educate school children on government and politics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/03/01/guest-blog-kady-weedop-who-is-studying-a-level-politics-gives-her-views-on-the-need-to-educate-school-children-on-government-and-politics/">GUEST BLOG: Kady Weedop, who is studying A Level Politics, gives her views on the need to educate school children on government and politics</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4965</id>
    <published>2022-03-01T14:27:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-01T14:27:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maria visits Chiltern Primary</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-visits-chiltern-primary" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP, Maria Miller, visited Chiltern Primary School, where she met with Mr Nathan Gazzard, the new Headteacher, and spoke with a group of pupils.
 
Maria said, “One of the things I am most grateful for, as we emerge from the pandemic, is the opportunity to once again visit local schools and to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-visits-chiltern-primary</id>
    <published>2022-03-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP wins refunds for residents of burned-out flats</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-wins-refunds-for-residents-of-burned-out-flats/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=local-mp-wins-refunds-for-residents-of-burned-out-flats" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps has won refunds for residents of Ashley Court, Hatfield, who were forced to leave their homes due to an electrical fire, and then subject to unfair service charges for housing they were unable to reside in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It has been over a year since the residents of Ashley Court were forced to leave their homes due to an electrical fire.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During this time residents, many of whom are vulnerable and require care, have been off-site &amp;#8211; residing in temporary accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Building work aimed at restoring Ashley Court has also been delayed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Previously, residents of Ashley Court were billed £225 per month in service charges for housing they had not occupied.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This monthly fee included charges for various services, including a Scheme Manager and Caretaker costs, which residents were not benefitting from.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In December 2021, local MP Grant Shapps wrote to Sanctuary Housing, the housing association responsible for managing Ashley Court, expressing his concern about “the impact on his constituents” nominally resident there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sanctuary Housing responded to Mr Shapps’ letter but at that time did not agree to waive the £225 a month charge.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In February, Mr Shapps wrote to the association once again (below), this time saying that he was putting it “on notice” over its unfair treatment of residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img width="729" height="1024" src="https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letter-729x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-40879" srcset="https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letter-729x1024.png 729w, https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letter-480x674.png 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) 729px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" width="729" height="1024" src="https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letterp2-729x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-40880" srcset="https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letterp2-729x1024.png 729w, https://www.shapps.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/280220letterp2-480x674.png 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) 729px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Following this most recent letter, Sanctuary Housing responded quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In a major victory for the residents, the association apologised, saying that it had got its “approach wrong” regarding Ashley Court, and that it would be refunding service charge payments to residents as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The association also said it would refund payments for deceased residents to their respective estates.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sanctuary Housing stated it would be conducting a “more detailed review” of how the residents of Ashley Court were put in their previous unfair situation and would share its findings with Mr Shapps’ office.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The association agreed to meet with Mr Shapps in March saying that its representative would apologise in person, and that it would put itself on the “appropriate footing” to work with him going forward. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Peter Hebden, County Councillor and Borough Councillor for Hatfield East, who has worked tirelessly on behalf of the residents of Ashley court, will also attend the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cllr Hebden said of the recent good news: “This is a fantastic step forward for the residents. There are other issues to be resolved but if Sanctuary Housing are adopting a new resident-focussed stance then I’m a lot more optimistic”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps gave his own thoughts on the matter adding: “This is a great result for the residents of Ashley Court, and I’m incredibly happy to have been part of the effort to facilitate it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As Councillor Hebden has said, this is a step forward for the residents, and I’m sure that our meeting with Sanctuary Housing will yield further results.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Putting residents in such an unfair situation was unacceptable, so I’m hoping that this outcome will go some way to putting their minds at ease.” &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-wins-refunds-for-residents-of-burned-out-flats/"&gt;Local MP wins refunds for residents of burned-out flats&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps has won refunds for residents of Ashley Court, Hatfield, who were forced to leave their homes due to an electrical fire, and then subject to unfair service charges for housing they were unable to reside in.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-wins-refunds-for-residents-of-burned-out-flats/">Local MP wins refunds for residents of burned-out flats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=40877</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T20:03:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T20:03:58Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Hatfield"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ukraine Donations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/02/ukraine-donations/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Many thanks to our Polish community for taking the initiative to send help to Eastern Poland for the Ukrainian refugees arriving there and all who have already given so generously, and many thanks to <a href="https://www.facebook.com/LlanelliRotaryClub/?__cft__[0]=AZXACMBdnoOQ8yM72i1IKaXtUIeYretNFhV95uHv3G8Ki2MaEgJTKzG3UNJd_3Mc9AZxqZDUR6CtywXIKIjU1feVDQqTbp0coFrgmcmHAOnBoG8ZTD5WaM7L7r_M35wdwXYonlNtSvyhKyahZjQnUGSw&amp;__tn__=kK-R">Llanelli Rotary Club</a>  for agreeing to handle money donations, so we can be confident that this money will be properly used.  </p>



<p>If you are able to make a donation to support the fundraising campaign then please visit the link below:</p>



<p> https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/RotaryLlanelliUkraine</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Many thanks to our Polish community for taking the initiative to send help to Eastern Poland for the Ukrainian refugees arriving there and all who have already given so generously, and many thanks to Llanelli Rotary Club for agreeing to handle money donations, so we can be confident that this money will be properly used. […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8385</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T17:53:44Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T17:53:44Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COMMENT: CONDEMNING PUTIN’S WAR IN UKRAINE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/comment-condemning-putins-war-in-ukraine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Like many in Clydebank and across West Dunbartonshire, my thoughts have been with the people of Ukraine as they face the tyranny and aggression of the Russian regime’s latest military onslaught. As I write this, Ukrainians have faced consecutive days of bombing as tanks roll-in following the full-scale invasion launched by Russia’s President Vladimir Putin. … </p>
<p class="link-more"><a href="http://martindocherty.scot/comment-condemning-putins-war-in-ukraine/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "COMMENT: CONDEMNING PUTIN’S WAR IN UKRAINE"</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/comment-condemning-putins-war-in-ukraine/">COMMENT: CONDEMNING PUTIN’S WAR IN UKRAINE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1771201</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T17:28:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T17:28:40Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Kirsty Watson</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Further sanctions taken against Belarus welcomed]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/02/28/further-sanctions-taken-against-belarus-welcomed/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10352</id>
		<updated>2022-02-28T12:35:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-28T12:32:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the SNP International Human Rights Spokesperson, Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP welcomed the announcement of further sanctions being taken against Belarus for their complicity in Russia&#8217;s attack on Ukraine, and awaits a response from the UK Government to how these sanctions will be targeted.]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Belarus-sanctions.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="2700997" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin is recruiting: Admin Officer/Constituency Assistant</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-recruiting-admin-officerconstituency-assistant" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Closing Date: 25 March 2022
 
Job Title: Admin Officer/Constituency Assistant
Working For: Robin Millar MP (Aberconwy)
Location: Constituency
Salary: As per IPSA pay scales
Length of Contract: Fixed term - 12 months
Job Details
Robin Millar MP is looking to recruit a part time Administration…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-recruiting-admin-officerconstituency-assistant</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Visa fees waived for non-UK service personnel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/visa-fees-waived-non-uk-service-personnel" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In a joint statement last week, the Home Office and Ministry of Defence announced a change in immigration rules to allow people who have served in the UK’s military to have their visa fees waived.  
UK Visa fees will now no longer apply to: Currently serving non-UK personnel who will have served at…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/visa-fees-waived-non-uk-service-personnel</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-148" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Make no mistake, the illegal and unprovoked Russian invasion of Ukraine is the biggest threat to peace and stability across Europe since 1945. No country has the right to attack another state – just like that. The sovereignty of a democratic state like Ukraine isn’t up for grabs to a predator - who…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-148</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on the Current Situation in Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/statement-on-the-current-situation-in-ukraine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#1e73be;">I want to express my solidarity with the people of Ukraine <span style="color:#dd3333;">but also want to commend those brave Russians who are standing up to Putin's warmongering</span></h3></div><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Over the last few days, I have received many emails from constituents, and indeed from across the country, expressing concerns and even outrage at the invasion of Ukraine, an independent sovereign state, by President Putin’s military machine. I distinguish the act of this dictator and tyrant, Putin, from the Russian people, who like most people everywhere, want to live their lives in freedom and peace. I want to express my solidarity with the people of Ukraine, but also I want to commend those brave Russians who are standing up to Putin’s warmongering. His erratic and irrational behaviour is a serious threat to us all.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>Putin’s attack on Ukraine is an unprovoked and unjustifiable outrage that will have tragic consequences for Ukraine, Europe and our world. It is a heinous violation of international law that breaks multiple treaties and commitments, including the fundamental principles of the UN Charter. Putin’s actions should be utterly condemned by all nations. As such, I regret that some countries in the UN Security Council failed to support a UN resolution calling for this yesterday.</em></p>
<p><em>This assault on the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine must now have serious consequences for Putin and his supporters. I am clear that there can be no space for equivocation when faced with the evil that Putin has unleashed. His actions pose a grave threat to the international order on which we depend and have broadly enjoyed since the end of the Second World War.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>We must now match our rhetoric with action. The hardest possible sanctions must be taken against all those linked to Putin and against the Russian Government’s interests, working in a coordinated and unified way with our allies to ensure the Putin regime faces the severest possible consequences for their actions.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>The UK sanctions earlier this week have been recognised as far too limited. Yesterday’s additional sanctions are wider reaching but there will undoubtedly need to be more. Some of you have proposed your own sanctions including ‘isolating </em><em>Russia completely’ and ‘stop buying oil, gas and other commodities from Russia’. I agree. Under Putin’s presidency, Russia must be seen as a pariah state and ostracised from the world economy.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>We need to move quickly to stop the influence of corrupt Russian money in the UK. Despite warning after warning, the Government failed to act, leaving Britain as the destination of choice for kleptocrats who hide their wealth under our noses. It has been going on for far too long and should not have taken an invasion of Ukraine for the Government to act. The Economic Crime Bill must now be brought forward, as well as introducing an Overseas Entities Bill.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>But we must prepare for the consequences of these sanctions against Russia in energy and financial markets, working with our allies and partners to manage disruptions and shocks.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>International co-ordination with our allies is imperative. This applies not just to sanctions, but to humanitarian aid and military defensive actions. We must work in conjunction with our NATO allies to mount our response against Putin.</em></p>
<p><em>In the short term, we must:</em></p>
<ul style="font-weight: 400;">
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul style="font-weight: 400;">
<li><em>ensure the Foreign Office is providing effective consular support and assistance, with sufficient staffing and resources, to help UK nationals and their families seeking to leave.  I have been pressing Ministers in the Foreign Office and Home Office for nearly a month now to make access to visas and travel documents for UK nationals and their families easier.  I am pleased there is an effort to streamline the process, but believe Ministers could, and should, have acted</em><em> far</em><em> more quickly.</em></li>
<li><em>provide urgent humanitarian assistance and to work with our partners and Ukraine’s neighbours to manage </em><em>the </em><em>large-scale displacement </em><em>that we are already seeing as </em><em>refugee</em><em>s</em><em> fl</em><em>ee their homeland</em><em>.</em></li>
<li><em>continue to play our part as a member of NATO to support and reinforce other NATO members on the Eastern flank.</em></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>As difficult as it is to predict irrational behaviour, we must try and anticipate Putin’s next steps. In relation to this, given the overwhelming evidence that Russian state actors have tried to disrupt and destabilise western democracies by disseminating disinformation through social media platforms such as Facebook, including at election times, I asked the Prime Minister what steps his Government was taking to prevent this happening now. Unfortunately this doesn’t seem to be on the Government’s horizon yet. It should be.</em></p>
<p><em>I don’t believe the Russian people want this war; this is an ageing and unstable leader with a warped view of what his legacy should be. The international community’s response must learn the lessons from history.</em></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><em>I’m grateful to everyone who has contacted me so far and for the humanity and kindness they have shown for the distress of the Ukrainian people. I’d particularly like to thank those of you who have offered to open up their homes to Ukrainian refugees. This is the Oldham and Saddleworth I’m so proud to serve.</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/statement-on-the-current-situation-in-ukraine/">Statement on the Current Situation in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/statement-on-the-current-situation-in-ukraine/">Statement on the Current Situation in Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6921</id>
    <published>2022-02-28T09:33:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-28T09:33:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="International"/>
    <category term="Ukraine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-72/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div>
<p>I was honoured to be re-elected as a vice-chair of the APPG Western Rail Link at its AGM this week. We have been campaigning for many years for the Department of Transport of the UK Government to joint fund with Heathrow Airport a rail link from Reading railway station to Heathrow Airport for passengers and freight, which the Conservatives committed to in 2012. The proposed <a href="https://www.networkrail.co.uk/running-the-railway/our-routes/western/western-rail-link-to-heathrow/">Great Western Rail Link</a> will go via Langley railway station. The application to construct the new line has been delayed again, with an estimate of sometime this year. Network Rail has said that the delay has been caused by the Court of Appeal’s ruling against expansion of Heathrow airport, and the impact of coronavirus on the aviation industry. When the project does go ahead, a tunnel will be constructed connecting Reading to Heathrow, each journey taking 25 minutes, whereas passengers currently take the Rail Air Bus which takes 50 minutes or have to go via Paddington station to get the Heathrow Express. Reading station and Heathrow airport have already built rail terminals in anticipation of the scheme going ahead. The proposed link is a Nationally Significant Infrastructure Project and planning permission can only be granted by a Development Consent Order. The DfT said that whilst it accepts the link, this is subject to a satisfactory business plan case and settling agreeable terms with Heathrow Airport. But it may be that the Treasury has delayed this, as it has done with many other schemes. The chair of our APPG Tan Dhesi MP for Slough raised the matter in Treasury Oral Questions last December, stating that he understood that a DfT application to fund the link was made to the Treasury as part of the Autumn Spending Review but was rejected. The Minister did not answer Tan’s question.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>I was proud to be re-elected as a vice-chair of the <a href="https://twitter.com/APPGonMND/status/1496435009284370432">Motor Neurone Disease APPG</a> at a virtual AGM followed by an event at which I was a guest speaker on Housing Adaptations and the Challenges Faced by People Living with MND. I spoke about the situation in Wales. At the beginning of 2012, the Welsh Homes For MND campaign was launched in order to highlight these challenges. The campaign wanted the Welsh Government to issue guidance to all local authorities to instigate a transparent, fast-track, non-means tested, process for housing adaptations and to report back on the process. MND representatives met with Welsh Government housing officials to discuss the campaign. There was a back bench debate in the Senedd on the importance of housing adaptations, and following the debate Julie James MS Swansea West Minister for Housing announced that the Welsh Government would remove the means test for small and medium disabled facilities grants, and provide an extra £1 million in grant aid. During last May’s Senedd election, 74 cross-party candidates supported the campaign. After the election, MSs attended a Senedd MND virtual event where people with MND and health professionals explained the importance of a fast-track process. The MND Association collected results from FOI responses from 19 of the 22 local authorities in Wales about fast-tracking and means-testing, which precipitated the launch of the “Adapt Now” report, highlighting that the housing adaptation process from application to installation is too long for people with a rapid progressing disease like MND. The <a href="https://www.mndassociation.org/get-involved/campaigning/take-action/adapt-now-welsh-homes-for-mnd/">report</a> was officially launched at a virtual event in the Senedd last October where people with MND told their stories of why the reforms in the Welsh Homes for MND campaign are absolutely vital to maintain independence and improve quality of life. Eluned Morgan MS, Welsh Government Health Minister has confirmed that all local authorities should remove means testing for small and medium adaptations by 2022, and the Welsh Local Government Association will look at implementing a unified model later this year.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>It was a privilege to be re-elected as vice-chair of the APPG for Archives and History at its AGM and future work meeting. We discussed the exciting proposal for an event about the 50th anniversary of the Watergate Scandal break-in at the Democratic National Committee Headquarters at the Washington DC Watergate Office Building in June 1972. The scandal rocked the presidency of Richard Nixon from 1972 until he resigned on 9th August 1974. The Nixon Administration continually tried to cover up its involvement, but the cash found on the 5 perpetrators was connected to the Nixon re-election campaign by the US Justice Department and the press. Nixon is the only US President to have resigned.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>I spoke in the Westminster Hall Debate secured by my dear friend Jess Morden MP for Newport East about the Cost of Living in Wales. In contrast to over 10 years of cuts dealt by the UK Tory Government and handed down to the people in Wales, I praised the approach of the Welsh Labour Government who has supplied <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1496510231429459969?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet">a package of £330 million</a> to tackle the cost of living crisis targeted at helping the most vulnerable with support schemes such as the winter fuel scheme and the discretionary assistance fund. I also congratulated the Welsh Labour Government for implementing its <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1496786989982486528?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Etweet">basic income pilot</a> scheme for care leavers in Wales which will give care leavers the support they deserve to develop into independent young adults.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>As a vice-chair of the <a href="https://appgtrophyhunting.wordpress.com/">APPG to Ban Trophy Hunting</a> I met Peter Egan and Eduardo Goncalves at the launch of a new poster campaign to urge the UK Government to urgently introduce its long-awaited Animals Abroad Bill which includes a pledge to ban trophies from over 7,000 species. The poster was displayed on a huge 5mx3m screen at the George V Statue opposite the House of Lords, and many parliamentarians attended to show their support. The UK Government’s Bill does not have a date, and there have been recent media reports suggesting the Bill may be shelved. Official figures show that British trophy hunters are killing hundreds of lions, polar bears, elephants, leopards, giraffes, and dozens of other species every year for trophies. Opinion polls repeatedly show that almost 9 out of 10 voters support a total ban, and want it implemented as soon as possible. We are calling on the UK Government to set a date to introduce its Bill, or to support the Hunting Trophy Import Private Members Bill promoted by John Speller MP, which has its second reading on Friday 18th March.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>As a Labour and Co-operative Party MP, I attended the virtual AGM meeting of the Neath Port Talbot and Swansea Co-operative Party branch and was re-elected as a vice-chair. We selected members to represent our Co-operative Party branch on local Labour Constituencies, and to represent us at the Wales Co-operative Council, which held its virtual AGM meeting on Saturday 26th February. I presented my regular Parliamentary Co-operative Party Group report at the Wales Co-operative Council meeting, and was extremely proud to be elected vice-chair of the Council. Jackie Jones, former MEP for Wales was elected chair, Cllr Sam Pritchard Swansea was elected treasurer, KC Gordon North Wales was re-elected secretary for the twentieth year, and Jackie Owen Wrexham, was elected women’s officer. The Wales Co-operative Party will be holding a fringe event at the Welsh Labour Conference taking place in Llandudno from 11-13th March, with guest speakers Vaughan Gethin MS Minister for Economy and Co-operatives in the Welsh Labour Government, Derek Walker Chief Executive of the Wales Co-operative Centre, and Huw Irranca-Davies chair of the Senedd Labour and Co-operative Group, chaired by Jackie Jones. The Wales Co-operative Council and the Wales Co-operative Centre are jointly hosting the fringe meeting, together with a Wales Co-operative Party stall at the Conference exhibition centre.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>On Sunday 27th February I attended a service in St David’s Church Neath where we prayed for peace and for the people of Ukraine, for their community and political leaders. We prayed for those institutions and leaders around the world who have the influence to work for peace.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch, please do not hesitate to email christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call us on 01639 630152 – we are here to help.</p>
</div>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was honoured to be re-elected as a vice-chair of the APPG Western Rail Link at its AGM this week. We have been campaigning for many years for the Department of Transport of the UK Government to joint fund with Heathrow Airport a rail link from Reading railway station to Heathrow Airport for passengers and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2628</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T16:18:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-25T16:18:32Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/ukraine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Friday 25 February 2022 Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is an unprovoked assault on a peaceful and sovereign nation. There can be no justification for the action that President Putin has taken. He has lied repeatedly to the Russian people and to the world about the situation in Ukraine. Mr Putin has falsely asserted time and […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6041</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T12:00:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-25T12:00:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Europe"/>
    <category term="International Affairs"/>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>War Crimes in Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/war-crimes-ukraine" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As British United Nations Commander in Central Bosnia I found a massacre site at a place called Ahmici on 22nd April 1993.  Over one hundred Bosnian Muslim civilians – mainly women and children -  had been murdered there.  Immediately I considered it to be genocide.  It was formally classified as…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/war-crimes-ukraine</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recognise the State of Palestine 22 February 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/24/recognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I was in #Gaza at start of peace process in 1991, but have seen #Palestinian hope for #peace and security turn to dust over 30 years with no progress.&lt;br&gt;Illogical for U.K. Gov to claim to support #TwoStateSolution without recognising BOTH states!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="Recognise State of Palestine, 24 February 2022" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/O9GN6SAnJVQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I want to start by declaring an interest in that I was a volunteer with Medical Aid for Palestinians in Gaza in 1991 and 1992.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And after visiting in 2016, helped them set up a breast cancer project between Scottish specialists and the local teams in Gaza and the West Bank.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I want to thank all the clinicians who take part in that on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to almost 55 years of occupation, the people of Gaza have suffered from 15 years of intense blockade and repeated military attacks every few years, which has degraded their civil infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The tap water, unlike in my time is now undrinkable; raw sewage pollutes, coastal fishing waters, and due to the destruction of the power plant in 2014, there&amp;#8217;s only intermittent electricity, including to hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This undermines the public health of Palestinians, but also the provision of health care; with the destruction of clinics and hospitals through military attacks and demolitions and difficulty in obtaining medical supplies with approximately a third of vital drugs running constantly close to zero stock. Many modern therapies are simply not available in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;#8217;s very difficult for patients to get permission, to travel to East Jerusalem, to access treatment. Gaza has no radiotherapy provision, which is important for preserving the breast in breast cancer patients. When I visited in 2016, all the women I met had undergone radical mastectomy because they couldn&amp;#8217;t access the treatment. But it&amp;#8217;s even more vital in other cancers, such as lung cancer, where it&amp;#8217;s the main treatment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And overall the World Health Organization report that 35 to 40% of patients who apply for permission to travel to Jerusalem are refused, delayed, or get no response. And all of this contributes to the poor survival of Palestinian cancer patients. On annual training visits prior to the pandemic, I&amp;#8217;ve also seen the impact of the occupation and fragmentation and in the West Bank,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;with communities separated from each other, their farmland, and particularly their water sources. Palestinians face constant harassment and obstruction. Their homes are demolished while settlements are relentlessly expanded in what is defacto annexation and conquest by concrete.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The UK has a particular responsibility as the 1917 Balfour declaration promised a national home for the Jewish people in Palestine, but that nothing shall be done, which may prejudice the civil and religious rights of the existing non-Jewish communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For over 70 years, the UK has recognized the State of Israel and honour that promise to the Jewish people, but broken it to the Palestinians.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So after 55 years of occupation, 15 years of Gaza blockade and the ongoing annexation of the west bank, the two-state solution is simply becoming unviable, unless there is a reversal of current Israeli policy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And there is no chance of that without external pressure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Government ministers repeatedly stand in this chamber and claim the UK supports a two state solution, but this is hollow if there isn&amp;#8217;t recognition of both of those states.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And that is a minimum, it must be combined with real action, to ensure no UK banks or companies profit from occupation or illegal settlements. I was working in Gaza at the start of the Madrid peace process. And by late afternoon saw young Palestinian men giving olive branches to Palestinian soldiers. That image of hope has crumbled to dust 30 years on. Immediate recognition is the minimum and is vital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F24%2Frecognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022%2F&amp;#038;title=Recognise%20the%20State%20of%20Palestine%2022%20February%202022" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/24/recognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022/" data-a2a-title="Recognise the State of Palestine 22 February 2022"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/24/recognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022/"&gt;Recognise the State of Palestine 22 February 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was in #Gaza at start of peace process in 1991, but have seen #Palestinian ... <a title="Recognise the State of Palestine 22 February 2022" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/24/recognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/24/recognise-the-state-of-palestine-22-february-2022/">Recognise the State of Palestine 22 February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Parliamentary Assistant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2387</id>
    <published>2022-02-24T18:12:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-24T18:12:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="Palestine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Post Pandemic Effects On Exporters</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-post-pandemic-effects-exporters" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of the issues concerning local businesses as we emerge from the pandemic has been the likely effect on exporters. With business trying to catch up on two years of relative quiet because of Covid, what was going to happen, particularly at Dover, as for the time we encounter the post-Brexit…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-post-pandemic-effects-exporters</id>
    <published>2022-02-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet to lead calls for Parliamentary reform on exempt accommodation in Birmingham </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-lead-calls-parliamentary-reform-exempt-accommodation-birmingham" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Today, Wednesday 23 February, Preet Kaur Gill MP will lead calls for reform to the exempt accommodation sector in the House of Commons.  </p>
<p>Labour’s Opposition Day debate will focus on exempt accommodation which in the last five years has overwhelmed Birmingham’s housing stock, increasing by 62% and now provides over 21,000 units with support to some of the most vulnerable people.  </p>
<p>As Preet Kaur Gill MP will explain, current regulation is extremely limited which is allowing “too many bad landlords getting into this sector for the wrong reasons, exploiting a toxic cocktail of relaxed regulation, a Conservative housing crisis and an epidemic of unmet need after years of council cuts.” </p>
<p>In her speech, Preet will share how working with local residents, Birmingham City Council and West Midlands Police she was able to successfully close Saif Lodge, an exempt property in the constituency which was causing huge problems for neighbours – the first order of its kind in the country.  </p>
<p>Preet will say to Government that this care cannot be provided on the cheap and that we must seek reform. It should be noted that there is no statutory definition of what care, support or supervision is in the context of exempt accommodation. Therefore, there needs to be five main asks for reform: </p>
<ol start="1"><li>
	A statutory definition of the care, support and supervision. 
	</li>
</ol><ol start="2"><li>
	Resources for local authorities to fund inspection programmes for exempt in their region. 
	</li>
</ol><ol start="3"><li>
	Ensure individuals and families housed in exempt have a link to the area they are placed. 
	</li>
</ol><ol start="4"><li>
	Give local authorities and the social housing regulator greater enforcement powers and strengthen the vetting process. 
	</li>
</ol><ol start="5"><li>
	Birmingham has called for government to align existing planning and HMO licensing policies to capture supported housing provision that is currently exempt from licensing and give local authorities powers to reject applications in a specific area on the grounds of oversupply. 
	</li>
</ol><p>Preet Kaur Gill, MP for Birmingham Edgbaston said, “Millions of pounds of taxpayer’s money is being shovelled to the operators of these exempt properties without apparent due diligence or scrutiny.  </p>
<p>“The Government has had reports from Prospect Supported Housing, Spring Housing, policy recommendations from Crisis, Birmingham City Council, as well as reports from multiple community groups. All of these reports are pointing in the same direction. Yet, the Government has failed to act. </p>
<p>“Lives are literally at stake. Survivors of domestic violence; prison leavers; care leavers; people with mental health and substance abuse issues deserve a housing system that supports their transition to happier, more independent lives and our communities in Birmingham deserve neighbourhoods that are peaceful and safe, not a magnet for crime.” </p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Standard (Image)</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Screenshot%202022-02-23%20171825.jpg" width="1500" height="847" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>1068 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2022-02-23T17:19:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-23T17:19:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Labour condemns Russian invasion of Ukraine]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-condemns-russian-invasion-of-ukraine/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11657</id>
		<updated>2022-02-23T16:13:42Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-23T16:13:42Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday the Prime Minister addressed the House of Commons in response to the Russian invasion of Donetsk and Luhansk in eastern Ukraine.<br />
Labour unequivocally condemns this invasion. It is an unjustifiable act of aggression from President Putin who seems determined to plunge Ukraine into a wider war. We are steadfast in our support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. And we are united with our international allies in our firm opposition to President Putin’s actions.<br />
Labour welcomed the sanctions announced yesterday by the Prime Minister against five Russian banks, and ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-condemns-russian-invasion-of-ukraine/">Labour condemns Russian invasion of Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/labour-condemns-russian-invasion-of-ukraine/"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Britain must respond to Putin with a full set of sanctions, now. <a href="https://t.co/156qPqa6t0">pic.twitter.com/156qPqa6t0</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Keir Starmer (@Keir_Starmer) <a href="https://twitter.com/Keir_Starmer/status/1496143999282909194?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 22, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Yesterday the Prime Minister addressed the House of Commons in response to the Russian invasion of Donetsk and Luhansk in eastern Ukraine.</p>
<p>Labour unequivocally condemns this invasion. It is an unjustifiable act of aggression from President Putin who seems determined to plunge Ukraine into a wider war. We are steadfast in our support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine. And we are united with our international allies in our firm opposition to President Putin’s actions.</p>
<p>Labour welcomed the sanctions announced yesterday by the Prime Minister against five Russian banks, and three Russian billionaires with financial interests in Britain. However, we must go further. The Government has yet to impose a full package of sanctions on Russia. The Labour Party is clear that the time to do this is now. We must also bring an end to the UK being a soft touch on Russian illicit finance. The leader of the Labour Party, Keir Starmer set out how to do this <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2022/feb/20/will-the-tories-hand-back-russian-cash-as-putin-threatens-war">here.</a></p>
<p>If we do not act decisively now, President Putin will once again take away the message that the benefits of aggression outweigh the costs. You can watch the response from the Leader of the Opposition to the Prime Minister’s statement in the clip above or you can read it in full <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-02-22/debates/057FABBB-4F1C-4425-A304-4A168EC069EB/Ukraine#contribution-5C18D9BA-5066-4D2F-9727-4E275606DA84">here</a>&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-7754" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/standing-up-for-social-care/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Liz-Kendall-MP-II-002-150x150.jpg" alt="Standing up for social care" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/standing-up-for-social-care/" class="wp_rp_title">Standing up for social care</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-7224" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/backing-better-health-services-for-beaumont-leys/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/DSCF6595-150x150.jpg" alt="Backing Better Health Services for Beaumont Leys" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/backing-better-health-services-for-beaumont-leys/" class="wp_rp_title">Backing Better Health Services for Beaumont Leys</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-9612" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-catches-up-with-local-police/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Liz-meeting-with-Rob-Randall--150x150.jpg" alt="Liz catches up with local police" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-catches-up-with-local-police/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz catches up with local police</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-3724" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-supports-appointment-of-minister-for-older-people/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/7.jpg" alt="Liz supports appointment of Minister for Older People" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-supports-appointment-of-minister-for-older-people/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz supports appointment of Minister for Older People</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-5060" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/supporting-our-armed-forces/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/DSCF5992-540x4042-150x150.jpg" alt="Supporting our armed forces" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/supporting-our-armed-forces/" class="wp_rp_title">Supporting our armed forces</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-condemns-russian-invasion-of-ukraine/">Labour condemns Russian invasion of Ukraine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Expiry of the Coronavirus Act</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/02/the-expiry-of-the-coronavirus-act/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Prime Minister has stated that he will allow all remaining temporary provisions of the Coronavirus Act to expire on 25 March 2022 as is written into the Coronavirus Act. I welcome this announcement. There has been a great deal of confusion about the Coronavirus Act and how the Government has used it. The Coronavirus Act did give the Government sweeping powers to introduce measures in response to the Covid-19 pandemic such as closing businesses, schools, and restricting gatherings. However, […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18533</id>
    <published>2022-02-23T13:03:27Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-23T13:03:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Forest Hills Driving School Closure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/02/22/petition-to-keep-forest-hills-driving-test-centre-open/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Driver &amp; Vehicle Standards Agency (DVSA) have announced their intention to close the Forest Hills Drive driving test centre on 10th April. This centre came into use in 1980 and for over forty years has been providing driving tests for people predominantly on the east of Southampton. Its closure will be a big blow to [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/02/22/petition-to-keep-forest-hills-driving-test-centre-open/">Forest Hills Driving School Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=4956</id>
    <published>2022-02-22T17:34:29Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-22T17:34:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Local Campaigns"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill responds to Herefordshire Council Cabinet Member for Transport and Infrastructure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/02/18/sir-bill-responds-to-herefordshire-council-cabinet-member-for-transport-and-infrastructure/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Cllr Harrington blames Herefordshire’s current pothole issues on austerity.   Roads are devolved to Herefordshire Council who have a statutory responsibility for managing and maintaining their roads as set out in the Highways Act 1980. Between 2020-2022, the Government provided... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/02/18/sir-bill-responds-to-herefordshire-council-cabinet-member-for-transport-and-infrastructure/#more-4233">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4233</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T09:25:24Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T09:25:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman welcomes £1.5M funding boost for Lincolnshire to support domestic abuse victims</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/02/17/matt-warman-welcomes-1-5m-funding-boost-for-lincolnshire-to-support-domestic-abuse-victims/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li><strong>Matt Warman has welcomed the Conservative Government’s decision to give councils £125 million to provide vital support services for domestic abuse victims in 2022-23, taking the total support to date to £330 million.</strong></li>
<li><strong>This funding will play an important role in funding healthcare, social workers and benefits, interpreters, immigration advice and other specialist services – so that victims of domestic abuse can get the support they need to rebuild their lives.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Building on the Government’s landmark Domestic Abuse Act, this is providing victims and their children with the support they need.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Matt Warman has welcomed the Government’s decision to give Lincolnshire £1,458,158 to provide vital support services for domestic abuse victims, helping victims recover and rebuild their lives.</p>
<p>The Government is providing £125 million to councils across England to make sure that safe accommodation spaces, such as refuges and shelters, can provide victims with vital support services including healthcare, social workers and benefits.</p>
<p>Interpreters, immigration advice, drug or alcohol support and other specialist services will also be funded and made available so that anyone who flees their home gets the help they need.</p>
<p>The funding Lincolnshire will receive from the Government will help them to increase the support they can offer domestic abuse victims, whilst allowing them to choose how the funding is spent to match local priorities and benefit those in need.</p>
<p>The Conservative Government also announced that it will consult on current housing rules, with the aim of giving victims more choice on where they rebuild their lives. By removing Local Connection Tests for abuse victims, this could help victims apply to social housing outside their local area, escaping the community their abuser lives in.</p>
<p><strong>Commenting, Matt Warman said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“Domestic abuse is a horrific crime, and we must do everything we can to help victims recover and rebuild their lives.</p>
<p>“I am pleased the Government is giving additional funding to Lincolnshire to help local victims of abuse and their children start again – with better services such as healthcare, social workers and benefits.</p>
<p>“Combined with the Conservative Government’s landmark Domestic Abuse Act, we are helping victims escape their abusers and making sure that perpetrators feel the full force of the law.”</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Commenting, Rough Sleeping and Housing Minister Eddie Hughes said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“This funding will give victims of domestic abuse and their children across the country the practical and emotional support to recover and rebuild their lives from this terrible crime.</p>
<p>“Through the landmark Domestic Abuse Act, the government has transformed the response to domestic abuse, helping to prevent offending and make sure victims are protected and supported.</p>
<p>“The consultations we are launching today build on this work and will help us give victims more options to move forward with their lives in the way that is right for them.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Commenting, Safeguarding Minister Rachel Maclean said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“Home is not the safe place it should be for domestic abuse victims and their families. The extra support provided today will provide a vital lifeline for victims as they try and rebuild their lives positively while feeling supported and protected.<br/>
“These are important changes that sit alongside the new measures in the Police, Crime, Sentencing and Courts Bill which will give victims of domestic abuse longer to report offences to the police, so that abusers do not evade justice.</p></blockquote>
<p>Notes to editors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Conservative Government has invested more than £330 million since 2014 to provide support for domestic abuse victims in safe accommodation.</strong> Refuge bed spaces have increased by more than 20 per cent in the past 12 years. On top of this, £4 million is being invested in the Respite Rooms programme which supports vulnerable rough sleepers impacted by domestic abuse (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/more-support-for-domestic-abuse-victims-to-rebuild-their-lives">DLUHC, Press release, 15 February 2022</a>).</li>
<li><strong>The Conservative Government’s landmark Domestic Abuse Act 2021 helps keep victims safe and ensures survivors of this horrendous crime get the support they need to rebuild this crime.</strong> The Act defines domestic abuse in law, strengthens protections for victims, and tackles perpetrators at the earliest stage – making sure they feel the full force of the law (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/domestic-abuse-bill-2020-factsheets/domestic-abuse-bill-2020-overarching-factsheet">HO, Policy paper, 31 January 2022</a>).</li>
<li><strong>The Conservative Government is giving domestic abuse victims more time to report assaults – ensuring abusers cannot evade justice.</strong> We are increasing the time to report incidents of common or assault and batter from six months to two years – protecting victims while bringing perpetrators to justice (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/domestic-abuse-victims-in-england-and-wales-to-be-given-more-time-to-report-assaults">MoJ, Press release, 4 January 2022</a>).</li>
</ul>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Matt Warman has welcomed the Conservative Government’s decision to give councils £125 million to provide vital support services for domestic abuse victims in 2022-23, taking the total support to date to £330 million. This funding will play an important role in funding healthcare, social workers and benefits, interpreters, immigration advice […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Matt Warman</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4039</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T10:30:55Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T10:30:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Commemorating Holocaust Memorial Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/02/16/commemorating-holocaust-memorial-day-2/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=640</id>
		<updated>2022-02-16T13:34:25Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-16T11:42:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/02/16/commemorating-holocaust-memorial-day-2/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-end-crisis-in-dentistry/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The current dental contract and under-investment makes work for dentists highly stressful and doesn’t allow them to provide the quality of care to their patients they feel they deserve. There are long-standing problems with burnout, recruiting and retention, with almost a thousand dentists leaving the NHS in England in the last financial year.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the British Dental Association, over 40 million NHS dental appointments have been lost since the start of the pandemic, which amounts to a whole year’s worth of NHS dentistry in pre-COVID times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith continued: “While the government has provided limited amounts of money for dentists to catch up on missed appointments, dental practices in my constituency tell me the funding is virtually unusable. It must be used by March and there is simply physically not enough time to fit these appointments in.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this was an issue brewing long before the pandemic, as even before COVID, there was only enough dentistry for around half of the adult population in England to see an NHS dentist every two years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the debate, Judith said: “There is not a week that goes by where I don’t have someone contacting me about the lack of dentists. We’ve lost a whole year of appointments while the government is giving with one hand and taking away with the other because the government just knows the money just cannot be spent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yorkshire and the Humber has the worst child oral health in the country, with twice the level of tooth decay than in the East of England. In Bradford, almost a thousand children under the age of 10 had to be admitted to hospital to have decayed teeth removed under a general anaesthetic last year. That is thousands of children who are in pain while they await surgery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We need a new deal that treats dentistry as an equal member of the NHS family and not as a Cinderella service. We must work to achieve a fully funded service where NHS dentistry is available to all. The government needs to act and it needs to act now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;84&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, service, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, government, service, year, speaking, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy"&gt;People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy" alt="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A year on from the start of the pandemic, Judith is joining Alzheimer’s Society, TIDE, Dementia UK and John’s Campaign to remember the tens of thousands of people with dementia whose lives have been lost to Covid and to call for lasting change this Coronavirus Action Day. Judith has written&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, lost, pandemic, year, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/282909116.gallery-1-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" alt="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith, alongside Susan Hinchcliffe, leader of the council and Tracy Brabin, candidate for West Yorkshire Mayor, has called for the Government to ensure there is a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop in the city centre. Representing all three of Bradford's Labour MPs, Judith said: "There is a world out there that&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;80&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse. Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes: “The current dental contract and under-investment makes […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2587</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T13:22:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T13:22:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Belt: How to save the lungs of London</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/green-belt-how-save-lungs-london" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My top priority for 2022 is protecting our green spaces and particularly preserving our Green Belt land in the south of the county. The last two years have taught us how precious these spaces are, their importance to the character of our communities, and the vital role they play in all of our…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/green-belt-how-save-lungs-london</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southern Rail Update – February 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Chris,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow up on previous emails about changes to the timetable in February, I wanted to confirm the plan.  We will be amending our timetables from Monday 28 February, following a period of significant staff absence due to Covid and a major blockade of engineering works on the Brighton mainline between 19-27 February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the picture is improving overall, and the direct impact of Covid on colleagues is reducing, its legacy continues to have an impact on our business and services.  One example is a backlog of driver training due to previous social distancing requirements where, for example, two people were not permitted to be in a train cab together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the short term, we have taken a prudent approach to adding services, with the aim of ensuring we can offer reliability, rather than having to cancel trains last minute and create large gaps in the service.  We want to thank customers for their patience and understanding throughout this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now starting to see more people return to rail, albeit in much lower numbers than before the pandemic, particularly as people continue to work from home some of the week. We will therefore be introducing a new timetable from Monday 28 February to ensure our services and resources are the best possible fit.  We are focusing on providing more capacity for commuters returning to the office. Our February timetable change includes more direct services to London Victoria and London Bridge, increases to peak services, especially in the early morning and in areas where there are no other public transport options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what this means specifically for your constituency, Southern services will return to the timetable used in the Autumn of 2021 from the 21 February.  This means that the direct routes to London Victoria from Epsom via Hackbridge and Epsom Downs via West Croydon will resume, as will Tattenham Corner’s fast trains to London Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the Autumn, something to be aware of is while the service from Epsom to London Bridge will resume, there will be a reduced frequency in the morning. Trains from Epsom to London Bridge will depart at 05:45, 07:16, 08:15 then every 30 minutes until 22:45. The reason being, as in September, the morning peak is the busiest point on the network and we will be seeking to spread our available crew resource as best we possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual journeys for the timetable of 28 February are due in journey planners this week and we will be increasing customer communications about the changes.  We advise customers to plan their journeys in advance and re-check before they travel, especially the weeks commencing 21 February and 28 February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior Stakeholder Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/"&gt;Southern Rail Update &amp;#8211; February 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Chris, To follow up on previous emails about changes to the timetable in February, I wanted to confirm the plan.  We will be amending our timetables from Monday 28 February, following a period of significant staff absence due to Covid and a major blockade of engineering works on the Brighton mainline between 19-27 February. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/">Southern Rail Update – February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6225</id>
    <published>2022-02-14T10:25:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-14T10:25:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-a-tale-of-two-reports" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p>Last week saw two publications from the UK Government, both of them were unedifying and deeply unsatisfactory in their own ways.</p>
<p>The Sue Gray update, which was supposed to be a complete, unredacted report of the rule-breaking parties at number 10 Downing Street, rightly got a lot of attention in the press.</p>
<p>I’ve received hundreds of emails from many of you, sharing your anger at the lack of respect and humility shown by the Prime Minister and his Government. I am sure it won’t surprise you that I share your frustration at the situation, and I wish I could do more than respond with words of agreement. Rest assured, in Parliament, I will continue to make your views on the subject heard.</p>
<p>The Sue Gray update was a heavily censored summary but made it clear that there had been ‘Serious failures of leadership” at Number ten. The Prime Minister cannot escape this verdict; he is the leader at No. 10. No amount of cover-up and no matter how high the mountain of lies, the fact is that he is unfit to hold office. He said he was “furious” with staff when the story first broke and, remember, gratefully accepted the resignation of his Press Secretary, Allegra Stratton, before Christmas. Yet, he thinks he can carry on regardless.</p>
<p>The second report published last week was the ‘Benefits of Brexit’ report. It was published alongside the Sue Gray report – obviously, a failed attempt to divert the news cycle. Frustratingly, it only got minimal coverage, and there was little to no opportunity to challenge the Government on their supposed ‘advantages of Brexit included in the report. (You can watch my full response <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XbYQGRBVD3Y&amp;ab_channel=DrewHendry">here</a>.)</p>
<p>The report is over 100 pages yet fails to acknowledge the catastrophic impacts of Brexit on businesses and households. It offers no solutions or answers. The report lists’ cheaper holidays in the EU’ as a flagship Brexit achievement. Hundreds of thousands of families are struggling to find the money to pay for fuel to drive to work because of the tory costs of living crisis – never mind holiday abroad.</p>
<p>The report goes on to celebrate the fact that Brexit is ‘Saving UK consumers money by allowing them to do more of their shopping duty-free.’ Again, talking up high-end shopping in airports when more and more folk can’t even afford to do their weekly food shop shows just how out of touch this UK Government are. Where’s the part of the report that acknowledges Brexit’s impact on prices; where’s the solution from this Government?</p>
<p>Of course, there was enough space in the report for an entire section dedicated to  ‘Global Britain’. Yet, it is hard to remember a time when the UK’s reputation was so much in tatters.</p>
<p>These two documents sum up Westminster – and why we now need to make our own decisions, here, in Scotland.</p>
<p>I will keep highlighting the severe impact of the cost of living crisis and the energy price hike on your families. I also want to remind you all that if there is anything you think I may be able to help your family with, please get in touch with my office. While I cannot promise to fix the problem, my team and I will do all we can to help or point you in the right direction. Please don’t suffer alone – support is out there.</p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com/">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last week saw two publications from the UK Government, both of them were unedifying and deeply unsatisfactory in their own ways. The Sue Gray update, which was supposed to be a complete, unredacted report of the rule-breaking parties at number 10 Downing Street, rightly got a lot of attention in the press. I’ve received hundreds …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6245</id>
    <published>2022-02-10T10:10:54Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-10T10:10:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="EU / Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Smear on Demand]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/02/08/smear-on-demand/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1611</id>
		<updated>2022-02-08T11:08:10Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-08T11:08:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="cancer"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="healthcare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="HPV"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="smear"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="women"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/02/08/smear-on-demand/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on the cost of living crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_costofliving" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Ofgem has announced that the energy price cap will increase by £693 from April.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_costofliving</id>
    <published>2022-02-04T13:39:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-04T13:39:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job advert: Caseworker for Tulip Siddiq MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/job-ad-caseworker-for-tulip-siddiq-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing date: Sunday 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Job title: Caseworker&lt;br&gt;Working for: Tulip Siddiq MP&lt;br&gt;Location: Constituency Office (Hampstead and Kilburn)&lt;br&gt;Salary: In line with IPSA payscales and dependent on experience&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team and support constituents as a caseworker. Previous experience of this or a similar role is desirable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The position will be based primarily in Tulip&amp;#8217;s constituency office in Hampstead and Kilburn and there will also be opportunities to work from the Parliamentary office in Westminster. We are happy to discuss options for flexible working at any stage including part-time remote working, flexi-time, job shares and other forms of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assist with surgeries and other meetings and follow up as appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Respond to daily correspondence and enquiries from constituents.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage professionally, confidentially and sensitively with members of the public, through telephone enquiries, emails, social media and face to face.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Liaise with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve issues facing constituents.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manage a large caseload of complex cases, exercising good judgement in taking decisions about how to procced and ensuring all identified actions are taken.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure all cases are logged in line with data protection legislation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Help other members of the team when needed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills Required&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Excellent written and oral communication skills as well as the usual IT skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clear and concise letter writing style.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to prioritise a demanding workload to meet deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to deal with issues sensitively and in a confidential manner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to work effectively in a small team.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sympathetic to the aims and objectives of the Labour Party.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview/Start dates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interviews will be held in London the week starting 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February and will involve written tasks. The start date will be as soon as possible after that, to be agreed with the successful candidate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applicants should send their CV and a one page covering letter to &lt;a href="mai&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x74;&amp;#x75;lip&amp;#46;&amp;#115;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x64;&amp;#x64;&amp;#x69;q.m&amp;#112;&amp;#64;&amp;#x70;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x72;&amp;#x6c;iam&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#x74;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6b;"&gt;&amp;#x74;u&amp;#x6c;i&amp;#x70;&amp;#46;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x69;d&amp;#x64;i&amp;#x71;&amp;#46;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#112;&amp;#64;&amp;#x70;a&amp;#x72;&amp;#108;&amp;#x69;&amp;#97;m&amp;#x65;n&amp;#x74;.&amp;#x75;&amp;#107;&lt;/a&gt; with the subject heading ‘Caseworker – Full name’. Due to the expected high volume of applications, only successful those applicants selected for interview will receive a response.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Closing date: Sunday 13th February 2022 Job title: CaseworkerWorking for: Tulip Siddiq MPLocation: Constituency Office (Hampstead and Kilburn)Salary: In line with IPSA payscales and dependent on experience Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team and support constituents as a caseworker. Previous […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Taggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5524</id>
    <published>2022-02-02T19:07:02Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-02T19:07:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Job ad"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>City Council Leader Responds to “Levelling Up” Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today Nottingham City Council Leader, Cllr David Mellen responded to the Government&amp;#8217;s long overdue &amp;#8220;Levelling Up&amp;#8221; White Paper, cautiously welcoming the next steps on devolution but highlighting that these words do little to reverse the damage that twelve years of unprecedented Conservative cuts has caused to Nottingham. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cllr Mellen said: “Nottingham people will hear the
Government talking about ‘levelling up’ today, but they will wonder what it
really means for them in their daily lives and what it means for the place they
call home. That is the big test for the Government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Words from Government Ministers won’t deal with the
soaring cost of energy and food or assist with the enormous pressures on
household budgets. In April many of the people I represent will see big
increases in National Insurance, steeply rising prices for home-energy and the
government’s adult social care levy added to Council Tax bills yet again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I’ve worked proactively with colleagues in other Councils
across Nottinghamshire to make the case to government about the investment our
area desperately needs after 12 long years of cuts and underfunding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’ve always been pro- devolution in Nottingham, but
detail in terms of additional powers and new investment must be forthcoming. If
Government is serious about genuine devolution for our area it has to be about
more investment, better transport infrastructure, higher skills for local
people and creating more good jobs in our area.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The East Midlands region has suffered greatly over the
past decade with chronic under investment. Our residents and our businesses
expect and deserve much better than the sustained funding cuts we’ve seen and
the huge regional funding variations with the East Midlands often losing out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the government is finally recognising that to create
stronger regional growth that the investment is required I absolutely welcome
that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is imperative that the Minister matches his word with
deeds and begins to deliver in a meaningful way.&amp;nbsp; As a Core City,
Nottingham has much to be proud of and much to build on. We have ambitious plans
to truly unlock the potential of our area and be at the heart of growth in our
region, plans that are ready to be put into action if we get the green light on
funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I urge the government to work with us, to adequately fund
local public services, which continue to be under severe strain, to invest in
the huge potential of Nottingham, Nottinghamshire and the East Midlands and to
start to deliver for people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/"&gt;City Council Leader Responds to &amp;#8220;Levelling Up&amp;#8221; Announcement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Today Nottingham City Council Leader, Cllr David Mellen responded to the Government’s long overdue “Levelling Up” White Paper, cautiously welcoming the next steps on devolution but highlighting that these words do little to reverse the damage that twelve years of unprecedented Conservative cuts has caused to Nottingham.  Cllr Mellen said: “Nottingham people will hear the...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/">City Council Leader Responds to “Levelling Up” Announcement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2703</id>
    <published>2022-02-02T15:06:59Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-02T15:06:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cllr Linda Bailey, Rest in Peace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/cllr-linda-bailey-rest-peace" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of our most dedicated, hugely respected and long-standing campaigners, Linda Bailey, sadly passed away on the 25th January 2022. Our thoughts are with her family and friends, who also very recently lost Linda’s husband, Bill.
During her decades of support for our Association and the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/cllr-linda-bailey-rest-peace</id>
    <published>2022-01-27T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Susah bermain akan membuat penghasilan macet dan berimbas pada kehidupan. Tapi hal tersebut bisa diatas dengan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Permainan taruhan sepakbola sudah menjadi kegiatan sehari hari bagi banyak orang. Tua muda atau pun dewasa memainkan permainan yang satu ini. Tak heran sebenarnya karena bola adalah permainan berbagai kalangan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sudah ada kecintaan terhadap permainan bola membuat permainan versi judi akan disukai. Hanya dengan menebak permainan sepele saja sudah akan bisa menghasilkan untung siapa yang tahan? Oleh karena itu tak heran minat memainkan taruhan sepakbola semakin membludak akhir akhir ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapi, ada dilema yang membuat permainantaruhan sepakbola banyak penggemar terjadi. Dilema tersebut adalah susah bermain. Banyak pemain akan membuat server sering mengalami trouble yang berakibat pada susah bermain. Sudah sering terjadi seperti pada pendaftaran cpns yang selalu membuat server breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleh sebab itu, untuk mengatasi permasalahan yang akan terjadi. Pastikan diri Anda menggunakan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Dengan link tersebut semuanya akan bisa teratasi, tetapi juga akan ada cara lainnya yang mungkin akan berfungsi untuk Anda. Tergantung dari permasalahan yang anda alami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif Resmi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untuk permasalahan link yang mengalami breakdown, Anda bisa menggunakan link alternatif. Setiap agen penyedia permainan pasti menyediakan link situs taruhan sepakbola terpercaya alternatif. Dengan link tersebut, Anda akan mendapatkan bantuan untuk tetap bermain meskipun server sudah tidak bisa dibuka karena kepenuhan user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link alternatif ini adalah lalu lintas alternatif bila lalu lintas pokok mengalami masalah. Jadi, lalu lintas browsing Anda dialihkan kepada cara lain. Meskipun menggunakan cara lain Anda akan tetap bisa digunakan dengan mudah tanpa harus melakukan hal khusus. Untuk menggunakannya, Anda hanya perlu mengakses seperti biasanya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lantas dimana tempat mendapatkan link alternatif? Tepatnya anda bisa mendapatkan link alternatif pada bagian laman pengenal. Atau mungkin lebih amannya Anda bertanya kepada costumer service. Mereka pasti akan memberikan link alternatif agar anggota anggotanya tetap bisa bermain meskipun situs utama breakdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bila Anda belum sempat mendapatkan link alternatif. Bergabunglah kepada forum diskusi karena biasanya mereka akan mendiskusikan link alternatif juga. Dengan begini Anda akan mendapatkan informasi yang bagus mengenai link terpercaya. Link terpercaya seperti ini pastinya akan berguna untuk Anda dapatkan permainan yang akurat serta aman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vpn, Proxy, Kpn Tunnel untuk Situs Terblokir&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sedangkan untuk permasalahan link live casino taruhan sepakbola terpercaya yang mengalami blokir. Anda bisa menggunakan vpn, proxy, kpn tunnel dan penyamar alamat ip. Dengan alamat ip yang disamarkan pasti akan tetap membuka situs yang mengalami blokir. Alat alat seperti ini banyak jenisnya namun yang direkomendasikan adalah vpn, proxy dan kpn tunnel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dengan ketiga alat tersebut, Anda akan bisa membuka situs yang terblokir tanpa susah. Untuk vpn cara kerjanya dengan aplikasi kebanyakan, sedangkan untuk proxy dan kpn tunnel kebanyakan cara kerjanya dengan browser. Tetapi tetap ada cara lainnya yang bisa Anda pergunakan sesuai dengan selera pribadi diri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cara kerja yang digunakan oleh alat alat ini sebenarnya tidak jaug berbeda dengan link w2ebsite taruhan sepakbola terpercaya. Tetapi disini alamat yang anda gunakan tetap sama dengan alamat utamanya. Tidak ada alamat yang berbeda karena yang akan disamarkan adalah ip Anda. Sebenarnya cara seperti ini akan lebih aman dibandingkan sebelumnya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semua masalah susah bermain pasti akan bisa teratasi bila Anda tahu permasalahannya. Sekarang zaman sudah canggih dan semuanya bisa Anda atasi tanpa perlu bantuan teknisi. Banyak aplikasi dan solusi untuk mengatasi permasalahan susah bermain. Oleh sebab itu selalu catat link website taruhan sepakbola terpercaya dari tempat Anda bermain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca Juga Tentang: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/provider-situs-slot-online-gacor-jackpot-terlengkap-2022/"&gt;Provider Situs Slot Online Gacor Jackpot Terlengkap 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain – Susah bermain akan membuat penghasilan macet dan berimbas pada kehidupan. Tapi hal tersebut bisa diatas dengan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Permainan taruhan sepakbola sudah menjadi kegiatan sehari hari bagi banyak orang. Tua muda atau pun dewasa memainkan permainan yang satu ini. Tak heran […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/">Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=27</id>
    <published>2022-01-25T06:31:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-25T06:31:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Judi Bola"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jakson</name>
							<uri>https://jakson.co</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Residents&#8217; Zoom meeting]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/</id>
		<updated>2022-01-11T18:16:55Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-23T12:19:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="In Parliament"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subscribe to my future newsletters&#160;here Dear Constituent, I hope you&#8217;re keeping safe and well. Please find my latest newsletter, with news of what&#8217;s been happening in Parliament and what&#8217;s coming up with Brexit. I&#8217;m also holding another zoom residents&#8217; meeting, on Friday 27th November &#8211; please get in touch for the details if you would [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters&nbsp;<a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/1507626306.png"></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>I hope you&#8217;re keeping safe and well. Please find my latest newsletter, with news of what&#8217;s been happening in Parliament and what&#8217;s coming up with Brexit. I&#8217;m also holding another zoom residents&#8217; meeting, on Friday 27th November &#8211; please get in touch for the details if you would like to join.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Invitation to Zoom residents&#8217; meeting&nbsp;&#8211; 7.30pm, Friday 27th November&nbsp;2020:</span></strong></p>
<p>Thank you to everyone who has joined my virtual residents&#8217; meetings so far. My next residents&#8217; meeting will be held at 7.30pm on Friday 27th November&nbsp;2020, again via&nbsp;Zoom, to discuss the latest on Brexit and Covid-19 measures, and answer any questions you may have.</p>
<p>If you’re a constituent and would like to attend, please reply to this email or email nigel.mills.mp@parliament.uk and I’ll send you the link to join the meeting.</p>
<p>As always, if you have a personal or specific issue you would like to raise with me, or for a virtual surgery appointment, do also continue to contact me by replying to this&nbsp;email or by ringing 01773 744341.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit update:</span></strong></p>
<p>Time is now getting very tight for a future partnership with the EU to be negotiated, agreed, ratified and in place in time for the end of the Transition period on 31 December 2020. The expectation seems to be that a deal will be done in the next few days or not at all (or at least not until next year).</p>
<p>The issues seem to be much the same as in my last update, namely fishing, equivalence of regulatory standards between the UK and the EU (the so called level playing field) and state aid rules. I&nbsp; have set out a summary of the these issues and potential areas of compromise below.</p>
<p>I remain of the view that the best way forward for the UK would be to agree a good deal with the EU covering not just trade but also security, law and order, travel rights for citizens etc. That said, if we can’t agree a deal which respects our right to govern ourselves than we should walk away. I have seen no sign that the Government will give up this key red line but equally there will need to be some compromises to achieve a deal. Avoiding tariffs on imports and exports is a huge prize that will make the move out of the EU much smoother. As vice-chair of the Select Committee scrutinising the negotiations with the EU, I have been examining many of the key issues for the negotiations and our preparedness– you can see the details <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-exiting-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-exiting-the-european-union">here</a> – and I am looking forward to in depth scrutiny of any deal in the coming weeks.</p>
<p><strong>Main outstanding issues:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fishing is a totemic Brexit issue, and out fishing industry has suffered especially badly over the last 40 years. Leaving the EU gives us the opportunity to rebuild our industry and catch a much higher proportion of the fish in our waters. Of course this means that EU fishing communities will lose out. The arguments are around how the quotas for each type of fish are calculated and how they are allocated between UK and EU fleets, with the UK wanting the default position under international maritime agreements of annual negotiations and the EU wanting to a long term agreement that retains most of their current access. The further challenge is that much of the fish caught in UK waters is exported to the EU. In reality it will take us many years to increase our fishing fleet and processing capacity so it would seem to me that a deal could be found based around gradual reductions in EU access to our waters via some form of transition.</li>
<li>The EU’s original negotiation position on the level playing field demanded dynamic alignment ie the UK would have to follow not just current EU rules but whatever they changed them to in key areas like environment, workers rights, taxation etc. In their view this would prevent us competing unfairly with them. This demand was very different to the wording agreed in the Political Declaration agreed a year ago which envisaged a non-regression clause ie we would not reduce key regulatory standards below the levels as at 31 December 2020. We could clearly never agree to blindly follow future EU rules over which we had no say. The discussion appears to have reverted back to non-regression clauses but with issues over how either side could enforce action against any breaches. Given that we are strengthening environmental standards and already go further than the EU rules in many areas on workers rights, I would not be too concerned about agreeing not to reduce standards in these areas. It would then seem possible to agree that if either side did make fundamental changes, the other side could give notice to terminate the trade deal either entirely on in part if they considered the issue serious enough.</li>
<li>State Aid rules restrict how much subsidy Governments can give to businesses. Currently if the UK government wishes to provide State Aid, we, like all EU members, need permission from the EU Commission. They also review whether policies like low tax rates or exemptions effectively represent State Aid. The UK has generally not been keen on State Aid in comparison to many other EU countries. Originally the EU seemed to want the UK to remain subject to the EU rules – clearly we could not as an independent country be in a position of following EU rules and especially not seeking permission from the EU. The talk seem to have progressed now to the UK being willing to set out rules which hare equivalent to EU ones on where State Aid can be used (indeed the WTO requires such rules anyway) but the dispute remains how these rules will be enforced so a UK government couldn’t just ignore them. The proposal seems to be for some sort of independent regulator but it strikes me that again, in extremis, giving notice to cancel the trade&nbsp; agreement would be an effective remedy.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Latest Covid-19 guidance:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can find the current Covid-19 guidance <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>, along with the support available for residents (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/worker-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/worker-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>) and businesses (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>). The latest business grants for businesses affected by the recent restrictions are now available through the local Council, which you can find <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/covid-19-business-grants/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/covid-19-business-grants/">here</a>. For constituents self-isolating who are struggling financially, there is also the £500 self-isolation NHS Test &amp; Trace Support payment, which you can find further details on the eligibility criteria for <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/benefits/test-and-trace-support-payment/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/benefits/test-and-trace-support-payment/">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">If you have any queries about the guidance or potential support available, as always, please don&#8217;t hesitate to get in touch.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Defence Spending update:&nbsp;</strong></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Last week, the Prime Minister announced an additional £24.1 billion in funding for our country&#8217;s defence, to help safeguard our security and revitalise our shipbuilding industry. Over the next four years, this investment will create 10,000 extra jobs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">This is the largest investment in our defence industry in the last 30 years and&nbsp;</span>will allow the Government to invest in cutting-edge technology &#8211;&nbsp;positioning the UK as a global leader in domains such as cyber and space and cementing the UK’s position as the largest defence spender in Europe and the second largest in NATO.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">I welcomed this update, and the increased investment, during the subsequent debate on it in the House. I also highlighted the need to spend this additional money wisely and efficiently, and buy from British suppliers wherever possible. You can find the debate in full <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-19a.487.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g501.6" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-19a.487.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g501.6">here</a>&nbsp;and read more about the investment <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/defence-secures-largest-investment-since-the-cold-war" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/defence-secures-largest-investment-since-the-cold-war">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">In Parliament:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">In Parliament I&#8217;ve continued my work on anti-corruption and pensions, with questions in the House on preventing economic crime to further reduce corruption. You can find my question to the Chancellor in full <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-09b.619.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g627.3" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-09b.619.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g627.3">here</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">With a local focus, I&#8217;ve also highlighted the importance of supporting the recovery of our high streets from the challenges caused by Covid-19, with one example being the recent announcement of the closure of many Argos stores, including the one in Alfreton. I know many independent retailers are also struggling (even though they&#8217;ve come up with many innovative ways to continue trading during this time), and so I will continue to raise this issue. You can find my most recent question in Parliament <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-05c.483.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g488.2" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-05c.483.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g488.2">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Lastly, on a positive note, I welcomed the announcement of an additional bank holiday for the Queen&#8217;s platinum jubilee, and raised the issue of support or grants for community groups to hopefully be able to organise events to commemorate and celebrate this big event &#8211; you can find more on this debate <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-12b.1086.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g1093.3" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-12b.1086.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g1093.3">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Pension Schemes Bill:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Earlier this month, I also contributed to a debate in Parliament on the new Pensions Schemes Bill, which continues to progress through the Houses (you can find out more about the bill <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-8693/" data-cke-saved-href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-8693/">here</a>). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">As a member of the Work &amp; Pensions Select Committee, I&#8217;ve been working on this Bill, and I took the opportunity of the debate in the Commons on the latest stage to highlight various amendments I was supporting, including the importance of encouraging a greater take-up of&nbsp;independent free guidance to help people decide which pension option&nbsp;is best for them, scam prevention measures, improving pension dashboards and encouraging pension funds to support investment in climate goals and positive social activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">I&#8217;m really keen for to make pensions guidance as close to mandatory as possible, for instance through auto-enrolment onto the pensions dashboard, as the current take-up of the free, good quality advice provided by Pensions Wise guidance service is very low. I will continue to push the Government to introduce measures to improve and promote usage of pensions advice services.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can find my speeches in full, and the rest of the debate,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-16b.55.2&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g68.1" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-16b.55.2&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g68.1">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Select Committees:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">In other Work &amp; Pensions Committee inquiries, we&#8217;re looking into Universal Credit and the wait for a first payment, the disability employment gap and DWP&#8217;s response to the Covid-19 pandemic, including the use of foodbanks and support available for people experiencing food and fuel poverty (which you can find more on <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/news/130962/committee-holds-session-on-support-for-people-claiming-benefits/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/news/130962/committee-holds-session-on-support-for-people-claiming-benefits/">here</a>). You can find more about all of these current inquiries and evidence sessions&nbsp;<a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/">here</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can also find full details of the evidence sessions recently held by the Committee on the Future Relationship with the European Union, as mentioned above, <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" rel="noopener">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">GDPR and privacy notice:</span></strong></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com?wpmllink=56631c0a7eeed56aa432bf53c6b13695&amp;history_id=83&amp;subscriber_id=5667" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com?wpmllink=56631c0a7eeed56aa432bf53c6b13695&amp;history_id=83&amp;subscriber_id=5667">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Nigel-signature.jpg"></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Statement on Plan B Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/planb" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Lots of people have been getting in touch to ask about my position on the Government's decision to move to Plan B and the votes in Parliament this week. Due to medical reasons I was unable to be in Parliament to vote, however, I wanted to set out my position on this important matter.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/planb</id>
    <published>2021-12-15T09:40:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T09:40:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Benefits of Distance Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">Right now, the pros of distance learning in school are not at all obvious to thousands of teachers. It seems that distance education is nothing but inconvenience, a threat to discipline and academic performance. But it isn't: distance education has many advantages. 

<strong>Here are some of them.</strong>

<strong> The opportunity to work with each student individually. </strong>

<strong>1) Distance teaching technology helps to find a personal approach to each student. </strong>There are times when a shy child is shy to work actively in a classroom where twenty classmates are staring at him. 
But such a shy kid feels freer at a distance, asks the teacher questions in a chat room, and successfully completes tasks. And the teacher can choose additional tasks for such students, which correspond to their aptitudes, to maintain an interest in learning. 
Distance learning is a great chance to get to know your students better.

<strong> 2) Automate routine processes.</strong>

Simply put, technology can take over the most boring part of a teacher's job. For example, checking homework and compiling classroom statistics. On average, using technologies with automatic checking will save at least 1-2 hours per day, if not more. This system works very simply: the teacher goes to the site, selects a subject, class and topic, finds the appropriate assignment and sends a link to the students, and then just look at the same site to see how they did. 

<strong> 3) A chance to learn new technology. </strong>

The high demand for teachers with distance learning experience is a reality. Knowing how to use interactive learning platforms, Google Docs, electronic workbooks, and video conferencing services increases your value in the job market and gives you a chance to find a part-time job at an online school (and there are many such schools, they are growing and in need of new personnel). But even more valuable are the skills to organize your time, work with students remotely, and be able to monitor and motivate them from a distance. If you can manage it now, by the next school year you can try your hand at online tutoring.

<strong>4) Game assignments. </strong>

Distance learning involves a very active use of digital technology. Including gamified tasks: online games, quizzes, interactive tasks for ingenuity. Let us not forget that for any child the game is the most natural way to learn the world. And older students like these more dry tasks from the textbook. Games not only make learning fun - they help to evaluate progress and bring to school an element of healthy competition. Learning games are not part of the official curriculum, but we recommend that you dilute regular assignments with them. A child who enjoys learning will make more progress than one who is bored in class.

<strong>Minuses of Distance Education</strong>

<strong>1. Limited choice</strong>

Unfortunately, not everything can be learned remotely. In some cases, you cannot do without practical studies under the guidance of an experienced tutor. You can study history or literature remotely, you can become an excellent designer or programmer. But you cannot learn to be a pilot or a surgeon.

Perhaps that will change in the near future. One day, virtual reality technology will allow people from different parts of the world to participate in collaborative lab work. When that happens, the list of professions and skills that can be learned remotely will greatly expand.

<strong>2. Lack of face-to-face interaction</strong>
Face-to-face learning is not only valuable as a set of knowledge. An important element of offline learning is personal communication. While getting traditional higher education, a student spends several years simmering in the swirling cauldron of university life. He interacts with professors and classmates in an informal setting. These interactions can generate amazing ideas and dramatically change people's lives.

<strong>3. the absence of positive "side effects</strong>
The fact that distance learning gives a person a specific set of knowledge can be considered not only a plus, but also a minus. By studying remotely, a person deprives himself of many of the positive "side effects" of academic education.

For example, the process of taking notes on long lectures trains the speed of writing, develops mechanical memory, and teaches on the fly to isolate the most important fragments from the flow of information. All these skills are very useful in everyday life, but distance learning does not provide them.</pre>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/">Benefits of Distance Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Right now, the pros of distance learning in school are not at all obvious to thousands of teachers. It seems that distance education is nothing but inconvenience, a threat to discipline and academic performance. But […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/">Benefits of Distance Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=191</id>
    <published>2021-11-10T09:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T09:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Community Spirit Within The Aberavon Constituency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/community-spirit-within-the-aberavon-constituency/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2731</id>
    <published>2021-10-04T12:24:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T12:24:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1615380759618">

<div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- ">

	
	<p>Steve Reed has asked Croydon Council to listen to local people over the future of South Norwood Library.  The library’s future is uncertain because the Conservative Government has cut funding to Croydon by 70% and pushed it into a financial crisis.</p>
<p>Local MP Steve Reed has spoken to residents and campaign groups who are fighting to save the library.  He’s now written to the Council asking them to consider how closing the library will affect the areas poorest residents who may not have access to WiFi or quiet spaces for learning or reading at home.  He’s also asked the Council to fully involve the local community before taking any decisions.</p>
<p>Steve Reed said: “Croydon Council is faced with some really difficult decisions after ten years of Conservative funding cuts.  But they do not have to go it alone. Now more than ever people want a say over what happens in their area. The Council should harness this enthusiasm and work with residents to come up with plan that could protect library services for South Norwood.”</p>
<p><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/ue8jCq7zvFrArvJhZnZ9o?domain=stevereedmp.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">You can see the full letter here.</a></p>
<p>If you would like to get involved in the campaign to save South Norwood library, email Steve at steve.reed@croydonlabour.org.uk</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	<div class="templatera_shortcode">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"/>

<div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center"><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span><div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"><div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey"><span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"/></div></div><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span>
</div></div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-">
	<ul>

	
		<li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7">
			<div class="item-holder">
				<div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true">
							<img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-pd7vw3u9f02hah596hrf1872w2mpjdjw6lnhj87yk8.png" data-mk-image-src-set="{&quot;default&quot;:&quot;https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg&quot;,&quot;2x&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;mobile&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;responsive&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}"/>


					
				</div>

				<div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">
						<span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333">Steve Reed</span>
					<span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1">Member of Parliment for Croydon North</span>
					
					<div class="clearboth"/>

					
<ul class="mk-employeee-networks">
			<li><a target="_blank" href="mailto:steve.reed.mp@parliament.uk" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-62252717410a1" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-622527174128a" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-6225271741422" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-622527174150e" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/></svg></a></li>
	</ul>
				</div>
			</div>
		</li>

					<div class="clearboth"/>
			</ul>
<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>
</div>

<div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155">

<div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text">

	
	<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steven Reed</a> is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/">reducing violent mental health restraint</a> became law. In June 2019 he launched <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/">Labour’s civil society strategy</a> outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>
</div></div>
	</div>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Reed MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10621</id>
    <published>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</updated>
    <category term="Croydon Community Notice Board"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time>
</div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=FbA6IxF7" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/>



  </div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>


</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Alec urges all constituents to book their COVID-19 vaccination or access the NHS Test &amp; Trace system if you have symptoms. </p>
<p><strong>Vaccine</strong></p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved a number of vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has organised the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, with all adults now eligible to book a vaccine. You can book your vaccine online <a href="https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/coronavirus-vaccination/book-coronavirus-vaccination/">here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Testing</strong></p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Help from Alec</strong></p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Alec urges all constituents to book their COVID-19 vaccination or access the NHS Test &amp; Trace system if you have symptoms. Vaccine The UK medical regulatory agency has approved a number of vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has organised the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, with all adults now eligible to book a vaccine....  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6225285d1154d" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6225285d1154d').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6225285d1154d","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6225285d1154d" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6225285d1154d" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6225285d1154d" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6225285d1154d" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6225285d1154d" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6225285d1154d" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6225285d1154d" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6225285d1154d" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6225285d1154d" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6225285d1154d_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6225285d1154d script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dyClVzGhaUOp27WxoxFDVV7g1ceybeC31OHiGHZnnITaxzCYfecyamUuP7SrRaKwZIY2_2W9JzU7MSBAJ3FgA' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
