<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-10-08T15:31:39Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Veterans in Action BBQ</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/veterans-in-action-bbq/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=veterans-in-action-bbq" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Over the last few years I’ve got to know this brilliant little charity quite well. We’ve done sponsored walks and visits, and as they’ve developed their facilities at Redenham, I’ve dropped by the catch up. And so it was last week when I dropped in to their annual barbecue when they thank supporters and let people have a look around. The brain child of Billy MacLeod MBE, the organisation works with veterans struggling with PTSD and other mental health challenges, giving them confidence and a sense of mission in their lives. It’s a really good example of a little platoon making a huge difference, rebuilding lives one by one. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over the last few years I’ve got to know this brilliant little charity quite well. We’ve done sponsored walks and visits, and as they’ve developed their facilities at Redenham, I’ve dropped by the catch up. And so it was last week when I dropped in to their annual barbecue when they thank supporters and let […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2958</id>
    <published>2022-10-08T14:48:01Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-08T14:48:01Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Treasury orthodoxy and Bank of England error</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/10/08/treasury-orthodoxy-and-bank-of-england-error/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This government was right to express concern about Treasury orthodoxy and should have added Bank of England error. Together these terrible twins visited on us the European Exchange Rate mechanism which gave us boom/ bust 1988-92, gave us the boom/ bust of the banking crash of 2006-9, and now threatens to give us the Quantitative easing boom/recession of 2020-23.  The government did need to cushion the blow of the energy crunch, and did need to offset the recessionary forces that have been unleashed by the surges in energy bills.</p>
<p>The Bank of England should take more of the blame for the slump in government bond prices from the Thursday of their rate rising statement through to the collapse the following Wednesday. Their decision to raise the official interest rate, to point to more rises to come and  their decision to sell bonds to drive longer interest rates higher was the main cause of the bond sell off. To avoid spooking the markets again when they end their temporary prop to the markets they should announce they will not sell any bonds at these depressed prices to reassure markets.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the Treasury has resumed its belief that economic policy has to be steered by a commitment to get debt as a percentage  of GDP down. In recent years pursuing this policy they have cajoled Chancellors to put in tax rises to do this. Instead a poorly performing economy has ended up with rises in state debt. The tax rises do not offset the extra spending all the time growth stays low. Last year when growth accelerated the deficit tumbled way below OBR forecasts.</p>
<p>The government should switch economic control to their growth target and the 2% inflation target. That  way we should allow lower tax rates as part of a growth strategy, and a counter inflation discipline that was sadly lacking in 2020-21.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This government was right to express concern about Treasury orthodoxy and should have added Bank of England error. Together these terrible twins visited on us the European Exchange Rate mechanism which gave us boom/ bust 1988-92, gave us the boom/ bust of the banking crash of 2006-9, and now threatens to give us the Quantitative…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33576</id>
    <published>2022-10-08T04:00:48Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-08T04:00:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conservative Conference</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/conservative-conference" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7266" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">7 October 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Conservative Conference</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>I have been in Birmingham attending the Conservative Party Conference this week.</p>

<p>I write before the speech by Prime Minister Liz Truss on Wednesday, but this Conference has provided her first opportunity to expand on her policy priorities to members and the public.</p>

<p>We live in extraordinary times. There is war in mainland Europe, which most people reading this column have never experienced before. The consequences of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine are most immediately and obviously felt by the tragedy he is inflicting on the people of Ukraine.</p>

<p>But the impact is being felt by us all, as energy costs have soared around the world.</p>

<p>Rising energy costs have led to inflation levels which we have not seen for 40 years, which in turn has led to the Bank of England raising interest rates to attempt to get inflation under control. This is impacting mortgages and will reduce economic activity.</p>

<p>These were the main issues which I was discussing in Birmingham, taking part in several panel discussions on how to bring down the cost of energy for households and businesses through accelerating take-up of renewable energy systems. </p>

<p>The Prime Minister is clearly committed to achieving Net Zero Britain. She has commissioned a review how best to get there. This includes stimulating energy security to make the country less dependent on both imported fossil fuels and high energy costs.</p>

<p>As a result of the current energy crisis, there is huge interest in how to accelerate the transition to renewable energies, whether for energy efficiency measures or electrification through heat pumps or solar PV systems and battery storage for our homes or business premises.</p>

<p>While I was banging the environmental drum, I was reassured by the significance of nature and importance to maintain environmental commitments in the comments that Ministers made.</p>

<p>I have experienced sufficient changes in administration and reshuffles under both Conservative and Labour governments to recognise that there is always some nervousness about new Ministers getting to know their portfolios and the potential for changes in direction or focus.</p>

<p>My message from the last few days in Birmingham, contrary to much reporting, is that there is a sense of realism at the heart of Government about the challenges the country faces, while war continues in Ukraine. </p>

<p>I am encouraged that for all the present uncertainties we shall provide the leadership to get the country through these difficulties and emerge in a better state, less dependent on other nations, or fossil fuels, for our future prosperity.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7266 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T21:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>10 ways we’re helping to tackle homelessness in Edinburgh this World Homeless Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13566/10-ways-we-re-helping-to-tackle-homelessness-in-edinburgh-this-world-homeless-day" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This Monday (10 October) marks World Homeless Day, which highlights the issues facing many people without a permanent home in our communities.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13566/10-ways-we-re-helping-to-tackle-homelessness-in-edinburgh-this-world-homeless-day</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T17:13:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T17:13:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[PM&#8217;s Future Is Already The Talk Of Tory Conference]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6448</id>
		<updated>2022-10-07T14:35:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-04T15:21:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="conservative party conference"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="kwasi kwarteng"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="liz truss"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="prime minister"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m told the PM and Chancellor planned to visit my constituency this week. They didn&#8217;t have the courtesy to tell me as parliamentary custom requires. Still, they also didn’t tell the Cabinet about the budget and&#160;forgetting to brief the markets unleashed chaos.&#160;&#160; The Tory Party is a ruthless election machine, capable of constantly reinventing itself<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">PM&#8217;s Future Is Already The Talk Of Tory Conference</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6452" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-4/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6452" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I&#8217;m told the PM and Chancellor planned to visit my constituency this week. They didn&#8217;t have the courtesy to tell me as parliamentary custom requires. Still, they also didn’t tell the Cabinet about the budget and&nbsp;forgetting to brief the markets unleashed chaos.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Tory Party is a ruthless election machine, capable of constantly reinventing itself to stay in power, but after 12 years they appear to have lost their way. They’ve reverted to that dangerous habit of picking a leader they didn’t want, simply to prevent someone they wanted even less. The last time they did that, they ended up with Ian Duncan Smith.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>He proved a disaster and was eventually ousted in a coup during a party conference. Tory coups are quite commonplace. Boris Johnson did it to Theresa May and then almost his entire Cabinet turned on him. What fate awaits the new PM?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Only weeks after taking over, she’s handed a resurgent Labour its biggest poll lead since records began. Her Chancellor quaffed champagne with the very financiers who profited from the pound&#8217;s misfortunes hours after his catastrophic budget. She was completely exposed during a disastrous round of local radio interviews last week and, on the first full day of her conference, was forced to admit that plans to give a huge tax cut to millionaires was a mistake. Her future is already the talk of the conference.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>She is apparently keen to model herself on Margaret Thatcher. I didn’t have much time for Mrs Thatcher but at least she was a conviction politician who knew her own mind. </p>



<p>Our new PM is a different kettle of fish. She started life as a Lib Dem who once wanted to abolish the monarchy. She was against Brexit and as recently as Sunday night was claiming she would tough it out over tax. She’s a conflicted individual who doesn’t appear to know what she believes. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Is she what we need at a time when the country faces so many difficulties? A lot of traditional Tory supporters are now asking that question and wondering how on earth they ended up with her.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/04/pms-future-is-already-the-talk-of-tory-conference/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Young Film Academy Subsidised Courses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/young-film-academy-subsidised-courses" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">The Young Film Academy Subsidised Courses</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-10-07T13:42:00+00:00">Fri, 10/07/2022 - 14:42</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1156 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T13:42:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T13:42:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Early October e-newsletter </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/early-october-e-newsletter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to read my mid August e-newsletter
 
I weld yr e-gylchlythyr hwn yn Gymraeg cliciwch yma</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/early-october-e-newsletter</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WBU World Middleweight Champion </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/wbu-world-middleweight-champion" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> It’s not often you get the chance to meet a world champion, so it was great to welcome Worksop’s Elle "Triple L" Coulson and her coach Chris Boyle from Team Xbox Boxing Academy Worksop.
Elle recently took home the WBU world middleweight title and brought it in to show me, along with her other…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/wbu-world-middleweight-champion</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne backs breakfast clubs for every child</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-breakfast-clubs-for-every-child/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-backs-breakfast-clubs-for-every-child" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235668" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/breakfast-clubs.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has welcomed Labour’s commitment to introducing breakfast clubs for every child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, the party outlined plans to rollout breakfast clubs to every primary school in England, providing access to fully-funded childcare and a healthy meal for every child. Recent analysis conducted by Labour showed that over 450,000 children in the North West currently have limited access to breakfast clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;69% of primary schools in the North West have ‘barriers’ to disadvantaged children and young people accessing provision, including the cost to families and schools of running breakfast clubs, a perceived lack of need in areas of high deprivation and caps on places for children on Free School Meals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Labour’s approach would be funded by money raised from abolishing non-dom tax status for the super rich. It is estimated that if Labour’s policy was implemented families could save over £60-a-week compared to other forms of before school childcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting on the announcement, Andrew Gwynne said: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m incredibly proud that Labour has committed to introducing breakfast clubs for every child at primary school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is clear, irrefutable evidence that breakfast clubs raise standards of learning for children, provide crucial before-school childcare and will help us build an economy fit for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step on the road to a modern system of childcare, and one that will make a real difference to families across Denton and Reddish.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-breakfast-clubs-for-every-child/"&gt;Gwynne backs breakfast clubs for every child&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has welcomed Labour’s commitment to introducing breakfast clubs for every child. Last week, the party outlined plans to rollout breakfast clubs to every primary school in England, providing access to fully-funded childcare and a healthy meal for every child. Recent analysis conducted by Labour showed that over 450,000 […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-backs-breakfast-clubs-for-every-child/">Gwynne backs breakfast clubs for every child</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235667</id>
    <published>2022-10-07T08:57:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-07T08:57:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="National"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn Newsletter 2022]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/10/05/autumn-newsletter-2022/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10590</id>
		<updated>2022-10-07T08:26:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:38:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="Newsletter"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been a lot happening over the past few weeks and I am glad to finally be getting back to Parliament after a short break during recess and due to the sad passing of the Queen. In that time, the new Government has announced a &#8216;mini&#8217; budget of a seismic scale &#8211; and which ... <a title="Autumn Newsletter 2022" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/10/05/autumn-newsletter-2022/" aria-label="More on Autumn Newsletter 2022">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Banbury Business Breakfast Club</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/banbury-business-breakfast-club" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was pleased to attend a meeting of the Banbury Business Breakfast Club today. Over 30 local business individuals were present from across the town.
It was good to discuss a range of topics with them including the Government’s recent mini-budget and support for businesses this winter.
This…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/banbury-business-breakfast-club</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett disappointed and concerned with new Southeastern timetable</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-disappointed-and-concerned-new-southeastern-timetable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Lord Commissioner of HM Treasury, met with the Rail Minister, Kevin Foster MP, at the Conservative Party Conference to express his disappointment and concern with the changes to the Southeastern timetable from December. 
Following the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-disappointed-and-concerned-new-southeastern-timetable</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MARTIN PRESSES PRIME MINISTER TO INTRODUCE PAID MISCARRIAGE LEAVE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/10/06/martin-presses-prime-minister-to-introduce-paid-miscarriage-leave/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;MP for West Dunbartonshire Martin Docherty-Hughes is calling on new Prime Minister Liz Truss to give the right to paid leave for parents who experience miscarriage before 24 weeks of pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the second reading of the Miscarriage Leave Bill in the Commons, local SNP MP Martin has signed a &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/12cGYQY-4wlq9j0MkgrW2mnZbS9PymtUR/view?usp=sharing"&gt;cross-party letter &lt;/a&gt;to Prime Minister Liz Truss and Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy Jacob Rees-Mogg calling for the UK government to review its position and back the Bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If successful, the Miscarriage Leave Bill would introduce a statutory right for parents to a minimum of three-days paid leave in the event of a miscarriage, ectopic pregnancy or molar pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The letter has been supported by 50 MPs from eight parties and independents as well as the Miscarriage Association, Mumsnet, Miscarriage Support, the Ectopic Pregnancy Trust, Tommy’s, Sands, SiMBA and campaigner Keeley Lengthorn.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Introduced by SNP MP Angela Crawley (Lanark and Hamilton East) under the Ten Minute Rule, the Miscarriage Leave Bill is set to&amp;nbsp;receive its second reading in December.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Up to one in four pregnancies will end in miscarriage however, there is currently no provision in place to support grieving parents through their loss&amp;nbsp;before 24 weeks of pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Countries including Australia and New Zealand have already introduced paid miscarriage leave and Northern Ireland is set to do so before&amp;nbsp;2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“There are many families in West Dunbartonshire who have gone through a miscarriage. It can be a devastating experience and there should be no concerns about having to take sick leave from work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I hope the Prime Minister listens to our campaign. I will be pressing the UK government to support the Miscarriage Leave Bill when it returns to the Commons for its second reading.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“By offering a statutory right to paid leave for parents who experience miscarriage before 24 weeks of pregnancy, the UK can take a positive step towards ending the stigma associated with pregnancy loss.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;““There is no cut off point for grief so there should not be a cut off point for providing&amp;nbsp;support to parents who experience miscarriage.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SNP MP Angela Crawley added:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A new Prime Minister brings a change to the heart of government and with that there is an opportunity for them to review and change their stance on miscarriage leave.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“My Private Members’ Bill will return to the Commons in December and I am hopeful that the new government will get behind it and support parents who experience miscarriage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“By providing a statutory right to paid leave in the event of a miscarriage, we can challenge the stigma and allow parents to properly grieve their loss.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscarriage Association National Director Ruth Bender Atik said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For many people, miscarriage is the loss of a baby, however early it happens, and is often felt as a bereavement like any other.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A period of statutory leave would not only allow people some time off to start their recovery, but it would also be a clear public recognition that pregnancy loss can have a very real and significant impact on those going through it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We wholeheartedly support this bill and hope the Government will take this opportunity to support people at a what can be an extremely difficult and distressing time.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information about support for families affected by miscarriage is available at: &lt;a href="http://www.miscarriageassociation.org.uk/"&gt;www.miscarriageassociation.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MP for West Dunbartonshire Martin Docherty-Hughes is calling on new Prime Minister Liz Truss to give the right to paid leave for parents who experience miscarriage before 24 weeks of pregnancy. Ahead of the second reading of the Miscarriage Leave Bill in the Commons, local SNP MP Martin has signed a cross-party letter to Prime ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="MARTIN PRESSES PRIME MINISTER TO INTRODUCE PAID MISCARRIAGE LEAVE" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/10/06/martin-presses-prime-minister-to-introduce-paid-miscarriage-leave/#more-1821377" aria-label="More on MARTIN PRESSES PRIME MINISTER TO INTRODUCE PAID MISCARRIAGE LEAVE">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821377</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T10:45:50Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T10:45:50Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Employment Rights"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Paid Miscarriage Leave"/>
    <category term="Prime Minister"/>
    <category term="UK government"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP welcomes Prime Minister Liz Truss speech to Conservative Party Conference 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning the Prime Minister set out our Conservative vision for the future. A country focussed on growth, aspiration and enterprise. Turning away from those who say much and do little, the anti-growth coalition we are so used to seeing on our screens and in the hall today.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Joins Local Councillors in Seeking to Save Cannon Street Rail Services </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-joins-local-councillors-seeking-save-cannon-street-rail-services" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham Bob Stewart is supporting a campaign lead by local Councillors from across the Beckenham constituency in calling on Southeastern Railways to reverse the decision to remove services to Cannon Street from the Hayes (Mid-Kent) line from the 11th December 2022. 
 
In…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-joins-local-councillors-seeking-save-cannon-street-rail-services</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[CHECKMATE!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=467</id>
		<updated>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/05/funding-opportunities-2-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><h3 style="text-align: center">Funding Sources</h3>
<p>Below is an updated list of funding for Voluntary Organisations and Charities as of 3rd October</p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Funding-Finder-September-2022.docx">Funding Finder September 2022</a></p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/3.10.22-funding-alert.pdf">3.10.22 funding alert</a></p>


<p/>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F05%2Ffunding-opportunities-2-2%2F&amp;title=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/05/funding-opportunities-2-2/" data-a2a-title="Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/05/funding-opportunities-2-2/">Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Funding Sources Below is an updated list of funding for Voluntary Organisations and Charities as ... <a title="Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/05/funding-opportunities-2-2/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/05/funding-opportunities-2-2/">Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2574</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T09:08:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T09:08:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Events &amp; Community Groups"/>
    <category term="charities"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="voluntary groups"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The UK has a world-beating science base – but The Tories don’t take science seriously</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/10/the-uk-has-a-world-beating-science-base-but-the-tories-dont-take-science-seriously/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong>The Tories don’t take science seriously.</strong></p>
<p><strong>I wish the new Science Minister well in her new position but the problem is the Tories just aren’t serious about science. We have had:</strong></p>
<p><strong>7</strong><strong>⃣</strong><strong>    Changes of Minister in 4 years</strong></p>
<p><strong>3</strong><strong>⃣</strong><strong>    Months without replacing the Science Minister position</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Government’s record on science speaks for itself </strong><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f9f5.png" alt="🧵" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;"/></strong></p>
<p><strong>It has also been revealed that Liz Truss is chairing just 3 of her cabinet committees – none of which have a science focus. Comparatively, Boris Johnson chaired 11 of his 20 committees – including the National Space Council.</strong></p>
<p><strong>After just three meetings and one year, Liz Truss has disbanded the National Science and Technology Council. The NSTC was established in 2021 to help make the UK a ‘global science superpower’.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The UK has a world-beating science base: we rank third, only behind the US in China in Science and Technology journal articles. Due to Tory lack of investment and strategy, we do not convert our rich science base into a high skill, high wage, high-productivity economy.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The average science minister lasts 9 months. We have had ‘Innovation strategy’, an ‘R&amp;D roadmap’, a ‘science plan’, an ‘Office for Science and Technology Strategy,’ ‘grand challenges’, industrial strategies, ‘sector deals’, ARIA and 2 re-organisations of UKRI.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The ‘Shared Prosperity Fund’ represents a 43% cut compared to previous funding, harming regions which were already in desperate need of investment. Concentration on GSE excludes the rest of the UK from growth, prosperity &amp; opportunity science provides.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The number 1 issue for UK based scientists and researchers right now is participation in the European Union’s Horizon Funding programme.  Losing access to Horizon would be a disaster for the UK’s leading researchers who’ve already lost collaborative opportunities.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The Government claimed to have a ‘Plan B’ for Horizon Europe. But after years of chaos and broken promises, we had the (now ex) Science Minister lobbying his own Government on Twitter to try and get the Treasury to properly fund a ‘Plan B’ alternative. </strong><strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/2049.png" alt="⁉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;"/></strong><strong/></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Tories don’t take science seriously. I wish the new Science Minister well in her new position but the problem is the Tories just aren’t serious about science. We have had: 7⃣    Changes of Minister in 4 years 3⃣    Months… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12769</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T20:43:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T20:43:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to Energy Minister – Energy Crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-energy-minister-energy-crisis/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=letter-to-energy-minister-energy-crisis" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content"&gt;&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"&gt;


&lt;div class="wp-block-file"&gt;&lt;object class="wp-block-file__embed" data="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/letter-energy-costs-041022-1.pdf" type="application/pdf" style="width:100%;height:600px" aria-label="Embed of letter-energy-costs-041022-1."&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;a id="wp-block-file--media-290b4122-7ef0-45fc-96fb-3211b0ff9d63" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/letter-energy-costs-041022-1.pdf"&gt;letter-energy-costs-041022-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/letter-energy-costs-041022-1.pdf" class="wp-block-file__button" download aria-describedby="wp-block-file--media-290b4122-7ef0-45fc-96fb-3211b0ff9d63"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-energy-minister-energy-crisis/"&gt;Letter to Energy Minister &amp;#8211; Energy Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-energy-minister-energy-crisis/">Letter to Energy Minister – Energy Crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6501</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T16:27:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T16:27:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Letters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-33" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was a disappointing start to the week with the news that Ashfield District Council have given Rumbles Café notice that they will terminate their license, forcing this great local to close. Rumbles Café has been at the heart of our local community in Sutton for the last 15 years, providing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-33</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP supports launch of National Independent Lifeboat Association</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/mp-supports-launch-national-independent-lifeboat-association" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Berwickshire MP, John Lamont, has welcomed a new charity that has been launched to assist the UK’s independent lifeboats to ensure the preservation of life on the water.
The National Independent Lifeboat Association (NILA) was founded by Anthony Mangnall MP and a host of independent lifeboats,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/mp-supports-launch-national-independent-lifeboat-association</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Karin Smyth MP brands Tory Government’s Budget a “mortgage bombshell” for families in Bristol South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/04/karin-smyth-mp-brands-tory-governments-budget-a-mortgage-bombshell-for-families-in-bristol-south/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=karin-smyth-mp-brands-tory-governments-budget-a-mortgage-bombshell-for-families-in-bristol-south" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has branded the Tory Government’s Budget a “mortgage bombshell” for families in the constituency. This comes as details have emerged showing each household will pay circa £1,500 per year more in higher interest payments.</p>
<p>The average rate on a two-year fixed-rate deal increased by an entire percentage point between last Monday and yesterday to 5.75 per cent, a post-financial crisis high.</p>
<p>The rise raised monthly repayments on a £200,000 home loan by £124 a month to £1,167 — £1,486 more a year. Last December the average rate on a two-year fix was 2.34%.</p>
<p>Following the announcement of the so-called Mini-Budget the Conservative Government has been buffeted by market turmoil as the cost of government borrowing has rocketed – which directly affects the cost of people’s mortgages and other borrowing. </p>
<p>The actions of the Tories also saw the pound crash in value. This resulted in the Bank of England having to bail the Government out to the tune of £65 billion. If no action would have been taken it was believed that several large pension schemes would have gone bust.</p>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, said:</p>
<p>“The Tory Government’s management of the economy has been nothing short of catastrophic. The actions of the Prime Minister and her Chancellor have placed a mortgage bombshell under households in south Bristol. On average households will now see a Tory premium of £1,500 per year added to their mortgage repayment: money people cannot afford.</p>
<p>“This is an economic crisis made in Downing Street, paid for by working people. </p>
<p>“The Chancellor’s recent speech to Tory Party Conference showed him to be completely out of touch. He mentioned “turbulence” being experienced in the hope of laughing off his mismanagement. It’s clear that the Tory Government cannot be trusted to run our economy. A Labour Government will bring regain the UK’s reputation for sound management of our finances and ensure the cost-of-living crisis is ended.”</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/04/karin-smyth-mp-brands-tory-governments-budget-a-mortgage-bombshell-for-families-in-bristol-south/">Karin Smyth MP brands Tory Government’s Budget a “mortgage bombshell” for families in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has branded the Tory Government’s Budget a “mortgage bombshell” for families in the constituency. […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/04/karin-smyth-mp-brands-tory-governments-budget-a-mortgage-bombshell-for-families-in-bristol-south/">Karin Smyth MP brands Tory Government’s Budget a “mortgage bombshell” for families in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3340</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T11:08:14Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T11:08:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ryders Hayes School wins Bursary to promote Science, Maths and Technology!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/ryders-hayes-school-wins-bursary-to-promote-science-maths-and-technology/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I was delighted to be able to visit Ryders Hayes School and hear about them being awarded a bursary to take the lead on raising aspirations in the important fields of Science, Technology, Engineering and Maths (STEM).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enthuse Partnership project, will enable pupils and staff to access a planned programme of high-quality teacher training and development, STEM Ambassadors in schools from the world of work, and STEM Clubs, providing funding for resources alongside exciting pupil activities to inspire the next generation of engineers, scientists and mathematicians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head Teacher, Sally Miner and all of her team are to be congratulated for once again undertaking a pioneering project such as The Enthuse Partnership project which will have real lasting benefit, developing the skills for tomorrow, today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all the staff and pupils at Ryders Hayes for another great visit.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was delighted to be able to visit Ryders Hayes School and hear about them being awarded a bursary to take the lead on raising aspirations in the important fields […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4322</id>
    <published>2022-10-04T09:17:31Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-04T09:17:31Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-173" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I welcome the recent statement from the Secretary of State for Health, Thérèse Coffey MP, outlining the Government’s ‘plan for patients’ and what it intends to do to tackle ongoing pressures facing the National Health Service, especially as we head towards the winter.
The plan will be achieved by…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-173</id>
    <published>2022-10-03T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-03T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP’s London marathon run raises over £4,000 for Great North Air Ambulance Service</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1436032/mp-s-london-marathon-run-raises-over-4-000-for-great-north-air-ambulance-service"/>
  <updated>2022-10-03T10:34:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1436032/mp-s-london-marathon-run-raises-over-4-000-for-great-north-air-ambulance-service</id>
  <summary type="text">Cumbrian MP Tim Farron has raised £4,300 for the Great North Air Ambulance Service by completing the London Marathon yesterday.
Tim finished the race in 4 hours 32 minutes and 37 seconds - 12 minutes faster than his effort last year.
The Great North Air Ambulance Service, who are celebrating their 20th anniversary this year, is funded entirely by donations from the public.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img class="content-edited" alt="Tim after the London Marathon" title="Tim after the London Marathon" src="/en/image/6tBqtP/360/270/tim-after-the-london-marathon.png" style="width: 360px; height: 270px; float: right;"/>Cumbrian MP Tim Farron has raised £4,300 for the Great North Air Ambulance Service by completing the London Marathon yesterday.</p>
<p>Tim finished the race in 4 hours 32 minutes and 37 seconds - 12 minutes faster than his effort last year.</p>
<p>The Great North Air Ambulance Service, who are celebrating their 20th anniversary this year, is funded entirely by donations from the public.</p>
<p>The charity provides the air ambulance service for Cumbria. From its base in Langwathby near Penrith it can reach any part of the county in just 15 minutes at speeds of 190mph.</p>
<p>Speaking after the run, Tim said: <em>"26 miles is a long way, but the only thing you can do is just keep plodding, soaking up the atmosphere of such a great day. It was a privilege to wear the Great North Air Ambulance vest and to know that we were raising funds for such a vital cause'</em></p>
<p><em>I am hugely grateful to everyone who sponsored me and in turn supported the Great North Air Ambulance Service.</em> <em>They are a wonderful charity who work tirelessly to save lives."</em></p>
<p>Tracey Wright, events co-ordinator at GNAAS, said: <em>"We'd like to offer a massive congratulations to Tim for not only completing a marathon, but beating his previous time by 12 minutes, which is amazing.</em></p>
<p><em>"Tim has raised a fantastic amount of money for our charity, which will enable our team to continue saving lives across the region, so we want to pass on our thanks to him and everyone who sponsored him."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/epsom-and-ewell-energy-support-scheme/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p><strong>Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme</strong></p>
<p>I am writing to you to ask for your help with a new local initiative that I have been working on with <strong>Citizens Advice Epsom &amp; Ewell, </strong>the local branch of Citizens Advice and <strong>Good Company</strong> which runs five food bank centres in Epsom and the surrounding area.</p>
<p>The current energy crisis is putting huge pressures on many people locally.  Although prices are being frozen for the next two years, and every household will receive a £400 discount on their energy bills this winter, paid over a six month period, many households are still struggling with the increases that have already taken place.</p>
<p>Part of the solution to the crisis is to improve energy efficiency for those who are struggling to pay their bills. But all too often people either do not know what solutions are available or cannot afford them or both.</p>
<p>The <strong>Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme</strong> is a plan to offer those running into difficulties immediate help with their bills, and then advice and financial support to improve energy efficiency or reduce energy consumption in their homes and so reduce bills going forward. This might include buying a more efficient appliance for them or helping with improved insulation.</p>
<p>To help support this programme we are asking local households who have less difficulty paying for these higher energy bills to donate their £400 support payments to the fund so that it can be used to help reduce the bills of those who are struggling. If you are able to do this, we would be very grateful, and all other donations are of course also very welcome.</p>
<p>As I said, the Scheme is being run jointly by the Good Company, which runs the local food bank, and Citizens Advice Epsom &amp; Ewell helped by local Churches. It will offer both advice sessions to help those who are not sure how to improve their energy efficiency as well as assistance paying for improvements.</p>
<p>If you can help, I would be very grateful. To make a donation, please visit our donations page at <strong><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/qha4CRO3xsv5RPExUNaYzD?domain=justgiving.com">www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme</a></strong>.  If you would like any further information, please drop me an email.</p>
<p>I hope you will be able to support this programme.</p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/epsom-and-ewell-energy-support-scheme/">Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme I am writing to you to ask for your help with a new local initiative that I have been working on with Citizens Advice Epsom &amp; Ewell, the local branch of Citizens Advice and Good Company which runs five food bank centres in Epsom and the surrounding area. The [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/epsom-and-ewell-energy-support-scheme/">Epsom and Ewell Energy Support Scheme</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6315</id>
    <published>2022-10-03T10:25:44Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-03T10:25:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Campaigns"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on the Myanmar Armed Forces and referral to International Criminal Court</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_myanmar_armed_forces_and_referral_to_international_criminal_court" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_myanmar_armed_forces_and_referral_to_international_criminal_court</id>
    <published>2022-10-03T10:32:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-03T10:32:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>GOVERNMENT ABANDON PLANS TO SCRAP THE 45% TAX RATE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/45taxrate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Responding to the news that the Government have abandoned plans to scrap the 45% tax rate, Catherine commented: “Just 10 days ago the Government announced its budget plans, including an irresponsible and unfunded tax giveaway to the richest people in our country, without providing any independent forecast on their impact. “Since then, we’ve seen the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/45taxrate/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">GOVERNMENT ABANDON PLANS TO SCRAP THE 45% TAX RATE</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7752</id>
    <published>2022-10-03T08:15:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-03T08:15:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="economy"/>
    <category term="features"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Standard Column – The next few months will be key</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/llanelli-standard-column-the-next-few-months-will-be-key/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;“There are decades where nothing happens and there are
weeks where decades happen.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;None more so than last month when in the space of only a
few days we saw the appointment of our fourth Prime Minister in the last six
years quickly followed by the death of Queen Elizabeth II.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Queen was a loyal and faithful public servant who
took her responsibilities seriously, dedicating her life to serving the British
people.&amp;nbsp; An influential figure and a
much-loved, reassuring presence for many generations, she will be greatly
missed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Her successor, King Charles III, will now need to show
the same level of empathy and understanding as he faces up to the years ahead
as Head of State not only for the United Kingdom but for many other countries
around the world too.&amp;nbsp; His surefootedness
in the days immediately after her death, whilst at the same time grieving the
loss of her not only as a monarch but, more importantly, as his mother was a
positive start.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now the official mourning period has ended, he has a
clear time window in which to set out his stall as the new King.&amp;nbsp; The next few months will be key.&amp;nbsp; What happens in the coming days and weeks
will decide how he is received by the public and how he will be judged for the
remainder of his reign.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The same can be said, of course, about Liz Truss, our new
Prime Minister.&amp;nbsp; After what seemed to be
a never-ending summer of debate within the Tory Party, she finally emerged as
the victorious candidate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Taking office at one of the most turbulent times in
recent history, she had only two days inside 10 Downing Street before everything
was turned upside down by the news coming from Balmoral.&amp;nbsp; In that brief time, she had already set about
appointing the least experienced, most extreme Cabinet she could think of.&amp;nbsp; Jettisoning to the backbenches anyone who had
not shown complete and utter devotion to her previously, it seems personal
loyalty came before any sense of assembling the best talents for the new PM.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Her only major announcement before the suspension of Parliament
was on energy prices with a proposal for an energy price guarantee so that the
average domestic energy bill will be no more than £2,500 per year for two years
from October 2022.&amp;nbsp; Totally avoiding any
questions relating to the overall cost of this policy, Truss also failed to
outline that her plans would in fact see richer people receiving twice the
amount of help than the poorest.&amp;nbsp; Neither
fair nor particularly effective.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am pleased that the Prime Minister has finally accepted
the principle of a price limit. However, under her Government’s plan prices
will still rise considerably. The plan put forward by Labour, on the other
hand, would ensure that there would not be a single penny more on bills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There is also a crucial question about who pays for these
measures. The Treasury estimates that energy companies could make £170 billion
in unexpected windfall profits over the next two years. That is why I have
supported a windfall tax since January and why I want to see the windfall tax
expanded.&amp;nbsp; Sadly, the Prime Minister has chosen to leave these vast
profits on the table and instead let working people pick up the bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to the cost of living crisis, the new Prime
Minister will have to deal with other pressing matters including how to prevent the expected NHS crisis in
England, the Russian invasion of Ukraine, finding a way through the Northern
Ireland Protocol difficulties and dealing with our Net Zero by 2050 climate
change commitments whilst securing our energy supply for the long term.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With
polling suggesting that voters become less impressed with her, the more they
see of her, she has a huge challenge to set convince the British public that
she can really make a difference.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How will it all work
out?&amp;nbsp; Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">“There are decades where nothing happens and there are weeks where decades happen.” None more so than last month when in the space of only a few days we saw the appointment of our fourth Prime Minister in the last six years quickly followed by the death of Queen Elizabeth II. The Queen was a […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8588</id>
    <published>2022-10-02T17:34:02Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-02T17:34:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John Swearing In]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/09/21/john-swearing-in/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5506</id>
		<updated>2022-09-30T12:25:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-09-21T12:09:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Members of the House of Commons and the House of Lords take an oath of allegiance to the Crown. This is called swearing in. Members can either swear in using a religious text or take a non-religious, solemn affirmation. They do this before taking their seats in Parliament. This can happen after a general election [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/09/21/john-swearing-in/"><![CDATA[
<p>Members of the House of Commons and the House of Lords take an oath of allegiance to the Crown. This is called swearing in. Members can either swear in using a religious text or take a non-religious, solemn affirmation. They do this before taking their seats in Parliament. This can happen after a general election or by-election.</p>



<p>As in this case, swearing in also happens after the death of the Monarch: for members of the House of Lords this is an obligation but for MPs it is optional and not doing so has no effect on them taking their seat or participating in business.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP urges households to take a meter reading before price hike on 1st October </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/09/29/isles-mp-urges-households-to-take-a-meter-reading-before-price-hike-on-1st-october/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is urging households across the islands to take energy meter readings before October 1 and ensure they are submitted in the next week to avoid being charged new rates for energy used before the price hike. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3926" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/meter-pic/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg" data-orig-size="2538,3698" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G780F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1664453753&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;640&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.04&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Meter pic" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=206" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=703" alt="" class="wp-image-3926" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=703 703w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=1406 1406w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=103 103w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=206 206w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/09/meter-pic.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 703px) 100vw, 703px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil also warned that reports from the Prime Minister Liz Truss that no household would pay more than £2500 were inaccurate and had led to the spread of misinformation. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He said: “Householders should take a meter reading by October 1 and then submit it to your energy provider. The reading does not have to be submitted on that day as this has previously crashed the systems but please ensure that meter readings are taken and noted, even take a photo of the reading for evidence, and then submit within a few days.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Nobody wants the September usage to be estimated into October usage because it will be a higher price. Also, in October you will be using more electricity.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is urging households across the islands to take energy meter readings before …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/09/29/isles-mp-urges-households-to-take-a-meter-reading-before-price-hike-on-1st-october/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3927</id>
    <published>2022-09-29T13:38:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-29T13:38:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A fairer, greener future with the Labour Party]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/a-fairer-greener-future-with-the-labour-party/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11772</id>
		<updated>2022-09-28T12:46:37Z</updated>
		<published>2022-09-28T12:41:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday the leader of the Labour Party, Keir Starmer gave a great speech at party conference setting out his vision for Britain under a Labour Government.&#160;<br />
It would be a Britain with its hope back, it’s confidence back… it’s future back. A country where aspiration is rewarded. Where working people succeed. A force for good in the world. A clean energy superpower.<br />
The fully funded policies announced in the speech to&#160; grow our economy and spread opportunity throughout the country stands in stark contrast to the shambolic budget that we saw last ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/a-fairer-greener-future-with-the-labour-party/">A fairer, greener future with the Labour Party</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/a-fairer-greener-future-with-the-labour-party/"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/profile_banners/14291684/1664002749/1500x500" alt="Image" width="445" height="148"></p>
<p>Yesterday the leader of the Labour Party, Keir Starmer gave a great speech at party conference setting out his vision for Britain under a Labour Government.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It would be a Britain with its hope back, it’s confidence back… it’s future back. A country where aspiration is rewarded. Where working people succeed. A force for good in the world. A clean energy superpower.</p>
<p>The fully funded policies announced in the speech to&nbsp; grow our economy and spread opportunity throughout the country stands in stark contrast to the shambolic budget that we saw last week from the conservatives.</p>
<p>Labour is ready for government.</p>
<p>You can read Keir Starmer&#8217;s speech<a href="https://labour.org.uk/press/keir-starmer-conference-speech/"> here </a>or watch it <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=niOsZksQKK0">here</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-6275" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-kendall-urges-women-not-to-miss-out-on-smear-tests-leicester-mercury-25-april/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/5.jpg" alt="Liz Kendall urges women not to miss out on smear tests (Leicester Mercury, 25 April)" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-kendall-urges-women-not-to-miss-out-on-smear-tests-leicester-mercury-25-april/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz Kendall urges women not to miss out on smear tests (Leicester Mercury, 25 April)</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-5773" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-meets-jobs-fair-recruits/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/5.jpg" alt="Liz meets job’s fair recruits" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-meets-jobs-fair-recruits/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz meets job’s fair recruits</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-3654" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-meets-shared-lives-plus-carers/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/30.jpg" alt="Liz meets &#8216;Shared Lives Plus&#8217; Carers" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-meets-shared-lives-plus-carers/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz meets &#8216;Shared Lives Plus&#8217; Carers</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-10809" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-mps-reflect-on-2020/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/13.jpg" alt="Leicester MPs reflect on 2020" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-mps-reflect-on-2020/" class="wp_rp_title">Leicester MPs reflect on 2020</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-5500" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-the-fight-against-breast-cancer/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/10.jpg" alt="Liz joins the fight against breast cancer" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-the-fight-against-breast-cancer/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz joins the fight against breast cancer</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/a-fairer-greener-future-with-the-labour-party/">A fairer, greener future with the Labour Party</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne-Marie calls for International Action to Decarbonise Global Aviation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-calls-international-action-decarbonise-global-aviation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Anne-Marie Trevelyan - Member of Parliament for Berwick-upon-Tweed - will tell countries worldwide to reduce aviation carbon emissions at the International Civil Aviation Organization Assembly today.
Decarbonising the aviation sector requires global action, new Transport Secretary Anne-Marie…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-calls-international-action-decarbonise-global-aviation</id>
    <published>2022-09-28T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-28T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mum’s Here With Us, Yet Already Gone</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/mums-here-with-us-yet-already-gone/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3151</id>
    <published>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Historic Week in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/a-historic-week-in-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Few of us will ever forget watching the majestic and dignified scenes of the funeral of Queen Elizabeth II on 19th September. It was an occasion which united millions of Britons in prayer, thanksgiving and reflection, as well as capturing the attention of even greater audiences watching around the world. On the Saturday evening before […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kieran Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6162</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T16:03:24Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T16:03:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes the Conservative Government’s Growth Plan, helping two million people across the East Midlands keep more of their hard-earned money</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/09/23/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-the-conservative-governments-growth-plan-helping-two-million-people-across-the-east-midlands-keep-more-of-their-hard-earned-money/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan, starting a new era focused on economic growth, whilst tackling the immediate energy crisis and removing barriers for businesses to build the infrastructure we need to grow the British economy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan puts more money in people’s pockets by cutting National Insurance and Income Tax – including an extra £330 a year from the cut to National Insurance contributions and saving families £1,400 on their energy bills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To deliver on this mission, the Chancellor has also announced 38 Investment Zones and over 100 infrastructure projects across the country to drive the investment and growth in the areas that need it the most.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan – setting out support for families with their energy bills and unleashing a new era of growth through tax cuts and investment incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Warman MP has welcomed the Chancellor’s measures set out for families across Boston and Skegness who will have their energy bills cut by up to £1,400 through the Energy Price Guarantee, whilst businesses eligible for The Energy Bill Relief Scheme will have their energy bills slashed by cutting the price of wholesale gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor also confirmed people across the East Midlands will benefit from personal tax cuts – cutting National Insurance contributions by 1.25 per cent, putting an extra £330 a year in people’s pockets and helping them with cost-of-living pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means two million people across the East Midlands region will save £255 a year thanks to the cut to National Insurance contributions, and 2.4 million people across the East Midlands will save £160 a year thanks to the slash to Income tax in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside these measures the Conservative Government announced further personal cuts – including cutting stamp duty permanently by doubling the nil-rate band to £250,000 (from £125,000), increasing the nil-rate band for first time buyers to £425,000 (from £300,000) and increasing the value of the property which first-time buyers can claim relief to £625,000 from (£500,000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These measures combined mean a typical family moving into a semi-detached property will save £2,500 on stamp duty and £1,150 on energy bills – and if they have a combined income of £50,000 around an additional £560 on tax. This is around £4,200 in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan also unleashes 38 Investment Zones across England, unlocking housing and driving growth through tax incentives and over 100 infrastructure projects that will be accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These measures will unleash growth through tax cuts and reform, tackle the immediate energy crisis, removing barriers for business, and building the infrastructure needed to grow the British economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Matt Warman MP said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“In the face of rising energy prices and cost of living pressures it is right that this Conservative Government has come forward with a serious support package and a plan for growth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I welcome support set out for people across Boston and Skegness today, including cuts to National Insurance contributions, Income Tax and Stamp Duty – all helping families to keep more of their hard-earned money.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Only the Conservatives can be trusted to make the reforms we need to grow our economy – delivering higher wages, lower taxes and more money for our public services.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, The Chancellor of the Exchequer said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Growth is not as high as it should be. This has made it harder to pay for public services, requiring taxes to rise and cost of living pressures to increase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We need to change this and be unashamed in our Growth Plan – expanding the supply side of the economy, through tax incentives and reform, whilst we help families now by cutting their energy bills by £1,400 a year and slashing personal taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“That is how we will deliver higher wages, greater opportunities, and crucially, fund public services, now and into the future.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan, starting a new era focused on economic growth, whilst tackling the immediate energy crisis and removing barriers for businesses to build the infrastructure we need to grow the British economy. The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan puts more money in people’s pockets by […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4127</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T14:20:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T14:20:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Welcomes Government’s Plan for Growth</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-governments-plan-growth" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, welcomes the Government’s Plan for Growth which was announced today.
In his first fiscal statement as Chancellor, Kwasi Kwarteng announced an ambitious plan to ensure that the UK economy grows by 2.5% a year. Achieving this higher…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-governments-plan-growth</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton welcomes news that the North-West is set to benefit from 6 of the Conservative Government’s 38 new Investment Zones</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-news-north-west-set-benefit-6-conservative-governments-38-new-investment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
The North-West is set to benefit from 6 of the 38 of the Conservative Government’s new Investment Zones to get their local economies growing across the region.


Investment Zones will benefit from tax breaks and planning freedoms to make them more attractive to businesses and investors – creating…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-news-north-west-set-benefit-6-conservative-governments-38-new-investment</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Question to the Chancellor on the Fiscal Event and Growth in the U.K.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-chancellor-fiscal-event-and-growth-uk" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Without growth, government just becomes an exercise in rearranging the deck chairs, so I absolutely welcome this unashamed focus on growth. As my hon. Friend Dr Spencer said, it is a vote of confidence in the future of our country. Let us look at the western link road in my constituency. Does my…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-chancellor-fiscal-event-and-growth-uk</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Questioning the Health Secretary in response to the statement, Judith asked:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With 9 out of 10 dental practices in England not accepting new NHS patients and with over 2000 dentists leaving the NHS in the last year alone, NHS dentistry is in crisis. So whilst today’s small changes are welcome, alongside the minor tweaks back in July, they are underwhelming given the scale of the crisis. &amp;nbsp;So when will the Secretary of State make full contract reform, with prevention at its heart, so that my constituents can access an NHS dentist when they need to?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Thérèse Coffey MP, Secretary of State for Health and Social Care said: “Well, the honourable lady is absolutely right and I completely agree with her – it is a real problem. We have started doing some changes already and we need to do that in more detail right across the country. My honourable friend the minister will be looking at that more intensely.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith has sent a cross-party letter including 60 other MPs to the new Prime Minister Liz Truss, warning that NHS dentistry is on ‘life support’ and calling for proper resources and reform to halt what the British Dental Association have called NHS Dentistry’s ‘slow death’.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking afterwards, Judith said: “While I’m glad the new Secretary says she ‘absolutely’ agrees with me, today’s announcements do very little to solve the problem. 98% of dentists in Bradford are closed to NHS patients. There is no point the government publishing that information online, if they’re doing nothing to improve the availability of appointments in the first place, or ensuring that NHS dentists stay in the NHS.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Minister after Minister has promised to fix this and none have delivered. This needs decisive reform, not the minor tweaks announced, to save NHS dentistry from collapse and make sure people across Bradford can get an NHS dentist when they need them.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“My constituents in Bradford South have waited long enough and the Government’s ambition does not match the scale of the task. This needs more than words and promises, it needs action.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Yesterday’s announcements on NHS dentistry by the Health Secretary don’t go nearly far enough to stop the crisis. I have again called for action so that my constituents can get an NHS dentist when they need one. &lt;a href="https://t.co/t3PRVCTpxJ"&gt;pic.twitter.com/t3PRVCTpxJ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1573227244167757824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 23, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-end-crisis-in-dentistry/" title="Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry"&gt;Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse. Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes: “The current&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, government, dentistry, judith, dentists, bradford, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-must-have-access-to-nhs-services-they-need/" title="People must have access to NHS services they need"&gt;People must have access to NHS services they need&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;87&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-must-have-access-to-nhs-services-they-need/" title="People must have access to NHS services they need"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="People must have access to NHS services they need" alt="People must have access to NHS services they need" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In her latest column, Judith writes about the impact of the cost of living and lack of access to NHS Services: Originally printed in the Telegraph and Argus, Weds 31 August 2022: "When I speak to residents across Bradford South, it is clear that the cost-of-living crisis is a huge&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, access, government, dentistry, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;84&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, action, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/nhs-dentistry-cannot-be-a-forgotten-cinderella-service/" title="NHS Dentistry cannot be a forgotten Cinderella service"&gt;NHS Dentistry cannot be a forgotten Cinderella service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/nhs-dentistry-cannot-be-a-forgotten-cinderella-service/" title="NHS Dentistry cannot be a forgotten Cinderella service"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="NHS Dentistry cannot be a forgotten Cinderella service" alt="NHS Dentistry cannot be a forgotten Cinderella service" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Speaking to the Telegraph and Argus, Judith has said there is a not a week goes by where she doesn't have someone contacting her about the lack of dentists. Judith said: "In February, I led a debate in parliament calling for immediate action from the government and warning that if&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, dentistry, judith, government, access, dentists, action, bradford, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning the Health Secretary in response […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2665</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T08:43:44Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T08:43:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Herefordshire Council’s Children’s Services</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/09/22/herefordshire-councils-childrens-services/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Ofsted report into Herefordshire Council’s Children’s Services makes for grim reading.  However from my own experience, the testimonies of numerous families are far worse and so I believe that Ofsted has, if anything, been generous to Herefordshire Council.  This... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/09/22/herefordshire-councils-childrens-services/#more-4430">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4430</id>
    <published>2022-09-22T15:12:35Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-22T15:12:35Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - A tribute to Her Late Majesty The Queen</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-tribute-her-late-majesty-queen" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am sure I speak for most people when I say that the last couple of weeks have been an extraordinary time. That the Queen is no longer with us cannot be a surprise given her age and length of service, but nevertheless the effect on the whole country has been deeply affecting.
Practically everyone…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-tribute-her-late-majesty-queen</id>
    <published>2022-09-22T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-22T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins takes the oath of allegiance to King Charles III</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/09/21/toby-perkins-takes-the-oath-of-allegiance-to-king-charles-iii/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/09/21/toby-perkins-takes-the-oath-of-allegiance-to-king-charles-iii/">Toby Perkins takes the oath of allegiance to King Charles III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/09/21/toby-perkins-takes-the-oath-of-allegiance-to-king-charles-iii/">Toby Perkins takes the oath of allegiance to King Charles III</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5098</id>
    <published>2022-09-21T13:23:17Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-21T13:23:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Important Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/an-important-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper">
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<div class="m8h3af8h l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk gh25dzvf n3t5jt4f">
<div dir="auto">I wanted to let you know that I will be undergoing hip replacement surgery this week which will mean I won’t be around over the next few weeks.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk gh25dzvf jikcssrz n3t5jt4f">
<div dir="auto">You may recall I had my first hip replaced in 2018. Unfortunately over the last 18 months or so, I have been experiencing severe pain in my other hip, for which I have been receiving excellent NHS support.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk gh25dzvf jikcssrz n3t5jt4f">
<div dir="auto">In the summer, my consultant revealed that the hip socket was now ‘bone on bone’ and I couldn’t put off the surgery any longer. I’m really grateful to all the surgical team and hope that my second hip replacement goes as well as the first!</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk gh25dzvf jikcssrz n3t5jt4f">
<div dir="auto">As a result of this major surgery, I will have limited mobility for 8 weeks or so, and you may not see me out and about in the constituency as usual.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="l7ghb35v kjdc1dyq kmwttqpk gh25dzvf jikcssrz n3t5jt4f">
<div dir="auto">Please be reassured that my staff and I will continue to support you, dealing with your cases. For urgent issues my team will arrange meetings with you, and I will join virtually when possible. My constituency office is open on Monday, Wednesday and Friday mornings from 9am-1pm. You can also contact me and my team on abrahamsd@parliament.uk or on 0161 624 4248 with your enquiries or to book an appointment.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/an-important-update/">An Important Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/an-important-update/">An Important Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7049</id>
    <published>2022-09-21T11:51:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-21T11:51:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Thank you for everything Ma'am</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2133-thank-you-for-everything-ma-am"/>
		<published>2022-09-19T20:15:04+01:00</published>
		<updated>2022-09-19T20:15:04+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2133-thank-you-for-everything-ma-am</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thank you for everything Ma’am.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/QueenElizabethII?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#QueenElizabethII&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2XH95wppAy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2XH95wppAy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1571908811593777158?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Thank you for everything Ma’am.&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/QueenElizabethII?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#QueenElizabethII&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2XH95wppAy"&gt;pic.twitter.com/2XH95wppAy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1571908811593777158?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 19, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conor and St Helens North pay tribute to Her late Majesty Queen Elizabeth II</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/09/12/conor-pays-tribute-to-her-late-majesty-queens-elisabeth-ii/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7533</id>
    <published>2022-09-12T15:27:30Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-12T15:27:30Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tribute to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/tribute-to-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii-in-parliament/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tribute-to-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii-in-parliament" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;div class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;How I got meeting the Queen badly wrong! My tribute to Her Majesty in parliament. &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZzbJ9cNu5k"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZzbJ9cNu5k&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP (@grantshapps) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/grantshapps/status/1568624083251634179?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;September 10, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Like many in this House, I had the opportunity to meet and speak to the Queen on numerous occasions, but unfortunately the relationship did not start particularly auspiciously. I was invited to Buckingham Palace for what, as other Members will know, is an ancient, complex process of becoming a Privy Councillor. It was so complicated that I was called to a side room with five colleagues to have the process explained. We were told, &amp;#8216;You will enter a large hall in Buckingham Palace, where Her Majesty will stand at one end. You will kneel on the red cushions, which go back some distance, on your right knees, holding a Bible in your right hand. You will switch that to your left hand, then take the Sovereign’s hand with your right hand and brush her hand, then stand and say, ‘Your Majesty.&amp;#8217; I thought, &amp;#8216;Brush her hand? Was that an instruction to brush her hand with my hand? With my sleeve? Or with a handkerchief?&amp;#8217; As I was about to ask, we were called into the performance of the great ceremony itself. I thought, &amp;#8216;No matter, I am fifth in the line to become a Privy Councillor, so I will watch my colleagues.&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;My colleagues were all swearing on the New Testament, but as I am Jewish I was swearing on the Old Testament. I was at the back of the line and I thought that I would watch what was happening. Unfortunately, as we went into this large hallway, I found that it was so long that I could not see what was happening in the ceremony at the front. As I got closer, the field of view narrowed and the girth of my colleague in front of me widened, and I still could not see what brushing the hand actually entailed. With palpitations, I nervously knelt in front of Her Majesty The Queen, on the red cushion right before her. I switched the Bible, the Pentateuch, from my right to my left hand, and stretched out my right hand. She stretched out her bare, ungloved right hand and, to my surprise, moved it towards my face. It moved towards my lips. I pursed my lips. And it stuck! For what felt like an age she tried to pull it away and then, suddenly, “pop!”, her hand pulled away. I wanted the ground beneath me in Buckingham Palace to swallow me whole, but I remembered to stand up. &amp;#8216;Your Majesty,&amp;#8217; I quavered. She looked me right in the eyes with those wonderful sparkling eyes, as if both to acknowledge what had happened and also to forgive me in one turn. She said, &amp;#8216;Yes!&amp;#8217;. Mr Speaker, we never spoke of it again. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;God save the King.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/tribute-to-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii-in-parliament/"&gt;Tribute to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II in Parliament&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My tribute to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II in Parliament.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/tribute-to-her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii-in-parliament/">Tribute to Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II in Parliament</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=44528</id>
    <published>2022-09-12T11:41:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-12T11:41:11Z</updated>
    <category term="From Grant"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tribute to Her late Majesty Queen Elizabeth II</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/tribute_to_her_late_majesty_queen_elizabeth_ii" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>*** CHECK AGAINST DELIVERY ***</p>
<p>Thank you Mr Speaker.</p>
<p>It is a solemn honour to pay tribute in this House to Her Late Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II.</p>
<p>I want to begin by offering condolences on behalf of my Barnsley constituents and myself to the Royal Family in their time of grief.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/tribute_to_her_late_majesty_queen_elizabeth_ii</id>
    <published>2022-09-09T15:51:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-09-09T15:51:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/09/09/her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I have no words to express my sorrow at the passing of Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II. No one has dedicated so much to the service of the public. Most of us can't remember a time when the Queen wasn't our head of state. She enriched all our lives and things will never be the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/09/09/her-majesty-queen-elizabeth-ii/">Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5059</id>
    <published>2022-09-09T09:39:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-09T09:39:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid Autumn Booster and Flu Vaccination Newsletter from Swansea Bay University Health Board</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/covid-autumn-booster-and-flu-vaccination-newsletter-from-swansea-bay-university-health-board/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="xmsonormal"><u><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Date: Thursday, September 1<sup>st</sup>, 2022</span></u></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><u><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Edition number: 38 </span></u></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">The roll out of the Covid autumn booster vaccine begins today (Thursday, September 1st) in Wales.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Those who are eligible will be invited to have it this autumn. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We’ll let you know when it’s your turn and where you need to go. There is no need to contact the health board or your GP to ask for an appointment. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Please be patient.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">If you’re eligible, you’ll receive an invite to have the booster at one location. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">This could be one of our local vaccination centres (Canolfan Gorseinon or Aberafan Shopping Centre), a community pharmacy or your GP surgery.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Some people will already have received their appointments, others will follow. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">If you receive a letter and wish to change or cancel your appointment, please follow the instructions on the letter.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Residents in care homes and the housebound will be visited by vaccinators.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">If you’re missing a booster you’ll move on to receive your autumn booster only, as this will be sufficient to increase your protection. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">The Covid autumn booster will support the immunity of those who are at greatest risk from the disease, improving their protection against severe illness and helping to protect the NHS during what is likely to be another challenging winter.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Those who are eligible for the booster will also be offered a separate flu vaccination, along with some others who will receive the flu vaccination only.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Those eligible are:</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       Pregnant women</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People aged 50 and over</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People with a long-term health condition (from six months for flu and aged five for Covid)</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People who live in a care home</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People with a learning disability</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People with a severe mental illness</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       People who live with someone who has a weakened immune system (from six months for flu and aged five for Covid)</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       Carers aged 16 and over</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       Frontline health and social care workers</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">•       All staff working in care homes for older adults</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Flu only</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">1.     Children aged two and three will be offered the nasal spray flu vaccination by their GP surgery.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">2.     School pupils from reception to year 11 will be offered the nasal spray flu vaccination in school.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We’re leaving no one behind. So if you’re missing a first or second Covid vaccine, please contact our booking team on 01792 200492 or 01639 862323, between 9am and 5pm, Monday to Saturday.</span></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Date: Thursday, September 1st, 2022 Edition number: 38   The roll out of the Covid autumn booster vaccine begins today (Thursday, September 1st) in Wales. Those who are eligible will be invited to have it this autumn. We’ll let you know when it’s your turn and where you need to go. There is no need […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ciaran Kearney</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2688</id>
    <published>2022-09-01T12:25:53Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-01T12:25:53Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Support with the cost of living</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/support-with-the-cost-of-living/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The cost of living crisis is the biggest issue facing our country at the moment. With food prices increasing, heating bills going up and taxes rising, I know this is a very difficult time for many families in Hampstead and Kilburn and across the country.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you are struggling to keep up with rising costs, angry about the lack of help, or are confused about what support is available to you:&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;you are not alone.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you do need help with the cost of living crisis, I have set up this page to signpost some of the available support and advice from some fantastic organisations. I am of course pushing the Government to provide much more support for families during this crisis, but I hope this page will be helpful in explaining some of the support that is currently available. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If there is anything I can do to help or if you have any questions &amp;#8211; or if you help to run or know of any organisations which should be added to this list &amp;#8211; please email me at &lt;a href="&amp;#x6d;&amp;#97;i&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x74;o:&amp;#x74;&amp;#x75;li&amp;#x70;&amp;#64;t&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#105;p&amp;#x73;&amp;#x69;dd&amp;#x69;&amp;#113;.&amp;#x63;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#109;"&gt;tul&amp;#105;&amp;#112;&amp;#x40;&amp;#x74;&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x69;psi&amp;#100;&amp;#100;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x71;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#x63;&amp;#x6f;m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Useful links&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government Help for Households:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://helpforhouseholds.campaign.gov.uk/"&gt;https://helpforhouseholds.campaign.gov.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brent Council cost of living help &lt;/strong&gt;is facilitated through the Brent Resident Support Fund (RSF), which is a discretionary support fund available to Brent residents who are in financial difficulties, for example struggling with food, utility bills and other household essentials. Find out more &lt;a href="https://www.brent.gov.uk/benefits-and-money-advice/resident-support-fund#overview"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camden Council&lt;/strong&gt;’s website has listed a range of options depending on the type of support you need. Find out more &lt;a href="https://www.camden.gov.uk/find-support-in-camden"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Lewis from&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Money Saving Expert has a cost of living help page here:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/budgeting-debt-help/"&gt;https://www.moneysavingexpert.com/budgeting-debt-help/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citizens Advice:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.citizensadvice.org.uk/debt-and-money/get-help-with-the-cost-of-living/"&gt;https://www.citizensadvice.org.uk/debt-and-money/get-help-with-the-cost-of-living/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check what benefits you can get&lt;/em&gt;: You may be able to claim benefits or increase your current benefits if you are of working age and on a low income, sick or disabled, of state pension age and on a low income, a carer or responsible for children. Find out more here:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.citizensadvice.org.uk/benefits/benefits-introduction/what-benefits-can-i-get/"&gt;https://www.citizensadvice.org.uk/benefits/benefits-introduction/what-benefits-can-i-get/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get your benefits early&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Most benefits can be paid early. This is a ‘short term benefit advance’. A small amount will be taken off future payments to pay it back – usually for 12 weeks. To ask for an advance, contact the DWP office that’s dealing with your benefit claim. You can find their contact details on any letter or email you’ve had from them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Energy and household bills&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;British Gas Energy Trust&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;is an independent charitable trust which helps families struggling with money and energy debt. They can provide free support to make sure you’re getting the support and benefits you’re entitled to and run a direct access energy debt programme. For more information visit:&lt;a href="http://www.britishgasenergytrust.org.uk/"&gt;&amp;nbsp;www.britishgasenergytrust.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Saving Trust&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;work to help save money on household bills:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.energysavingtrust.org.uk/"&gt;www.energysavingtrust.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Heat the Human, not the Home&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;have tips on keeping yourself warm:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.moneysavingexpert.com/utilities/heat-the-human-not-the-home-save-energy"&gt;www.moneysavingexpert.com/utilities/heat-the-human-not-the-home-save-energy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Food&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brent Food Bank: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://brent.foodbank.org.uk/get-help/"&gt;https://brent.foodbank.org.uk/get-help/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you have not been referred to Brent Foodbank before, you can visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Brent Hubs&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;who are based at libraries across Brent. Their advisors can provide support with benefits, housing, debt etc, as well as issue you a food bank voucher code if appropriate. For details of their drop-in service, just visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.brenthubs.com/"&gt;Brent Hubs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can also contact the national&amp;nbsp;Help Through Hardship&amp;nbsp;line:&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;0808 208 2138&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;(free phone number 9am – 5pm)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camden Food Bank:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://camden.foodbank.org.uk/"&gt;https://camden.foodbank.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Please call &lt;strong&gt;0300 330 1157&lt;/strong&gt; to speak to Camden Citizens Advice Bureau, a referral agency partner of Camden Foodbank, who will be able to issue you with a voucher if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Family Support&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Government&lt;/strong&gt; page on Help for Families can be found&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://helpforhouseholds.campaign.gov.uk/help-with-childcare-costs/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Childbirth Trust: &lt;/strong&gt;Provides free advice and guidance for expecting mothers or new mothers: &lt;a href="https://www.nct.org.uk/"&gt;https://www.nct.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hopscotch Women&amp;#8217;s Centre&lt;/strong&gt; offers advice and advocacy for women experiencing domestic abuse, and general benefits advice: visit &lt;a href="https://hopscotchuk.org/"&gt;https://hopscotchuk.org/&lt;/a&gt; or call them on 020 7388 8198.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Healthy Start Scheme:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;If you’re more than 10 weeks pregnant or have a child under 4, you may be entitled to get help buy healthy food and milk. You’ll be sent a Healthy Start card with money on it that you can use in some UK shops to buy items such as: milk; fresh, frozen, and tinned fruit and vegetables; instant formula milk; Healthy Start vitamins. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.healthystart.nhs.uk/"&gt;www.healthystart.nhs.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sure Start Maternity Grant:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;A one-off payment of £500 to help towards the costs of having a child. You usually qualify if you are having your first child, or if you are expecting a multiple birth, and if you or your partner receive certain benefits. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.gov.uk/sure-start-maternity-grant"&gt;www.gov.uk/sure-start-maternity-grant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax Free Childcare:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;You can get up to £500 every 3 months (up to £2,000 a year) for each of your children to help with the costs of childcare. For every £8 you pay into this account, the government will pay in £2 to use to pay your provider. You can get Tax-Free Childcare at the same time as 30 hours free childcare if you’re eligible for both. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.healthystart.nhs.uk/"&gt;www.gov.uk/tax-free-childcare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bills and costs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broadband ‘social tariffs’.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;If you are on certain benefits, you may be entitled to cheaper broadband. Many companies offer these social tariffs, but they are not well advertised. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.moneysavingexpert.com/compare-broadband-deals/broadband-social-tariffs"&gt;www.moneysavingexpert.com/compare-broadband-deals/broadband-social-tariffs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Railcards.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;There are several different railcards available, they usually cut a third off the bill and most cost £30 a year. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.railcard.co.uk/"&gt;www.railcard.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advice4Renters&lt;/strong&gt; is a local organisation which offers support and legal advice to people living in private rented accommodation: &lt;a href="https://adviceforrenters.org/get-support"&gt;https://adviceforrenters.org/get-support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Financial Advice&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re struggling with debt or with managing your finances, there are several local and national organisations who can provide a variety of free help, advice and support:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brent Advice Matters: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bam.org.uk/"&gt;https://www.bam.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt Free London:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://debtfree.london/"&gt;https://debtfree.london/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;StepChange:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.stepchange.org/"&gt;https://www.stepchange.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Debtline:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.nationaldebtline.org/"&gt;https://www.nationaldebtline.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt Advice Foundation:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.debtadvicefoundation.org/"&gt;https://www.debtadvicefoundation.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Government&lt;/strong&gt; Cost of Living Support factsheet can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cost-of-living-support/cost-of-living-support-factsheet-26-may-2022"&gt;https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/cost-of-living-support/cost-of-living-support-factsheet-26-may-2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn2Us&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a national charity providing practical help to people who are struggling financially. They have a Benefits Calculator, which takes less than 10 minutes to complete and it will tell you which means-tested benefits you may be entitled to, a Grant Search and a Helpline. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.turn2us.org.uk/"&gt;www.turn2us.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money Saving Expert&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;can help with advice on making savings at&lt;a href="http://www.moneysavingexpert.com/"&gt;&amp;nbsp;www.moneysavingexpert.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step Change Debt Charity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;supports those struggling with debt. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.stepchange.org/"&gt;www.stepchange.org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or call 0800 138 1111&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MoneyHelper&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;offers free support in managing your money. For more information visit:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.moneyhelper.org.uk/"&gt;www.moneyhelper.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or call 0800 011 3797&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator"/&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mental Health Support&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you require urgent mental health support please call&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="tel:116123"&gt;116 123&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to talk to Samaritans or email:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="&amp;#x6d;ai&amp;#x6c;&amp;#116;o&amp;#x3a;&amp;#106;o&amp;#x40;&amp;#x73;a&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x61;ri&amp;#x74;&amp;#97;n&amp;#x73;&amp;#46;o&amp;#x72;&amp;#x67;"&gt;jo&amp;#64;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x61;ri&amp;#116;&amp;#97;&amp;#x6e;&amp;#x73;&amp;#x2e;org&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for a reply within 24 hours. They also offer non-urgent offer confidential support which can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.samaritans.org/"&gt;https://www.samaritans.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you would prefer to get help via text, text &amp;#8220;SHOUT&amp;#8221; to 85258 to contact the Shout Crisis Text Line, or text &amp;#8220;YM&amp;#8221; if you&amp;#8217;re under 19. You can see more information here: &lt;a href="https://giveusashout.org/"&gt;https://giveusashout.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re under 19, you can also call&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="tel:0800%201111"&gt;0800 1111&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to talk to&amp;nbsp;Childline. The number will not appear on your phone bill. Find more information here: &lt;a href="https://www.nspcc.org.uk/"&gt;https://www.nspcc.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mental Health Camden.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; This website provides a search directory of many support services in Camden to make it easier to find the support that is right for you: &lt;a href="https://www.mentalhealthcamden.co.uk/whats-available"&gt;https://www.mentalhealthcamden.co.uk/whats-available&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brent Council’s Website &lt;/strong&gt;provides information about some support services and further advice that may be useful: &lt;a href="https://www.brent.gov.uk/adult-social-care/health-and-wellbeing/promoting-mental-wellbeing"&gt;https://www.brent.gov.uk/adult-social-care/health-and-wellbeing/promoting-mental-wellbeing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beat &lt;/strong&gt;are an eating disorder charity who can be contacted online at &lt;a href="https://www.beateatingdisorders.org.uk/"&gt;https://www.beateatingdisorders.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt; or you can call their helpline at 0808 801 0677&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mind &lt;/strong&gt;provide advice and support to empower anyone experiencing a mental health problem. They also provide advice on how to cope during a crisis: &lt;a href="https://www.mind.org.uk/need-urgent-help/what-can-i-do-to-help-myself-cope/"&gt;https://www.mind.org.uk/need-urgent-help/what-can-i-do-to-help-myself-cope/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youngs Minds &lt;/strong&gt;are a UK wide mental health charity providing support for young people. Their website which also includes useful information for parents can be found here: &lt;a href="https://www.youngminds.org.uk/"&gt;https://www.youngminds.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The cost of living crisis is the biggest issue facing our country at the moment. With food prices increasing, heating bills going up and taxes rising, I know this is a very difficult time for many families in Hampstead and Kilburn and across the country. If you are struggling to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5561</id>
    <published>2022-08-31T16:43:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-08-31T16:43:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="crisis"/>
    <category term="support"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Breed Specific Legislation]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/08/31/breed-specific-legislation/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1684</id>
		<updated>2022-08-31T14:12:06Z</updated>
		<published>2022-08-31T14:12:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Animal"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Animal Welfare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Breed Specific Legislation"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="crime"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Dogs"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="legislation"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/08/31/breed-specific-legislation/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s August email newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-august-email-newsletter/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3328</id>
		<updated>2022-08-10T16:54:20Z</updated>
		<published>2022-08-09T11:23:53Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Constituent, Welcome to my August email newsletter. It has been an eventful few weeks in British politics, with the resignation of Boris Johnson launching a leadership contest in which we are now in the final stage. Conservative Party members up and down the country will now decide whether Rishi Sunak or Liz Truss will [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-august-email-newsletter/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my August email newsletter. It has been an eventful few weeks in British politics, with the resignation of Boris Johnson launching a leadership contest in which we are now in the final stage. Conservative Party members up and down the country will now decide whether Rishi Sunak or Liz Truss will become the next Conservative Party leader and Prime Minister.</p>



<p>In this newsletter, you will find updates on: the Conservative Party leadership contest, local bus services, my work with the Organisation for Security and Co-operation in Europe, local community action projects, and my annual summer survey to hear what you think.</p>



<h1>Leadership contest &#8211; and online poll:</h1>



<p>As&nbsp;you will be aware, Boris Johnson resigned as Conservative Party leader and Prime Minister on the 7th July.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During his time in office, Boris Johnson achieved much, getting Brexit done; organising one of the fastest Covid-19 vaccination programs in the world; and supporting Ukraine against the unprovoked aggression of Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is now a process that must be followed to select the next Conservative Party leader and Prime Minister. This process involves the Parliamentary Conservative Party selecting two final candidates through a series of votes. These two candidates are now&nbsp;put to a vote with all members of the Conservative Party up and down the country, and the winner of this vote becomes the leader of the party and Prime Minister. Rishi Sunak and Liz Truss have been selected as the final two candidates to enter the vote with Conservative Party members.</p>



<p>At the beginning of this leadership campaign, I created a poll to better understand your views on the candidates and your favourite to become leader and Prime Minister. We had a fantastic response to that poll, and I would like to thank those of you who took the time to complete it.</p>



<p>Now that we are in the final stage of the leadership election, with Rishi Sunak and Liz Truss selected as the final two candidates, I have created another poll for you to share your views about these two candidates. Like the previous poll, it should only take a minute or two to complete and I would be very interested to learn what you think about the final candidates.</p>



<p>You can find the poll <a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/conservative-leadership-poll/">here</a>.</p>



<h1>Transpeak bus service:</h1>



<p>I am pleased to inform residents that the Transpeak bus connecting Derby and Buxton, through Belper and Ambergate, will continue. The service was due to be reduced to just one bus a day in each direction from Sunday, 10th July onwards. However, thanks to a funding boost from Derbyshire County Council the bus will continue to run at the same level of service as before – once an hour from Monday to Saturday, and once every two hours on Sunday.</p>



<p>The bus is set to be subsidised for up to 6 months to allow time for passenger numbers to recover, as they are yet to return to pre-pandemic levels. I have been calling for Government funding to be used by Derbyshire County Council to maintain existing services for some time, so I thoroughly welcome this decision.</p>



<p>I know residents have also raised the issue of the 1A bus service through Waingroves with me, so I&#8217;ve also been raising this issue with the County Council. </p>



<h1>The Organisation for Security &amp; Co-operation in Europe:</h1>



<p>From the 2nd-6th July, I attended the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe’s (OSCE) annual session in Birmingham, in which over 300 delegates from 56 parliaments met to discuss the future of international security in Europe. In the face of Russia’s barbaric and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, the current state of security and co-operation in Europe is at its most precarious since the end of the cold war. Summits like these are, therefore, absolutely vital for maintaining cooperation and order throughout Europe and the rest of the world.</p>



<p>I attended as a member of a cross-party delegation of 10 MPs and Peers led by John Whittingdale MP. During the session, the Parliamentary Assembly strongly denounced Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. Agreeing upon a resolution that “calls upon the Russian Federation to establish an immediate ceasefire and withdraw Russian troops from the whole of Ukraine.”</p>



<p>Further committee sessions discussed human rights, victims of terror attacks, the role of non-governmental organisations, economic growth following Covid-19, sustainable energy, and recent increases in migration. The OSCE stands for lasting security in Eurasia through justice, problem-solving and development. The Parliamentary Assembly enables the strengthening of common values between the countries involved, particularly in times of international crisis. It is, therefore, a great privilege to be involved and to support this vial work.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>National Citizen Service visit:</h1>



<p>On the 8<sup>th</sup> July I met with a&nbsp;group of young people from the National Citizen Service (NCS) in Alfreton. The National Citizen Service is a voluntary program for 15–17 year-olds offering real world experience as well as opportunities for personal development. The program normally runs in the summer and consists of a week staying away from home working on social action projects that benefit the community. It is a great way for young people to make new friends and accomplish something to be proud of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was a real pleasure to meet the NCS group in Alfreton and hear about their projects that are actively improving local communities, and to discuss a range of interesting questions they’d prepared. The group had been organising a fund-raising event at the Miners Arms to raise money for Ashgate Hospice, which turned out to be a brilliant success.</p>



<p>If you would like to learn more about NCS and how to get involved, <a href="https://wearencs.com/">click here.</a></p>



<h1>Summer survey &amp; visits:</h1>



<p>Recess is a break during the Parliamentary calendar in which neither the House of Commons nor the House of Lords sits. It allows time for MPs to focus on their constituencies away from Westminster. The House of Commons rose this year on the 21<sup>st</sup> July and will return on the 5<sup>th</sup> of September, also the date in which we will learn the winner of the Conservative leadership contest and the next Prime Minister.</p>



<p>Over the last few weeks, I&#8217;ve been&nbsp;out and about in Amber Valley delivering my annual summer survey. The purpose of this survey is to get your views on some of the biggest issues facing our constituency and the nation. This helps inform my decisions on how best to represent you in Westminster, and which local issues my team and I should focus on in our area. If you see me out and about, please feel free to come and have a chat, even if it is not about politics. If you’d like to do the summer survey online, you can also&nbsp; complete it <a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/residents-survey-2022/">here.</a></p>



<p>In addition to delivering surveys, I have also been using my time in recess so far to visit local farms and industry. On the 25<sup>th</sup> July I visited Crowfields Farm in Langley Mill where, among other things, we discussed food security, sustainable food production and the volatile markets created by the energy price spikes and Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<h1>Other local news &#8211; <em>and don&#8217;t forget to vote for Shipley Country Park!</em></h1>



<p>Historic England has announced a grant of nearly £10,000 for MSDS Heritage to realise a project which will explore the old working-class communities and cottage industry that once existed within Holbrook. The project is called ‘Holbrook’s Hidden Heritage’ and will involve archaeologists working with local schools and volunteers to create workshops, events, web content, open days, and pop-up events.</p>



<p>Holbrook in 1845 contained 54 stocking-frame workshops, with 152 stocking frames operated by workers with materials supplied by the mills at Milford and Belper. Learning more about our past can inspire pride and a sense of community in the present, so I hope this project gets the attention it deserves.</p>



<p>In other local news, as some of you will have seen from my social media, Shipley County Park has been nominated for Fields in Trust UK’s Favourite Parks award 2022. Voting is now open to decide the nations favourite park and will close at noon on the 18th August. If a park finishes within the top 20% of votes, it will receive recognition as a ‘Local Favourite’. The four Home Nation winners will then be shortlisted before the UK’s favourite park is announced.</p>



<p>Shipley Country Park is an exceptionally valuable local space. And when local parks have acted as a sanctuary for so many over the past few years, now is our chance to celebrate the spaces where we could get outdoors, move, relax, and meet with loved ones.</p>



<p>Please show your support by voting online before Thursday 18th August: <a href="http://www.fieldsintrust.org/favourite-parks/nominations">www.fieldsintrust.org/favourite-parks/nominations</a></p>



<p><strong>Derby Telegraph column:</strong></p>



<p>My latest column for the Derby Telegraph, focusing on the cost of living crisis and some of the issues that will be facing our new Prime Minister, is available to catch up on <a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/derby-telegraph-column-july-2022/">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom</h2>



<p>The availability of free education is a gift, but only if it can come with high quality. Google Classroom has given students in classrooms around the country an online option to supplement their learning. A potential downside to these options is the inability to meet with professors and apply classroom learning. As a part of the University of Washington system, we have found the use of Google Classroom during the quarter distance courses produced good results for both parties. Distance learning is here to stay and has only grown over time. If you want to make sure you aren’t left behind in a digital world, you may want to consider your options and how they will help or hurt your future professional prospects.</p>



<p>Google Classroom is a reliable one-stop-shop for managing all of your coursework and communication. It is definitely worth checking out if you are in a distance learning program, or even just want to streamline some of your everyday communication tasks.</p>



<h3>Benefits and Drawbacks</h3>



<p>There are several other features that set Google Classroom apart from the competition. It is a free tool and it works on computers and mobile devices through the GAFE platform. The discussion features of Google Classroom do an excellent job at encouraging interaction between students and teachers, making it a very effective tool for working with groups of all sizes. The major drawback to Google Classroom is that it is a relatively new tool, so it does not work with iPads, Android tablets or Kindle Fires. The lessons created within Google Docs can be exported directly into Google Classroom on the computer, but in order to view or edit those documents or upload them onto the iPad tablet, students will have to use other third-party tools such as Documents 5 and iBooks Author.</p>



<h2>Integration</h2>



<p>If you are using Google Classroom for your teaching and learning, it is important to note that it does require integration with Google Apps for Education. This means that you are using Gmail along with Calendar and Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides) etc., so the other school faculty members need to have access to all of these tools. The obvious way to do this is through the use of a domain. It is required that you have a domain in order to use Google Classroom or any other GAFE tool/application.</p>



<p>By going through a step by step process, one can easily move one’s entire digital repository into Google Classroom for easy organization and management; therefore, allowing access to all student work without having to worry about losing any data or files that are not needed for a current class engagement.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom Future Prospects</h2>



<p>According to the Scholastic Parent &amp; Child list of the most popular educational apps , in 2015 Classroom wasn’t one of them, indicating that this tool is still relatively new and also relatively unknown. While the design is nothing particularly innovative, the new Google Classroom 2022 is a promising step towards more effective and efficient learning, especially in a classroom setting. Though it appears to be geared towards teachers, students will benefit from having access to Google Classroom, whether they’re in an online or a traditional classroom. With that said, it should be noted that it may take some time before this update fully penetrates into secondary schools and universities. But nonetheless, Google Classroom is off on the right foot, leaning further into an online world which we’ll all have to face sooner or later.</p>



<h2>Bottom Line</h2>



<p>Google Classroom has made a huge impact in the world of educational technology, especially for teachers who don’t have face-to-face access to students. It’s a powerful tool that will likely continue to be developed and improved upon, as educators keep gravitating towards it.</p>



<p>In the end, there is no one best way to teach and learn, but instead many valid options. Whether you are interested in the low-cost education of a MOOC or the high-end technology of Sketchfab virtual reality tours, it’s exciting to see that educational technology is progressing at a rapid rate. Let’s hope that as more schools begin to adopt innovative techniques like Google Classroom, we will continue to see positive changes in how students learn around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission. Google […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=211</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet visits Birmingham school as they link up with children in Nigeria in lead up to 2022 games</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-visits-birmingham-school-they-link-children-nigeria-lead-2022-games" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Today, Preet Kaur Gill MP joined with pupils at St Paul's School for Girls to take part in online activities with children in Nigeria in the run up to the Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games. Preet and the children linked up with Bomas Academy in Jos, Nigeria, and exchanged information about their families, school life and favour subjects. </p>
<p>Steve Frew, who took gold in the 2002 games and 400m champion Lesley Owusu also joined them at the school for a morning of sporting activities. The event was part of Commonwealth Connections - a partnership between the British Council and the Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games. It involves 60 primary, secondary, and special schools in the West Midlands linking up with 60 schools across 10 Commonwealth countries. Through the partnership, children explore cultures and beliefs and learn how to communicate with people from different backgrounds and perspectives through sports and arts.  </p>
<p>Preet Kaur Gill, MP for Birmingham Edgbaston, said: “Our wonderful city of Birmingham is one of the most diverse in the world and truly reflects the Commonwealth. It’s fantastic to see Commonwealth Connections promoting collaboration and encouraging young people to make new connections with people from different backgrounds and different countries. </p>
<p>“The Sustainable Development Goals 2030 affect us all and it’s vital young people, as future leaders, understand why these are so important. By talking to people across the world with different perspectives of how climate change and sustainability is impacting people’s lives is how we show how global Britain can be a force for good.” </p>
<p>During the event, St Paul’s School for Girls was presented with a British Council foundation level <a href="https://www.britishcouncil.org/school-resources/accreditation/international-school-award/about" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">International School Award</a> by the organisation’s Senior Schools Consultant, John Rolfe MBE. The award champions schools that have shown a commitment to embedding international awareness and understanding in their classrooms and curriculums. The £500k Commonwealth Connections project is co-funded by Birmingham 2022 and the British Council.  </p>
<p>The British Council is delivering the project with Birmingham Education Partnership (BEP) and the children’s charity the Youth Sport Trust (YST). BEP has nominated its flagship Birmingham Arts School to lead on delivery of the arts and culture strand of the project. </p>
<p>ENDS </p>
<p>For more information, please contact: </p>
<p>Notes to Editors  </p>
<p>About Commonwealth Connections </p>
<p>Commonwealth Connections is a joint project from the British Council and the Birmingham Organising Committee for the 2022 Commonwealth Games.  </p>
<p>Running from the autumn 2021 until July 2022, it is twinning 60 schools in Birmingham and the West Midlands with counterparts in Ghana, India, Jamaica, Kenya, Nigeria, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Trinidad and Tobago, Uganda, Zambia </p>
<p>The British Council is delivering the project in partnership with Birmingham Education Partnership (BEP) and the Youth Sport Trust (YST).  </p>
<p>Supporting 120 primary, secondary and special schools in Birmingham/West Midlands and across 10 Commonwealth countries to use sport, arts and culture to learn about the Commonwealth and their own identities, in a way that focusses the attention and excitement of young people and their communities on the 2022 Commonwealth Games in Birmingham </p>
<p>About the British Council </p>
<p>The British Council is the UK’s international organisation for cultural relations and educational opportunities. We build connections, understanding and trust between people in the UK and other countries through arts and culture, education and the English language. In 2019-2020 we reached over 75 million people directly and 758 million people overall including online, broadcasts and publications. Founded in 1934 we are a UK charity governed by Royal Charter and a UK public body. We receive a 14.5 per cent core funding grant from the UK government. www.<a href="http://www.britishcouncil.org/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">britishcouncil.org</a> </p>
<p>About the Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games    </p>
<p>The Birmingham 2022 Commonwealth Games, which will be held from 28 July until 8 August 2022, will be a once in a lifetime opportunity to put the city, the region and its people on the global stage.       </p>
<p>The Games is already proving to be a catalyst for transformation across the West Midlands, attracting new investment and funding, creating jobs and apprenticeships for local people and new opportunities for local businesses, as well as accelerating projects that will ensure the region is ready to host a fantastic sports and cultural celebration.       </p>
<p>Birmingham 2022 will be the Games for everyone, bringing people together from across Birmingham and the region, to provide a warm welcome to millions of visitors during the summer of 2022.     </p>
<p>Find out more at <a href="http://www.birmingham2022.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">www.birmingham2022.com</a>       </p>
<p> </p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Standard (Image)</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/WhatsApp%20Image%202022-05-19%20at%201.09.16%20PM.jpeg" width="1518" height="908" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>1095 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2022-05-19T13:03:19Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-19T13:03:19Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[“An attack on workers’ rights”: Alex backs care workers’ in campaign against de-recognition of trade unions by Barchester Healthcare]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/03/an-attack-on-workers-rights-alex-backs-care-workers-in-campaign-against-de-recognition-of-trade-unions-by-barchester-healthcare/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14435</id>
		<updated>2022-03-03T10:35:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-03-03T10:35:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham has backed and local care workers as they campaign against a care home provider’s decision to refuse to negotiate agreements with their trade unions on pay and conditions. Barchester Healthcare, which operates Billingham Grange Independent Hospital in Billingham has moved to scrap trade union recognition agreements, which will see care [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/03/an-attack-on-workers-rights-alex-backs-care-workers-in-campaign-against-de-recognition-of-trade-unions-by-barchester-healthcare/">“An attack on workers’ rights”: Alex backs care workers’ in campaign against de-recognition of trade unions by Barchester Healthcare</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time>
</div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=0KHgyujV" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/>



  </div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-634197ad27055" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-634197ad27055').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"634197ad27055","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-634197ad27055" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-634197ad27055" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="634197ad27055" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_634197ad27055" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_634197ad27055" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_634197ad27055" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_634197ad27055" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_634197ad27055" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_634197ad27055" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_634197ad27055_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-634197ad27055 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dyet0R4qyfM58_in7faMjEu_Q3rIXWkVqWB6CRPNQsHbtV94fz1VkLwlxtLs0hcrwNZXH7lipYxaEmK1t1zuw' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
