<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-07-24T03:49:50Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Memo to an incoming PM   Help Cabinet government work better</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/07/23/memo-to-an-incoming-pm-help-cabinet-government-work-better/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the most important things a PM does is choose people for senior Cabinet roles. These choices are best based on talent, energy and understanding of the jobs concerned. Whilst of course the overall balance of the Cabinet has to take into account wings of the party, geographical spread and loyalties these should be secondary issues to the more normal matters in selection that are related to  being able to doing the job well. Cabinet members do not get a phase in or training period when they first join. They are expected from Day1 to be able to make decisions, defend their department and show knowledge of their topics regardless of their background and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PM should have regular review meetings with the senior Cabinet members one to one. These meetings should be to give guidance to a Cabinet member over PM preferences and how the departmental policy and priorities can fit into the general strategy. They are also occasions when the Cabinet member can ask for support and assistance, and the PM can show understanding of a colleague&amp;#8217;s plight and mentor where necessary. As there are too many Cabinet positions to report one to one to the PM senior Cabinet members should perform the role for more junior Cabinet members. The Chancellor should guide the Chief Secretary, the Foreign Secretary the Overseas Aid and Trade Ministers etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cross departmental strategies like levelling up or greening government should come to Cabinet for determination. Conflicts between departments over issues should come to cabinet or committee for resolution. A Cabinet member should be held responsible for a policy entirely or mainly within their own department. So the Chancellor should be responsible for tax strategy and the Home Secretary responsible for migration policy. Given the importance of these to government as a whole the PM should keep them under review in the one to ones and they should report to Cabinet regularly as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of the most important things a PM does is choose people for senior Cabinet roles. These choices are best based on talent, energy and understanding of the jobs concerned. Whilst of course the overall balance of the Cabinet has to take into account wings of the party, geographical spread and loyalties these should be…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33129</id>
    <published>2022-07-23T04:01:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-23T04:01:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up 22 July 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/22/weekly-round-up-22-july-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-22-july-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Two weeks ago, Conservative Party MPs voted to oust Boris Johnson saying he couldn’t be trusted to be our Prime Minister anymore. On Monday night, at about 10pm, 342 of them voted to have confidence in the Prime Minister and his government. Yes, you read that right. Within two weeks of baying for him to leave they quickly regrouped to support him to save themselves from a General Election. </p>
<p>It’s clear that the Conservative Party has run out of ideas and the country has run out of faith in them. I voted no confidence in the Government because it is clear that whoever takes over from Boris Johnson does not have a mandate to govern and will be unable to solve the issues facing the country.</p>
<p>Indeed, the result of the Conservative Party MPs ballots shows they are divided from top to bottom. Liz Truss and Rishi Sunak will now parade themselves in front of an estimated 200,000 Conservative Party members this summer. This vote will decide the Prime Minister for the entire country.</p>
<p>When we hear the policy ‘solutions’ – and I use that term in the loosest sense – from Sunak and Truss we hear of dogmatic answers to the wrong questions. Unfunded spending commitment and tax cuts will not solve inflation nor the growing national debt racked up by the Government in the past 12 years. Today we discovered that national debt interest repayments have now hit £19.4bn – that’s up over £10bn from last June. It’s clear that the Conservative contenders to be Prime Minister are not going to be responsible with taxpayers’ money.</p>
<p>This week the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee launched its new inquiry into non-executive directors with questions from experts. The session explored the activities, appointment process and accountability mechanisms for non-executives, hearing from experts who have carried out research in this area at the Institute for Government, University College London Constitution Unit and Commission for Smart Government.</p>
<p>Non-executives are appointed by Secretaries of State to sit on the boards of government departments and provide challenge on departmental performance and delivery. The Committee’s inquiry was launched in June to examine a lack of transparency around their activities, influence, and effectiveness in UK Government governance structures.</p>
<p>It was also Health Questions this week. I pressed minister on why the Government barely mentioned social care when responding to the Urgent Question on ambulance waiting times. The Government’s approach to healthcare is short-sighted as they fail to ever consider social care properly. If we don’t tackle the chronic understaffing in social care or the broken model it is based upon, we will not solve the NHS waiting times.</p>
<p>Parliament has now gone into Summer Recess. What that means is the Commons, the Committees and all the other aspects of legislative scrutiny will now go on pause until September when the schools return. However, work will continue in the office supporting constituents.</p>
<p>There will be no more weekly round-ups until September when Parliament returns, but please do keep in touch.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/22/weekly-round-up-22-july-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 22 July 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Two weeks ago, Conservative Party MPs voted to oust Boris Johnson saying he couldn’t be trusted to be our Prime […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/22/weekly-round-up-22-july-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 22 July 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3316</id>
    <published>2022-07-22T07:50:02Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-22T07:50:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conor leads debate on British glass and St Helens’ role in making it world’s best</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/07/21/conor-leads-debate-on-british-glass-and-st-helens-role-in-making-it-the-worlds-best/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7449</id>
    <published>2022-07-21T16:00:15Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-21T16:00:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-roundup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Monday lunchtime Jess Morden MP Newport East hosted the Westminster event to celebrate the Welsh Arts Review 10th Anniversary. It was very interesting to listen to authors read out their contributions to the recently published anthology “<a href="https://uk.bookshop.org/books/home-to-you-10-years-of-wales-arts-review/9781739851705?fbclid=IwAR24jrBd3a5D0RgvqfsEKol7XylJSmCIVLNtt3p64MSSRujDE31UqxGlf5E">Home to You:10 Years of Wales Arts Review</a>”.</p>
<p>For the last decade Wales Arts Review has sought to publish some of the best critical writing from Wales and about Wales. Tracing the cultural ties between Wales and the wider world. This latest publication asks what it means to be Welsh in a globalised digital culture and how Wales responds to international crisis and controversies. Gary Raymond, presenter of The Review Show on BBC Radio Wales, is the editor and he began the event by reading out his forward to this latest anthology.</p>
<p>It was a pleasure to meet Chris Roberts from South Wales Police at the PCSO event to mark the 20th Anniversary of the creation of PCSOs, sponsored by Unison. PCSOs are the face of the local police force, out on the streets, talking to people, supporting officers, preventing crime, and building relationships with local residents. We have wonderful PCSOs in Neath and I really value the service that they give in our communities, day in day out.</p>
<p>The business in the chamber was the debate on the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-11/debates/494EDB6D-EEC5-45D2-97F1-009F2398D942/Energy(OilAndGas)ProfitsLevyBill">Energy (Oil and Gas) Profits Levy Bill</a>. After many hours of debate, votes were taken on amendments, clauses, and new clauses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Labour voted against that – Clause 2 which creates a new investment allowance that producers have 91p in tax relief for every £1 they invest, which would see billions in windfall tax revenue going straight back to firms making mega profits – stand part of the Bill and lost by ayes 284 to noes 202.</li>
<li>Labour New Clause 3 required the U.K. Government to review the impact of bringing forward the start date of the windfall tax from when the Government announced it on 26th May to when Labour called for it on 9th January. Labour lost this vote by ayes 203 to noes 289</li>
</ul>
<p>Deferred Divisions were taken at the end of the Bill votes:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Draft Conduct of Employment Agencies and Employment Businesses (Amendment) Regulations 2022 vote was taken, and Labour voted against, losing by ayes 289 to noes 202.</li>
<li>Labour voted for the Humble Address: Liability of Trade Unions in Proceedings in Tort (Increase in Limits on Damages) Order 2022 and lost by ayes 201 to noes 290.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-11">House of Commons – Hansard – 11th July 2022</a></p>
<p>On Tuesday morning I attended the APPG on Liver Disease and Liver Cancer AGM and we re-elected my friend Wayne David MP Caerphilly as chair. We heard oral evidence on the need for a comprehensive review of adult liver services from Professor Stephen Ryder, Consultant Professor in Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust, and a patient told us of his personal experience of late liver disease diagnosis and secondary care. The Chief Executive of British Liver Trust, Pam Healy OBE, set out the steps we need to take to raise awareness of all aspects of liver diagnosis and treatment. In May 2021, NHS England stated that they would be undertaking a national review of adult liver services, but the earliest this would happen is 2022/23.</p>
<p>Pam told members of the APPG that we need action now, because 90% of liver disease is preventable, but three quarters of people are diagnosed with cirrhosis at crisis point in hospital when it’s too late for effective treatment. Research shows that only 26% of areas in U.K. have an effective pathway for early detection and management of liver disease. Wales and in particular our Heath Board, SBUHB do have this pathway in place.</p>
<p>On Tuesday afternoon the Petitions Committee held an informal, confidential, Roundtable on petitioning Parliament, as preliminary work, which will form part of a potential enquiry into petitioning which the Petitions Committee may decide to conduct. We heard from three academics who have researched petitions and public participation regarding: starting and signing petitions; scrutiny and public engagement with petitions; petition outcomes; and experiences beyond the U.K. Parliament.</p>
<p>We heard from: Professor of Politics at University of Leeds, Cristina Leston-Bandeira who published “<a href="https://www.researchgate.net/project/The-Petitions-Committee-in-the-UK-Parliament-developing-a-new-style-of-public-engagement">The Petitions Committee in the U.K. Parliament developing a new style of public engagement”</a> in 2019; Professor of Politics at University of Sheffield, Felicity Matthews who focuses on researching about the exercise of power in the policy process and relationships between government, parliament, and citizens;  Professor of Democratic Politics and Deputy Director of the Constitution Unit at University College London, Alan Renwick, has vast expertise in the mechanisms through which citizens can participate formal politics, and citizens assemblies.</p>
<p>Later in the afternoon, as a Labour and Co-operative MP, I attended the regular Co-operative Party Parliamentary Group meeting to review current campaigns and to plan future campaigns that we will start in September.</p>
<p>The business in the Chamber was the remaining stages of the <a href="https://bills.parliament.uk/bills/3137">Online Safety Bill</a> in which I couldn’t take part, nor vote on, because Parliamentary convention states that I must remain independent, as I have been a co-chair of the Online Safety Bill Committee.</p>
<p>The debate was contributed to by many members from across the Chamber, and by all members of the Bill Committee. MPs voted on the following amendments, clauses, and new clauses at the end of the debate:</p>
<ul>
<li>New Clause 3 required violence against women and girls (VAWG) to be on the face of the Bill and required tech companies to prevent and address VAWG as defined in the Istanbul Convention. Labour lost the division by ayes 226 to noes 292.</li>
<li>SNP Amendment 187 to add at page 186, end of line 32, schedule 7, “human trafficking, which Labour supported and lost by ayes 229 to noes 294.</li>
<li>New Clause 14, making judgements on content, outlines methods that platforms will have to use to make judgements, and that it is unworkable at scale and at pace. If this clause operates as Labour imagines it means huge amounts of content that is close to being illegal will not be acted upon. Labour opposed the new clause and lost by ayes 288 to noes 229.</li>
<li>New Clause 7, introduced by the Labour Front Bench, regarding user generated porn content, was defeated by ayes 220 to noes 285.</li>
<li>Amendment 31 required that the Secretary of State’s definition of content that is harmful to adults and content that is harmful to children must be debated on the floor of the House. Labour lost by ayes 188 to noes 283.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-12">House of Commons – Hansard – 12th July 2022</a></p>
<p>On Wednesday morning I signed the book of commemoration for the Srebrenica Genocide, coordinated by the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) on Srebrenica. On Monday 11th July, twenty-seven years ago, in the first ever United Nations declared safe area, thousands of men and boys were systematically murdered and buried in mass graves. This was the worst atrocity on European soil since the Second World War, and occurred alongside forced deportation, torture, and systematic sexual violence across Bosnia by Bosnian Serb forces as part of their goal to create a “Greater Serbia”.</p>
<p>Then I joined the “Time to Care: boosting the economy and gender equality through investment in social care” Unison event. Guest speakers Christina McAnea, General Secretary of Unison; Karin Smyth, Shadow Minister for Social Care; Clare Evelyn Akoto, cabinet Member for Health and Well-being, Southwark Council; and Dr Mary-Ann Stephenson, Director of the Women’s Budget Group spoke about the U.K. starting to recover from the pandemic in the face of the worst cost-of-living crisis in a generation, investment in industries that have been particularly affected is needed and this can boost our flagging economy. Proper investment in social care by the U.K. Government must be considered a driver of economic recovery, rather than merely a burden on public finances.</p>
<p>Late Wednesday morning, I joined the AGM of the APPG for Dog Welfare chaired by Dr Marc Abraham BVM&amp;S MRCVS to elect officers and to plan forthcoming discussions from September, which will include dog control issues; the worrying rise in canine fertility clinics; and a documentary preview on the illegal puppy trade. We heard from guest speaker Wayne David MP Caerphilly about his recent <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2022-07-07a.1094.0&amp;s=Home+Secretary">Adjournment Debate</a> which focused on Dangerous Dogs. Wayne also spoke in the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-06-06/debates/E7DC68B3-E1E5-449B-B922-F3333187C8FB/Breed-SpecificLegislation">Petitions Debate</a> that I opened about the reform of the Dangerous Dogs Act 1991 which has not operated as it was intended to prevent dog incidents, and many dogs have been taken away from their owners because of the way they look, not because they exhibit dangerous behaviour. We all agreed that responsible dog ownership is a priority, and that the legislation must be reformed.</p>
<p>I sat in my usual spot on the very back bench at PMQs and most MPs were taken aback when Boris Johnson made what he said was his final appearance at PMQs. We were expecting his last appearance to be on Wednesday 20th July. MPs across the House wondered where he was going to be on the 20th that was more important than being at PMQs.</p>
<p>As chair of the APPG for Vegetarianism and Veganism I opened an online event to discuss plant-based meals for climate friendly catering in the public sector. Earlier this year the IPCC highlighted the uptake of plant-based diets as an opportunity to reduce greenhouse gas emissions. The <a href="https://www.theccc.org.uk/publication/sixth-carbon-budget/">6th Carbon Budget</a> released last year by the U.K. Committee on Climate Change recommended that the government set an ambitious target for meat and dairy reduction and called on the public sector to be leaders by providing more plant-based options.</p>
<p>Last month, the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/government-food-strategy">Government Food Strategy</a> was finally published, which was its long-awaited response to Henry Dimbleby’s <a href="https://www.nationalfoodstrategy.org/">National Food Strategy for England</a>. We heard from Phil Rees-Jones, Director of Services for Cardiff University; Anna Taylor, Chief Independent Advisor to Henry Dimbleby; and Councillor Ian Middleton, and the Catering Operations Manager, Gail Witchell both from Oxfordshire County Council. There followed a lively Q&amp;A from the many people who joined this online event.</p>
<p>I dashed off to chair a debate in Westminster Hall led by Mike Amesbury on the provision of careers guidance in schools. The debate was well attended by MPs from across the House. <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-13/debates/16ADC431-015A-40EC-8731-CC36152A63C2/CareersGuidanceInSchools">Careers Guidance in Schools – Westminster Hall – 13th July 2022</a></p>
<p>The business in the Chamber was the Northern Ireland Protocol Bill, and many MPs from all Parties contributed to this very important debate. Many amendments, clauses and new clauses were laid, and the following were pressed to a division:</p>
<ul>
<li>Labour Front Bench Amendment 26 required Ministers of the Crown to set out a legal justification for altering the effect of the Northern Ireland Protocol in domestic law. Labour lost the division by ayes 231 to noes 313.</li>
<li>Amendment 8 adds Article 18 (Democratic Consent in Northern Ireland) of the Northern Ireland Protocol to the list of articles that a Minister of the Crown cannot exercise powers conferred by subsection (2) and cease to have effect in the U.K. to any extent. Labour lost the division by ayes 230 to noes 308.</li>
<li>Labour opposed that clauses 15 and 16 stand part of the Bill. These clauses would give Ministers broad powers to disapply other parts of the Protocol beyond those specified under the Bill, and Ministers would be able to do this through regulations rather than primary legislation. These powers would be used on the basis of a range of “permitted purposes” which include safeguarding social and economic stability; protecting the Good Friday Agreement; and ensuring the flow of trade between Northern Ireland and Great Britain. Labour lost the division by ayes 308 to noes 231.</li>
<li>Labour Front Bench’s New Clause 10 aimed to prevent the U.K. Government from having the power to make unilateral changes to the terms of the Northern Ireland Protocol in a way that would breach the UK’s international legal obligations and was defeated by ayes 229 to noes 300.</li>
<li>Stephen Farry MP, Alliance Party of Northern Ireland, moved amendment 24, which would remove from clause 4 the measures that strip out the heart of the protocol, namely article 5 which relates to the management of the customs union and single market as they pertain to Northern Ireland, making it an excluded provision under domestic law. Labour supported this amendment, but it was defeated by ayes 212 to noes 285.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-13">House of Commons – Hansard – 13th July 2022</a></p>
<p>On Thursday I chaired Westminster Hall debates beginning with the Select Committee Statement on the Second Report of the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-07-14/debates/22071455000001/AccessToCashInScotland">Scottish Affairs Committee: Access to Cash in Scotland</a>, HC 80, presented by Pete Wishart MP, chair of the committee. Convention of the House states that Mr Wishart had up to 10 minutes to deliver the report, then MPs could ask questions about the report, for a total of up to 10 minutes, which would be answered one question at a time by Mr Wishart. The debate was over-subscribed and unfortunately some MPs did not have the opportunity to ask their question because we ran out of time.</p>
<p>The next debate was opened by Jim Shannon MP for Strangford, and MPs considered <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-07-14/debates/57ED11CF-8E5B-4264-BB47-C13354BE03BB/NHSPPESupplyChainsForcedLabour">forced labour and NHS PPE supply chains</a>. Mr Shannon spoke at length about the terrible exploitation of adults and children who work many hours for a pittance. The SNP spokesperson, and the Opposition spokesperson agreed that this must be addressed. The Minister delivered the U.K. Government’s position and answered questions that were put to her.</p>
<p>Friday Sitting Days are back after being suspended since the first lockdown due to the pandemic. On this first Friday sitting I was privileged to present my Private Members Bill to ban the import and export of shark fins and items associated with shark fins into and out of the U.K. – <a href="https://bills.parliament.uk/bills/3207">Shark Fins Bill</a></p>
<p>I was listed third on the Order Paper, and it’s always unpredictable as to how many PMBs will actually be debated, because if a PMB listed before you is “talked out”, which is in essence filibustering until time runs out at 2.30pm, or the two PMBs in front take up all the allotted time to 2.30pm that’s the end of the matter, and my PMB would fall without being heard. I was delighted when the two PMBs in front of me were supported by the U.K. Government Minister. Therefore, there was time for more PMBs to be debated, and I had the immense privilege to present my PMB.</p>
<p>Sharks are truly incredible animals that have been around for over 400 million years – long before dinosaurs. Many sharks live in U.K. waters, from basking sharks to Greenland sharks. The basking shark is the UK’s largest fish growing up to 11 metres long and weighing up to 7 tonnes, the size of a double decker bus. But out of 500 species more than a quarter are listed from vulnerable to critically endangered. Research has shown that at least 73 million sharks would have to be killed every year to match the volume of shark fins traded in the global market, that’s 1 million to 2 million tonnes a year. It is likely that shark finning is a significant driving force.</p>
<p>My PMB only applies to fins that have been removed from the body of a shark. It does not ban the sale or consumption of shark fins if the fins are removed after the shark is dead and the shark was caught legally and sustainably. This would disproportionately impact communities where shark fin soup is a traditional delicacy. My PMB makes sure that shark finning cannot take place by any vessel fishing in U.K. waters, or by any U.K. vessel fishing in non-U.K. waters.</p>
<p>And because it relates to devolved administrations, legislative consent will be sought from the devolved administrations during the passage of the Bill, but I understand that they are supportive.</p>
<p>Many MPs spoke in support of my PMB, and some stakeholders who have been campaigning for many years to ban shark finning watched from the public gallery, in particular Shark Guardian and Bite Back. At the end of the debate the Minister confirmed that the U.K. Government supported my PMB and that it would also cover banning the 20kg of dried shark fin that people are currently allowed to bring into the U.K. for personal use.</p>
<p>I felt very humble that my PMB had achieved its Second Reading and thanked everyone for their support. It will now proceed into Bill Committee in the autumn.</p>
<p><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-07-15/debates/FFD16FD9-DAAF-4876-8B55-86C7083443EA/SharkFinsBill">Shark Fins Bill – Hansard – 15th July 2022</a></p>
<p>Back in the constituency, I was delighted to spend time with the <a href="https://www.peoplescollection.wales/users/66211?fbclid=IwAR1N6PT-bNp3voDyytrMRlBJjmaAsf-eUCiFCkraw2dBkbd64TbW9XiTJek">Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company</a> who have spent many years restoring the Neath Abbey Ironworks. As a vice-chair of the APPG for Industrial Heritage, at our last meeting of the APPG, I highlighted the amazing work of the Friends. I suggested that members of the APPG should visit the Ironworks, and, that the Friends should address a meeting of our APPG in Westminster.</p>
<p>I am very proud of the tremendous progress that these wonderful volunteers have made, and I look forward to welcoming colleagues of the APPG to Neath sometime in the autumn.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday lunchtime Jess Morden MP Newport East hosted the Westminster event to celebrate the Welsh Arts Review 10th Anniversary. It was very interesting to listen to authors read out their contributions to the recently published anthology “Home to You:10 Years of Wales Arts Review”. For the last decade Wales Arts Review has sought to publish […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2679</id>
    <published>2022-07-21T11:18:49Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-21T11:18:49Z</updated>
    <category term="My Weekly Round-up"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby calls on residents to back local parks in UK wide-vote</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/20/toby-calls-on-residents-to-back-local-parks-in-uk-wide-vote/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/20/toby-calls-on-residents-to-back-local-parks-in-uk-wide-vote/">Toby calls on residents to back local parks in UK wide-vote</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/20/toby-calls-on-residents-to-back-local-parks-in-uk-wide-vote/">Toby calls on residents to back local parks in UK wide-vote</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5063</id>
    <published>2022-07-20T14:31:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-20T14:31:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John speaks with GBNews about why he is backing Penny Mordaunt to be the next PM]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/14/john-speaks-with-gbnews-about-why-he-is-backing-penny-mordaunt-to-be-the-next-pm/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5457</id>
		<updated>2022-07-14T13:49:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-07-14T07:47:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/14/john-speaks-with-gbnews-about-why-he-is-backing-penny-mordaunt-to-be-the-next-pm/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back the Track Walk!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/back-the-track-walk/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track.</p>
<p>In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which the team have been working on and to see the aqueduct where bridge repairs are being undertaken.</p>
<p>The ‘Back the Track’ team of volunteers continue to do a fantastic job locally and it is good to see the Mclean Way being used and enjoyed by so many.</p>
<p>I really enjoyed the walk and chat. Thank you.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track. In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4232</id>
    <published>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/april-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5551" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for April 2022</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for April 2022</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5550</id>
    <published>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dzwmLsvmo-viuCWlLvsOU2i7_ZwnyQL_L_bdcy4iAf4wLgU8GnG9teTFnAZrVQ3zM8oWKqdo3Kkbgmv0_cgLQ' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
