<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2020-11-27T10:41:45Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 27 November</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Yesterday, the Government announced that South Yorkshire will be in Tier 3 restrictions from 2 December. I’ve been clear that we must not stay there a moment longer than we have to, which is why I’m pushing for a clear roadmap out of restrictions and for fairer economic support package for our residents and businesses. This week’s Spending Review was a golden opportunity to provide that immediate support; deliver on the Government’s manifesto commitment to level up the North of England; and reward those workers who have kept our country going. It was an opportunity that the Chancellor failed to take.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne marks Lancashire Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-marks-lancashire-day/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-marks-lancashire-day" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233091" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day-1024x535.png" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day-1024x535.png 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day-300x157.png 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day-768x401.png 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day-1080x564.png 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Lancashire-Day.png 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, is today marking Lancashire Day, the annual celebration of the historic County Palatine of Lancaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lancashire&amp;#8217;s county day is celebrated on 27 November as it was on this day in 1295 that the first elected representatives from Lancashire were called to Westminster by King Edward I to attend what later became known as “The Model Parliament”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administrative boundaries of Lancashire have changed multiple times over the years, but the historic boundary &amp;#8211; determined by the rivers Tame and Mersey &amp;#8211; mean that all but the Dukinfield part of the Denton and Reddish constituency falls within the ancient County Palatine of Lancaster which was established in 1182.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old boundary markers are still found on some of the bridges, like at Broomstair in Denton, or in names, like the &amp;#8216;Lancashire Bridge&amp;#8217; over the Mersey in the middle of Merseyway, Stockport, and at Lancashire Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local government reorganisations have blurred historic ties over time with Reddish moved into Stockport County Borough in 1901 and the Heatons gradually subsumed by Stockport between 1835 and 1913. Audenshaw and Denton became part of the new borough of Tameside in 1974. Both Stockport and Tameside became part of Greater Manchester at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite these changes, the Duchy and County Palatine of Lancaster remains as a legal entity and administrative unit on the historic borders, rather than those of the current Lancashire County Council area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwynne has ensured that the county flag will be raised at Denton Town Hall today to mark the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Gwynne said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Lancashire Day is an absolutely fantastic opportunity for us to celebrate our heritage, wherever we are within the historic County Palatine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;As the MP for Denton and Reddish, I also think it&amp;#8217;s a great way of celebrating a shared heritage for parts of the constituency that are currently divided between Stockport and Tameside boroughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This year is a bit different as a result of COVID restrictions, but as always I thought it was important to get the Red Rose flying from Denton Town Hall.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233090" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-1020x1024.jpeg" alt="" width="1020" height="1024" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-1020x1024.jpeg 1020w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-300x300.jpeg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-768x771.jpeg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-1530x1536.jpeg 1530w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1-1080x1084.jpeg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/EnydC-NXMAEBOHc-1.jpeg 1594w" sizes="(max-width: 1020px) 100vw, 1020px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-marks-lancashire-day/"&gt;Gwynne marks Lancashire Day&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, is today marking Lancashire Day, the annual celebration of the historic County Palatine of Lancaster. Lancashire’s county day is celebrated on 27 November as it was on this day in 1295 that the first elected representatives from Lancashire were called to Westminster by King Edward I to attend […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-marks-lancashire-day/">Gwynne marks Lancashire Day</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233088</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T09:47:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T09:47:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Revised timetable for radical plan for future growth</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13048/revised-timetable-for-radical-plan-for-future-growth" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Councillors on our Planning Committee are being asked to consider a revised timetable next week, for a radical plan to build a more sustainable future as the Capital grows in the coming years.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13048/revised-timetable-for-radical-plan-for-future-growth</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T09:18:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T09:18:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Three cheers for overseas aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2020/11/27/three-cheers-for-overseas-aid/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I am glad the UK spends money on ships and equipment that go  to assist countries facing flood and tempest. I am in admiration of  our medics and armed forces when they sometimes go to help treat and contain dangerous infectious diseases abroad. I am pleased the UK as one of the leading and richest countries of the world helps alleviate and tackle poverty in the developing nations. </p>



<p>The UK should set out what it can do and what it is good at, and should be generous where need arises and where we have the means to help. I want to see reform of our budgets and our activities in these areas so we achieve more with better value for taxpayers. </p>



<p>I went along with the Conservative leaderships’ support for hitting the 0.7% target of GDP, though I have  misgivings about such targets. I do not think we should commit to spend a  certain proportion of a fluctuating and usually growing number. We should decide on spending on a case by case basis and against our general budget background. We do not pledge to spend a fixed proportion of GDP on health or education or policing, but look at those budgets in the light of needs and costs. I trust the government will now repeal the 0.7% pledge in our law codes.</p>



<p>Labour  will doubtless oppose such a change. They  averaged under 0.4% of GDP on  overseas aid in  their period in government 1997-2010, despite pretending  to support the international commitment to spend around twice as much as they managed. They never explained why during all those years they did not do what now they say we must do. Those who want to see more overseas aid spent might do better to lobby the EU and its member countries who spend together well below the 0.5% the UK is now indicating as a new temporary level. </p>



<p>Last year the UK again spent 0.7% or £15bn on overseas aid. £10bn of this was spent on projects and activities we chose along with the recipient country in so called bilateral aid. The balance of £5bn was spent by our giving the money to the EU and other multinational bodies to spend as they saw fit in so called multilateral aid. As we leave the EU it is a good time to bring our overseas aid spending back in house and decide on how we can best help those in need.  We should also look at the full support we give, which goes wider than the items allowed under international conventions to be called Overseas Aid. Some of our Defence expenditure is aid, being used to help bring peace to strife torn countries and providing assets to tackle disasters. </p>



<p>I want us to identify the areas where we have most expertise and can do most to help. Maybe the UK should specialise in a few areas like the provision of clean water to each home, the provision of primary education to all girls as well as boys in poor countries and the roll out of programmes to tackle infectious diseases. </p>



<p>We should follow certain guidelines. The money should for preference be spent in  the country we are trying to help, using as much local labour and skills as possible. Where we need advanced country inputs these should usually come from people and companies based in  the UK. We should work on  the principle that it is better to teach a hungry person to fish and farm  for themselves rather than sending them food parcels. The aim is to get countries out of poverty, not into dependence. More trade is often of more help than more aid. </p>



<p>It will be great to see us achieve more by concentrating our efforts in areas where we have most to offer, harnessing public and private sectors together, and taking control with more  programmes we run for the benefit of the poorer countries. . </p>



<p/>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am glad the UK spends money on ships and equipment that go to assist countries facing flood and tempest. I am in admiration of our medics and armed forces when they sometimes go to help treat and contain dangerous infectious diseases abroad. I am pleased the UK as one of the leading and richest […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29112</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T05:13:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T05:13:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Harriett Baldwin seeks assurances on our humanitarian support for South Sudan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-baldwin-seeks-assurances-our-humanitarian-support-south-sudan" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Harriett Baldwin opposes the cut to our aid budget and seeks reassurance that there will be no cuts to the vital programme in South Sudan. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-baldwin-seeks-assurances-our-humanitarian-support-south-sudan" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>4996 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T22:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Lachlan Skinner</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Worcester MP urges caution as tiering system returns across the country]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/11/worcester-mp-urges-caution-as-tiering-system-returns-across-the-country/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2075</id>
		<updated>2020-11-26T21:30:44Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-26T21:30:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Coronavirus"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Treasury"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="business"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="coronavirus"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Tier 2"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worcester MP Robin Walker has urged caution as Worcester will move into ‘tier 2’ of the new restrictions come into force next week. The current national restrictions will end on December 2 and the tiering system will return across the country. It was confirmed today that Worcester will come into the ‘high alert category’ which [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/11/worcester-mp-urges-caution-as-tiering-system-returns-across-the-country/"><![CDATA[<p>Worcester MP Robin Walker has urged caution as Worcester will move into ‘tier 2’ of the new restrictions come into force next week. The current national restrictions will end on December 2 and the tiering system will return across the country.</p>
<p>It was confirmed today that Worcester will come into the ‘high alert category’ which will see shops, gyms and personal care establishments re-open.</p>
<p>Robin urged people in Worcester to safely show their support for local businesses which have had to close down in the crucial run up to Christmas. Robin has also reinforced the need to comply with the new measures when they come in place to ensure that Worcester can move into the tier one, medium alert category.</p>
<p>Decisions on which area goes into which tier are primarily based on 5 key epidemiological indicators; case detection rates in all age groups, case detection rates in the over-60s, the rate at which cases are rising or falling, positivity rate (the number of positive cases detected as a percentage of tests taken), and pressure on the NHS, including current and projected occupancy.</p>
<p>The indicators are designed to provide a full picture of what is happening with the virus in any area so that suitable action can be taken.</p>
<p>The first review of the tier allocations will take place on December 16, with the potential for areas to move down a tier before Christmas if they are making progress in slowing the spread of the virus.</p>
<p>Speaking after the announcement of the tiers, Robin said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I want to again thank the people of Worcester for all the sacrifices that they have made this year and once again I urge people to comply with tiering system when it comes into effect so that we can move into Tier 1 as soon as possible.&#8221;</p>
<p>“From December the 2nd, businesses across the UK and in Worcester will reopen and most fitness activities will be allowed again.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I am pleased that shops will be able to remain open in Worcester from the 2nd of December, especially coming into Christmas and going forward our testing capacity and start to roll out the vaccines as quickly as possible.”</p>
<p>“I know the coming weeks are going to be difficult, but we need to do whatever we can by supporting our local businesses and buying locally, whether that be in person or through click and collect.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>ENDS</p>
<p>Notes to editors</p>
<p>For further information on the new measures, please see:</p>
<p>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know</p>
<p>https://www.gov.uk/guidance/full-list-of-local-restriction-tiers-by-area</p>
<p>In tier 2:</p>
<ul>
<li>you must not socialise with anyone you do not live with or who is not in your support bubble in any indoor setting, whether at home or in a public place</li>
<li>you must not socialise in a group of more than 6 people outside, including in a garden or a public space – this is called the ‘rule of 6’</li>
<li>businesses and venues can continue to operate, in a <a class="govuk-link" href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/working-safely-during-coronavirus-covid-19">COVID-Secure</a> manner, other than those which remain closed by law, such as nightclubs</li>
<li>pubs and bars must close, unless operating as restaurants. Hospitality venues can only serve alcohol with substantial meals</li>
<li>hospitality businesses selling food or drink for consumption on their premises are required to:
<ul>
<li>provide table service only, in premises which sell alcohol</li>
<li>close between 11pm and 5am (hospitality venues in airports, ports, transport services and motorway service areas are exempt)</li>
<li>stop taking orders after 10pm</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>hospitality businesses and venues selling food and drink for consumption off the premises can continue to do so after 10pm as long as this is through delivery service, click-and-collect or drive-through</li>
<li>early closure (11pm) applies to casinos, cinemas, theatres, museums, bowling alleys, amusement arcades, funfairs, theme parks, adventure parks and activities, and bingo halls. Cinemas, theatres and concert halls can stay open beyond 11pm in order to conclude performances  that start before 10pm</li>
<li>public attendance at outdoor and indoor events (performances and shows) is permitted, limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors</li>
<li>public attendance at spectator sport and business events can resume inside and outside, subject to <a class="govuk-link" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">social contact rules</a> and limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors</li>
<li>places of worship remain open but you must not socialise with people from outside of your household or support bubble while you are indoors there, unless a legal exemption applies</li>
<li>weddings and funerals can go ahead with restrictions on numbers of attendees – 15 people can attend wedding ceremonies and receptions, 30 people can attend funeral ceremonies, and 15 people can attend linked commemorative events such as wakes  or stonesettings.</li>
<li>organised outdoor sport, and physical activity and exercise classes can continue</li>
<li>organised indoor sport, physical activity and exercise classes will only be permitted if it is possible for people to avoid mixing with people they do not live with (or share a support bubble with). There are exceptions for indoor disability sport, sport for educational purposes and supervised sport and physical activity for under-18s, which can take place with larger groups mixing</li>
<li>you can continue to travel to venues or amenities which are open, but should aim to reduce the number of journeys you make where possible</li>
<li>if you live in a tier 2 area, you must continue to follow tier 2 rules when you travel to a tier 1 area. Avoid travel to or overnight stays in tier 3 areas other than where necessary, such as for work, education, youth services, to receive medical treatment, or because of caring responsibilities.You can travel through a tier 3 area as a part of a longer journey</li>
<li>for international travel see the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office travel advice for your destination and the travel corridors list</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/11/worcester-mp-urges-caution-as-tiering-system-returns-across-the-country/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/11/worcester-mp-urges-caution-as-tiering-system-returns-across-the-country/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southampton to Enter Tier 2 Post National Lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/southampton-to-enter-tier-2-post-national-lockdown/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It was announced earlier today that Southampton will be placed in Tier 2 (High Alert) when the national lockdown restrictions come to an end next week. From 2nd December, mixing between households under the ‘rule of six’ will only be permitted in public outside. People must not socialise with anyone you do not live [...]</p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/southampton-to-enter-tier-2-post-national-lockdown/">Southampton to Enter Tier 2 Post National Lockdown</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p> </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=2986</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T20:05:50Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T20:05:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bill Wiggin comment on Foreign Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/11/26/bill-wiggin-comment-on-foreign-aid/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This year has brought about unprecedented change and hardships for many, including the public purse.  The Government is committed to buildings hospitals, schools and funding important infrastructure projects in this country.  Over 1 million Nurses, Doctor’s and those on the lowest wages... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/11/26/bill-wiggin-comment-on-foreign-aid/#more-3697">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3697</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T17:51:29Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T17:51:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Amber Valley &amp; Derbyshire Tier update from the 2nd December 2020]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3042</id>
		<updated>2020-11-26T17:01:51Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-26T16:53:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2nd December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2<sup>nd</sup> December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. Cases for the week to 20 November were 367, down from 580 the week before. This equates to 274 cases per 100,000 well above the national average. The local area of Openwoodgate and Holbrook with a rate of cases of nearly 600 per 100,000 was the 4<sup>th</sup> highest area in England. The overall average for Derbyshire was 248 cases per 100,000, and England 217. The decision by the Government was based on this data plus the relatively high level of cases in the over 60s and the occupation levels of local hospitals.</p>
<p>The move into tier 3 means that from Wednesday 2 December non-essential shops can re-open along with personal care providers like hairdressers and barbers. Indoor and outdoor leisure activities can resume but groups and classes cannot take place indoors. You can meet in groups of up to 6 in outdoor public spaces like parks, but not meet in private gardens or indoors. Sadly pubs and restaurants cannot reopen. The full details are available on the Gov.UK site as are the details of support for businesses affected by these restrictions.</p>
<p>The Tier 3 decision will be reviewed again in 2 weeks’ time. If the recent fall in the number of cases continues then there is a good chance the county can be moved into Tier 2 before Christmas allowing us all some more freedoms, and enabling hospitality venues to open.</p>
<p>I would like to thank everyone who has obeyed the rules during lockdown helping bring about the substantial reduction in cases last week. I would urge everyone  to stick to the rules  for the rest of the lockdown and then the tier 3 rules afterwards so that we can get the virus under control locally and left more restrictions in a couple of weeks’ time.</p>
<p>You can find the rules in full for tier 3 <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know#what-tiers-mean">here</a> and you can still register for my zoom residents&#8217; meeting at 7.30pm on Friday (27th November 2020) by emailing nigel.mills.mp@parliament.uk.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP helps launch campaign to give £1,000-a-year boost for 1,290 carers in South Lakeland</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1384880/mp-helps-launch-campaign-to-give-1-000-a-year-boost-for-1-290-carers-in-south-lakeland"/>
  <updated>2020-11-26T16:56:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1384880/mp-helps-launch-campaign-to-give-1-000-a-year-boost-for-1-290-carers-in-south-lakeland</id>
  <summary type="text">On Carers Rights Day, South Lakes MP Tim Farron and the Liberal Democrats have launched a campaign calling on the Government to raise Carer's Allowance by £1,000 a year, to help support 1,290 unpaid carers in South Lakeland during the coronavirus pandemic.
The Liberal Democrat proposals centre around increasing Carer's Allowance from its current rate of £67.25 a week to £87.25, in line with the £20 a week uplift in Universal Credit announced at the start of the pandemic.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Carers Rights Day, South Lakes MP Tim Farron and the Liberal Democrats have launched a campaign calling on the Government to raise Carer's Allowance by £1,000 a year, to help support 1,290 unpaid carers in South Lakeland during the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>The Liberal Democrat proposals centre around increasing Carer's Allowance from its current rate of £67.25 a week to £87.25, in line with the £20 a week uplift in Universal Credit announced at the start of the pandemic.</p>
<p>The latest government figures show that 731 unpaid carers in South Lakeland currently receive Carer's Allowance.</p>
<p>However, the Liberal Democrats are also calling for the 559 people who are entitled to Carer's Allowance but do not receive it due to overlapping benefits - mostly older carers on low incomes - to be given the extra £20 a week as well.</p>
<p>The party's leader, Ed Davey, who has promised to "be the voice of the 9 million carers in our country", has written to the Prime Minister urging him to recognise the "challenges that have been made even harder by coronavirus."</p>
<p>Tim said: <em>"Unpaid carers are doing such a remarkable and important job in almost impossible circumstances.</em></p>
<p><em>"Our wonderful carers deserve our support, but they are too often forgotten or ignored.</em></p>
<p><em>"Put simply: we need to care for our carers."</em></p>
<p>Launching the campaign, Liberal Democrat Leader Ed Davey said: <em>""Many carers are facing extreme financial hardship. They have been struggling for months, often relying on foodbanks to feed themselves and the people they care for.</em></p>
<p><em>"So Liberal Democrats are calling on the Government to support carers by raising Carer's Allowance by £1,000 a year, now."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Actions Businesses should take to be ready for the end of the Transition Period]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/11/26/actions-businesses-should-take-to-be-ready-for-the-end-of-the-transition-period/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4478</id>
		<updated>2020-11-26T16:17:42Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-26T13:52:08Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re an exporter, below is a useful checklist of things to make sure you’re as ready as possible for the end of the Brexit transition period on January 1st 2021. In addition, the Government have a programme of webinars where businesses can get direct support from experts.Sign up at: https://www.gov.uk/guidance/help-and-support-if-your-business-trades-with-the-eu]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/11/26/actions-businesses-should-take-to-be-ready-for-the-end-of-the-transition-period/"><![CDATA[
<p>If you’re an exporter, below is a useful checklist of things to make sure you’re as ready as possible for the end of the Brexit transition period on January 1<sup>st</sup> 2021.</p>



<p>In addition, the Government have a programme of webinars where businesses can get direct support from experts.<br>Sign up at: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/help-and-support-if-your-business-trades-with-the-eu" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.gov.uk/guidance/help-and-support-if-your-business-trades-with-the-eu</a></p>


<a href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Business-Help.pdf" class="pdfemb-viewer" style="" data-width="max" data-height="max"  data-toolbar="bottom" data-toolbar-fixed="off">Business-Help<br/></a>
<p class="wp-block-pdfemb-pdf-embedder-viewer"></p>



<p></p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Epidemiological predictions – Analysis of prior model failure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2020/11/epidemiological-predictions-analysis-of-prior-model-failure/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Epidemiological predictions – Analysis of prior model failure, a presentation provided to ministers on 26 November 2020 further to this report: Summary of methodological issues in epidemiology, all by Mike Hearn, plan99.net.</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18318</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T14:23:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T14:23:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Technology"/>
    <category term="Ideas"/>
    <category term="Liberty"/>
    <category term="Modelling"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CADEY committee meets for update on campaign to boost lifesaving defibrillators</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/11/cadey-committee-meets-for-update-on-campaign-to-boost-lifesaving-defibrillators/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The CADEY committee, chaired by Beverley and Holderness MP Graham Stuart, has met virtually for an update on its campaign to increase the number of lifesaving defibrillators across the constituency.</p>
<p>Formed in 2018, CADEY – standing for Community Access Defibrillators East Yorkshire – identified 63 communities without a publicly accessible defibrillator when it was formed. This has since been reduced by more than half by offering match-funding schemes with parish councils, as well as by asking businesses to use community funds to help purchase them.</p>
<p>The committee’s latest meeting on 20th November brought Graham together with representatives from the Yorkshire Ambulance Service (YAS) as well as health and welfare charities the HEY Smile Foundation, Help for Health and NURSE.</p>
<p>With the help of 50% match-funding from NURSE, six new defibrillators are due to be installed in the coming weeks and months, including in South Dalton and Mappleton, while publicly accessible defibrillators in Kilnsea and Rise have now been added to the YAS database so they are able to direct patients to them in an emergency.</p>
<p>Graham said, “So many cardiac arrests happen outside of hospitals – 30,000 a year – and only one in every ten people survive. There’s no magic bullet of course, but raising awareness of the importance of CPR and defibrillators can make a massive difference because every minute without treatment reduces someone’s chances of survival by 10%.</p>
<p>“I’m delighted as well that we’ve seen CPR training added to the national curriculum, because some other countries which teach it regularly have almost twice the survival rates.</p>
<p>“Knowing where your nearest defibrillator is and being confident to use it are two simple steps that can save lives.”</p>
<p>Leading charities have raised concerns that survival rates could be getting worse after one-third of British adults said that they didn’t know whether they should be giving CPR during the pandemic, or if it has to be performed by trained clinicians in suitable PPE. Official guidance from the Resuscitation Council recommends placing loose material over the patient’s mouth and nose before performing hands-only CPR.</p>
<p>The CADEY committee is also working up plans to send postcards across Beverley and Holderness, with information about what to do in case of emergency alongside the location of the closest available defibrillator. The committee will be encouraging people to stick these on their fridge, so the information is close to hand in an emergency.</p>
<p>The postcards will also invite people to download the free what3words app, which has given every 3-metre square in the world a unique combination of words. Their system is already used by YAS to quickly identify where to go on call-outs and giving YAS the three words corresponding to your exact location can save paramedics vital minutes to help in the fight to save lives.</p>
<p>The postcards will feature space for people to write in the what3words corresponding to their home address, so that YAS know exactly where to head to and can tell the caller where their closest defibrillator is.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The CADEY committee, chaired by Beverley and Holderness MP Graham Stuart, has met virtually for an update on its campaign to increase the number of...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10831</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T14:18:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T14:18:18Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="CADEY"/>
    <category term="Charity"/>
    <category term="Defibrillators"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Hospital"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shropshire placed in Tier 2 when lockdown ends</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/shropshire-placed-tier-2-when-lockdown-ends" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="6841" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">26 November 2020</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Shropshire placed in Tier 2 when lockdown ends</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Shropshire will be placed in the High level of restrictions once the national lockdown ends on 2nd December, the government has confirmed today.</p>

<p>The High level – Tier 2 – means people will not be able to socialise with anyone they do not live with, or is not in their support bubble, in any indoor setting. People will be able to meet outside, according to the rule of six.</p>

<p>Businesses, including retail, and venues can continue to operate, in a COVID-Secure manner, other than those which remain closed by law, such as nightclubs. Pubs and bars must close, unless operating as restaurants, but will be able to sell food and drink for consumption off the premises as long as this is through delivery service, click-and-collect or drive-through.</p>

<p>Mr Dunne said: “Tier 2 is not without considerable challenges, but it does mean businesses and hospitality offering meals will be able to operate in a modified and COVID-secure way in the run up to Christmas, which is welcome.</p>

<p>It is encouraging to see COVID19 cases coming down through the current national measures, and it will be important to sustain this downward trajectory of cases once we return to the tiered approach, to give Shropshire the best chance to moving to the Tier 1 level as soon as possible.”</p>

<p>If you live in a Tier 2 area, you must continue to follow Tier 2 rules if you travel to a Tier 1 area. People should avoid travel to, or overnight stays in, Tier 3 areas other than where necessary, such as for work, education, youth services, to receive medical treatment, or because of caring responsibilities. You can travel through a Tier 3 area as a part of a longer journey.</p>

<p>More information on Tier 2 restrictions can be found at: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know">https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know</a></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6841 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T13:54:01Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T13:54:01Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP “Following the rules together we can get out of these tough measures.”</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-following-rules-together-we-can-get-out-these-tough-measures" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP “Following the rules together we can get out of these tough measures.”
The Government has announced that Hampshire has been placed in Tier 2 High Alert - local covid restriction level in order to safeguard the gains made during the period of national restrictions.
The first review point…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-following-rules-together-we-can-get-out-these-tough-measures</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Northumberland to be placed in Tier 3 from 2 December</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/northumberland-be-placed-tier-3-2-december" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today's announcement from the Health Secretary confirmed that Northumberland would be placed into Tier 3 as we exit the naitonal lockdown on Wednesday 2nd December.
There is more information on the Covid Winter Plan, the Christmas bubbles, expansion of support bubbles and the route out of measures…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/northumberland-be-placed-tier-3-2-december</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett backs Chancellor’s package to deal with economic emergency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-chancellors-package-deal-economic-emergency" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Vice Chairman of the Conservative Party, has strongly endorsed the Chancellor of the Exchequer’s Spending Review 2020, which aims to deliver on the peoples' priorities. “The emphasis on jobs, infrastructure and economic growth, as well…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-chancellors-package-deal-economic-emergency</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP backs staff call to prevent Remote Air Traffic Control</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/11/26/isles-mp-backs-staff-call-to-prevent-remote-air-traffic-control/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Isles MP Angus MacNeil is backing calls by Prospect Union to protect island jobs by opposing the centralisation of Air Traffic Control functions to Inverness.</p>



<p>Prospect members in Air Traffic Control at Highlands and Islands Airports Limited (HIAL) are to be balloted on industrial action over HIAL’s plans to push on with its remote towers project.</p>



<p>Commenting Mr MacNeil said: “This is an inevitable consequence of HIAL’s high handed approach to people’s jobs and livelihoods and damaging the island economy by taking critical, well paid jobs out of the area.  It is time now for the Scottish Government to step in.</p>



<p>“HIAL’s answers have not been good enough. Air Traffic Control staff and the public deserve better. The Transport Minister needs to get involved and our Air Traffic Control services need to be kept in Benbecula and Stornoway.”</p>



<p>Prospect have stressed that any industrial action will have no effect on emergency services and if action is taken it will be after the Christmas holiday period.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="1659" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2017/05/18/macneil-scottish-parliament-backs-full-devolution-of-fisheries-after-brexit-tories-must-respect-will-of-parliament/angus-pic/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg" data-orig-size="2976,5312" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.9&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;SM-G920F&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1495108923&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.3&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;40&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.00073529411764706&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Angus pic" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=168" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=574" alt="" class="wp-image-1659" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=574 574w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=1148 1148w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=84 84w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=168 168w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2017/05/angus-pic.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 574px) 100vw, 574px"/></a></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Isles MP Angus MacNeil is backing calls by Prospect Union to protect island jobs by opposing the centralisation of Air …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/11/26/isles-mp-backs-staff-call-to-prevent-remote-air-traffic-control/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3239</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T11:47:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T11:47:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Great news on NHS funding. Lots more needs to be done and I will make sure local people are at the heart of it</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1714-great-news-on-nhs-funding-lots-more-needs-to-be-done-and-i-will-make-sure-local-people-are-at-the-heart-of-it"/>
		<published>2020-11-26T11:21:49+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-26T11:21:49+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1714-great-news-on-nhs-funding-lots-more-needs-to-be-done-and-i-will-make-sure-local-people-are-at-the-heart-of-it</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Great news on NHS funding. Fantastic we have 14,800 more nurses than a year ago &amp;amp; on way to 50,000 more over next 3 years. Lots more needs to be done and I will make sure local people are at the heart of it. Just like we will be for the vaccine roll out, exciting news next week👍&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1331920168281321473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 26, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Great news on NHS funding. Fantastic we have 14,800 more nurses than a year ago &amp;amp; on way to 50,000 more over next 3 years. Lots more needs to be done and I will make sure local people are at the heart of it. Just like we will be for the vaccine roll out, exciting news next week👍&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1331920168281321473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 26, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jonathan Djanogly welcomes Japan trade deal but calls for more Parliamentary scrutiny</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-welcomes-japan-trade-deal-calls-more-parliamentary-scrutiny" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Djanogly welcomes the trade agreement with Japan but calls for more UK Parliamentary scrutiny noting that the deal had to be ​approved by a vote in the Japanese Parliament, but not in the UK. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-welcomes-japan-trade-deal-calls-more-parliamentary-scrutiny" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5012 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T22:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CHRISTMAS GUIDANCE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Scottish Government has agreed a cautious and limited relaxation of the rules on household meetings to support people over the Christmas period. First Minister Nicola Sturgeon stressed it is clear that there is a risk inherent in any relaxation … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/">CHRISTMAS GUIDANCE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Docherty-Hughes</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1470708</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T15:42:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T15:42:40Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter on Israeli-Palestinian Peace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/letter-on-israeli-palestinian-peace/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following Catherine’s debate in Parliament last week making the case for an international fund for Israeli-Palestinian Peace, she has written to Minister James Cleverly. The UK has a chance to seize this crucial opportunity to support multilateral efforts to advance peace in the Middle East. Text of letter: Rt Hon James Cleverly MP Minister of … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/letter-on-israeli-palestinian-peace/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Letter on Israeli-Palestinian Peace</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=6999</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T15:15:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T15:15:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="peace fund"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Borderlands accelerated as Chancellor announces spending</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borderlands-accelerated-chancellor-announces-spending" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Chancellor of the Exchequer has announced a raft of new measures to protect jobs amid the serious economic hit from coronavirus, including an acceleration of the Borderlands Growth Deal.
The Spending Review focussed on getting the UK through the economic hit of the coronavirus whilst investing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borderlands-accelerated-chancellor-announces-spending</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>White Ribbon Day 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/11/white-ribbon-day-2020/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="7903" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/11/white-ribbon-day-2020/white-ribbon-graphic/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=799%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="799,600" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="White Ribbon Graphic" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=790%2C593&amp;ssl=1"/>
<p> Today I am supporting <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hashtag/whiteribbonday?__eep__=6&amp;__cft__[0]=AZX7Zr2W8krP09Nw-tC7pBm56xcqiMu5-shF4JL0Fsg7C9aJ0-rwzLZ9BpFph8TQBZmzmgG0JeFQn1opFreGeUZJllWiugph6QUTnIkg0T7YfsoJmFS7Fsfzsq2Yvefi6YuWEpBE2_K4sD1kRxk3kjqBRizN9toiyc69zMpLaj_5Gi6VmR-Ab9XyTK0GMQe8xxvzr9RAYVAXhaF_cGrkm3YX&amp;__tn__=*NK-R">#WhiteRibbonDay</a>, which marks the start of 16 days of action to raise awareness of violence against women.</p>



<p>2020 has seen a shocking increase in domestic abuse and other forms of violence against women around the world and we must never remain silent.</p>



<p>Everyone can work together to prevent violence and make sure our homes and communities are safe for all.</p>



<p/>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="7903" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/11/white-ribbon-day-2020/white-ribbon-graphic/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=799%2C600&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="799,600" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="White Ribbon Graphic" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/White-Ribbon-Graphic.jpg?fit=790%2C593&amp;ssl=1"/>Today I am supporting #WhiteRibbonDay, which marks the start of 16 days of action to raise awareness of violence against women. 2020 has seen a shocking increase in domestic abuse and other forms of violence against women around the world and we must never remain silent. Everyone can work together to prevent violence and make […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7902</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T11:30:35Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T11:30:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated
announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce
the spread of Covid-19 in England.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed
once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to
ensure we keep people safe and well. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is vital that careful consideration is given
to ensuring the right areas are placed in the right tiers. While we welcome the
way the three tiers recognise that different areas require different approaches
to managing the virus, we believe that Nottingham City Council is uniquely
placed to understand the best interests of its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last month, Nottingham was placed in tier 2 before being
stepped up to tier 3, alongside our partners in the neighbouring
Nottinghamshire County Council. At that time, we had one of the highest rates
of Covid-19 in the country. Since then, we have seen a significant and
sustained reduction in the rate of Covid-19 in Nottingham City, with 40
consecutive days of falling Covid cases and counting. We now sit below the
national average for rates per 100,000 population and are ranked 121&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;
Lower Tier Local Authority nationally. I’m sure you would agree this is a
dramatic and impressive turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our rate is now 50 per cent lower than when we were last
placed into tier 3. We believe our sustained lower rate of Covid-19 should be
reflected in the way Nottingham is allocated a tier this time around.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our fall in cases of Covid-19 is a reflection of the hard
work which has taken place, along with neighbouring councils, the police,
businesses and our city’s two universities – as well as with the local NHS. All
organisations have united in a shared response to reducing the spread of the
virus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also, of course, attributable to the efforts of our
local communities, and their support in adhering to the guidelines and
restrictions in place. We feel that people in Nottingham have worked hard to
bring down the rate of Covid-19 in our communities and among our older
population – and that our position in the tier system should reflect this
decrease.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We know that ongoing restrictions will continue to have a
significant impact on our businesses, our hospitality sector and our
communities. It is vital the right decisions are made for our city.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We would like the opportunity to build on Nottingham’s
successful partnership work in a way that allows us more freedom to reopen key
parts of our economy: to keep restaurants and indoor entertainment venues open
and to ensure our city can begin to reopen in a way that is safe, supported and
protected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would welcome the opportunity to discuss this further.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;br&gt;Cllr David Mellen&lt;br&gt;Leader, Nottingham City Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/"&gt;Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Prime Minister, I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce the spread of Covid-19 in England. It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2569</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Return of grassroots sports</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/return-of-grassroots-sports/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday this week I was in the chamber of the House of Commons to hear the Prime Minister announce that the national COVID lockdown will end on 2 December to be replaced with a tiered system. This is obviously very good news, and this easing of the restrictions is a result of the success […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5408</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T08:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T08:30:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID Survey...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/covid-survey-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <form class="webform-client-form webform-client-form-1427" action="/rss.xml" method="post" id="webform-client-form-1427" accept-charset="UTF-8">
          <div><fieldset class="webform-component-fieldset webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset form-wrapper"><legend><span class="fieldset-legend">Your contact details</span></legend><div class="fieldset-wrapper"><div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-civicrm_contact static webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-existing">
<input data-hide-method="hide" data-no-hide-blank="0" class="civicrm-enabled" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_existing" type="hidden" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_existing]" value=""/>

</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-first-name">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-first-name">First Name <span class="form-required" title="This field is required.">*</span></label>
 <input required="required" placeholder="First Name" class="civicrm-enabled form-text required" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_first_name" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-first-name" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_first_name]" value="" size="20" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-last-name">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-last-name">Last Name <span class="form-required" title="This field is required.">*</span></label>
 <input required="required" placeholder="Last Name" class="civicrm-enabled form-text required" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_last_name" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-contact-last-name" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_contact_last_name]" value="" size="20" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-address-street-address">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-street-address">Street Address </label>
 <input placeholder="Street address" class="civicrm-enabled form-text" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_address_street_address" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-street-address" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_address_street_address]" value="" size="60" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-address-city">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-city">City </label>
 <input placeholder="City" class="civicrm-enabled form-text" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_address_city" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-city" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_address_city]" value="" size="20" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-address-postal-code">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-postal-code">Postal Code <span class="form-required" title="This field is required.">*</span></label>
 <input required="required" placeholder="Postal Code" class="civicrm-enabled form-text required" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_address_postal_code" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-address-postal-code" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_address_postal_code]" value="" size="7" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-email webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-email-email">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-email-email">Email </label>
 <input class="email civicrm-enabled form-text form-email" placeholder="Email" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_email_email" type="email" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-email-email" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_email_email]" size="20"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-1-phone-phone">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-phone-phone">Phone Number </label>
 <input placeholder="Phone number" class="civicrm-enabled form-text" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_1_phone_phone" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-1-phone-phone" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_1_phone_phone]" value="" size="20" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textfield webform-component--civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-contact-2-phone-phone">
  <label class="element-invisible" for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-2-phone-phone">Mobile </label>
 <input placeholder="Mobile" class="civicrm-enabled form-text" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_contact_2_phone_phone" type="text" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-contact-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-contact-2-phone-phone" name="submitted[civicrm_1_contact_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_contact_2_phone_phone]" value="" size="20" maxlength="128"/>
</div>
</div></fieldset>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-markup webform-component--spacer3">
 
</div>
<fieldset class="webform-component-fieldset webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset form-wrapper"><div class="fieldset-wrapper"><div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-select webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-348">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-348">Do you support the announcement made on Monday by the Prime Minister that gyms and non-essential shops will re-open from 2nd December? </label>
 <select class="civicrm-enabled form-select" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_348" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-348" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_348]"><option value="" selected="selected">- None -</option><option value="1">Yes</option><option value="2">No</option><option value="3">Not sure</option></select>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-select webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-349">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-349">Do you think that a tiered approach after December 2 (similar to what was in place before lockdown 2) is a good idea? </label>
 <select class="civicrm-enabled form-select" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_349" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-349" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_349]"><option value="" selected="selected">- None -</option><option value="1">Yes</option><option value="2">No</option><option value="3">Not sure</option></select>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-select webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-350">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-350">There is currently a debate about what to do at Christmas. Which of the following comes closest to your view? </label>
 <select class="civicrm-enabled form-select" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_350" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-350" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_350]"><option value="" selected="selected">- None -</option><option value="1">The virus doesn't care about Christmas. We must not relax restrictions at all</option><option value="2">Some restrictions should be lifted as the Government has suggested</option><option value="3">All restrictions should be lifted for Christmas</option><option value="4">None of the above</option></select>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-select webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-351">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-351">How concerned are you about getting coronavirus on a scale of 1 to 5 where 1 is not concerned at all and 5 is very concerned? </label>
 <select class="civicrm-enabled form-select" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_351" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-351" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_351]"><option value="" selected="selected">- None -</option><option value="1">1</option><option value="2">2</option><option value="3">3</option><option value="4">4</option><option value="5">5</option></select>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-select webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-352">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-352">When the vaccinations have been approved, do you plan to be vaccinated? </label>
 <select class="civicrm-enabled form-select" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_352" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-352" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_352]"><option value="" selected="selected">- None -</option><option value="1">Yes</option><option value="2">No</option><option value="3">Not sure</option></select>
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-textarea webform-component--civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset--civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-353">
  <label for="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-353">Please use this space to give me any other views about the current coronavirus pandemic </label>
 <div class="form-textarea-wrapper resizable"><textarea class="civicrm-enabled form-textarea" data-civicrm-field-key="civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_353" id="edit-submitted-civicrm-1-activity-1-fieldset-fieldset-civicrm-1-activity-1-cg52-custom-353" name="submitted[civicrm_1_activity_1_fieldset_fieldset][civicrm_1_activity_1_cg52_custom_353]" cols="60" rows="4"/></div>
</div>
</div></fieldset>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-markup webform-component--spacer">
 
</div>
<div class="form-item webform-component webform-component-markup webform-component--opt-out-at-any-time">
 <p>I will take care of your data. You can find my privacy policy <a href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/legal-and-privacy">here</a>.</p>
</div>
<input type="hidden" name="details[sid]"/>
<input type="hidden" name="details[page_num]" value="1"/>
<input type="hidden" name="details[page_count]" value="1"/>
<input type="hidden" name="details[finished]" value="0"/>
<input type="hidden" name="form_build_id" value="form-P35zT5XxlNF-tmgz4Wq1e49lzHExS5tZgjE2D_5XEA0"/>
<input type="hidden" name="form_id" value="webform_client_form_1427"/>
<div class="form-actions"><input class="webform-submit button-primary btn-primary btn form-submit" type="submit" name="op" value="Submit"/></div></div>
        </form>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>admin781027</name>
    </author>
    <id>1427 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T06:43:32Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T06:43:32Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Policy Issues raised by constituents SEPTEMBER 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/11/policy-issues-raised-by-constituents-september-2020/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img data-attachment-id="10659" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/11/policy-issues-raised-by-constituents-august-2020-2__trashed/policy-issues-september-2020/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?fit=743%2C1065&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="743,1065" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Policy issues SEPTEMBER 2020" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?fit=209%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?fit=700%2C1004&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10659" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?resize=700%2C1003&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="1003" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?w=743&amp;ssl=1 743w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?resize=209%2C300&amp;ssl=1 209w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Policy-issues-SEPTEMBER-2020.png?resize=714%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 714w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10663</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T15:41:14Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T15:41:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thoughts on Covid-19 Winter Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/thoughts-covid-19-winter-plan" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday’s statement by the Prime Minister at last ends lockdown, I sincerely hope forever! We return on Wednesday 2nd December to a 3-tier system. But that system will impose even more stringent measures. My fear is that most of the country will be in tier two or three with very few in tier one.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/thoughts-covid-19-winter-plan</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Big Spending Boost for Defence!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/big-spending-boost-for-defence/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last week’s announcement of an additional £16.5 billion boost for defence represents the biggest spending boost for our Armed Forces for more than 30-years.</p>
<p>This will result in 10,000 new jobs a year, it will help revitalise UK shipbuilding, help the UK to become a world leader in cyber and space as well as allowing us to invest more resources in research and development.</p>
<p>Our Armed Forces do a tremendous job from keeping us safe to assisting with humanitarian operations. Their sense of duty and their professionalism is an example to us all and this additional support for defence spending is very welcomed news.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week’s announcement of an additional £16.5 billion boost for defence represents the biggest spending boost for our Armed Forces for more than 30-years. This will result in 10,000 new jobs a year, it will help revitalise UK shipbuilding, help the UK to become a world leader in cyber and space as well as allowing […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3474</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T11:28:28Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T11:28:28Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Funding Sources</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/23/covid-19-funding-sources/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><h3 style="text-align: center">COVID-19 funding sources</h3>
<p>Below is an updated list of COVID-19 funding for Voluntary Organisations, Charities and Businesses as of 20th November 2020.</p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/New-COVID-19-Funds-communities-as-at-20.11.2020.docx">New COVID-19 Funds communities as at 20.11.2020</a></p>


<p/>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F23%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;title=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/23/covid-19-funding-sources/" data-a2a-title="COVID-19 Funding Sources"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/23/covid-19-funding-sources/">COVID-19 Funding Sources</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 funding sources Below is an updated list of COVID-19 funding for Voluntary Organisations, Charities ... <a title="COVID-19 Funding Sources" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/23/covid-19-funding-sources/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/23/covid-19-funding-sources/">COVID-19 Funding Sources</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=1644</id>
    <published>2020-11-23T10:51:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-23T10:51:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="charities"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="voluntary groups"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Residents urged to submit their views on landfill extension planning application</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/o7IyKBXP77E/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4758</id>
    <published>2020-11-22T17:55:50Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-22T17:55:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-34/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I want to send my huge congratulations to staff and students at Ysgol Hendrefelin this week for their accreditation with the prestigious British Council’s International School Award. This award recognises the incredible and innovative work of schools across the UK to connect their pupils to the world through modern languages, classroom exchanges, and connections with young people around the globe. Learning languages is so important – it gives us access to new cultures and ideas and allows us to broaden our understanding of the world.  Well done Ysgol Hendrefelin.</p>
<p>I was pleased to chair a debate in Westminster Hall this week on fuel poverty. This always becomes an issue in the lead up to winter, but this year, there will be an added strain on so many tightened household budgets. One of the major obstacles in tackling fuel poverty is the inefficient nature of our older housing. Poorly insulated properties leak heat and so more energy is needed to keep the house warm. As well as supporting those in fuel poverty in the short-term, we really need a national strategy to not only ensure developers are building energy efficient homes, but also that we are supporting homeowners to make their houses more energy efficient. This will not only contribute to lower household bills, but it will also help us reduce our carbon footprint.  This is an important issue that intersects the economy, social inequality, and the environment, and one which it is vital that we tackle.</p>
<p>This week is Usdaw’s annual Respect for Shopworkers Week which they run as part of their Freedom From Fear campaign which seeks to tackle the rising problem of violence and abuse towards our fabulous frontline retail workers. Our shopworkers have done so much to keep us well stocked and our morale high during this crisis and I am shocked to see the appalling treatment that many of them have experienced. I am pleased to support this campaign and would encourage all constituents to sign <a href="https://petition.parliament.uk/petitions/328621">Usdaw’s petition</a> to call on the UK Government to enact legislation to create a specific offence of abusing, threatening, or assaulting a retail worker with a penalty that shows that we are serious about stopping these disgusting attacks.</p>
<p>It’s Anti-Bullying Week this week and it’s important to support the campaign. Bullying can have a long-lasting effect on those who experience and witness it, but by working together, by sharing our experiences, and by educating young people, we can reduce bullying. We all have a part to play – parents, teachers, politicians, celebrities, and young people themselves – we can all speak out against bullying and speak up for those experiencing it.</p>
<p>We marked International Men’s Day this week and it’s a chance to make sure men know that reaching out for help with a physical or mental health problem is not a sign of weakness, but rather a sign of strength. In 2017, sadly 12,031 men died from prostate cancer, a rise from 11,307 in 2014. It is so important that men go to their GP when something doesn’t seem right – if problems are caught earlier, they are much easier to deal with. In 2018, it is astonishing that 4,903 men took their own lives – that’s 13 men dying every day, making up 3 in 4 of all suicides in the UK. We need to talk more about men’s mental health and make it clear that there is help available for men. Domestic abuse is another area where men have suffered, and evidence shows 1 in 3 people who experience domestic abuse are men.</p>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch about matters that fall under my work as an MP, please do not hesitate to drop us an email on christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call us on 01639 630152. My staff are working from home to comply with the social distancing measures, but, as always, we remain there should you need to get in contact with us.</p>
<p>I hope you stay well, and remember – observe social distancing, wash your hands regularly and keep Wales safe.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I want to send my huge congratulations to staff and students at Ysgol Hendrefelin this week for their accreditation with the prestigious British Council’s International School Award. This award recognises the incredible and innovative work of schools across the UK to connect their pupils to the world through modern languages, classroom exchanges, and connections with […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2309</id>
    <published>2020-11-20T16:09:19Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-20T16:09:19Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We’re halfway there, so well done</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>As we approach the halfway point of the Government’s nationwide lockdown, I want to thank constituents and businesses for abiding by the new restrictions.</p>
<p>The Government has lost control of the virus, and my first duty is to keep my constituents safe. That is why I voted for the lockdown. Nobody voted for the regulations with anything but a heavy heart. I did not come into Parliament to restrict people’s freedoms.</p>
<p>This period must be used to undertake the transfer of test and trace to local public health departments, including a full resource transfer. In addition, the Government must ensure that the NHS and social care are fully prepared with adequate PPE, as high as possible uptake of flu vaccinations and regular testing regimes.</p>
<p>I have proposed measures to protect the clinically vulnerable and providing ‘supportive shielding’ so that people don’t experience the devastating isolation that happened last time. We must also make sure we have simple, coherent messaging with local community engagement as well as monitoring and enforcement capacity to support people complying during the lockdown.</p>
<p>Local restrictions have had a devastating effect on people living in care homes and their families.  As co-Chair of the APPG on Dementia I have received heart-breaking stories from Oldhamers, unable to visit their loved ones for months on end, and who have seen a marked deterioration in their condition, particularly for those living with dementia.</p>
<p>I secured a Westminster Hall debate on the impact of coronavirus on people living with dementia, their families and carers last week, where I challenged the Minister on these issues. I pressed the Minister to report back to Parliament on her trial of visitor testing which starts on 16<sup>th</sup> November in 30 care homes, with the intention of rolling out testing for visitors across the country in December.  It is essential that family members are able to safely visit their loved ones in care homes, especially as we approach Christmas.</p>
<p>I have also been challenging the Government on how they’ve been awarding Covid-related contracts. Billions of pounds of public money has been awarded to private companies often with no experience in delivering medical supplies. The Government’s repeated refusal to come clean about where this public money has left no option but to compel the Government to come clean through the courts. This is why I partnered with Caroline Lucas MP, Layla Moran MP and the Good Law Project in legal action to force the Government to publish details of private covid and PPE related contracts.</p>
<p>Whilst we recognise that at the beginning of the pandemic we needed to move quickly, this does not justify the Government’s wholesale disregard for transparency including the publication of contracts awarded. The Government has now disclosed that at least £17 billion worth of Covid-19 contracts have been awarded by the Department of Health and Social Care since April, with over £4 billion of these contracts being hidden. The transparency gap is therefore growing.</p>
<p>I am pleased that last week the High Court granted our judicial review to challenge the Government’s persistent failure to publish these contracts. The hearing is scheduled for mid-January 2021 and I’ll keep you informed of our progress.</p>
<p>Do look after yourselves and stay safe.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/">We’re halfway there, so well done</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/">We’re halfway there, so well done</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6722</id>
    <published>2020-11-20T12:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-20T12:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Activities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/update-activities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I take no pleasure in the downfall of anyone but I am pleased that Mr Cummings has left Downing Street. His behaviour over a trip north to Durham and visit to Barnard Castle apparently caused a major rift in relations between himself and the Prime Minister. At the time I thought it unacceptable and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/update-activities</id>
    <published>2020-11-20T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Joins Advisory Board of the John Mills Institute for Prosperity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-joins-advisory-board-of-the-john-mills-institute-for-prosperity/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2930" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1.jpg 1024w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1-980x490.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1-480x240.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color"&gt;Earlier this month I was delighted to be personally invited by renowned businessman, entrepreneur and philanthropist, John Mills to join the advisory board of his new Institute for Prosperity recently. The nine person advisory board is made up of a group of cross-party MPs, former MPs and Peers. All of whom have Ministerial or Shadow Ministerial experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Institute was set up earlier this year by Mr Mills who is also the founder and Chairman of South Shields based consumer goods company JML, which sells high-volume consumer products in the UK and 85 countries worldwide.&amp;nbsp;The Institute’s aim is to increase prosperity, growth and equality by putting a more successful economic future at the heart of British political discourse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;South Shields, like many towns across the country have been decimated by lack of investment and deindustrialisation and many have been forgotten by successive governments. Growing up I watched this powerful and prosperous industrious town slowly wither and as a result 100’s of skilled jobs, like that of my fathers disappeared too along with much needed investment. So, I am delighted to work alongside John and parliamentary colleagues to do all we can to find a consensus, to provide a platform to bring people with fresh ideas together and to find new solutions to Britain’s economic problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Earlier this month I was delighted to be personally invited by renowned businessman, entrepreneur and philanthropist, John Mills to join the advisory board of his new Institute for Prosperity recently. The nine person advisory board is made up of a group of cross-party MPs, former MPs and Peers. All of whom have Ministerial or Shadow […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2020-11-19T14:30:14Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-19T14:30:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ashfield MP says track and trace was 'first class' for him - and the Prime Minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week, I was delighted to have had breakfast with the Prime Minister in Downing Street where we spoke about my hopes for Ashfield and Eastwood.
It was a productive meeting and I am confident that this Government will deliver the investment our area has been crying out for now for decades.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister</id>
    <published>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two simple priorities; protect people, protect jobs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/two-simple-priorities-protect-people-protect-jobs/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-simple-priorities-protect-people-protect-jobs" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;For Government, there should be two simple priorities during this pandemic; the first is to protect people in our communities by preventing the virus from spreading, the second is to protect jobs and livelihoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Healthy communities need as close to full employment as possible, not just because families need to put food on the table, but also because a failure to protect jobs has far-reaching adverse effects. Countless academic studies have shown a strong link between personal, family and community health and people having a sense of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;It matters to the fabric of our society. That’s why I’ve spent so much of my time as your MP arguing for ways to protect jobs and ensuring people have financial help to navigate this emergency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Seven months into this pandemic and over 3 million people are still getting no support from the UK Government. The Scottish Government is doing what it can to plug the gaps in support but, it’s gone beyond the funding it’s had from Westminster, and without borrowing powers cannot go much further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Ordinary folk in our community abandoned because they don’t fit into one of the Chancellors narrow groups. They are newly self-employed, freelancers or owners of micro-business and those often forced by circumstance to work in the gig economy. They are the photographers, musicians, drivers, small business owners and young entrepreneurs just starting out. They pay their taxes, they’ve done everything right and need a safety net in their hour of need like everyone else. It shouldn’t matter if it’s a little trickier to work out how to estimate their support, as HMRC claim &amp;#8211;&amp;nbsp; this is about doing what is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;These 3 million people have no or little work and have had no support from the Chancellor. Many cannot even claim Universal Credit because of its failings and inflexibility as a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;They are getting more desperate by the day and need their safety net. I have raised their plight many times with the Chancellor and will continue to do so. Colleagues, including some Tory backbenchers, have joined me, in these calls. We’ve offered countless solutions, but the Chancellor seems determined not to act – just as they have refused to give the Scottish Government borrowing powers so it can step in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Last week, I asked the Minister if it is simply the case that they don’t care – once again, he chose to duck the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up to date with new articles at &lt;a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;www.drewhendrymp.scot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about my work in parliament at &lt;a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com"&gt;www.theyworkforyou.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/two-simple-priorities-protect-people-protect-jobs/"&gt;Two simple priorities; protect people, protect jobs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;Drew Hendry MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>For Government, there should be two simple priorities during this pandemic; the first is to...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/two-simple-priorities-protect-people-protect-jobs/">Two simple priorities; protect people, protect jobs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5588</id>
    <published>2020-11-17T08:00:36Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-17T08:00:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Business"/>
    <category term="COVID 19"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Libraries</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Really pleased to see this news, especially for Bradford on Avon and Melksham. Libraries are more important than ever as many of us will be spending more time at home this month. Thank you to all the staff involved who are making this possible!</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/">https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/">Libraries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Really pleased to see this news, especially for Bradford on Avon and Melksham. Libraries are more important than ever as many of us will be spending more time at home this month. Thank you to all the staff involved who are making this possible! https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/">Libraries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33829</id>
    <published>2020-11-15T15:55:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-15T15:55:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Wiltshire Council"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lockdown Discretionary Grant/Grant Dewisol y Cyfnod Clo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/lockdown-discretionary-grantgrant-dewisol-y-cyfnod-clo" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following review of initial round of applications we have been able to release sufficient funds to re-open the Lockdown Discretionary Grant.
This grant is for those people who are NOT eligible to apply to the Lockdown Non Domestic Rate Grant. 
Please note businesses are not eligible to apply for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/lockdown-discretionary-grantgrant-dewisol-y-cyfnod-clo</id>
    <published>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - Businesses, small and large </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-businesses-small-and-large" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we all get used to the second lockdown there are difficulties for huge numbers of people, ranging from churchgoers to gym enthusiasts. But my biggest worry is the effect on businesses, as keeping people at work is so important for reasons that go well beyond the economic.
It was timely, then,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-businesses-small-and-large</id>
    <published>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith tells Government ‘the people of the north will hold you to account’ on rebalancing the economy.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning I took part in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanJarvisMP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DanJarvisMP&lt;/a&gt; debate on support for the economy in the North. We need a fundamental rebalancing of our economy after Covid. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this Government to account for their promises and their actions. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iCcp6jNBhp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iCcp6jNBhp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the
economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was
fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s handling of the Covid crisis, and in
particular their approach to local restrictions and regional packages of
financial support, has shown that too often the needs of the North are still an
after-thought or, worse, ignored altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Instead of
establishing a clear and transparent framework of support, proportionate to
need, the Government has employed a strategy of divide and rule.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are now in a national lockdown of course, and the
furlough scheme has been extended until March, but the Government must set out
exactly what will happen at the end of this period. They have indicated we will
go back into the tiered system, but many businesses in Bradford will simply not
survive if we go straight back into tier 2 or 3 with the current level of
support.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the short term, the Government must ensure that whatever
the restrictions are after December 2nd, there is a fair set of financial
support that takes into account how long an area has been under local
restrictions. For each measure, the Government should produce an impact
assessment by region, which includes the impact on regional inequality and the
regional economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the longer term, we need a fundamental rebalancing of our
economy. Levelling up rhetoric and the odd project here and there will not be
enough. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this
Government to account for their promises and their actions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith also called for reform of the Treasury’s ‘Green Book’
which is used to make decisions on Government investment, as it currently
“skews investment and therefore growth into where it already happens, rather
than where it needs to happen”. In response, the Government announced they
would be publishing the revised Green Book at this year’s spending review on
the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, support, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;90&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" alt="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has welcomed the latest proposals for tougher sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving and urges the government to act on them without delay Responding in Parliament, Leader of the House Jacob-Rees Mogg said: " “I thank the hon. Lady for the campaigning she's done on this very&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, judith, will, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/imgID149097243-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" alt="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A version of this article was first published in The Times Ever since I heard Matt Hancock, in a recent interview, extol the virtues of getting seven hours sleep a night through this pandemic, I’ve been thinking about what keeps me awake at night. At the top of my list&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: local, government, support, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;67&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: restrictions, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2359</id>
    <published>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[REMEMBRANCE DAY 2020]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=338</id>
		<updated>2020-11-11T10:44:30Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-11T10:43:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>‘Remembrance As Vital As Ever’ Says Grant Shapps MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/remembrance-as-vital-as-ever-says-grant-shapps-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=remembrance-as-vital-as-ever-says-grant-shapps-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Ex-RAF Serviceman Steve McNamara Remark on Remembrance Sunday 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional remembrance memorial services have halted by the coronavirus pandemic, preventing gatherings around memorials and cenotaphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps believes that this should not lessen our commitment to remembering those who have died in war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting the Hatfield Memorial Garden, Mr Shapps said: “Today cuts very deep inside really because it makes you recall…the ultimate sacrifice that so many have given to make sure that we have the freedoms that we have today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s so easy to forget what they went through- the horror of it all- so that we could live in peace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve McNamara, an RAF veteran from Welwyn Garden City with grandfathers who fought in both First and Second World Wars, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think every generation has historic, cataclysmic events that define them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For this generation, it is probably COVID. It has produced heroes and victims, and I think these will be remembered in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps also spoke of the vital role of the Armed Forces in the battle against the virus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a Remembrance Sunday like no other, as we battle this coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But the thing to remember is that a lot of the people that we’re here commemorating and thanking, are actually out there serving right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thousands internationally, but also at home in the battle against the virus- for example in Liverpool, helping with mass-testing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps laid a wreath at the Hatfield memorial. He said: “I think in the Armed Forces we have as much to thank today as we ever have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s why Remembrance Sunday- even remembering it slightly differently than usual is so important.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video of the visit was produced, which you can view below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=555&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F1044960589283599%2F&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=560" width="1280" height="1280" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Welwyn Hatfield MP and Ex-RAF Serviceman Steve McNamara Remark on Remembrance Sunday 2020.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30047</id>
    <published>2020-11-08T08:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-08T08:30:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Hatfield Memorial Garden"/>
    <category term="Remembrance Sunday"/>
    <category term="Steve McNamara"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>APPG on Democracy in Burma Statement on Upcoming Elections in Burma</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/appg_on_democracy_in_burma_statement_on_upcoming_burma_elections" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Ahead of Burma's Election later this month, the All-Party Parliamentary Group for Democracy in Burma released the following statement, raising their concerns about the credibility of the elections. </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/appg_on_democracy_in_burma_statement_on_upcoming_burma_elections</id>
    <published>2020-11-04T17:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-04T17:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Financial support for those in the North</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2020/11/04/financial-support-for-those-in-the-north/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It could not be more clear that the North is being treated completely differently to the South. I took the opportunity yesterday to question the Chief Secretary to the Treasury, Steve Barclay, about what financial support package would be available to businesses and workers going forward:</p>
<blockquote><p>Prior to this lockdown announcement, we had had almost universal calls for an extension to the full furlough scheme in areas with tighter restrictions, which Ministers had rejected for months. Despite that, the Government saw fit to announce a new version of this on Saturday, only hours before the previous furlough was due to be replaced by an inferior scheme for us in the north, as further restrictions were becoming inevitable in many areas. Many people in the north therefore now believe that until workers in the south were to be affected by the national lockdown, they were somehow thought to be worth less. Businesses in Gateshead and elsewhere are desperate for clarity and certainty to help them in planning and so that they know whether and how they can survive. Will the Chief Secretary commit today to publishing details of a comprehensive, ongoing financial support package available to businesses and their workers in areas that will continue to need it, where tiers of restrictions might, sadly, have to continue after 2 December?</p></blockquote>
<p>The full debate can be found at: <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-03a.162.0&amp;s=ian+mearns#g174.0">https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-03a.162.0&amp;s=ian+mearns#g174.0</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It could not be more clear that the North is being treated completely differently to the South. I took the opportunity yesterday to question the Chief Secretary to the Treasury,</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20751</id>
    <published>2020-11-04T11:53:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-04T11:53:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Spoken Contributions"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kickstart Scheme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2020/kickstart-scheme/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=kickstart-scheme" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;
October: Kit Malthouse urges local employers to take up the £2bn Kickstart
Scheme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Government’s £2billion
apprenticeship scheme covers the whole cost of hiring an apprentice. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Kit Malthouse
MP: ‘We must create opportunities for young people and back businesses”&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Kit Malthouse
has written to the largest local employers and small business groups urging
them to take up the government’s world leading £2 billion “Kickstart” apprenticeship
scheme designed to get 16-24-year olds into work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The
government will fully fund each “Kickstart” job &amp;#8211; paying 100% of the
age-relevant National Minimum Wage, National Insurance and pension
contributions for 25 hours a week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition,
the government will grant businesses £1,500 per placement to cover the set up
costs or any support or training that may be required.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are 635
unemployed 16-24-year olds across Test Valley, with 315 in Andover, getting
them into work is vital for their long-term career prospects.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Businesses
need to be able to offer 30 apprenticeship placements to apply, or they can go
through an intermediary. Locally, the Hampshire Chamber of Commerce, Enham
Trust and New Forest Business Partnership are all administering applications
for the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kit
Malthouse MP said: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Young people’s jobs are being especially hard
hit by COVID and at a vital time for their professional development. The skills
and experienced gained early in a career provide the solid foundation needed to
grow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the same time businesses can’t afford to
take many risks in these uncertain times, so the government will cover the cost
and eliminate the risk. The kickstart scheme is a win-win for businesses and
apprentices and I encourage employers of all shapes and sizes to sign up.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chancellor of
the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak said:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This isn’t just about kickstarting our
country’s economy – it is an opportunity to kickstart the careers of thousands
of young people who could otherwise be left behind as a result of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The scheme will open the door to a brighter
future for a new generation and ensure the UK bounces back stronger as a
country.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">27th October: Kit Malthouse urges local employers to take up the £2bn Kickstart Scheme Government’s £2billion apprenticeship scheme covers the whole cost of hiring an apprentice. Kit Malthouse MP: ‘We must create opportunities for young people and back businesses” Kit Malthouse has written to the largest local employers and small business groups urging them to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2816</id>
    <published>2020-11-03T12:57:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-03T12:57:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<figure id="attachment_2049" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2049" style="width: 428px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2049" src="http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-300x76.png" alt="" width="438" height="111" srcset="http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-300x76.png 300w, http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-768x195.png 768w, http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1.png 905w" sizes="(max-width: 438px) 100vw, 438px"/><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2049" class="wp-caption-text">(Newspaper column as seen in The Pigeon in October 2020)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This month sees the end of the Coronavirus Jobs Retention Scheme, which was put in place at the start of lockdown to avoid mass job losses. It leaves many people in Bristol South facing a very uncertain future.</p>
<p>I, and my Labour colleagues, have been pushing to see the scheme extended for those hardest hit sectors which are still unable to operate properly due to ongoing restrictions. Disappointingly, the Government chose to ignore the calls from us, from business owners, trade unions, think tanks, the cross-party Treasury Select Committee and some of its own MPs; in doing so, it has let down hundreds of thousands of people working in vulnerable industries such as hospitality, leisure, travel and the arts.</p>
<p>Bristol South does not have lots of large employers which can accommodate mass remote working set up. Families across Bristol South rely on paid work with Bristol Airport and in cafes, bars and restaurants as well as the creative sector. It’s home to lots of small businesses, many of which were struggling before the pandemic hit and this has made things a hundred times harder. I’ve heard from local business owners and self-employed people with heartbreaking stories of their family business, in the community for decades employing local people, suddenly facing financial ruin and closure as a result of this pandemic.</p>
<p>The percentage of people claiming unemployment-related benefits in Bristol South has already risen from 3.6% in March to 6.2% this summer, and this is likely to increase further. I’m hearing from lots of people who’ve always worked and have never had to apply for government support before. And it’s hitting women and young people particularly hard. We must act now to avert the biggest jobs crisis of a generation.</p>
<p>The Government announced the launch of a Kickstart scheme to support younger jobseekers in August, but we’re yet to see this in action and there appears to be no job guarantee at the end of it. I welcome the offer of extra paid incentives for businesses taking on new apprentices and would encourage employers in Bristol South to explore this further, but they too will need jobs at the end of their training and, at the moment, there is no guarantee there either.</p>
<p>This piecemeal approach is not enough. We need a national plan for job retention and creation as well as retraining. I will continue lobbying the Government on this and am working on plans for my 2021 jobs and apprenticeships fair to help link local people up with jobs and training opportunities. In the meantime, there is help available locally to support people with job hunting and employability skills, see <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/16/support-for-employers-and-jobseekers/"><strong>here</strong></a> for more details.</p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/" target="_blank">OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The percentage of people claiming unemployment-related benefits in Bristol South has already risen from 3.6% in March to 6.2% this summer, and this is likely to increase further.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/" target="_blank">OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2810</id>
    <published>2020-10-28T17:10:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-28T17:10:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Newspaper Columns"/>
    <category term="newspaper column"/>
    <category term="pigeon"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tories deny free school meals to 2 million children</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/10/22/9045/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Conservative MPs – including all Scots Tories – refuse to back free meals for children in school holidays Yesterday afternoon in the House of Commons, Brendan O’Hara MP led for the SNP in the Opposition Day debate on access to free school meals and called on the UK Government to commit to tackling widespread poverty, […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9045</id>
    <published>2020-10-22T13:31:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-22T13:31:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rubbish dumping survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="caldera-grid" id="caldera_form_1" data-cf-ver="1.9.2" data-cf-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;&lt;div id="caldera_notices_1" data-spinner="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-admin/images/spinner.gif"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;form data-instance="1" class="CF5f8c811d77adc caldera_forms_form cfajax-trigger" method="POST" enctype="multipart/form-data" id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1" data-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc" aria-label="Flytipping on Cotterills Lane" data-target="#caldera_notices_1" data-template="#cfajax_CF5f8c811d77adc-tmpl" data-cfajax="CF5f8c811d77adc" data-load-element="_parent" data-load-class="cf_processing" data-post-disable="0" data-action="cf_process_ajax_submit" data-request="https://liambyrne.co.uk/cf-api/CF5f8c811d77adc" data-hiderows="true"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" id="_cf_verify_CF5f8c811d77adc" name="_cf_verify" value="a32b43a838"  data-nonce-time="1606473258" /&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_wp_http_referer" value="/feed/" /&gt;&lt;div id="cf2-CF5f8c811d77adc_1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_id" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_ct" value="1"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="cfajax" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_cr_pst" value="7970"&gt;
&lt;div class="hide" style="display:none; overflow:hidden;height:0;width:0;"&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Company&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="text" name="company" value="" autocomplete="off"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-1"  class="row  first_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_949637" class="form-group" id="fld_949637_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_949637Label" for="fld_949637_1" class="control-label"&gt;First name &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_949637" class=" form-control" id="fld_949637_1" name="fld_949637" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_949637Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3720579" class="form-group" id="fld_3720579_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3720579Label" for="fld_3720579_1" class="control-label"&gt;Surname &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_3720579" class=" form-control" id="fld_3720579_1" name="fld_3720579" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_3720579Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_377714" class="form-group" id="fld_377714_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_377714Label" for="fld_377714_1" class="control-label"&gt;Postcode &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_377714" class=" form-control" id="fld_377714_1" name="fld_377714" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_377714Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8339186" class="form-group" id="fld_8339186_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8339186Label" for="fld_8339186_1" class="control-label"&gt;Email &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="email" data-field="fld_8339186" class=" form-control" id="fld_8339186_1" name="fld_8339186" value="" data-type="email" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_8339186Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id="fld_3670460_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8286015" class="form-group" id="fld_8286015_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8286015Label" for="fld_8286015_1" class="control-label"&gt;Has the dumping and littering problem in the area reduced recently?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_8286015" value="" data-field="fld_8286015" class="form-control" id="fld_8286015_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_8286015Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Not Sure"  data-calc-value="Not Sure" &gt;
						Not Sure					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_5317914" class="form-group" id="fld_5317914_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_5317914Label" for="fld_5317914_1" class="control-label"&gt;What further steps would you like to see taken?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;textarea name="fld_5317914" value="" data-field="fld_5317914" class="form-control" id="fld_5317914_1" rows="4"    aria-labelledby="fld_5317914Label" &gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_7237774" class="form-group" id="fld_7237774_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_7237774Label" for="fld_7237774_1" class="control-label"&gt;Would you be willing to join a residents’ group?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_7237774" value="" data-field="fld_7237774" class="form-control" id="fld_7237774_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_7237774Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Maybe"  data-calc-value="Maybe" &gt;
						Maybe					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3572997" class="form-group" id="fld_3572997_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3572997Label" for="fld_3572997_1" class="control-label"&gt;Can Liam email you about news and campaign updates? &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_3572997" value="" data-field="fld_3572997" class="form-control" id="fld_3572997_1"  required="required"  aria-labelledby="fld_3572997Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Liam can email me					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						Liam cannot email me					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_4555323" class=" form-control" id="fld_4555323_1" name="fld_4555323" value="1" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_3061013" class=" form-control" id="fld_3061013_1" name="fld_3061013" value="2020 Oct Flytipping Survey" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;hr id="fld_6111107_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_432351" class="form-group" id="fld_432351_1-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class=""&gt;
	&lt;input  class="btn btn-default" type="submit" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1" value="Submit" data-field="fld_432351"  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;input class="button_trigger_1" type="hidden" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1_btn" value="" data-field="fld_432351"  /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-2"  class="row  last_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/"&gt;Rubbish dumping survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/">Rubbish dumping survey</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=7970</id>
    <published>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Flytipping"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Leisure Centres are a lifeline for so many of us, we can’t let them fail</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/09/30/our-leisure-centres-are-a-lifeline-for-so-many-of-us-we-cant-let-them-fail/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1253</id>
    <published>2020-09-30T10:32:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T10:32:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency News"/>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 50% of furloughed jobs in the Tees Valley are ‘at risk’]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/09/almost-50-of-furloughed-jobs-in-the-tees-valley-are-at-risk/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13752</id>
		<updated>2020-09-17T09:26:28Z</updated>
		<published>2020-09-17T09:11:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alex Cunningham condemns government for putting thousands of North East jobs at risk. Latest figures suggest 350,700 jobs in the North East are still fully furloughed – including 81,300 here in the Tees Valley. Of those furloughed roles in the Tees Valley, 36,300, or 45%, are deemed to be at risk when the scheme is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/09/almost-50-of-furloughed-jobs-in-the-tees-valley-are-at-risk/">Almost 50% of furloughed jobs in the Tees Valley are ‘at risk’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Network Rail is preparing the final stages of delivering step-free access at Garforth Railway Station, it has been announced. </p>
<p>Alec had been campaigning for new step-free access at Garforth for over a decade before finally securing funds direct from the Department for Transport. Alec will continue to work closely, cross-party, with Garforth’s Independent Councillors to represent the views of residents through the planning process. </p>
<p>Announcing the scheme in 2014, the then Transport Secretary Patrick McLoughlin said: “After years of false starts and broken promises under Labour, it is a testament to the local Conservative MP Alec Shelbrooke’s persistent campaigning that I can announce that this scheme is finally happening for the people of Garforth”.</p>
<p>Since 2014 Alec has been in regular contact with Transport officials pushing for firmer plans and no further delays. He also raised the matter several times in the House of Commons Chamber. </p>
<p>But today it has been announced that the final stage before construction is now underway.</p>
<p>Alec said: “Today I’m delighted that Network Rail has formalised a plan with four options for stakeholders to choose from before the submission of a full planning application to Leeds City Council. It is my hope that Leeds City Council can deal with the application swiftly to avoid no further delays”.</p>
<p>“I have been campaigning for step-free access at Garforth Station for many years. We had an original plan submitted but this then incurred unnecessary delays along the way but I have been committed to providing disabled people and pushchair users with the same access to travel as everyone else – and delivering step-free access at Garforth station will help thousands more people travel easily and without additional cost, time or stress”.</p>
<p>Previously, Garforth resident Mrs Morris said: “We’ve waited far too long for disabled access at Garforth. The elderly, disabled and those with pushchairs have not been able to use the station so we’re extremely grateful to Alec for fighting alongside us to deliver this disabled access”. </p>
<p>The Government’s Access for All programme was first launched in 2006 and has delivered more than 200 accessible routes into selected stations so far.</p>
<p>A further 1,500 stations have received smaller scale improvements such as accessible toilets, platform humps to reduce stepping distances and improvements to help those with a visual or hearing impairment.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/">Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Network Rail is preparing the final stages of delivering step-free access at Garforth Railway Station, it has been announced. Alec had been campaigning for new step-free access at Garforth for over a decade before finally securing funds direct from the Department for Transport. Alec will continue to work closely, cross-party, with Garforth’s Independent Councillors to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/" title="ReadGarforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/">Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1727</id>
    <published>2020-08-19T16:04:10Z</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T16:04:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
