<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-03-05T19:34:07Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Jack Gebhard</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Worcester is top priority for £4.8 billion Levelling Up Fund]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/03/worcester-is-top-priority-for-4-8-billion-levelling-up-fund/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2182</id>
		<updated>2021-03-05T18:09:23Z</updated>
		<published>2021-03-05T18:09:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Front Page"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Local Government"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Treasury"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Worcester City Council"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Chancellor of the Exchequer today announce that Worcester has been named as one of the top priority areas to benefit from a £4.8 billion fund that will provide capital investment for major projects. The Levelling Up Fund was announced at the 2020 Spending Review to support places like Worcester to grow their economies and [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/03/worcester-is-top-priority-for-4-8-billion-levelling-up-fund/"><![CDATA[<p>The Chancellor of the Exchequer today announce that Worcester has been named as one of the top priority areas to benefit from a £4.8 billion fund that will provide capital investment for major projects.</p>
<p>The Levelling Up Fund was announced at the 2020 Spending Review to support places like Worcester to grow their economies and bind communities.</p>
<p>The Fund will focus on capital investment in local infrastructure, and will build on prior programmes such as the Future High Streets Fund which Worcester is benefitting by £18 million from, and the Towns Fund bid which has the opportunity to transform Worcester.</p>
<p>Bids will be favoured that have a visible impact on people and their communities. This includes a range of high value local investment priorities, including local transport schemes, urban regeneration projects and cultural assets.</p>
<p>Applications to the fund will be managed by local authorities and today’s budget allocated £150,000 to support them in writing their bids.</p>
<p>Worcester MP Robin Walker said:</p>
<p>“This news is a further commitment to Worcester by our government and demonstrates a real desire to level up opportunities to areas like ours.</p>
<p>“I lobbied hard for us to be included in the Future High Streets Fund and I was delighted when we were allocated £18 million for our City Centre in December last year. That funding will allow Worcester City Council to purchase and redevelop sites for cultural, commercial and residential use. In particular it will enable the reopening of the long-neglected Scala theatre providing Worcester with a major cultural boost and allowing for the Worcester Live theatre group to move from their site at the Swan to a better connected city centre location.</p>
<p>“I have also worked with the Towns Fund Board to ensure the Town Improvement Plan is exciting and ambitious and I was delighted when this was submitted last month. It is possible we will benefit from a £28 million cash injection from government, matched by funding from Worcester City Council that has the potential to transform our city.</p>
<p>“I now look forward to working with my colleagues in government and Worcester City Council to ensure we see the maximum possible impact from the Levelling Up Fund.”</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/03/worcester-is-top-priority-for-4-8-billion-levelling-up-fund/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/03/worcester-is-top-priority-for-4-8-billion-levelling-up-fund/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-45/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Saturday 27th February <a href="https://www.llafur.org/">Llafur</a> held their second Zoom event in their Spring Series “Migration and Wales” dedicated to the memory of Llafur’s President Hywel Francis, who sadly and tragically passed away on the 14th February. Part 1 of the series is looking at “Communities and People”, and this meeting’s theme was “Revisiting Tiger Bay”. Chair of Llafur Ian Rees introduced the event which was chaired by Vice President Gaynor Legall. We heard from three speakers, Trevor Godbold, Yasmin Begum and Mymuna Soleman, reflecting on the history of Tiger Bay.</p>
<p>On Monday 1st March we celebrated St David’s Day, but in a very different way due to the restrictions imposed on our nation by the coronavirus pandemic. However, it was very uplifting to see the many photographs of children dressed in Dewi Sant costumes.</p>
<p>On Tuesday 2nd March, in advance of the UK Government’s Budget, I attended the <a href="https://www.gapsinsupportappg.org/events/appg-gaps-in-support-meeting-2nd-march-2021">Gaps in Support All Party Parliamentary Group</a>. As vice chair of the Group, I paid tribute to my dear friend Hywel Francis. We discussed the APPG <a href="https://www.gapsinsupportappg.org/news/prebudgetreport">Pre-Budget Report</a>and listened to trade union leaders, Roy Rickhuss, General Secretary of Community Union and Mike Clancy General Secretary of Prospect, representing the views of their members who have received little, or no, support from the Chancellor, and suggestions for solutions.</p>
<p>As an officer of the <a href="http://appgmutuals.coop/">All-Party Group for Mutuals</a>, I attended the first evidence session for our enquiry into the planned demutualisation and takeover of Liverpool Victoria by Bain Capital. We listened to and asked questions of Martin Shaw, CEO of Association of Financial Mutuals, and John Gilbert Friendly Societies and Mutual Insurance Legal Expert.</p>
<p>On Tuesday afternoon it was the funeral of Hywel Francis. His cortège left his home in Crynant, passed up the Dulais Valley through Seven Sisters and Onllwyn, then down through Taibach to Margam Crematorium for a family funeral. Hywel’s friends and colleagues lined the streets to pay their respects. I stood outside the Palace of Culture (Onllwyn Welfare) with Wayne Thomas (NUM), Sian Williams (South Wales Miners Library), Rob Humphries, Cllr. Dean Cawsey (County Councillor for Onllwyn, where Hywel was born), Lesley Smith of Dove Workshop and Onllwyn Choir – Hywel has been President for 40 years – and many, many more people. Matthew Sims, the conductor of Onllwyn Male Voice Choir and also independent funeral director, walked in front of the hearse, and stopped the cortège in front of the Palace of Culture. We brought the Banners – South Wales Miners, Seven Sisters Lodge, Abercraf Lodge – it was a truly iconic moment that will stay with me throughout my life.</p>
<p>On Tuesday evening I attended the PCS Union Parliamentary Zoom call. We received an update into the number of coronavirus cases, the health and safety issues, and the proposed industrial action by PCS members working at the DVLA. The six MPs across the Swansea region have signed a <a href="https://www.pcs.org.uk/news/itv-news-investigation-focuses-on-dvla-covid-safety">statement</a> of support for the workers.</p>
<p>Later that evening, as a Labour and Co-operative MP, I attended the AGM of the Swansea Neath Port Talbot Co-operative Party branch zoom meeting and was honoured to be elected vice-chair.</p>
<p>The big news in Westminster this week was the Budget.  Sadly, the Chancellor gave a very weak and disappointing response to the enormous impact of the pandemic on our communities. In a country that has experienced both the worst death toll and the worst economic crisis, we needed to see a Budget that put people first, that emphasised the importance of investment in job creation and training, that ensured businesses were given the support they need to rebuild and return strongly, and that supported the families that have suffered so much.</p>
<p>Instead, we see no immediate support for business and suggestions of tax rises that will hit struggling families hard. This is not levelling up; this is returning to the same insecurity and inequality that has wreaked havoc over the past ten years. An unequal economy is not a prosperous one. We need investment across the whole of the UK, and jobs to give people the security and the local economies the strength that they need to really rebuild after this crisis.</p>
<p>Although he extended the Furlough scheme and the uplift in Universal Credit, it was only for six months, creating a new cliff edge for people in receipt of support at the end of September. The majority of the three million excluded from the Chancellor’s support schemes, remain without support. The Chancellor’s only concession being to extend support to the newly self-employed with tax returns for 2019/20. The Welsh Labour Government has filled in the gaps by providing the most generous support package in the UK despite its funding from the UK Government being cut, for example the £2 billion Economic Resilience Fund has secured 141,000 jobs in Wales. But this UK Conservative Government Budget yet again has cut funding to Wales by 4% per head in real terms than in 2010-11 and provided nothing in capital spend for the future. This is played out against the background of the Internal Market Act which has taken back powers from devolved nations. The Counsel General for the Welsh Government and MS for Neath Jeremy Miles has issued proceedings against the UK Government alleging that the Act is contrary to the devolution settlement. There was good news for Neath in that the Chancellor announced the long awaited £30 million funding for the Global Centre of Rail Excellence to be built on the Nant Helen Opencast site and Washery in Onllwyn. This project has been driven by Welsh Government in partnership with landowners Celtic Energy and rail companies, and I eagerly await written confirmation of the contract agreement.</p>
<p>This week is Food Waste Action Week. Staggeringly, around a third of the food we produce worldwide is lost or wasted and not surprisingly, it’s having a significant impact on climate change. There are so many ways that we can make little changes to the way we eat to support the environment. For those who do eat meat, consider having a few vegetarian meals each week – there are some fantastic recipes out there for curries, pasta dishes, and soups that can help you feel healthy and environmentally friendly. We can also try and shop local as much as we can to ensure that our food has as small a carbon footprint as possible and with the added bonus of helping local businesses. We can do so much to <a href="https://www.lovefoodhatewaste.com/fwaw">stop wasting food</a>, which will also benefit our wallets as well. Make a list and plan your meals and portions for the week, making sure to consider how you can use up leftovers and what food could be frozen and kept for later. Check your fridge temperature and turn it down to 5°C or lower to keep your food fresher for longer and keep an eye on use-by dates to make sure you use up food before it goes off.</p>
<p>We also marked World Book Day on Thursday, another of those days that has gained a new significance thanks to the lockdown. The OECD have found that reading for pleasure is the single biggest indicator of a child’s future success – more than their family’s circumstances, their parents’ educational background, or their income. It’s so important, therefore, that we encourage children to read and ensure that everyone, regardless of their family budget and circumstances, is able to access reading materials that are fun and inspirational. There are so many fantastic children’s authors out there and every child should be able to find books that match their interests, from dinosaurs to space, sports to history. <a href="https://www.npt.gov.uk/1214">Neath’s libraries</a> are still operating an online and ‘call and collect’ service – take a look if you aren’t already a member and see what books interest you and your children!</p>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch about matters that fall under my role as an MP, please do not hesitate to drop me an email on christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call on 01639 630152. My staff are working from home to comply with the social distancing measures, but, as always, we remain there for you should you need our help.</p>
<p>I hope you stay well, and remember – observe social distancing, wash your hands regularly and keep Wales safe.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Saturday 27th February Llafur held their second Zoom event in their Spring Series “Migration and Wales” dedicated to the memory of Llafur’s President Hywel Francis, who sadly and tragically passed away on the 14th February. Part 1 of the series is looking at “Communities and People”, and this meeting’s theme was “Revisiting Tiger Bay”. […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2425</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T18:00:48Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T18:00:48Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/03/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-7/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Supported DVSA to provide a new driving test centre in High Wycombe Met with the Conservative Party Chairman Met the Chancellor of the Exchequer with the 1922 Committee Met with the Minister for Covid Vaccine Deployment Briefed by the Office for Budget Responsibility on our economic and fiscal outlook Met with local businesses, Bucks Business First and the Minister for Tourism &amp; Sport for him to answer questions and help businesses […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy-Anne Hickey</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18409</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T17:45:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T17:45:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="#Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Census 2021: Sunday 21 March</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2021/03/05/census-2021-sunday-21-march/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3808</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T17:27:31Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T17:27:31Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Save Our Campsites! </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/save-our-campsites" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/girlguide%20campsite.jpg?itok=k13mOoL5" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p class="MsoNormal">Today a local girl guide leader contacted Jon Cruddas MP to inform him of the sad and worrying news of a proposal to close the Girlguiding campsites at Chigwell Row and Cudham Shaw. The campsites offer vital green spaces for local young people of all backgrounds.  </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">This news of closure will be a blow to so many young people in Dagenham and Rainham. The Cudham Shaw site houses Copps Cottage, which is designed for girls with disabilities, ensuring they have access to a Girlguiding camping experience. The campsites are all situated within London Boroughs meaning the closures will significantly impact girls from BAME backgrounds as well as those with disabilities.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">
                <strong>Jon Cruddas MP: <em>“The news of the proposal to close the Girlguiding campsites in Dagenham and Rainham is devastating. Considering the events of this year, it is essential now more than ever that young people have a positive and safe outlet. The closure of these campsites will take this important outlet away from many people. I encourage the residents of Barking and Dagenham to sign the petition to retain these valuable facilities.”</em></strong>
              </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">If you would like to demonstrate your support, please sign the Change.org petition below:</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">
                <a href="https://www.change.org/p/girlguiding-london-and-south-east-region-don-t-close-our-region-campsites?recruiter=false&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_initial&amp;utm_term=psf_combo_share_message&amp;recruited_by_id=4f467510-7c44-11eb-ad23-035637456d94&amp;utm_content=mit-27650344-10%3Av3" target="_blank">https://www.change.org/p/girlguiding-london-and-south-east-region-don-t-close-our-region-campsites?recruiter=false&amp;utm_source=share_petition&amp;utm_medium=facebook&amp;utm_campaign=psf_combo_share_initial&amp;utm_term=psf_combo_share_message&amp;recruited_by_id=4f467510-7c44-11eb-ad23-035637456d94&amp;utm_content=mit-27650344-10%3Av3</a>
              </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal"> </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal"> </p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/dagenham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Dagenham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/rainham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Rainham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/girlguides" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Girlguides</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/campsites" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Campsites</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>margaret</name>
    </author>
    <id>1480 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T16:56:53Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T16:56:53Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne: Take part in Census Day on 21st March</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-take-part-census-day-21st-march" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="6912" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">5 March 2021</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne: Take part in Census Day on 21st March</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>Census Day on 21st March will help plan services and secure funding for South Shropshire, says local MP Philip Dunne.</p>

<p>The Census national survey is undertaken every 10 years, organised by the independent Office for National Statistics. Households are receiving a letter in the post now, which explains how to take part. The letter will contain a household access code, which you should use to complete the census online. You can also request a paper version if you prefer.</p>

<p>Information from the census helps plan and fund public services, including transport, education and healthcare. Charities and voluntary organisations often use it as evidence to get funding. It also helps businesses to understand customers and, for example, decide where to locate their premises. You must complete the census questionnaire by law or you could be fined up to £1,000. The census should take around 10 minutes per person to complete.</p>

<p>Mr Dunne said: “It is vital people take part in the Census, as this snapshot will be used to inform decisions around planning and delivering services for South Shropshire into the future.</p>

<p>As a former Defence Minister, I am particularly pleased to see a new question in the census gauging the number of people with previous military service in the UK. Veterans make a huge contribution to UK life, but they can also require more complex health and mental health services, so it is important we have as much information as possible to plan these services.”</p>

<p>Census 2021 will ask people aged 16 years and over questions on three new topics. These are:</p>

<ul type="disc"><li>previous service in the UK Armed Forces</li>
	<li>gender identity</li>
	<li>sexual orientation</li>
</ul><p>The sexual orientation and gender identity questions are also voluntary, like the religion question. As with all questions about identity, people can answer in the way that best represents them by using the response options, including write-in options, provided.</p>

<p>If you need help completing the Census, there will also be a dedicated contact centre offering help through phone, webchat, email, social media or text message. You can call the contact centre free on 0800 141 2021.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6912 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T16:16:18Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T16:16:18Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A question of priorities – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-question-of-priorities-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-question-of-priorities-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233339" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/TR-Budget.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a bit of an advantage over me this week. By the time you read this, the Chancellor the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, will have delivered his Spring Budget and you’ll probably have a good idea about what the Government will be spending and on what. As I write, I don’t yet know the full details. I probably know more than I should as the Chancellor is not a shy and retiring type. Instead, he’s spent the last week or so boasting to anyone who’ll listen, leaking announcements and starring in his own long self-promotional video (paid for by all of us as taxpayers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor’s ego aside, I thought I’d use my column this week to talk about some of what I think should be in the Budget. Firstly, we have seen throughout this crisis just how important our key workers are. For months we clapped our carers, but now it seems that the Government want to freeze the pay of many of them. A pay freeze, in real terms, is a pay cut and that’s no way to thank those who have done so much to get us through the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They like to pretend now that they had nothing to do with it, but the reality is that the Tories have spent 11 years of cutting public services to the bone – whether that’s schools, the police (half of Britain’s police stations have closed since they came to power), the NHS or local councils. These same public services have been on the frontline during this crisis. They need proper investment, as they will also be on the frontline of our recovery from the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also some scandals that have emerged or ballooned during the pandemic which require urgent action. The Chancellor has spent months ignoring those – largely self-employed and freelancers – who have been excluded from any financial support, and the Government have proposed a solution to the cladding scandal that will lead many to lose their homes or declare bankruptcy as they pay for the negligence of others. It is up to the Chancellor to address these scandals and millions will be watching in hope that he does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate over the Budget for the next few days and weeks will be dominated by spin, but we need more than just slick self-promotion from the Chancellor – we need real action in the face of this crisis, so I’ll be looking very carefully at what the proposals actually are and not what the Chancellor wants us to believe they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-question-of-priorities-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/"&gt;A question of priorities &amp;#8211; my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>You have a bit of an advantage over me this week. By the time you read this, the Chancellor the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, will have delivered his Spring Budget and you’ll probably have a good idea about what the Government will be spending and on what. As I write, I don’t yet know the full […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-question-of-priorities-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">A question of priorities – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233338</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T16:09:42Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T16:09:42Z</updated>
    <category term="National"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP says Impact Assessment Report finishes HIAL’s plans</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/03/05/isles-mp-says-impact-assessment-report-finishes-hials-plans/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="3426" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/20210211_170121-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg" data-orig-size="3088,4128" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.9&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-A202F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1613062880&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3.6&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;80&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.01&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="20210211_170121" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=224" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=766" alt="" class="wp-image-3426" width="386" height="515" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=386 386w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=772 772w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=112 112w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=224 224w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/03/20210211_170121.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 386px) 100vw, 386px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has welcomed yet another nail in the coffin to HIAL’s ill-thought, island-damaging plans for empire building at Inverness Airport. HIAL’s plans which would cost the public purse £2.5 million extra, each and every year, are now seen for the ill-conceived, ill-thought through concepts they always were.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil, who has just written to Audit Scotland to look into this huge potential waste of public money, advises HIAL to confine this nonsense to the dustbin now and for government to get a grip over the wayward waste of public money which has cost us £6.5 million to get to the point of understanding that removing jobs from islands and harming communities is not the way for a Scottish Government agency to go.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Currently our airports provide excellent local jobs with no issues of staff retention, particularly when local staff are recruited, in both Stornoway and Benbecula. The money that HIAL have wasted so far could have upgraded all our airports and secured these jobs with a lot less ongoing cost to the public purse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Islands will be particularly impacted with a loss of high quality jobs in the community if the high cost alternative of centralising in Inverness were to go ahead. Our fragile islands will lose population, this is surely not something that Scottish Government Ministers will sit back and let happen, playing Pontus Pilate is not a responsible option where fragile communities are concerned. Currently our airlines, our ferry companies, our crofting commission, even the board of the Gaelic language are headquartered off the islands, and so much more besides. Regardless of politics everyone needs to rally around and lend support to the issue for keeping these jobs on the islands.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If HIAL don’t drop these plans, Audit Scotland needs to investigate at least two alternatives that are cheaper than HIAL’s pet project and which would keep jobs on the islands. However, hopefully these plans will be consigned to the dustbin of history and our communities can breathe a sigh of relief, with the government saving many millions annually in the process.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has welcomed yet another nail in the coffin to HIAL’s ill-thought, island-damaging …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/03/05/isles-mp-says-impact-assessment-report-finishes-hials-plans/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3422</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T15:40:05Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T15:40:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Walsall Healthcare Trust recognised by the Government!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/walsall-healthcare-trust-recognised-by-the-government/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">I was delighted that Matt Hancock recognised the incredible work being undertaken across Walsall and my own Aldridge-Brownhills constituency to roll out the vaccine.</div>
<div dir="auto">The effort to deliver the vaccine has been an amazing effort and I would like to add my own congratulations to Richard Beeken, Darren Fradgley and all our healthcare professionals, Walsall Council, and volunteers for everything that they are doing!</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">Matt Hancock Tweet: –</div>
<div dir="auto">I’d like to thank Richard Beeken, Darren Fradgley and the team at Walsall Manor Hospital for their incredible work during the pandemic, and more recently for ensuring the vaccination programme is progressing well in Walsall.</div>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">I’d also like to thank Mike Bird and the team at Walsall Council for the work they are doing, with GPs and health partners, to ensure vaccination sites are set up across the borough, including the Oak Park Centre at Walsall Wood which is up and running already, and the former T J Hughes site which will soon be capable of doing over 3500 jabs per day.</div>
<div dir="auto">
<div style="width: 848px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-3577-1" width="848" height="480" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Hancock-Video-2021.mp4?_=1"/><a href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Hancock-Video-2021.mp4">http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Hancock-Video-2021.mp4</a></video></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was delighted that Matt Hancock recognised the incredible work being undertaken across Walsall and my own Aldridge-Brownhills constituency to roll out the vaccine. The effort to deliver the vaccine has been an amazing effort and I would like to add my own congratulations to Richard Beeken, Darren Fradgley and all our healthcare professionals, Walsall […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3577</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T14:24:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T14:24:00Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Women from Edinburgh’s present celebrate those from its past to mark International Women’s Day </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13122/women-from-edinburgh-s-present-celebrate-those-from-its-past-to-mark-international-women-s-day" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Marking International Women’s Day 2021 curators from Museums &amp; Galleries Edinburgh have taken the opportunity to shine a spotlight on a selection of fascinating women from Edinburgh’s past. </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13122/women-from-edinburgh-s-present-celebrate-those-from-its-past-to-mark-international-women-s-day</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T13:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T13:54:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My speech in response to the Budget, 4 March</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/03/05/my-speech-in-response-to-the-budget-4-march/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I welcome the extension of help to individuals and companies. All the time people cannot go to work or businesses cannot trade and all the time that there are pandemic regulations and social distancing that impede people going about their normal business, it is vital that the Government offer alternative income and support. I am pleased that the Government came up with a big response originally, and it is necessary to carry it on for as long as these restrictive measures remain in place.</p>
<p>I also welcome the fact that the OBR has decided that we will be borrowing £39 billion less in the current year than in its recent November forecast. I think that serves as a reminder or a warning to all those trying to debate the economy based on a set of figures; these are very uncertain times. It is difficult for the official forecasters to come up with accurate figures, and we should be especially suspicious of ideas based on what the deficit might be in a couple of years’ time. This deficit will fall very rapidly.</p>
<p>Assuming the great success of the vaccines continues, and assuming that we can relax and get people back to normal work and normal business within a few weeks or months, we will then see the deficit come down because so much of the deficit has been caused by the special pandemic measures.</p>
<p>The figures confirm that around £250 billion of extra spending in 2020-21 was the direct result of the special pandemic measures, and that there will be another large figure in the first part of 2021-22. We want to see the end of all those special expenditures—because people have better-paid jobs to go back to, businesses are trading successfully, and there is turnover and profit coming back to our small and large businesses—and so much of that expenditure was a poor substitute for being able to do the thing itself.</p>
<p>There was of course some loss of tax revenue, and again, we would expect to see tax revenue rise quite rapidly as soon as people can trade properly again, as soon as there are more transactions in the economy, and as soon as we are making more goods and providing more services to each other, as I am sure we will. So the Chancellor is right to say that the crucial step to getting the economy back to health, the deficit down and the numbers back into shape is to promote a recovery. He is right to want more investment in our economy.</p>
<p>The public sector numbers show public sector investment going up, and it is very important that good projects are chosen that will have a good payback. It is very important, too, that the tax incentives are correctly honed so that we get the boost in private sector investment that we want. The Chancellor is also right not to rush out any new fiscal rules.</p>
<p>We will need a new set of rules in due course, however, and they must be geared to a faster growth policy and a policy about levelling up and investing in great projects around the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>That must be linked to sensible discipline on public finances and, above all, to keeping the good control of inflation that we have had for a number of years now. It is reassuring that the OBR and the Bank of England are very confident that inflation will remain low, which gives us a bit more flexibility, but we need to watch that inflation situation.</p>
<p>I note that the OBR thinks the balance of payments is going to be weak for two or three years, and that provides an opportunity. In the post-Brexit world there are huge opportunities that we can exploit more easily in import substitution. Why do we not, for example, with our great green policies, plant many more trees and make sure there is much more sustainable husbandry of trees so that we replace many of the timber imports?</p>
<p>And while we are about it, can we replace the pelleted timber coming in to produce power at Drax with home-produced sustainable timber? We should also put in sufficient electricity capacity, because if we want an electrical revolution we will need a lot more capacity, and while we are doing that we should get rid of the imported electricity through the interconnector, which we rely on more and more for no particular reason.</p>
<p>We used to be able to have all our own power provided in the UK with a decent margin and I suggest we return to that. We can do a lot more on food and fish, too. I urge the relevant Ministers and Departments to promote food and fish, and also to make sure that the grant schemes and regulations that are now under our control are used to increase our capacity so that we start to substitute many of the items that are coming in.</p>
<p>A recovery needs more orders and more investment in capacity; it requires excitement over new products and services and the restoration of old products and services. That must be the single thing that most motivates all the relevant Ministries and Government policy, because the only way to get this very big deficit down is to have more revenue and less expenditure, and the only legitimate expenditure to cut is all the spending we have been doing as a poor substitute for a decent economy with well-paid jobs and successful businesses.</p>
<p>So I say, let’s go for growth; let’s do everything we can to promote more things being made and grown and sold within the United Kingdom. There are huge opportunities, and that will be good economics.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I welcome the extension of help to individuals and companies. All the time people cannot go to work or businesses cannot trade and all the time that there are pandemic regulations and social distancing that impede people going about their normal business, it is vital that the Government offer alternative income and support. I am…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29815</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T13:51:47Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T13:51:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Debates"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz speaks about lack of support for social care in the Budget]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-about-lack-of-support-for-social-care-in-the-budget/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=10917</id>
		<updated>2021-03-05T12:06:39Z</updated>
		<published>2021-03-05T10:54:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Caring for older people"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Liz in the news"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="liz kendall"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="National"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Social Care"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Supporting families"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rishi Sunak&#8217;s budget on Wednesday had absolutely no mention of social care. This pandemic has exposed the impact of 10 years of social care funding cuts, and our carer workers and families deserve better.<br />
The Chancellor then told the BBC that the reason that social care plans hadn&#8217;t been brought forward was that the Government were trying to build cross-party support. As Shadow Care Minister, this has not once been raised with me, or other members of the Shadow Health Team. This is despite of me asking about it multiple times ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-about-lack-of-support-for-social-care-in-the-budget/">Liz speaks about lack of support for social care in the Budget</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-about-lack-of-support-for-social-care-in-the-budget/"><![CDATA[<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-10917-1" width="720" height="720" poster="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot-2021-03-05-at-10.43.13.png" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/210304-WATO.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/210304-WATO.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/210304-WATO.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Rishi Sunak&#8217;s budget on Wednesday had absolutely no mention of social care. This pandemic has exposed the impact of 10 years of social care funding cuts, and our carer workers and families deserve better.</p>
<p>The Chancellor then told the BBC that the reason that social care plans hadn&#8217;t been brought forward was that the Government were trying to build cross-party support. As Shadow Care Minister, this has not once been raised with me, or other members of the Shadow Health Team. This is despite of me asking about it multiple times over the last year.</p>
<p>Proper cross-party talks isn&#8217;t the Government deciding and expecting other parties to agree. It&#8217;s about finding common ground that will last for years to come.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The Prime Minister said over 18 months ago that he had a plan to fix social care. We need to see this plan urgently and end the crisis in social care once and for all.</p>
<p>Read more coverage in the <a href="https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-9327917/Boris-Johnsons-failure-fix-social-care-stain-nation-expert-says.html">Daily Mail</a>, <a href="https://news.sky.com/story/budget-2021-what-wasnt-in-chancellor-rishi-sunaks-economic-statement-12234872">Sky News,</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.yorkshirepost.co.uk/news/opinion/columnists/excuses-dont-wash-for-continued-lack-of-social-care-plan-the-yorkshire-post-says-3154884">the Yorkshire Post</a>, <a href="https://inews.co.uk/news/budget-2021-insulted-nhs-staff-denied-pay-rise-896440">the i, </a>and the <a href="https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/politics/boris-johnson-no-social-care-23607343">Daily Mirror</a>.</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-6286" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/fears-as-3-7-million-women-overdue-for-vital-smear-tests/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/5.jpg" alt="Fears as 3.7 million women overdue for vital smear tests (The Sun, 24 April)" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/fears-as-3-7-million-women-overdue-for-vital-smear-tests/" class="wp_rp_title">Fears as 3.7 million women overdue for vital smear tests (The Sun, 24 April)</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-2566" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-is-joined-by-tory-mps-in-supporting-glenfield-hospital/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/11.jpg" alt="Liz is joined by Tory MPs in supporting Glenfield Hospital" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-is-joined-by-tory-mps-in-supporting-glenfield-hospital/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz is joined by Tory MPs in supporting Glenfield Hospital</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-10541" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/care-home-coronavirus-outbreaks-cast-doubt-on-official-phe-data/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/14.jpg" alt="Care home coronavirus outbreaks cast doubt on official PHE data" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/care-home-coronavirus-outbreaks-cast-doubt-on-official-phe-data/" class="wp_rp_title">Care home coronavirus outbreaks cast doubt on official PHE data</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-4105" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/ageing-positively-conference/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/6.jpg" alt="Ageing Positively Conference" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/ageing-positively-conference/" class="wp_rp_title">Ageing Positively Conference</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-6530" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/we-must-get-justice-for-child-abuse-victims-and-provide-a-safer-future-lizs-latest-leicester-mercury-column/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/22.jpg" alt="We must get justice for child abuse victims and provide a safer future &#8211; Liz’s latest Leicester Mercury column " width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/we-must-get-justice-for-child-abuse-victims-and-provide-a-safer-future-lizs-latest-leicester-mercury-column/" class="wp_rp_title">We must get justice for child abuse victims and provide a safer future &#8211; Liz’s latest Leicester Mercury column </a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-about-lack-of-support-for-social-care-in-the-budget/">Liz speaks about lack of support for social care in the Budget</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/210304-WATO.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="0" type=""/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Karin Smyth MP condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS in this year’s Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/03/05/karin-smyth-mp-condemns-the-government-for-neglecting-the-nhs-in-this-years-budget/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=karin-smyth-mp-condemns-the-government-for-neglecting-the-nhs-in-this-years-budget" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p><b>Karin Smyth MP condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS in this year’s Budget</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS, social care and schools in the Budget announced by the Chancellor on Wednesday.  With just one mention of the NHS, and no mention of social care or school funding, Smyth has criticised the Government for having the wrong priorities.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Budget documents revealed that NHS England core resource spending, including Covid spending, will fall from £147.7 million this year down to £139.1 million next, meaning there is no plan to deal with the ongoing cost to the NHS from Covid-19.  The Government has also not allocated any additional resources to tackle the crisis now facing cancer care or waiting lists that have built up during the crisis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The climate emergency and job crisis were also neglected in Wednesday’s budget announcement, with no new investment for green recoveries in key industries including automotive, aerospace and steel, and just £20m announced for floating offshore wind technology. </span></p>
<p><b>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, said: </b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“This Budget was the opportunity to put our country back on the road to recovery and right the wrongs of the last decade by rebuilding our economy, but the Chancellor is simply papering over the cracks and has shown how out of touch he is with what this country needs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Today’s speech saw just one mention of the NHS and no mention of the huge challenges facing social care. With no plan for NHS recovery, this Budget is ignoring the enormous backlog of cases that have built up during the crisis and is following through with plans to freeze pay for our key workers in the public sector.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“I am also gravely concerned that in this Budget the Chancellor has turned his back on the green stimulus that the jobs and climate emergency is crying out for.  Labour has repeatedly called for a £30bn green economic recovery which would create so many opportunities for youth employment and apprenticeships in clean industries in Bristol.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The Chancellor should have learned lessons from the pandemic, but instead he is choosing to go back to the same insecure economy and unequal society so cruelly exposed by the virus. He has got his priorities totally wrong.”</span></p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/03/05/karin-smyth-mp-condemns-the-government-for-neglecting-the-nhs-in-this-years-budget/">Karin Smyth MP condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS in this year’s Budget</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth MP condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS in this year’s Budget Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/03/05/karin-smyth-mp-condemns-the-government-for-neglecting-the-nhs-in-this-years-budget/">Karin Smyth MP condemns the Government for neglecting the NHS in this year’s Budget</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2876</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T12:04:54Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T12:04:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne-Marie's latest email newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-maries-latest-email-newsletter-2" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Update from Westminster and Northumberland
Good morning everyone. There has been a lot of Budget news this week (you can read my Budget update HERE if you missed it) but here is what else has been going on that you may have missed.

Great news from my colleague Liz Truss that the UK and US have…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-maries-latest-email-newsletter-2</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 5 March 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron5mar" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>This week marks ten years since I was first elected as the MP for Barnsley Central in a by-election. My time in Parliament has often felt like an endless whirlwind of events: three General Elections; a Mayoral election; two era-defining referenda; conflicts in Libya and Syria; political, economic and health crises. In other words, plenty to keep me busy!</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron5mar</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T11:14:20Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T11:14:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Great to catch up with local St John Ambulance volunteers helping with vaccine rollout</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1778-great-to-catch-up-with-local-st-john-ambulance-volunteers-helping-with-vaccine-rollout"/>
		<published>2021-03-05T08:40:15+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-05T08:40:15+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1778-great-to-catch-up-with-local-st-john-ambulance-volunteers-helping-with-vaccine-rollout</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Great to catch up with local &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stjohnambulance?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@stjohnambulance&lt;/a&gt; volunteers and listen to the amazing work they are doing in the vaccine rollout. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SJAEastComms?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SJAEastComms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1367754495229300739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Great to catch up with local &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/stjohnambulance?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@stjohnambulance&lt;/a&gt; volunteers and listen to the amazing work they are doing in the vaccine rollout. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SJAEastComms?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SJAEastComms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1367754495229300739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;March 5, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Harriett Baldwin speaks in Budget debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-baldwin-speaks-budget-debate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Harriett Baldwin welcomes the Budget, in particular innovative measures to encourage business investment and growth but calls for a rethink on the scrapping of the 0.7% GNI commitment to international aid. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-baldwin-speaks-budget-debate" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5060 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2021-03-05T06:05:13Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-05T06:05:13Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex urges TS19 residents to get tested]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/03/alex-urges-ts19-residents-to-get-tested/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14029</id>
		<updated>2021-03-04T17:23:05Z</updated>
		<published>2021-03-04T17:22:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Responding to news that the South African variant of Covid has been identified in the TS19 area, Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham said: “It is right that we act quickly and cautiously with any new variant of Covid-19, and I’d urge everyone over 16 in the TS19 postcode to get tested – and register it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/03/alex-urges-ts19-residents-to-get-tested/">Alex urges TS19 residents to get tested</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catherine visits Newcastle Racecourse Vaccine Centre to thank local heroes as 50,000th Vaccine delivered today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-visits-newcastle-racecourse-vaccine-centre-to-thank-local-heroes-as-50000th-vaccine-delivered-today/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, MP for Newcastle North, today (4th March 2021) visited the Covid-19 vaccination centre at Newcastle Racecourse in her constituency in Gosforth. Catherine joined Rebecca Haynes, Chief Operating Officer for Newcastle GP Services, Dr Jane Carman who is lead GP at the centre for the day, and Andy Robinson from the Tyne and Wear Fire and Rescue Service to visit the site and see … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-visits-newcastle-racecourse-vaccine-centre-to-thank-local-heroes-as-50000th-vaccine-delivered-today/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Catherine visits Newcastle Racecourse Vaccine Centre to thank local heroes as 50,000th Vaccine delivered today</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7133</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T16:45:07Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T16:45:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - The Tenterden &amp; East Sussex Railway 60th Year Appeal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-tenterden-east-sussex-railway-60th-year-appeal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">It is I hope a sign of the times that this week I am writing about something which indicates better things to come. This is the 60th anniversary appeal of the Kent &amp; East Sussex Railway, which is looking forward to welcoming back passengers to its station in Tenterden this summer.
The railway…</content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-tenterden-east-sussex-railway-60th-year-appeal</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Crown Heights Relief Fund </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/crown-heights-relief-fund" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP Maria Miller has been working with residents in Crown Heights, who have contacted her about the problems with fire safety identified in the blocks.
Maria has been in direct contact with the chief operating officer of the building management company and also the Chief Fire Officer for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/crown-heights-relief-fund</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Punitive tariffs on Borders textile mills removed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/punitive-tariffs-borders-textile-mills-removed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The International Trade Secretary (Rt Hon Liz Truss MP) has announced that she has come to an agreement with her US counterpart to remove US tariffs on cashmere and Scotch whisky from Monday.
The removal will last for four months to allow US and UK negotiators to come to a wider agreement on trade…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/punitive-tariffs-borders-textile-mills-removed</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2021 Budget: Key Announcements </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/2021-budget-key-announcements" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today saw the Chancellor of the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, set out the government’s Budget for 2021. The last year has been incredibly tough for individuals, families, businesses and the country as a whole, so it was critical that the Chancellor set out a budget which focused on protecting the jobs…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/2021-budget-key-announcements</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TORY UK BUDGET WILL WORSEN INEQUALITY IN WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/tory-uk-budget-will-worsen-inequality-in-west-dunbartonshire/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has responded to the UK Chancellor’s Spring Budget statement, warning that it fails to deliver the level of support needed to help hard-pressed families and businesses recover from the coronavirus crisis. The Westminster government has … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/tory-uk-budget-will-worsen-inequality-in-west-dunbartonshire/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/tory-uk-budget-will-worsen-inequality-in-west-dunbartonshire/">TORY UK BUDGET WILL WORSEN INEQUALITY IN WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1522302</id>
    <published>2021-03-04T08:39:24Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-04T08:39:24Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John sets out the reasons he supports the Chancellor&#8217;s Budget]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/03/03/john-sets-out-the-reasons-he-supports-the-chancellors-budget/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4700</id>
		<updated>2021-03-03T17:08:15Z</updated>
		<published>2021-03-03T17:08:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Local Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Regenerating Weston"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[John sets out the three main reasons he supports The Chancellor&#8217;s Budget&#8230;]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/03/03/john-sets-out-the-reasons-he-supports-the-chancellors-budget/"><![CDATA[
<p>John sets out the three main reasons he supports The Chancellor&#8217;s Budget&#8230;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="John Penrose reacts to the Chancellor&#039;s Budget" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GX-RDG9mYQc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
  <title>Failure to announce any new money for cancer treatment will cost thousands of lives – MP</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1395887/failure-to-announce-any-new-money-for-cancer-treatment-will-cost-thousands-of-lives-mp"/>
  <updated>2021-03-03T16:12:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1395887/failure-to-announce-any-new-money-for-cancer-treatment-will-cost-thousands-of-lives-mp</id>
  <summary type="text">Responding to the Chancellor's failure to announce any new investment for cancer services in today's Budget, South Lakes MP Tim Farron said: "I am astonished and horrified that this Budget does not contain a single penny for boosting cancer treatment and in fact the word 'cancer' isn't even mentioned at all in the entire Budget document.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Responding to the Chancellor's failure to announce any new investment for cancer services in today's Budget, South Lakes MP Tim Farron said<em>: "I am astonished and horrified that this Budget does not contain a single penny for boosting cancer treatment and in fact the word 'cancer' isn't even mentioned at all in the entire Budget document.</em></p>
<p><em>"Leading clinicians say this is the biggest cancer crisis in their lifetimes, with an enormous backlog of patients missing out on life-saving treatment.</em></p>
<p><em>"Our cross-party campaign has been meeting with ministers on an almost monthly basis and practically begging them to act but they clearly just aren't listening.</em></p>
<p><em>"As a result of the Government failing to listen and failing to invest in boosting treatment, we will unnecessarily lose tens of thousands of lives to this dreadful disease."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>£25m to be spent on projects the Staveley area</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/s4VxcvG7plo/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4779</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T16:08:25Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T16:08:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Budget 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/budget-2021" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Djanogly MP: Budget shows Government’s commitment to protecting jobs and livelihoods as we build our future economy. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/budget-2021" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5027 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T15:43:08Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T15:43:08Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Birmingham faces the biggest levelling up challenge in the UK</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/birmingham-faces-biggest-levelling-challenge-uk" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Today, the Chancellor of the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak MP, will have delivered his budget but we need to make sure that it is fair and doesn’t see Birmingham left behind. </p>
<p>Our city has enjoyed neither the prosperous Conservative cronyism of the south nor the solidarity of northern cities. Rather, the UK’s second city has its own identity, as the leading economy of the Midlands. But what does that mean in real terms?</p>
<p>When it comes to today’s budget, this puts us at great risk of being left behind by the Government’s levelling up agenda.</p>
<p>Last month, the Centre for Cities published its Cities Outlook 2021 which showed that Birmingham is the city facing the biggest levelling up challenge in the country. Following a decade of austerity and underinvestment compared to other regions, Birmingham went into this pandemic with weakened foundations that is now having a direct impact on families across the city. </p>
<p>Our city has since been hit disproportionately by Covid, with high infection rates and some of the highest hospital admissions in Europe, pinballing between varying degrees of restrictions, and forcing businesses to close. Our city now has one of the worst unemployment rates in the country, which Centre for Cities proposes would need to be reduced by 6.7% in order for Birmingham to be levelled up and put on an equal footing with the rest of the country.</p>
<p>Compounding these astonishing challenges, Birmingham has continually lost out under this Conservative government:</p>
<ul><li dir="ltr">
	The Conservative West Midlands Mayor, Andy Street’s own analysis shows that he has secured just 5% of the £3.2bn government investment for which the West Midlands Combined Authority bid.
	</li>
<li dir="ltr">
	The British Business Bank’s Future Fund for start-up funding has seen business in London receive nearly 29 times more than the West Midlands. 
	</li>
<li dir="ltr">
	Per capita, support for our culture sector from the Culture Recovery Fund is the lowest of any region in England.
	</li>
<li dir="ltr">
	West Midlands Police is penalised by the police allocation formula, and the promised 1,200 new officers will not make up the 2,200 lost in the preceding decade. Violent crime meanwhile has doubled in three years. 
	</li>
<li dir="ltr">
	Across my constituency of Edgbaston, when it comes to connectivity, 2% of premises do not even have 10mbps download speeds compared to the national average of 1.4%, with clusters of broadband blackspots in the most deprived areas like Bartley Green. Action on the digital divide has been pushed back time and again.
	</li>
<li dir="ltr">
	Despite promises that the Government would do “whatever it takes” to support councils, Birmingham City Council is now facing a £100m budget black hole.
	</li>
</ul><p>If you were to look at any of these points on a singular basis, it could be easy to disregard the city as occasionally missing out. However, that is why it is so important that we look at the levelling up agenda holistically. When you look at the bigger picture, it is blatantly clear how the Centre for Cities has such significant risks for our city.</p>
<p>This can’t go on, and we need the Government to make good on its promise to level up the left behind areas of our country. </p>
<p>We need investment in transport infrastructure; in training to get young people who have been so badly hit by this crisis back into education, or work as proposed in Labour’s Jobs Promise; and funding to create new jobs and attract investment in our city. </p>
<p>As Liam Byrne has laid out in detail, this should start with accelerating green investment in our region, as well as providing proper support to Birmingham’s vibrant cultural sector to ensure it is prepared to make the most of the opportunities afforded by the Commonwealth Games next year.</p>
<p>It is crucial that the National Infrastructure Bank, the Levelling Up Fund and UK Share Prosperity Fund have the financial clout to help places like Birmingham recover and rebuild following this crisis. </p>
<p>As the UK’s second city, Birmingham has the people, the expertise, the diversity and community resilience to bounce back from this crisis, but after years of underinvestment and now Covid, we need to see action, not more promises, from Conservative administrations on levelling up. </p>
<p>Today, we must see the start of a vision that meets the task of our times, unlocks opportunity for my constituents, and finally gives Birmingham and the West Midlands a fair share. </p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Standard (Image)</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/tom-w-EfenihYvjD8-unsplash_0.jpg" width="640" height="427" alt="Photo by Tom W on Unsplash"/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>919 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T15:02:27Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T15:02:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chancellor Announces a Freeport for Southampton</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/chancellor-announces-a-freeport-for-southampton/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It is excellent news that the Chancellor of the Exchequer announced today in his Budget that Southampton has been awarded freeport status. The Solent Freeport will cover sites across the region, including the Port of Southampton and Southampton Airport and will facilitate billions of investment and promises thousands of high quality jobs for the region [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/chancellor-announces-a-freeport-for-southampton/">Chancellor Announces a Freeport for Southampton</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3072</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T14:25:20Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T14:25:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP lobbies Minister for Schools hard to include Hornsea School in future rounds of funding for the School Rebuilding Programme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/03/graham-stuart-mp-lobbies-minister-for-schools-hard-to-include-hornsea-school-in-future-rounds-of-funding-for-the-school-rebuilding-programme/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/03/graham-stuart-mp-lobbies-minister-for-schools-hard-to-include-hornsea-school-in-future-rounds-of-funding-for-the-school-rebuilding-programme/meeting-with-headteacher-and-chair-of-govenors-at-hornsea-school-and-language-college-jan-21-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-11162"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-11162" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Meeting-with-Headteacher-and-Chair-of-Govenors-at-Hornsea-School-and-Language-College-Jan-21-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150"/></a></strong></p>
<p>Local MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, had a virtual catch up with Headteacher of Hornsea School and Language College (HSLC), Steve Ostler, and the Chair of Governors, Graham McDonald, after the Government confirmed all pupils were set to return to school on 8 March, as part of their roadmap for leaving lockdown.</p>
<p>Graham heard about the school’s plans to welcome pupils back in March, particularly their impressive testing regime, which they are aiming to have available daily, including weekends. Steve emphasised that 80% of the school community has opted in for the testing they are offering.</p>
<p>They also discussed the Government’s ten-year School Rebuilding Programme from which Steve is hoping to secure funding to upgrade existing buildings and for new buildings. On 5 February, the first 50 schools were confirmed for the first wave of funding. Unfortunately, HSLC was not included. Nonetheless, Graham is determined to lobby the Schools Minister to ensure HSLC is included in upcoming rounds. Graham will visit the school to see exactly what work needs to be done.</p>
<p>Graham Stuart said, “I am delighted to hear that Steve and his team are going above and beyond with their weekend testing plans for their school community, and I applaud their enthusiasm to welcome pupils back to school next week – I wish them every success.</p>
<p>“I know they are disappointed not to make the first round of funding for the School Rebuilding Programme, but I will continue to lobby the Minister to include them in future rounds of funding and I am looking forward to visiting the school very soon.”</p>
<p>Steve said, “I really appreciate Graham having a catch up with us so we could update him on our progress. We are really looking forward to welcoming the kids back next week – I think the quicker we get them back, the better for everyone concerned.</p>
<p>“Inevitably we are disappointed not to be included in the first round for the Rebuilding Programme, but I am thrilled that Graham will be coming to visit the school and I am grateful for the work he is putting in to help us secure funding.”</p>
<p>Graham McDonald said, “It was great to chat with Graham again and I am delighted he is keen to visit the school, so we can show him the work needs to be done.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, had a virtual catch up with Headteacher of Hornsea School and Language College (HSLC), Steve Ostler, and...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=11161</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T09:34:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T09:34:06Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="Covid-19"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Education"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Hornsea"/>
    <category term="Schools"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>30% of Folkestone &amp; Hythe vaccinated</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/30-of-folkestone-hythe-vaccinated/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">NHS data published on 26th February showed that over one third of residents in the Folkestone and Hythe district had received at least their first dose of the COVID-19 vaccine. This is above the national average, and the highest vaccination rate in Kent. I would like to thank everyone who has been involved in the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5596</id>
    <published>2021-03-03T06:29:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-03T06:29:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chancellor urged to use budget to tackle the ever widening divide between the South of England and the rest of the country</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/03/02/chancellor-urged-to-use-budget-to-tackle-the-ever-widening-divide-between-the-south-of-england-and-the-rest-of-the-country/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor has the opportunity in his budget to tackle some of the long standing economic and social issues that are holding back towns and cities across the Midlands and the North. He and his Party has spoken much of levelling up, but over the past decade of successive Conservative Governments, inequality across the country has risen and a number of long standing issues have been left unchecked.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; As Nottingham and the rest of the country looks to emerge from the Covid crisis it’s more important than ever that policy and action from the Government matches the rhetoric. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Covid effect on the UK has been significantly worse than all of our comparator nations, both in terms of the economic downturn and the Covid death rate. Covid has exposed significant wealth and health inequalities that are sadly more pronounced in the UK than most other developed nations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The UK Covid death rate per head of population has been one of the highest in the world &lt;a href="https://www.kingsfund.org.uk/press/press-releases/highest-rates-excess-deaths-in-the-world-ons-deaths-data-2020"&gt;https://www.kingsfund.org.uk/press/press-releases/highest-rates-excess-deaths-in-the-world-ons-deaths-data-2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The impact of Covid has been much more significant in more financially deprived communities and amongst black and other minority ethnic groups &lt;a href="https://www.nhsconfed.org/resources/2020/12/perspectives-from-the-front-line-disproportionate-impact-covid-19-bme-communities"&gt;https://www.nhsconfed.org/resources/2020/12/perspectives-from-the-front-line-disproportionate-impact-covid-19-bme-communities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The economic downturn in the UK has also been one of the most severe in the world. OECD statistics show that the UK has suffered the biggest economic decline of all major developed nations in recent reporting &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55143285"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-55143285&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The
Chancellor has an opportunity now to deal with some of the big structural
issues that have been damaging to the health and wealth of vast swathes of the
population for far too long. I’d urge the Chancellor to use his budget to begin
to deal with regional inequality, health inequality, skills inequality and
wealth inequality as well as investing in sustainability and environmental
projects. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My
key asks of the Chancellor:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make the £20 Universal Credit uplift permanent&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More investment in regional transport infrastructure. The East Midlands has the lowest transport infrastructure in the country at just £268 per head in 2019 compared to £903 per head in London. &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-50592261"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-50592261&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give a pay increase to Britain’s heroic key workers. Our front line key workers such as care workers, nurses, bin lorry crews and park rangers are the true heroes of the Covid crisis and they deserve much more than a pay freeze that will see their income reduce in real terms.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stop the vast majority of Council Tax increases that come from the Government’s adult social care precept by introducing a new, national funding formula for care services for the elderly. For many years Government has committed to introduce a new system of funding, but to date this hasn’t happened. The effect of the 3% adult social care precept is that council tax bills continue to rise at a time when many households are already struggling with their finances. &lt;a href="https://www.lgcplus.com/politics/lgc-briefing/councils-must-not-be-forgotten-in-the-council-funding-debate-16-02-2021/"&gt;https://www.lgcplus.com/politics/lgc-briefing/councils-must-not-be-forgotten-in-the-council-funding-debate-16-02-2021/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reform business rates urgently and extend the business rates holiday so that businesses have the ability to recover as Covid restrictions ease. For too long high street traders have been punished while online businesses are effectively incentivised unnecessarily. Right now retailers and hospitality businesses with buildings on our high streets in towns and city centres across the country are fighting for survival. The unfairness of the business rates system must be tackled to protect businesses and jobs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stop the cuts to council services that are happening across the country by honouring the pledge to refund councils in full for the costs of Covid. At this very moment Councils are having to balance their budgets for the next financial year whilst still in the midst of the pandemic and the social and economic consequences of it. Key workers are losing their jobs and essential local public services are under threat of cuts or closure because of the combination of reductions in Government funding over the past decade plus the significant unreimbursed costs of Covid. In Nottingham the unfunded Covid cost currently stands at £29million for this financial year alone.  With Councils legally obliged to set balanced budgets with no deficit each and every year there is no way out of service and job cuts without Government support and right now is the worst possible time to inflict further damage to local communities. &lt;a href="https://www.local.gov.uk/ps10-billion-spending-review-investment-needed-protect-and-improve-local-services"&gt;https://www.local.gov.uk/ps10-billion-spending-review-investment-needed-protect-and-improve-local-services&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The
Chancellor has the ability to tackle many of these long standing issues in his
budget. There are huge opportunities post Covid, but the Chancellor must act to
reform the policies that hold far too many communities back. I know that many
people will be watching closely to see if he does. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sam Webster, &lt;br&gt;Portfolio Holder for Finance at Nottingham City Council &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/03/02/chancellor-urged-to-use-budget-to-tackle-the-ever-widening-divide-between-the-south-of-england-and-the-rest-of-the-country/"&gt;Chancellor urged to use budget to tackle the ever widening divide between the South of England and the rest of the country&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Chancellor has the opportunity in his budget to tackle some of the long standing economic and social issues that are holding back towns and cities across the Midlands and the North. He and his Party has spoken much of levelling up, but over the past decade of successive Conservative Governments, inequality across the country...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/03/02/chancellor-urged-to-use-budget-to-tackle-the-ever-widening-divide-between-the-south-of-england-and-the-rest-of-the-country/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/03/02/chancellor-urged-to-use-budget-to-tackle-the-ever-widening-divide-between-the-south-of-england-and-the-rest-of-the-country/">Chancellor urged to use budget to tackle the ever widening divide between the South of England and the rest of the country</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2638</id>
    <published>2021-03-02T18:37:07Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T18:37:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Conwy and Llandudno Junction - Your Health </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/conwy-and-llandudno-junction-your-health" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Helo
Mae'r Bwrdd Iechyd mewn partneriaeth â Chyngor Bwrdeistref Sir Conwy a Chymorth Gwirfoddol a Chymunedol Conwy yn ystyried pa fath o wasanaethau iechyd a lles fydd pobl sy'n byw yng Nghonwy a Chyffordd Llandudno a'r cyffiniau ei angen yn y dyfodol.   Rydym eisiau gwybod am y gwasanaethau yr…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/conwy-and-llandudno-junction-your-health</id>
    <published>2021-03-02T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RELEASE: Drew Hendry MP &amp; Jason Isaacs Support Marie Curie ‘s 35th Great Daffodil Appeal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-drew-hendry-mp-jason-isaacs-support-marie-curie-s-35th-great-daffodil-appeal/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=release-drew-hendry-mp-jason-isaacs-support-marie-curie-s-35th-great-daffodil-appeal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Drew Hendry MP, Chair of the UK Government All-Party Parliamentary Group for Terminal Illness, and Harry Potter actor, Jason Isaacs, have joined forces to support end of life charity Marie Curie provide care and support to more people living with a terminal illness.</p>
<p>Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch &amp; Strathspey MP Drew Hendry and Marie Curie Ambassador Jason Isaacs, are backing the Great Daffodil Appeal, Marie Curie’s biggest annual fundraising campaign held every March. The campaign, which reached its 35<sup>th</sup> anniversary in March, has for the first time, had to cancel all of the public collections, leaving the charity with a potential loss of over £3 million.</p>
<p>The last 12 months have been extremely difficult as key fundraising events have been cancelled and all Marie Curie’s charity shops have had to close. Last year, the charity saw a 16.5% rise in the number of people they cared for at end of life, compared to 2019 and their support line saw a 20% increase in calls too.</p>
<p>Drew has pledged his support to the Great Daffodil Appeal and is encouraging constituents in Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch &amp; Strathspey to donate and wear one of the charity’s daffodil pins to help fund vital care and support for people living with a terminal illness, and their families, in a year where Marie Curie have been on the frontline providing care to people dying both with and without coronavirus.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mr Hendry said:</p>
<p>“I am delighted to support Marie Curie’s Great Daffodil Appeal this March. I work closely with Marie Curie as part of my ongoing work as Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group for Terminal Illness and the work they do to support people at the end of their lives, and their families, is remarkable.</p>
<p>“Every five minutes, someone in the UK dies without getting the care and support they need at the end of their life, and this last year has been a stark reminder to us all of just how valuable end of life care and support is, that’s why I’m supporting this appeal and asking my constituents to do the same.”</p>
<p>Jason, who became a Marie Curie Ambassador in 2018, said:</p>
<p>“Marie Curie does amazing things, and when people don’t have the family members around, they provide love. Towards the end of life, they help the end to be as serene and beautiful and loving as it can be. The work Marie Curie do is needed now more than ever as the Covid-19 pandemic has had a big impact on their ability to fundraise.</p>
<p>“So, I’m here to support them and the Great Daffodil Appeal and encourage everyone to wear their daffodil or join in fundraising any way they can as every donation means that when the time comes, Marie Curie can be there for people and their loved ones when they need it most.  For anyone who chooses to support them too, you’re supporting a really wonderful charity.”</p>
<p>Ruth Driscoll, Head of Policy and Public Affairs at Marie Curie, said:</p>
<p>“Having the support of Drew and Jason makes a huge difference to our Great Daffodil Appeal, which we need people to support more than ever this year.</p>
<p>“Over the past year, our nurses, doctors and other staff have been on the frontline providing care for people dying both with and without coronavirus. But still too many people miss out on the care and support they need at the end of life.</p>
<p>“By donating and wearing a daffodil pin in March you are helping us to support more people at the most difficult time of their lives. We want to make sure that everyone affected by terminal illness, wherever they may live, gets the right support, at the right time – whether that is high quality nursing care, emotional and practical support, or fast access to the benefits they need.”</p>
<p>During the Great Daffodil Appeal the first annual National Day of Reflection will take place. Since the first lockdown began in 2020, millions of people have been bereaved. Join Marie Curie on 23 March, the first anniversary of UK lockdown, for a day to reflect and commemorate this tragic loss of life.</p>
<p>For more information on how to fundraise, donate or set up a virtual collection for Marie Curie’s Great Daffodil Appeal visit: <a href="http://www.mariecurie.org.uk/daffodil">www.mariecurie.org.uk/daffodil</a></p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/">www.drewhendrymp.scot </a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com/">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-drew-hendry-mp-jason-isaacs-support-marie-curie-s-35th-great-daffodil-appeal/">RELEASE: Drew Hendry MP &amp; Jason Isaacs Support Marie Curie ‘s 35th Great Daffodil Appeal</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Drew Hendry MP, Chair of the UK Government All-Party Parliamentary Group for Terminal Illness, and...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-drew-hendry-mp-jason-isaacs-support-marie-curie-s-35th-great-daffodil-appeal/">RELEASE: Drew Hendry MP &amp; Jason Isaacs Support Marie Curie ‘s 35th Great Daffodil Appeal</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5993</id>
    <published>2021-03-02T11:24:44Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T11:24:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Welfare"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;A year on from the start of the pandemic, Judith is joining Alzheimer’s Society, TIDE, Dementia UK and John’s Campaign to remember the tens of thousands of people with dementia whose lives have been lost to Covid and to call for lasting change this Coronavirus Action Day. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith has written about the need for a national rehabilitation strategy to support people with dementia to recover as we leave lockdown&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labourlist.org/2021/03/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/?fbclid=IwAR0jW7qJ52UrmRgHs5nd0XHOgXNK2nLSzVWnbdxSRwHcquLAK5pyfemd2J4"&gt;You can read the full article here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/column-failure-on-vaccine-rollout-is-not-an-option/" title="Column: Failure on vaccine rollout is not an option"&gt;Column: Failure on vaccine rollout is not an option&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;92&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In this week's Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus, Judith speaks on the importance of getting the coronavirus vaccination programme right, and calls on the Government to do more to support people with the economic effects of the pandemic.  You can read here article by clicking here to go the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: article, read, pandemic, people, support, coronavirus, judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;92&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, day, lockdown, people, support, call, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-step-up-with-clear-plan-for-national-economic-recovery/" title="Government must step up with clear plan for national economic recovery"&gt;Government must step up with clear plan for national economic recovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-step-up-with-clear-plan-for-national-economic-recovery/" title="Government must step up with clear plan for national economic recovery"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Government must step up with clear plan for national economic recovery" alt="Government must step up with clear plan for national economic recovery" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In this week's Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus MP's column, Judith speaks about the importance of a strong plan for post-covid economic recovery and the vital importance of apprenticeships. You can read the full article on the T&amp;amp;A website by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: article, full, read, judith, national, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, dementia, people, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-plan-to-vaccinate-key-workers/" title="Judith calls for plan to vaccinate key workers"&gt;Judith calls for plan to vaccinate key workers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;90&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has called on the Prime Minister during a House of Commons statement to set out a plan to vaccinate key workers - including teachers, police officers, and shop workers - after the most vulnerable groups have been reached. You can read the full story in the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, full, read, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A year on from the start of the pandemic, Judith is joining Alzheimer’s Society, TIDE, Dementia UK and John’s Campaign to remember the tens of thousands of people with dementia whose lives have been lost to Covid and to call for lasting change this Coronavirus Action Day. Judith has written about the need for a […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2470</id>
    <published>2021-03-02T09:40:02Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-02T09:40:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Press release:- Newcastle MP demands the Chancellor use the budget to close gaps in support.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2021/03/press-release-newcastle-mp-demands-the-chancellor-use-the-budget-to-close-gaps-in-support/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ahead of Wednesdays budget Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah has written to the Chancellor Rishi Sunak to demand action over those excluded from covid-19 support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 13th Chi held a digital town hall in Newcastle Central for businesses and constituents who have not been able to access the support they needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chi said “&lt;em&gt;At my town hall I heard from a Newcastle business that had been forced into administration and others that received no support since the pandemic began. Millions of people have been excluded from all support during the pandemic with thousands in my constituency alone. People are being left behind through no fault of their own, and viable businesses are going under because of government inaction. Exclusion from support is having a significant impact on the mental health of so many people and their families, it is also damaging to the local economy. On February 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; I wrote to the Chancellor to share the real life experiences of my constituents, but I am yet to receive a response. Rishi Sunak must take the opportunity of the budget to close gaps in support or risk losing more businesses.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="10862" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2021/03/press-release-newcastle-mp-demands-the-chancellor-use-the-budget-to-close-gaps-in-support/excluded-town-hall/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?fit=1762%2C991&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1762,991" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="excluded town hall" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?fit=300%2C169&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?fit=700%2C394&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10862" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?resize=700%2C394&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="394" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?w=1762&amp;amp;ssl=1 1762w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?resize=300%2C169&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?resize=1024%2C576&amp;amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?resize=768%2C432&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?resize=1536%2C864&amp;amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/excluded-town-hall.jpg?w=1400&amp;amp;ssl=1 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes for editors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Chi’s letter to Rishi Sunak: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Rishi,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday the 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February I held a digital town hall meeting for individuals and businesses in Newcastle Central that have been excluded from covid support. At this meeting I heard about the significant impact that exclusion has had on my constituents and the significant gaps that remain in the Government’s support package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The town hall raised a number of questions for yourself. I am writing to you to request answers for my constituents to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of Covid 19 support for the coach sector has forced a coach business in my constituency into insolvency. The owner and director is now concerned about the impact this insolvency will have on his position as a director at another firm. Can you reassure him that his position at his other firm will not be impacted by this insolvency?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like many businesspeople across the country the director of a rail travel firm in my constituency has been forced to take out thousands of pounds of loans secured against personal assets to ensure the survival of the business. These directors need to know what support and reassurances you will offer them with regards to their personal liabilities?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A takeaway sandwich business in my constituency, dependent on the footfall from local school children, does not have a business bank account, because of this they have been excluded from the bounce back loan scheme. What steps are you taking to help those in this situation gain access to the bounce back loan scheme?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The funding provided to local authorities such as Newcastle City Council is described as discretionary but local authorities do not have full discretion over how it is awarded. For example, some grants are only accessible by businesses forced to close. Will you make more funding available which can be accessed by all businesses impacted by the pandemic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A public sector employee whose job was impacted by Covid19 was made redundant and told that furlough was not an option in the public sector. What alternative provisions are there to support public sector employees?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March 2020 you stated that the Government will do ‘whatever it takes’ to help UK workers and businesses. However, I am concerned that a year later there are still people and businesses in my constituency that do not have access to the support that they need. I look forward to receiving your answers to my questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the best,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chi Onwurah                                                                                 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Labour MP for Newcastle upon Tyne Central&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Minister for Digital&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, Science and Technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Ahead of Wednesdays budget Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah has written to the Chancellor Rishi Sunak to demand action over those excluded from covid-19 support. On February 13th Chi held a digital town hall in Newcastle Central for businesses and… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10861</id>
    <published>2021-03-01T16:19:47Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-01T16:19:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Situation Report on Covid-19 Vaccinations Locally</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/situation-report-covid-19-vaccinations-locally" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I know everyone will be as thrilled I am that finally we have a credible route out of this ghastly lockdown. After this truly dreadful year, every citizen of this country yearns for this to be the lockdown finale. With that in mind, I was very encouraged by the roadmap set out by the Prime Minister…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/situation-report-covid-19-vaccinations-locally</id>
    <published>2021-03-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>February 2021 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/february-2021-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;div class="wp-block-image"&gt;&lt;figure class="aligncenter size-medium"&gt;&lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/25f5c9e9bc42/tulip-siddiq-mp-february-2021-enewsletter"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" width="300" height="157" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-300x157.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5408" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-300x157.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-1024x536.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-768x402.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-105x55.png 105w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-669x350.png 669w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter-630x330.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Newsletter.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center has-medium-font-size"&gt;&lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/25f5c9e9bc42/tulip-siddiq-mp-february-2021-enewsletter"&gt;Click here to read my February 2021 Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In my newsletter, you will find information about the work I’ve been doing this month as Member of Parliament for Hampstead and Kiburn and Labour’s Shadow Minister for Children and Early Years:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Encouraging take up of the vaccine&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;End the cladding scandal&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less than two weeks left to bring Nazanin home&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Holocaust&amp;nbsp;Memorial Day&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;LGBT+ Labour event on adoption rights&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thumbs Up For Early Years&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Meeting with special school headteachers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Local community support&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to read my February 2021 Newsletter In my newsletter, you will find information about the work I’ve been doing this month as Member of Parliament for Hampstead and Kiburn and Labour’s Shadow Minister for Children and Early Years: Encouraging take up of the vaccine End the cladding scandal […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5407</id>
    <published>2021-02-26T19:17:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-26T19:17:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="February"/>
    <category term="update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP tables EDM on Myanmar Coup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_tables_edm_on_myanmar_coup" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On 24 February, Rushanara Ali MP tabled a Parliamentary Early Day Motion (EDM) on the current political and security situation in Myanmar</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_tables_edm_on_myanmar_coup</id>
    <published>2021-02-25T18:09:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T18:09:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 General Debate 22/02/2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/02/25/lockdown-easing/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This week I took part in the Parliamentary debate on COVID-19, following the Prime Minister&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;roadmap out of lockdown&amp;#8217; announcement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I opened by paying tribute to all those involved in delivering the vaccine across the 4 nations of the UK, including healthcare staff, volunteers and the armed forces. At the time of my contribution, 1,445,488 first doses of the vaccine had been administered in Scotland alone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Public Health Scotland&amp;#8217;s initial data shows a vaccine effectiveness rate of between 84% and 94% in reducing Covid-related hospitalisations; welcome news indeed. However, we must still proceed cautiously and do everything we can do suppress the virus as moving too fast simply risks it remaining in circulation and mutating into new, vaccine resistant strains.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I was, therefore, concerned when the PM, despite promising to focus on &amp;#8216;data rather than dates&amp;#8217;, nonetheless proceeded to announce a long list of dates whereby they hope to lift various restrictions, and still without ensuring certain basic measures are in place, including the provision of an effective &amp;#8216;test, trace, isolate and SUPPORT&amp;#8217; system as lockdown restrictions are eased and tightening travel restrictions for those coming into the UK.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The idea that you either choose public health or you choose the economy is a false dichotomy as we know from other countries which have successfully followed elimination strategies that acting quickly and stringently with Covid allows for the safe re-opening of more economic sectors at earlier stages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the debate here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ww-Fvwx_zcc"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ww-Fvwx_zcc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="22/02 Covid Debate" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ww-Fvwx_zcc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h3&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford MP&lt;/h3&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we move into the second year of covid, and despite still being in lockdown, there are key positives to be celebrated. The vaccine roll-out is progressing quickly, and staff in all four national health services should be congratulated, along with the Army, who have provided logistical expertise, and the thousands of volunteers who have helped to ensure the safety and organisation of vaccination centres. Vaccine uptake has been way above expectations and, with the hope that vaccination will prevent viral transmission as well as protecting the recipient, everyone who rolls up their sleeve is contributing to the fight against the pandemic. However, concerns remain about lower vaccine uptake among certain groups, including some who are particularly vulnerable to covid, such as BAME communities. Anyone offered the vaccine should take up their appointment. If they have questions, there is information on the NHS websites, or they can ask their local GP practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until now, any increase in covid cases has led to an inevitable rise in hospitalisation and deaths just a few weeks later, but as more vulnerable groups are vaccinated, that is starting to change. We are already seeing the benefit to those who were vaccinated first in Scotland. An analysis of over 1 million vaccine recipients by Public Health Scotland has today revealed a reduction in hospitalisation of between 85% and 94% for the two vaccines. Owing to its integrated structure, Scotland’s NHS was able to get permission from the Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency to deliver the Pfizer vaccine to all elderly care homes from 13 December. That has led to a 62% drop in deaths among residents throughout January. That dramatic fall will, we hope, be replicated in data across the rest of the UK in just the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Prime Minister has highlighted, one possible threat to the success of the vaccination programme would be the importation of a more vaccine-resistant variant, such as that which has arisen in South Africa and has already been shown to be resistant to antibodies from those who have recovered from covid. This threat makes it inexplicable that when the UK Government have finally decided to set up monitored border quarantine, it is on such a limited basis—so much for following the science! There should be mandatory quarantine for arrivals from all countries, as there is nothing to prevent someone from travelling from South Africa or Brazil via a third country. The South African variant is already present in at least 35 other countries and new variants could be evolving as we speak. The Government’s suggestion that people will be able to travel abroad for summer holidays seems to be courting danger, as many countries will not be vaccinated and therefore pose an increased risk that holidaymakers would bring back new variants; surely this is a sacrifice we could all accept if it allowed children to be in school and our domestic economy to open up. This measure must, however, be combined with support for the aviation, aerospace and international tourism sectors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Prime Minister’s road map out of lockdown, I welcomed the suggestion that decisions that would be based on data rather than dates, but he then proceeded to announce a whole list of dates. Although it is good to see cases falling so dramatically across the UK, from almost 60,000 a day to just over 11,000 a day, case levels are still more than double what they were when SAGE&amp;nbsp;called for a lockdown on 21 September. The number of covid patients in hospital is 10 times what it was last September and only just dropped below the peak of the first wave last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Scotland has maintained lower case levels throughout the second and third waves, progress in all four nations is slowing, and this is thought to be due to the greater infectiousness of the B117 Kent variant. Thankfully, this variant appears to be just as sensitive to the immune response induced by current vaccines, but every time the virus spreads and replicates itself, there is an opportunity for mutation and the risk of a problematic domestic variant emerging, including one that might be resistant to our current vaccines. The UK has already faced three waves of covid and three lockdowns, and it is important that current restrictions remain until case levels have been driven low enough to give the vaccine programme a chance to succeed and health services time to recover. It is not a matter of setting the economy against public health; it is through stopping community spread that we would be able to get our domestic economy and society back up and running.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once covid levels have been brought down, it is critical to have an effective system to test, trace and isolate those who could be carrying the virus, in order to keep control of the outbreak. Unfortunately, one in eight cases are still not being reached by NHS Test and Trace, and surveys suggest that as few as one in three people are isolating when required. The commonest reason is that they cannot afford to lose their income, yet more than half of those applying for the Government’s support payment are being turned down, which makes it very unlikely that they would then isolate. The Government need to widen the eligibility criteria and review the level of payment, which is less than the minimum wage. It is in everyone’s interest to ensure that those who could be carrying the virus isolate so we avoid onward spread. All these measures carry a cost, but when we see the flourishing domestic economies of the countries that acted quickly and stringently last year, we can see the cost of not taking action, both in lives and in economic damage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;amp;linkname=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;amp;linkname=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;amp;linkname=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;amp;linkname=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;amp;linkname=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F02%2F25%2Flockdown-easing%2F&amp;#038;title=COVID-19%20General%20Debate%2022%2F02%2F2021" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/02/25/lockdown-easing/" data-a2a-title="COVID-19 General Debate 22/02/2021"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/02/25/lockdown-easing/"&gt;COVID-19 General Debate 22/02/2021&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week I took part in the Parliamentary debate on COVID-19, following the Prime Minister’s ... <a title="COVID-19 General Debate 22/02/2021" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/02/25/lockdown-easing/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/02/25/lockdown-easing/">COVID-19 General Debate 22/02/2021</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2084</id>
    <published>2021-02-25T11:28:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-25T11:28:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Health, Wellbeing, &amp; Social Justice"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="Covid-Variant"/>
    <category term="Lockdown"/>
    <category term="Quarantine"/>
    <category term="Test-Trace-Isolate-Support"/>
    <category term="Travel Restrictions"/>
    <category term="Vaccines for All"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett backs PM’s roadmap and highlights support for businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-pms-roadmap-and-highlights-support-businesses" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Vice Chairman of the Conservative Party, spoke virtually in the House of Commons debate yesterday (23 February) on Supporting Businesses and Individuals.
Sir David began his speech by welcoming the roadmap that will guide us cautiously…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-pms-roadmap-and-highlights-support-businesses</id>
    <published>2021-02-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Five years on: The health effects of the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Act on Children and Disabled People</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/five-years-on-the-health-effects-of-the-2016-welfare-reform-and-work-act-on-children-and-disabled-people/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Health in All Policies APPG launch inquiry report on <span style="color:#06396a;">the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Act</span></h3></div><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>A new report by a cross party group of MPs as part of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Health in All Policies which I Chair has concluded that, five years on, the effect of the <a href="https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2016/7/contents/enacted">Welfare Reform &amp; Work Act 2016</a> has been ‘devastating’ to the health and wellbeing of people on low incomes.</p>
<p>The report which was launched today <a href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/210221_HIAP-A4-Report-Debbie-Abrahams.pdf"> can be read here.</a></p>
<p>This<a href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/210221_HIAP-A4-Report-Debbie-Abrahams.pdf"> report</a> shows there is strong evidence from several sources that the cuts in social security support have contributed to increasing poverty and financial hardship in low income households which has particularly affected the poverty levels of children and disabled people.</p>
<p>The analysis has found overwhelming evidence showing how the Act has pushed many low income households into poverty and financial hardship, disproportionately affecting children and disabled people. The report describes the strong evidence showing the adverse causal relationship that this poverty has had on the health and well-being of those affected, particularly children, with every 1% increase in child poverty associated with an extra 5.8 infant deaths per 100,000 and a third of the increases in infant mortality between 2014 and 2017 attributed to rising poverty.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/210221_HIAP-A4-Report-Debbie-Abrahams.pdf">report</a> also reveals how the treatment of those people reliant on social security by the Department for Work and Pensions often leaves them feeling worthless and even ‘dehumanised’.</p>
<p>Looking at 5 specific measures within the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Act – the benefit cap, the benefit freeze, the two child limit, the abolition of £30 a week support for disabled people who were unfit for work (ESA WRAG) and the extension of sanctions to ‘responsible carers’ (parents of pre-nursery age children) – the APPG inquiry sought to identify the impacts of  these specific measures on household income and the impact that this may have on the behaviour and health of claimants and their families in the context of the 2012 social security cuts, and other wider ranging tax and public service changes.</p>
<p>The APPG also looked at the Government’s objectives for the 2016 Act to see how effective the measures had been in achieving these objectives and has made 16 recommendations including</p>
<ul>
<li>Making the social safety net sufficient for people not in full-time work to receive a minimum income for healthy living</li>
<li>Making permanent the £1,000-a-year increase in the standard allowance for Universal Credit</li>
<li>Removing sanctions and reduce conditionalities in benefit payments</li>
<li>Eradicating benefit caps and lifting the two-child limit</li>
<li>Providing tapering levels of benefits to avoid cliff edges</li>
<li>Ending the five-week wait for Universal Credit and providing cash grants for low-income households</li>
<li>Giving sufficient Government support to food aid providers and charities.</li>
</ul>
<p>In 2015 we looked at the <em>potential</em> impacts of the Welfare Reform and Work Bill on child poverty and health, and we wanted to compare these with the <em>actual</em> impacts. Again the focus was on the relationship between poverty, inequality and health, and in particular child health. (Read the APPG’s earlier report <a href="https://www.fph.org.uk/media/1374/appg-health-in-all-policies-inquiry-into-child-poverty-and-health2.pdf"><strong>here</strong></a>.)</p>
<p>Five years on, we have conducted a follow-up review of the actual impacts of the Welfare Reform and Work Act 2016.</p>
<p>There is a growing evidence base of the direct and negative impacts of different aspects of the social security system on the mental and physical health of claimants and their families, in addition to the indirect impacts mediated by poverty as a result of having inadequate income from work and/or social security support.</p>
<p>In addition to quantitative evidence we looked at qualitative studies which pointed to a process of ‘dehumanising’ claimants that eroded their self-esteem and confidence, making them feel worthless. In some cases, the whole experience had proved too much for some claimants and they have taken their own lives.</p>
<p>It’s important to note the knock-on impact that this ill health will have on health services and for social protection to be recognised as mitigating against socio-economic health risk factors.</p>
<p>Although the Government achieved their aim of cutting welfare spending by introducing these measures – working age spending on social security has shrunk by £34bn since 2010 – there has been minimal impact on helping to get people into work who wouldn’t have got into work without these measures.”</p>
<p><a href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/210221_HIAP-A4-Report-Debbie-Abrahams.pdf">The full report</a> was launched with a panel of speakers to discuss the findings and recommendations of the report including:</p>
<p>Professor Clare Bambra, University of Newcastle</p>
<p>Helen Barnard, Joseph Rowntree Foundation</p>
<p>Ellen Clifford, Disabled People Against Cuts</p>
<p>Professor David Taylor Robinson, University of Liverpool</p>
<p>Geoff Fimister, Disability Benefits Consortium</p>
<p>‘Aurora’ (not her real name) – a widowed parent of two children</p>
<p><strong>‘Aurora’</strong> said: “Our situation has been greatly impacted by the changes to the benefits system. We can no longer afford the essentials to ensure even a basic standard of living. After rent and deductions are paid there is nothing left. I do not feel supported by the DWP, and I feel our group have been ignored. The pandemic highlights a desperate requirement for reform.</p>
<p>“We need help to participate and become productive members of society. It is our children who invariably suffer, poverty has lasting effects, they bare the consequences of these policies.”</p>
<p><strong>Helen Barnard, JRF Director</strong>, said: “In the last year, millions more people have turned to social security to help them stay afloat during the pandemic. The importance of a strong social security system to act as an anchor for all of us, preventing us being swept into poverty by unexpected events, illness or job loss has never been clearer.  This APPG report demonstrates starkly the damage done to individuals, families and communities by weakening social security.</p>
<p>As we look forward to the easing of the public health emergency, we must learn the lessons of the pandemic and of previous recessions and ensure that social security is strengthened. There is a long way to go before the economic storm passes; the government must live up to the promise of bringing us through that storm safely, starting by keeping the £20 uplift to Universal Credit and extending it to those on legacy benefits who have been unjustly excluded from additional support so far.</p>
<p><strong>Professor David Taylor-Robinson, University of Liverpool</strong>, said: “Even before covid-19, extremely disturbing trends in health were emerging in England. Growing child poverty, homelessness, and food poverty led to an unprecedented rise in infant mortality, mental health problems, and stalling life expectancy, especially for women in the poorest areas and cities. These were the same areas where 10 years of austerity measures had hit the poorest groups the hardest.</p>
<p>“The APPG report shows how reductions in social security for families with children have hit the most vulnerable communities. In addition larger cuts in government funding to local authorities with higher proportions of children in poverty have meant a reduction in spending on vital preventive services in areas where they were needed most.</p>
<p>“We know that rising child poverty has myriad adverse impacts on multiple aspects of child health and development that will have repercussions for decades to come. It is time for the government to reverse these extremely concerning trends, establishing a welfare system that protects children from poverty and material deprivation.”</p>
<p><strong>Geoff Fimister, Policy Co-Chair, Disability Benefits Consortium</strong>, said: “As the economic fallout from the Covid crisis threatens to make life even tougher for disabled people, in or out of work – and as the Chancellor prepares his Budget and the Government proposes to announce details of its disability strategy later this year – this important report could hardly be more timely. It sets out clearly the impacts of austerity on disabled people and the measures needed to set a new direction and start to put things right.</p>
<p>The Disability Benefits Consortium is a network of more than 100 organisations concerned with achieving real social security for disabled people. We gave evidence to this inquiry – based on our research and on feedback from our members – and are very pleased to see such clear and well-founded analysis and  recommendations. We hope that the Government will take notice.”</p>
<p><strong>Professor Clare Bambra of Newcastle University</strong> commented: “Our results show the importance to protecting people’s mental health of adequate social safety nets. This is particularly relevant now as the lock down and the COVID-19 pandemic is already leading to deteriorations in people’s mental health. Our research suggests that the current increase to Universal Credit of £20 per week should be maintained in order to protect the mental health of the most vulnerable in our society.”</p>
<p><strong>Ellen Clifford, </strong><strong>Disabled People Against Cuts</strong>, said: “I very much welcome the report launched today. Since 2010, extensive work has been undertaken by Disabled People’s Organisations, charities, academics and journalists to investigate, document and research the disproportionate impacts of welfare reform measures on those with the lowest incomes in society including disabled people. Interrogating and reflecting upon that wide evidence-base, the APPG has produced a stark report that succeeds in cutting through the spin and selective use of figures to present a hard-hitting portrait of Britain today. We are the sixth richest country in the world and yet infant mortality is rising and life expectancy declining. The Resolution Foundation calculated that by 2022, the total annual savings in spending for working age social security claimants from 2010 would be £34billion.</p>
<p>“In December 2020, the Marmot Review and analysis into the UK’s “high and unequal” Covid-19 death toll exposed key causes of this as existing poverty and inequalities driven by 10 years of austerity including social security cuts. Even after the £20 per week Universal Credit uplift, benefit claimants are receiving just 43.4% of the minimum income standard (MIS), which is the amount required for an acceptable standard of living. For those still on legacy benefits who have never been granted an uplift, their incomes are just 33.9% of the MIS. Many of these are disabled people, many have been shielding for over a year now and have seen their expenditures rise sharply as a result. The Disability Benefits Consortium recently published findings showing that 66% of disabled people on legacy benefits surveyed are having to choose between eating or heating.</p>
<p>“The news that the Universal credit uplift is set to continue for a further six months is welcome, but we need to urgently pressure the government into extending the uplift to legacy benefits. There is no question that the failure to do so has been detrimental to disabled people’s health and I echo the report recommendation calling for research into the long-term health effects of different social security levels to be carried out by the Department for Work and Pensions in conjunction with the Department for Health and Social Care. Ultimately what we need is a new social security system, one that provides a genuine safety net for all and that guarantees a decent standard of living. Only then will we begin to see a reversal of the regressive health and inequality trends of the past decade.”</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/five-years-on-the-health-effects-of-the-2016-welfare-reform-and-work-act-on-children-and-disabled-people/">Five years on: The health effects of the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Act on Children and Disabled People</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/five-years-on-the-health-effects-of-the-2016-welfare-reform-and-work-act-on-children-and-disabled-people/">Five years on: The health effects of the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Act on Children and Disabled People</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6752</id>
    <published>2021-02-22T14:42:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-22T14:42:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Events"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Speeches"/>
    <category term="Children"/>
    <category term="Disabled People"/>
    <category term="Poverty"/>
    <category term="Reform Act"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Croydon Covid-19 Vaccine Update and FAQs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/02/19/croydon-covid-vaccine-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
		&lt;div class=" vc_custom_1613906773647"&gt;

&lt;div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- "&gt;

	
	&lt;p&gt;The vaccination programme is expanding across South West London and there are now over 238,000 vaccines across 40 vaccination centres, including 25 GP led centres, 8 hospital hubs, 4 pharmacy-led services and 3 large vaccination centres. With over 70% of vaccines delivered at primary care sites GPs have been leading the way in vaccinating local people to make sure vaccines are offered to all over 70s and front-line health and care staff by Monday 15 February 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone aged 70 and over who hasn’t  yet had an invitation for a vaccination is being asked to come forward and contact the NHS to book a jab through the national booking service&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/5Bo9CMw3pC82rVDIkA4pC?domain=nhs.uk"&gt;www.nhs.uk/covid-vaccination&lt;/a&gt; or by calling 119 free of charge between 7am and 11pm seven days a week. The national booking service allows people to book an appointment at their nearest large vaccination centre or pharmacy service. If a suitable and convenient slot is not available people can also call their GP practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FAQs about the vaccine and booking an appointment from NHS South West London Clinical Commissioning Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am confused about my second dose of the vaccine. Can you explain this to me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both vaccines have been authorised on the basis of two doses because the evidence from the clinical trials shows that this gives the maximum level of protection.  To ensure as many people are vaccinated as quickly as possible, the Department for Health and Social Care now advise that the second dose of both the Oxford/AstraZeneca and the Pfizer/BioNtech vaccine should be scheduled up to 12 weeks apart.  The evidence doesn’t show any risk to not having the second dose other than not being as protected as you otherwise would be.  Please be reassured that there are no safety concerns in the new guidance, and it will not impact on how effective the vaccination is in protecting you from Covid-19 once the course is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not need to do anything to arrange your second dose. The NHS will contact you with your appointment details. Wait to be contacted. The second dose completes the course and is likely to be important for longer-term protection. It&amp;#8217;s important to get both doses to protect yourself against coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have a second appointment booked already and you should have a record card with details of your next appointment written on it, this will be around 12 weeks after your first appointment and at the same location where you received your first dose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happens if I am over 70 and haven’t been contacted by my GP?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now the NHS has asked people to wait until they are contacted to help ensure that those who are most vulnerable are protected first- and that remains the case for most people. However, whilst we have now vaccinated well over 84% of over 70s, to ensure absolutely everyone is offered the vaccine, people aged 70 and over can now contact the NHS so they can be vaccinated by the middle of this month. The easiest way to arrange a vaccination is through the national booking services which can be accessed at &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/NJuaCNL3qixZW5JFjbh0z?domain=nhs"&gt;www.nhs.uk/covid-vaccination.&lt;/a&gt; If you are unable to book online can call 119 free of charge, anytime between 7am and 11pm seven days a week. The national booking service allows people to arrange a vaccination at their nearest vaccination centre or pharmacy service. If a suitable and convenient slot is not available people can also call their GP practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are the COVID-19 vaccines safe for people with long term conditions?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccines will be approved if it is considered safe for people with long-term conditions.  These vaccines are safe and effective for the vast majority of people – they have been tested on tens of thousands of people and assessed by experts. Your GP can advise on when you are eligible and will contact you with an appointment when it’s your turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A very small number of people who are at risk of COVID-19 cannot have the vaccine – this includes people who have severe allergies. Everybody will also be screened for potential allergic reactions before getting vaccinated. All vaccinators will have the training they need to deal with any rare cases of adverse reactions, and all venues will be equipped to care for people who need it – just like with any other vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MHRA have updated their guidance to say that pregnant women and those who are breastfeeding can have the vaccine but should discuss it with a clinician to ensure that the benefits outweigh any potential risks. Women of childbearing age, those who are pregnant, or breastfeeding should read the &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/JXEECP73vFm0wA9t6dSaW?domain=nhs.uk/"&gt;detailed information available on NHS.UK&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I need to do before I get my vaccine?  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHS will contact you and invite you to book a vaccine appointment when it’s your turn. You may receive a phone call, letter or text message from your GP practice or a letter from the national booking service, so it’s useful to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep an eye out to make sure you receive the message (for example if you have a mobile phone but don’t typically use text messages)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;let your GP surgery know if you are caring for someone with underlying health conditions who would struggle to cope if you became unwell. You can help the vaccination effort by emailing your GP practice or using its website to make sure your local surgery knows you are an unpaid carer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update your contact details if they have changed lately – it’s a good time to make sure your GP practice has the most up to date information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as you’re registered with a GP and have up to date contact details you should receive an invitation in due course. For more information how to register with a GP and to find your local surgery visit: &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/JmNNCRO3xslG6PoHQhY3c?domain=nhs.uk"&gt;www.nhs.uk/register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out about what to expect at your vaccine appointment please visit: &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/0Ej7CVA3BFK2JjmfEopLi?domain=nhs.uk/"&gt;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/coronavirus-vaccination/what-happens-at-your-appointment/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are teachers eligible to receive a vaccine?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NHS is currently only offering vaccines to people within England&amp;#8217;s first four priority groups, in line with the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (JCVI) guidelines. This does not include teachers, unless they also meet age or health-related criteria. Vaccinating the priority groups first will save the most lives and provide the quickest and safest route out of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	&lt;div class="templatera_shortcode"&gt;
&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	
&lt;div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"&gt;&lt;span  style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"&gt;&lt;span  style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	
&lt;div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-"&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;

	
		&lt;li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7"&gt;
			&lt;div class="item-holder"&gt;
				&lt;div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true"&gt;
							&lt;img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-p3e8df66hifr61ujtsy3de06brye7ymf0j8fspmldk.png" data-mk-image-src-set='{"default":"https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg","2x":"","mobile":"","responsive":"true"}'/&gt;


					
				&lt;/div&gt;

				&lt;div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person" &gt;
						&lt;span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333"&gt;Steve Reed&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1"&gt;Member of Parliment for Croydon North&lt;/span&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

					
&lt;ul class="mk-employeee-networks"&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="mailto:&amp;#115;&amp;#116;ev&amp;#101;.re&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#46;m&amp;#112;&amp;#64;p&amp;#97;&amp;#114;l&amp;#105;ament.&amp;#117;k" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-604286bb6d96e" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"&gt;&lt;path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-604286bb6db21" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"&gt;&lt;path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-604286bb6dc9c" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"&gt;&lt;path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-604286bb6dd88" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"&gt;&lt;path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;

					&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
		&lt;div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155"&gt;

&lt;div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text"&gt;

	
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Steven Reed&lt;/a&gt; is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on &lt;a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/"&gt;reducing violent mental health restraint&lt;/a&gt; became law. In June 2019 he launched &lt;a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/"&gt;Labour’s civil society strategy&lt;/a&gt; outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/02/19/croydon-covid-vaccine-update/"&gt;Croydon Covid-19 Vaccine Update and FAQs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk"&gt;Steve Reed MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/02/19/croydon-covid-vaccine-update/">Croydon Covid-19 Vaccine Update and FAQs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Reed MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10607</id>
    <published>2021-02-19T16:29:12Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T16:29:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Croydon Community Notice Board"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Successful cross-party letter with nearly 100 signatures supporting my School Breakfast Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/successful-cross-party-letter-with-nearly-100-signatures-supporting-my-school-breakfast-bill/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I recently coordinated a cross party &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EmmaLewellBuck/status/1362465057054076930?s=20" data-type="URL" data-id="https://twitter.com/EmmaLewellBuck/status/1362465057054076930?s=20"&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; with Robert Halfon MP which gathered almost 100 signatures across both Houses in support of my School Breakfast Bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As a result of the reduced parliamentary calendar during lockdown, my Bill has been indefinitely postponed. However, with child food insecurity rising and the educational attainment gap growing, there is now an urgency for this Bill.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am deeply concerned that the Government’s National School Breakfast Programme reaches just 7% of the schools meeting the government’s own eligibility criteria and that funding will end altogether in July 2021. This will leave thousands of children without access to the free school breakfast they have come to rely on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposed School Breakfast Bill would address this issue. The Bill proposed scaling up school breakfast funding to all the 8,700 schools with high levels of disadvantage in England. The Bill also proposed making support to schools permanent at a cost of just over £300m annually. This could be funded by the Soft Drinks Industry Levy (SDIL) which continues to raise approximately £340m each year. In addition to this, research from Sustain has found more than £700m raised from the Levy since 2018 is unaccounted for. The unspent SDIL revenue can be allocated towards scaling up school breakfast provision.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I really hope the Government accepts our proposals in the School Breakfast Bill so that every child at risk of hunger can have a free, nutritious school breakfast and be ready to start their day of learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I recently coordinated a cross party letter with Robert Halfon MP which gathered almost 100 signatures across both Houses in support of my School Breakfast Bill. As a result of the reduced parliamentary calendar during lockdown, my Bill has been indefinitely postponed. However, with child food insecurity rising and the educational attainment gap growing, there […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=3008</id>
    <published>2021-02-19T14:13:35Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-19T14:13:35Z</updated>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hatfield based company helps roll out 1 million devices to disadvantaged children as 8,860 make their way to Hertfordshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/hatfield-based-company-helps-roll-out-1-million-devices-to-disadvantaged-children-as-8860-make-their-way-to-hertfordshire/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hatfield-based-company-helps-roll-out-1-million-devices-to-disadvantaged-children-as-8860-make-their-way-to-hertfordshire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p><strong>Hertfordshire has now received 8,860 laptops and tablets to help support disadvantaged children and young people while they learn at home. More than 1 million devices have now been delivered with more on their way.</strong></p>



<p>MP for Welwyn Hatfield Grant Shapps has welcomed the announcement that pupils across Hertfordshire have benefited from 8,860 laptops and tablets to date, as the government hits an important milestone in its rollout of devices to support disadvantaged students.</p>



<p>Hatfield based company Computacenter has been a key part of the £400 million Department of Education scheme, as well as assisting the Computers for Kids initiative.</p>



<p>The Department announced last month a further 300,000 laptops and tablets to help even more disadvantaged children and young people learn at home.</p>



<p>In addition, the government is partnering with the UK’s leading mobile network operators to provide free data to disadvantaged families, alongside a further £300 million being invested in tutoring programmes building on the existing £1 billion Covid Catch Up Fund.</p>



<p>Commenting, Transport Secretary Grant Shapps said: “No child should miss out as a result of the disruption caused by this pandemic. It’s been our priority to equip the children in most need with the tools they need to get on with their learning.</p>



<p>“It’s great to see that so many electronic devices have been delivered across the country. It’s also brilliant to see a company based here in Welwyn Hatfield take a leading role in supplying these devices.</p>



<p>“Of course, whilst we hope that our children will be back learning in school as soon as possible, we will do everything in our power to give them the world-class education they deserve as they learn at home.</p>



<p>Over 1 million laptops and tablets delivered, with 8,860 to Hertfordshire kids alone, will go a long way in helping us deliver this.”</p>



<p>Education Secretary Gavin Williamson said: “I know what a challenging period this has been for pupils, teachers and parents – but it has been nothing short of inspiring to see schools and staff going above and beyond, as they always have done, to give our pupils the very best education possible.”</p>



<p>“I want parents to know that we’ll continue to do everything we can to protect our children’s education at this unprecedented time and ensure they have the tools they need to get on with and make the most of their lives”.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hertfordshire has now received 8,860 laptops and tablets to help support disadvantaged children and young people while they learn at home. More than 1 million devices have now been delivered with more on their way.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=32533</id>
    <published>2021-02-18T14:57:30Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-18T14:57:30Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:51</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery_0.png?itok=hoGEwHMK" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that funding is in place for a new medical centre for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>


</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>426 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:51:44Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:51:44Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/02/12/6420/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6420</id>
    <published>2021-02-12T15:43:16Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T15:43:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Policy and Issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MELKSHAM CAMPUS UPDATE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-campus-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-embed-handler wp-block-embed-embed-handler"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="fb-post" data-href="https://www.facebook.com/MichelleDonelanChippenham/posts/2321901054611149" data-width="552"/>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-campus-update/">MELKSHAM CAMPUS UPDATE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-campus-update/">MELKSHAM CAMPUS UPDATE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33915</id>
    <published>2021-02-11T19:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T19:20:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Melksham"/>
    <category term="Wiltshire Council"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>*Cold Weather Payments*</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/cold-weather-payments/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=cold-weather-payments" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The cold weather has been harsh enough recently to trigger the Cold Weather Payments System, and some residents will receive an additional £25 towards the costs of heating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eligibility of CWPS is for those who are currently in receipt of some benefits, with pension credit serving as the most common eligibility criteria.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Residents in the following postcodes will be eligible; RG28, SO21, SP10, SP11, SP4, SP9, RG19, RG20, RG21, RG22, RG23, RG25, RG26, RG7&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A full list of eligibility criteria can be found at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gov.uk%2Fcold-weather-payment%2Feligibility%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR2KSAMnLquwZ-GrJEvkTUoHI5Pkaf2CVc5V0cLiwjNeQvXIIaI3OfAURfs&amp;amp;h=AT3IH1TahltgHRS9HV5x1PLwV5TxJpX85UsGq5s9nuk0F9JVVq5AmyD4GJ1NMQxPg-xQfsJo6pZLYQfYo4Wvu0YmoAonvugiW2mRjq3vgK8hbLr0tBYQZnIkvZAleqzIW1W-giiQykibBs_GfePie-Uw_KejhvTKHmdQBoBuKOvTrr5UD75mVyL-ET2QBfGr0xX8rxn79tqojyVitnusl2XsnSUAA8gVjhj0LBEc0qjiL4LTqTgUNGwlWcfZmoKa9MJetHK_3A26I2do8eq4oJr_C8BROH6YiaEh3ERfAKjEMR5BSXNw_AUhBj5VSU6cWrqIei1Rlqudx7ZUdoYWs4l_UMBn8Z648LUsjkfTq8BM6egNBKAhszqO6e8ZXZSMgaImrCF7mGb1o0gKAFsPDTKUfSPqe4hOuX2IGf9Z1fkHcCF5iRZPZ6jy24-bBLYQiHkf7gF0gwlC0B3yf1JL3XDdoFuE06n77Nga7pLNX-W3afcFiZdGxCMaODYpPCAr_z7MX2k4WmFJMxk437BsMulynszmG7QfVY8HcLOuaYlBWJb9POEz3aozKDg-y33CRgan183XuYgyE7U5js2-8w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://www.gov.uk/cold-weather-payment/eligibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The cold weather has been harsh enough recently to trigger the Cold Weather Payments System, and some residents will receive an additional £25 towards the costs of heating. Eligibility of CWPS is for those who are currently in receipt of some benefits, with pension credit serving as the most common eligibility criteria. Residents in the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2845</id>
    <published>2021-02-09T15:32:23Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T15:32:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[BATTLING FOR OUR BUSINESSES]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/02/08/battling-for-our-businesses/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=347</id>
		<updated>2021-02-08T13:46:13Z</updated>
		<published>2021-02-08T13:46:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/02/08/battling-for-our-businesses/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/02/08/battling-for-our-businesses/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/02/08/battling-for-our-businesses/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Winter 2020/2021 newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2021/01/29/winter-2020-2021-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy New Year and welcome to my new MP newsletter. Like most people my movements have been hugely curtailed due to the pandemic and I haven’t managed to be out and about as I’d want for several months. I am, however, still very busy with parliamentary business and I wanted to share with you some […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9190</id>
    <published>2021-01-29T13:15:05Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-29T13:15:05Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Reopening of Gyms and Leisure Centres]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2021/01/28/reopening-of-gyms-and-leisure-centres/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=459</id>
		<updated>2021-01-28T16:05:49Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-28T16:05:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2021/01/28/reopening-of-gyms-and-leisure-centres/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Brexit to coronavirus and everything in between - Ashfield MP reflects on eventful first year in office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From sending Boris Johnson into isolation, to being trolled on social media, dealing with coronavirus and Brexit, it’s been a busy year for former miner Lee Anderson who has clocked up one year representing his home turf as Ashfield MP.
The married dad of two, raised in Huthwaite, is the area’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s December Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3047</id>
		<updated>2020-12-30T11:33:26Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-30T11:32:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters here</p>
<p></p>
<p>Dear Constituent,</p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" /></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. Under these challenging circumstances, I nevertheless wish you a very safe and happy new year in 2021.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Heanor Future High Streets Fund bid success &#8211; £8.5 million:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following Heanor&#8217;s bid towards the Government&#8217;s £830 million Future High Streets Fund, I&#8217;m delighted that Heanor has been successful and has been awarded over £8.5 million to help transform its town centre and recover from the pandemic. You can find the full details of the Borough Council&#8217;s bid <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/">here</a>, which focuses on plans to regenerate the Market Place and Grammar School site. The Council now have a few months to confirm the final version of their plans, and I look forward to continuing to support and work with them to ensure we can maximise this funding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit deal latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister reached a deal with the EU regarding our future relationship after the end of the transition period, from the 1st January 2021. Parliament has been recalled today, on the 30th December, to consider the deal and vote on it. You can read the deal <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union">here</a> and the legislation enabling it <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf" data-cke-saved-href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf">here</a>. The select committee on the Future Relationship with the EU on which I serve has published a report on the deal this morning, which you can read <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/">here</a>.</p>
<p>I can confirm I will be supporting the deal when it comes to a vote later.</p>
<p>Many constituents have contacted me throughout the negotiation period, and I think this deal delivers on the key areas whilst also providing certainty and security for businesses and residents already impacted by Covid-19.</p>
<p>This deal delivers on Brexit, the referendum and last year&#8217;s election result by taking back control of our laws, borders, money, trade and fisheries.</p>
<p>&#8211; there is no role for the European Court of Justice and no requirement for the UK to follow EU law, so <strong>regaining parliamentary sovereignty</strong>;</p>
<p>&#8211; we will <strong>trade with the EU on the basis of zero tariffs and zero quotas</strong>, which will allow businesses to be able to trade smoothly and continue to access EU markets;</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Allows us to introduce our own modern subsidy system. </strong>This new subsidies system will operate in a that best suits the interests of UK industries &#8211; outside the EU State Aid regime.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> offers streamlined <strong>co-operation on law enforcement</strong>, ensuring we continue to effectively tackle serious organised crime and counter terrorism, protecting the public, and bringing criminals to justice. It also provides for future cooperation between the UK and EU on emerging security challenges, such as cyber and health security, including continuing to work together on tackling the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p><strong>- Recognises UK sovereignty over our fishing waters and puts us in a position to rebuild our fishing fleet and increase quotas, overturning the inequity that British fishermen have faced for over four decades. </strong>By the end of the five year transition we will have full control of our waters and the amount of fish available to UK fishermen will have risen from half to two-thirds.</p>
<p><strong><strong>- Provides for the UK’s participation in certain EU programmes, furthering our commitment to making the UK a science and research superpower. </strong></strong>This deal will fulfil our manifesto commitment to participate in the Horizon Europe programme, but also the Euratom Research and Training programme, and the space programme, Copernicus.</p>
<p>The deal also includes arrangements for airlines and hauliers that provides them with certainty, and gives people the ability to travel to and from the EU easily for work and holidays; a social security agreement that has practical benefits for UK citizens including accessing healthcare when travelling in the EU; and agreements on energy which will benefit consumers by helping to keep prices down.</p>
<p>As I set out in previous newsletters, compromises were necessary to achieve a deal, especially on fishing and the level playing field. Having been through the deal I am satisfied that these compromises are acceptable in the context of the importance of tariff free access to the EU market. This is a good deal achieved at great speed and gives us the best possible platform to make a success of Brexit.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus guidance latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following the last review of the tier restrictions on 16 December, Amber Valley and all of Derbyshire remained in the tier 3 restrictions. The next review takes place today. Amber Valley currently has a high case rate, of 332 cases per 100k, which is one of the highest in Derbyshire, and up 44% on the previous week. This is a very concerning situation and may lead to further restrictions being out in place locally.</p>
<p>On the positive side, mass testing has started in Swadlincote in the south of the County and will spread further in the county, including to Amber Valley early in the new year. This programme, along with similar roll outs in health, care and school settings will help identify cases earlier and slow the spread.</p>
<p>Vaccines are also now starting to be rolled out across the County, and I&#8217;m pleased that Ripley is one of the first primary care centres to begin rolling out the vaccine, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/">here</a>. Now that the Oxford vaccine has been approved for us, the roll out of vaccination should increase rapidly at dedicated centres as well as local GPs and pharmacies. Please do wait to be contacted about the vaccine though rather than asking your GP.</p>
<p>We are now at a critical point in this pandemic with cases rising rapidly and the problems of 2 new variants. But the end is in sight now we can rapidly vaccinate the most vulnerable. At this time we all need to show as much caution as possible to reduce the number of cases and minimise the new restrictions needed. We’ve got this far, let’s not ease off now.</p>
<p>I will continue to engage with ministers, the public health team and the local NHS to ensure that this area sees the full roll out of the vaccines and mass testing as soon as possible and that support is in place for those who can’t work and those businesses forced to close as a result of the tier measures.</p>
<p>You can read my contributions in Parliament here including on highlighting the need to roll out the vaccine to people who are unable to leave their homes as soon as logistics allow <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4">here</a> and about consideration of more localised geography for tier restrictions <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As always, you can find the latest Covid-19 guidance, and support available, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus &#8211; support for local businesses &amp; high streets:</span></strong></p>
<p>In Parliament, I&#8217;ve continued to highlight the difficulties faces by our local businesses, such as the events industry and conference centres (you can read my question to the Secretary of State for Business on this <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4">here</a>), and supporting local high streets (which you can read more on <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4">here</a>).</p>
<p>I welcome the Chancellor&#8217;s announcement of the extension of the furlough scheme until the end of April 2021, and the extension of the business loan schemes until the end of March. You can find more information on the support and grants available for you or your business <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></span></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills" data-cke-saved-href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like me on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" /></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/">How to write a script for an e-course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/">How to write a script for an e-course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rubbish dumping survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="caldera-grid" id="caldera_form_1" data-cf-ver="1.9.3" data-cf-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;&lt;div id="caldera_notices_1" data-spinner="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-admin/images/spinner.gif"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;form data-instance="1" class="CF5f8c811d77adc caldera_forms_form cfajax-trigger" method="POST" enctype="multipart/form-data" id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1" data-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc" aria-label="Flytipping on Cotterills Lane" data-target="#caldera_notices_1" data-template="#cfajax_CF5f8c811d77adc-tmpl" data-cfajax="CF5f8c811d77adc" data-load-element="_parent" data-load-class="cf_processing" data-post-disable="0" data-action="cf_process_ajax_submit" data-request="https://liambyrne.co.uk/cf-api/CF5f8c811d77adc" data-hiderows="true"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" id="_cf_verify_CF5f8c811d77adc" name="_cf_verify" value="3b2e3177a1"  data-nonce-time="1614972577" /&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_wp_http_referer" value="/feed/" /&gt;&lt;div id="cf2-CF5f8c811d77adc_1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_id" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_ct" value="1"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="cfajax" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_cr_pst" value="7970"&gt;
&lt;div class="hide" style="display:none; overflow:hidden;height:0;width:0;"&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Email&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="text" name="email" value="" autocomplete="off"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-1"  class="row  first_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_949637" class="form-group" id="fld_949637_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_949637Label" for="fld_949637_1" class="control-label"&gt;First name &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_949637" class=" form-control" id="fld_949637_1" name="fld_949637" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_949637Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3720579" class="form-group" id="fld_3720579_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3720579Label" for="fld_3720579_1" class="control-label"&gt;Surname &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_3720579" class=" form-control" id="fld_3720579_1" name="fld_3720579" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_3720579Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_377714" class="form-group" id="fld_377714_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_377714Label" for="fld_377714_1" class="control-label"&gt;Postcode &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_377714" class=" form-control" id="fld_377714_1" name="fld_377714" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_377714Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8339186" class="form-group" id="fld_8339186_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8339186Label" for="fld_8339186_1" class="control-label"&gt;Email &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="email" data-field="fld_8339186" class=" form-control" id="fld_8339186_1" name="fld_8339186" value="" data-type="email" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_8339186Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id="fld_3670460_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8286015" class="form-group" id="fld_8286015_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8286015Label" for="fld_8286015_1" class="control-label"&gt;Has the dumping and littering problem in the area reduced recently?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_8286015" value="" data-field="fld_8286015" class="form-control" id="fld_8286015_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_8286015Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Not Sure"  data-calc-value="Not Sure" &gt;
						Not Sure					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_5317914" class="form-group" id="fld_5317914_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_5317914Label" for="fld_5317914_1" class="control-label"&gt;What further steps would you like to see taken?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;textarea name="fld_5317914" value="" data-field="fld_5317914" class="form-control" id="fld_5317914_1" rows="4"    aria-labelledby="fld_5317914Label" &gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_7237774" class="form-group" id="fld_7237774_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_7237774Label" for="fld_7237774_1" class="control-label"&gt;Would you be willing to join a residents’ group?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_7237774" value="" data-field="fld_7237774" class="form-control" id="fld_7237774_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_7237774Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Maybe"  data-calc-value="Maybe" &gt;
						Maybe					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3572997" class="form-group" id="fld_3572997_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3572997Label" for="fld_3572997_1" class="control-label"&gt;Can Liam email you about news and campaign updates? &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_3572997" value="" data-field="fld_3572997" class="form-control" id="fld_3572997_1"  required="required"  aria-labelledby="fld_3572997Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Liam can email me					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						Liam cannot email me					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_4555323" class=" form-control" id="fld_4555323_1" name="fld_4555323" value="1" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_3061013" class=" form-control" id="fld_3061013_1" name="fld_3061013" value="2020 Oct Flytipping Survey" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;hr id="fld_6111107_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_432351" class="form-group" id="fld_432351_1-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class=""&gt;
	&lt;input  class="btn btn-default" type="submit" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1" value="Submit" data-field="fld_432351"  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;input class="button_trigger_1" type="hidden" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1_btn" value="" data-field="fld_432351"  /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-2"  class="row  last_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/"&gt;Rubbish dumping survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/">Rubbish dumping survey</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=7970</id>
    <published>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Flytipping"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hull MP reacts to the Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/hull-mp-reacts-budget" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12px;"&gt;Diana Johnson spoke in the Commons debate on the Chancellor's Budget Statement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12px;"&gt;The Hull North MP's remarks ranged across several key issues for Hull North, including support for workers over the Coronavirus, the NHS and public health, flood resilience and devolution for the Humber.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/14"&gt;Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item odd"&gt;&lt;a href="/tags/devolution"&gt;devolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/7"&gt;Fair deal for Hull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>884 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-3822029382927366640</id>
    <published>2020-03-06T13:22:00.003+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-06T13:22:42.576+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Raise the rate"/>
    <title type="text">Raise the Rate debate</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="true" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" height="313" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FYvonneFovargue4Makerfield%2Fvideos%2F613975099449506%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/3822029382927366640/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html" title="Raise the Rate debate"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6042877cd4c26" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6042877cd4c26').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6042877cd4c26","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6042877cd4c26" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6042877cd4c26" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6042877cd4c26" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6042877cd4c26" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6042877cd4c26" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6042877cd4c26" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6042877cd4c26" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6042877cd4c26" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6042877cd4c26" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6042877cd4c26_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6042877cd4c26 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxz2SLEYsKm7TH7y1VMWf4cvfZyckQWg1oHOI-Ccb2Kdke7f2guiIbqlXNh788DGSJumejRMYfnxMDIhaxq9g' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~3/QVJ5Ukdon9g/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~4/QVJ5Ukdon9g" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>118389 - George Freeman - 08-Dec-2017 (Tabled)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/content/118389-george-freeman-08-dec-2017-tabled" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;George Freeman&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To ask the Secretary of State for International Development, what recent discussions she has had with her counterpart in the Lebanese Government on the potential forced return of refugees to Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-statements/written-question/Commons/2017-12-08/118389" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-stateme…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2472 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thank you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" rel="attachment wp-att-281"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="281" data-permalink="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" data-orig-size="640,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 09-06-2017, 10 43 04 (2)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=300%2C186" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" src="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=640%2C396" alt="" width="640" height="396" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?w=640 640w, https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=300%2C186 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will be closing down shortly, but you can keep up to date with my work on my &lt;a href="http://www.carolynharris.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;main webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Google+" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;#038;title=Thank%20you" data-a2a-url="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" data-a2a-title="Thank you"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  We did it! Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me. I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East. This website will be closing down shortly, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>linzi_isaac</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/?p=279</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcoming the Fantastic Ryanair Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/2016/01/11/welcoming-the-fantastic-ryanair-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport.<br/>
Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result.<br/>
The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here.<br/>
The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well.<br/>
It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have been ongoing for a considerable length of time now, have resulted in success for both Ryanair and the Northern Ireland economy.<br/>
We have a very proud aerospace industry here in Northern Ireland and it is very much engrained in our manufacturing heritage with the likes of Shorts Brothers, now Bombardier, having been established in Northern Ireland since the end of the Second World War.<br/>
We have gone through an extremely difficult 18 months in County Antrim with the announced closures of both the JTI Gallaher tobacco plant and the Michelin tyre factory bringing about almost 1800 redundancies and this investment is a huge step forward in finding new jobs and new opportunities for the people of this area.<br/>
Ryanair’s investment of £300 million will boost our local wage economy enormously and all of our local businesses and town centres will reap the benefits as a result.<br/>
Ryanair are also in discussions with Tourism Ireland to explore the possibility of introducing five new routes and I have every faith that Tourism Ireland and all other sectors who would benefit from such an arrangement will do everything they can to ensure its successful delivery.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport. Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result. The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here. The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well. It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/?p=1623</id>
    <published>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795</id>
    <published>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
