<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-11-19T06:37:04Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>A Minister in office is not always in power</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/11/19/a-minister-in-office-is-not-always-in-power/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The events of recent weeks have shown that it is possible to be a Minister in office unable to see through changes of policy or enforcement of laws in ways the public and Ministers wish.</p>
<p>At the Home Office successive Ministers have made clear their wish to end people trafficking across the Channel. There has been a change of the law, yet still lawyers and legal processes conspire to delay final decisions on cases. People can claim to have been trafficked yet we do not seem able to return to their home from whence they were trafficked. People claim they are asylum seekers yet they have come immediately from the safe country of France, and often came from another safe country before France. Two Home Secretaries have now been briefed against and complained about by civil servants. The Ministers have doubtless become frustrated at the lack of help to design a law which works or to enforce a law which was said to work. The idea is meant to be Ministers set out the aims of policy and provide the resources, whilst officials get on with implementing it in the best way.</p>
<p>At the Treasury Ministers are told they need to follow Bank and OBR orthodoxy. There has been a  notable lack of self criticism or curiosity as to how the UK has an 11% inflation rate when Ministers have endorsed a constant target of 2% inflation and left the Bank free to set interest rates, interfere in bond markets and oversee the overall banking  system to bring this about.  Nor has there been much public exploration of why successive OBR forecasts have been tens of billions out in recent years, and how this can lead Ministers to accept wrong judgements based on bad data. Treasury Ministers need to be more sceptical of the advice they are getting as so far it has landed us with an unwelcome inflation and may soon land us in an unwanted recession.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The events of recent weeks have shown that it is possible to be a Minister in office unable to see through changes of policy or enforcement of laws in ways the public and Ministers wish. At the Home Office successive Ministers have made clear their wish to end people trafficking across the Channel. There has…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33868</id>
    <published>2022-11-19T05:06:50Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-19T05:06:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More bus and other Public Transport service complaints</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/11/more-bus-and-other-public-transport-service-complaints/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">I want to share with you another email from a constituent in response to my campaign to improve the quality of &amp; information on Bus services in Newcastle. </span><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Public money is going to private bus companies for terrible services, all the while my constituents’ businesses are losing money.</span></strong></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="12898" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/11/more-bus-and-other-public-transport-service-complaints/bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4r8/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?fit=1080%2C1080&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1080,1080" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Bus service complaint 18 nov 22 4R8" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?fit=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?fit=700%2C700&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-12898 size-large" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=700%2C700&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="700" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=1024%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=300%2C300&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=150%2C150&amp;ssl=1 150w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=768%2C768&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?resize=230%2C230&amp;ssl=1 230w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Bus-service-complaint-18-nov-22-4R8.jpg?w=1080&amp;ssl=1 1080w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I want to share with you another email from a constituent in response to my campaign to improve the quality of &amp; information on Bus services in Newcastle. Public money is going to private bus companies for terrible services, all… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12897</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T18:38:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T18:38:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chesterfield MP welcomes free digital training organised by Google</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/18/chesterfield-mp-welcomes-free-digital-training-organised-by-google/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/18/chesterfield-mp-welcomes-free-digital-training-organised-by-google/">Chesterfield MP welcomes free digital training organised by Google</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/18/chesterfield-mp-welcomes-free-digital-training-organised-by-google/">Chesterfield MP welcomes free digital training organised by Google</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5137</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T17:28:18Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T17:28:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up 18 November 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/18/weekly-round-up-18-november-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-18-november-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>It was a big week in Parliament with the Autumn Statement – otherwise known as the fourth Budget of 2022. Across Bristol South, ordinary people have seen their rents and mortgages go up and will now face bigger energy bills from April while their salaries are stretched further and further. The Chancellor could have used this week’s statement to give a proper helping hand to those in need, instead the only winners from the Budget are the bankers with newly uncapped bonuses, the oil and gas giants who can continue to make record profits and fill the pockets of shareholders and the non-doms who make their home in UK but refuse to pay their taxes. </p>
<p>This is a clapped-out Tory Government who protect the billionaires and energy giants while local families across Bristol South struggle to make ends meet. Because of the choices made today by the Conservatives we have the highest tax levels in 75 years and yet public services are being left to crumble.</p>
<p>This week the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee (PACAC) met to discuss whether lobbying rules should be stricter and heard from Jon Gerlis, a Public Relations and Policy Manager with the Chartered Institute of Public Relations, Liam Herbert, the Chair of Public Affairs Board of the Public Relations and Communications Association, and Harry Rich, the Registrar of Consultant Lobbyists in the Office of the Registrar of Consultant Lobbyists. In his written evidence, Harry Rich called for tougher rules around ministerial and official meetings with lobbyists. Various organisations, including Transparency International, have argued that the current rules around lobbying leave much of the industry unregulated and therefore open to abuse. Only consultant lobbyists are currently required to register under the Lobbying Act; in-house lobbyists do not have to. The question of whether think tanks, charities, trade bodies, and NGOs should be included in the requirements of registration under the Act are also under discussion. </p>
<p>I was pleased to visit a number of events in Parliament this week. Firstly, I dropped in on an online fraud event by Santander UK to find out more about what businesses and government can do to prevent online fraud and scams. £600million was stolen already during the first half of this year from UK consumers according to UK Finance data. Santander’s website provides latest fraud updates where their fraud team share details of the most recent financial fraud or scams that have been reported or discovered. Scammers have developed sophisticated means of parting people from their money and we must all remain vigilant and be cautious about making any transactions that are out of the ordinary. If you think you may have been a victim of fraud, it is vital that you contact your bank straight away. It may be embarrassing but so many people are the victim of fraud and there is support out there. </p>
<p>It is Pancreatic Cancer Awareness Month. The signs and symptoms of pancreatic cancer include indigestion, pain in your tummy or back, changes to your poo, losing weight without meaning to, and jaundice. Pancreatic cancer affects men and women in the same way although the symptoms may vary. Pancreatic cancer often doesn’t cause symptoms in the early stages. As the cancer grows, it may start to cause symptoms. The symptoms may not be specific to pancreatic cancer, and they may come and go to begin with. This can make pancreatic cancer hard to diagnose. This makes is vital that if you begin to experience any symptoms, that you go to see your GP. Obviously, these symptoms may be caused by something completely different, but if it is cancer, the earlier it is caught, the better the chances for recovery. Visit Pancreatic Cancer UK for more information.</p>
<p>There was also a brilliant event in Parliament on Tackling Gambling Stigma. This important for both those who experience gambling addiction themselves to have a safe space where they can hear from others who are going through the same or similar addiction and the consequences it has on their lives and for the general public and professions who need an understanding of what it is like to live with gambling harm. We need to remove the stigma of gambling addiction if we are to help more people. It takes a lot to reach out and to admit to a problem with gambling and that’s before people have to try to rid themselves of the addiction. The more knowledge we have, the more tools we have to deal with any issues that we may end up facing.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/18/weekly-round-up-18-november-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 18 November 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It was a big week in Parliament with the Autumn Statement – otherwise known as the fourth Budget of 2022. […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/18/weekly-round-up-18-november-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 18 November 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3381</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T17:02:27Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T17:02:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scottish Living Wage award for Edinburgh action group</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13599/scottish-living-wage-award-for-edinburgh-action-group" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Edinburgh Living Wage Action Group celebrated another success last night (Thursday 17 November) when it was named winner of the Outstanding Leadership Award at the annual Scottish Living Wage Awards.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13599/scottish-living-wage-award-for-edinburgh-action-group</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T16:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T16:30:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John welcomes the Chancellors attempt to get the next big bang to happen, but asks for more specific dates on certain reforms and roll-out of powers]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/11/18/john-welcomes-the-chancellors-attempt-to-get-the-next-big-bang-to-happen-but-asks-for-more-specific-dates-on-certain-reforms-and-roll-out-of-powers/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5559</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T15:15:35Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T15:15:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/11/18/john-welcomes-the-chancellors-attempt-to-get-the-next-big-bang-to-happen-but-asks-for-more-specific-dates-on-certain-reforms-and-roll-out-of-powers/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid Autumn Booster and Flu Vaccination Newsletter from Swansea Bay University Health Board</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/covid-autumn-booster-and-flu-vaccination-newsletter-from-swansea-bay-university-health-board-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="xmsonormal"><u><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Date: Friday, November 18th 2022</span></u></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><u><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Edition number: 40</span></u></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Welcome to the latest edition of our newsletter.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We start with an important message from Executive Director of Public Health at Swansea Bay University Health Board, Keith Reid.</span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We’re pleased to announce we’ve reached the one-million-dose milestone in our Covid vaccination programme.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">That’s all the first, second, third (for some people) and booster doses delivered across Swansea and Neath Port Talbot so far.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">It’s a remarkable achievement and gives us an opportunity to thank everyone who has played a part.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We appreciate you, the public, putting your faith in us through one of the most challenging periods in the NHS’ history.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">No matter how well planned out, no vaccination programme could achieve anything without the support of those it has been designed to help. So thank you.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">It was a little under two years ago that the first Pfizer vaccines were delivered to the health board.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">In the weeks before that day and since, a remarkable number of people and organisations have worked together to roll out these doses on a scale never seen before.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">They include those who plan the programme, building contractors, Bay Studios, Margam Orangery, Canolfan Gorseinon Centre, health board vaccinators, the military, pharmacists, health care support workers, administrators, volunteers, bus operators, booking staff, security staff, GP practices, community pharmacies, colleagues and elected representatives on Swansea and Neath Port Talbot councils, community groups, charities and Aberafan Shopping Centre.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">And it’s not over. We are learning to live with the coronavirus and a huge part of that is maintaining levels of immunity.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">The current autumn booster roll out will help to do that as we head into a difficult winter where flu is also likely to make a comeback. </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">So please, if you’re eligible for the Covid booster and flu vaccines, take up the offer.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">As to what’s next, no one can really say for sure right now.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">But whatever lies ahead, we will continue to work hard for you, listening, learning, adapting and improving as we move forward.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">What stage is the vaccination programme at?</span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We’re on course to have offered everyone who is eligible in our health board area a Covid vaccination by the end of November and a flu vaccination by the end of December. This is in line with the ambition set out in the Welsh Government’s winter respiratory vaccination strategy.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We know, however, that some people are unable to reach our vaccination centres for their Covid booster, so we organise outreach sessions with the Immbulance mobile vaccination clinic and at pop-up clinics across our area. These are also handy for those who may not have been able to make an earlier appointment. They are drop-in sessions, so no appointment is needed.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Next week’s timetable is below.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Immbulance and pop-up clinic timetable – week beginning Monday, November 21<sup>st</sup></span></b></p>
<p class="xmsolistparagraph" style="text-indent: -18.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Symbol;">·</span><span style="font-size: 7.0pt; font-family: 'Times New Roman',serif;">         </span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Monday, November 21<sup>st</sup> – The Immbulance will be at Bonymaen Community Centre, Bonymaen Road, Bonymaen, Swansea, SA1 7AW, 10am to 5pm. Ages 12+ at risk and all 50 and over. Covid autumn booster vaccination only.</span></p>
<p class="xmsolistparagraph" style="text-indent: -18.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Symbol;">·</span><span style="font-size: 7.0pt; font-family: 'Times New Roman',serif;">         </span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Tuesday, November 22nd and returning on Tuesday, December 6<sup>th</sup> – The Immbulance will be at Morfa Shopping Park, Brunel Way, Swansea, SA1 7BP, 10am to 5pm. Ages 12+ at risk and all 50 and over. Covid autumn booster vaccination only.</span></p>
<p class="xmsolistparagraph" style="text-indent: -18.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Symbol;">·</span><span style="font-size: 7.0pt; font-family: 'Times New Roman',serif;">         </span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Wednesday, November 23<sup>rd</sup> – There will be a drop-in session for the Ukrainian refugee community at The Grand Hotel, Station Road, Port Talbot, SA13 1DE, 10am to 5pm. Primary Covid vaccinations and booster.</span></p>
<p class="xmsolistparagraph" style="text-indent: -18.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Symbol; color: black;">·</span><span style="font-size: 7.0pt; font-family: 'Times New Roman',serif; color: black;">         </span><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Thursday, November 24<sup>th</sup> – <span style="color: black; background: white;">There will be a drop-in session at Trallwn Community Centre, Bethel Road, Trallwn, Swansea, SA7 9QP, 10am to 5pm. Ages 12+ at risk and all 50 and over</span></span>. Covid autumn booster vaccination only.</p>
<p class="xmsolistparagraph" style="text-indent: -18.0pt;"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: Symbol;">·</span><span style="font-size: 7.0pt; font-family: 'Times New Roman',serif;">         </span><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/SweEC9105CkNXRMpFo5sU7?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Go to this page on our website for the full Immbulance and pop-up clinic timetable.</span></a></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif; color: black;">Am I eligible?</span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/SweEC9105CkNXRMpFo5sU7?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Go to this page on our website and use the eligibility checker if you’re not sure if you’re eligible for the Covid autumn booster or flu vaccination.</span></a></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">The page also has information on how to get the vaccinations and videos explaining why vaccination is important.</span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/KhFFC0YG6tGg5JMLcDj9Z_?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Go to this page on our website for the answers to frequently asked questions about the Covid autumn booster and flu vaccination.</span></a></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">And finally…</span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><b><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">We’re leaving no one behind. So if you’re missing a first or second Covid vaccine, please contact our booking team on 01792 200492 or 01639 862323, between 9am and 5pm, Monday to Saturday.</span></b></p>
<p class="xmsonormal"><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Verdana',sans-serif;">Thanks for reading.</span></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Date: Friday, November 18th 2022   Edition number: 40 Welcome to the latest edition of our newsletter. We start with an important message from Executive Director of Public Health at Swansea Bay University Health Board, Keith Reid.   We’re pleased to announce we’ve reached the one-million-dose milestone in our Covid vaccination programme. That’s all the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ciaran Kearney</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2699</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T14:41:27Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T14:41:27Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz calls for a real plan for growth after the Chancellor&#8217;s Autumn Statement]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-real-plan-for-growth-after-the-chancellors-autumn-statement/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11881</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:57:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:39:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Liz in the news"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I spoke to both ITV News Central and BBC East Midlands Today about the Chancellor&#8217;s Autumn Statement.&#160;<br />
My constituents and people across the East Midlands are having to pay the price for the Conservatives crashing the economy, with rising bills, energy prices and mortgages.<br />
Yet all we got yesterday was more of the same from the Tories: more taxes on working people, low investment in public services and not the support businesses need.&#160;<br />
We need a fresh start and a proper plan for growth. You can see Labour&#8217;s Shadow Chancellor, Rachel Reeves, ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-real-plan-for-growth-after-the-chancellors-autumn-statement/">Liz calls for a real plan for growth after the Chancellor&#8217;s Autumn Statement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-real-plan-for-growth-after-the-chancellors-autumn-statement/"><![CDATA[<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-11881-2" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/BBC-east-mids.mp4?_=2" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/BBC-east-mids.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/BBC-east-mids.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Yesterday I spoke to both ITV News Central and BBC East Midlands Today about the Chancellor&#8217;s Autumn Statement.&nbsp;</p>
<p>My constituents and people across the East Midlands are having to pay the price for the Conservatives crashing the economy, with rising bills, energy prices and mortgages.</p>
<p>Yet all we got yesterday was more of the same from the Tories: more taxes on working people, low investment in public services and not the support businesses need.&nbsp;</p>
<p>We need a fresh start and a proper plan for growth. You can see Labour&#8217;s Shadow Chancellor, Rachel Reeves, set out our alternative <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-11-17/debates/97DB3122-0068-46CD-B026-F757C8DF39AF/AutumnStatement#contribution-88A8E7B8-3E44-4B9E-8F3A-4B3B9936F09A">here.</a></p>
<p>You can see the comments I made to ITV Central below.</p>
<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-11881-3" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Itv-clip-for-FB.mp4?_=3" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Itv-clip-for-FB.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Itv-clip-for-FB.mp4</a></video></div>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" ><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-10695" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/let-them-hold-hands-a-heartbreaking-picture-of-britains-chaotic-care-home-visiting-rules/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/29.jpg" alt="Let them hold hands: a heartbreaking picture of Britain&#8217;s chaotic care home visiting rules" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/let-them-hold-hands-a-heartbreaking-picture-of-britains-chaotic-care-home-visiting-rules/" class="wp_rp_title">Let them hold hands: a heartbreaking picture of Britain&#8217;s chaotic care home visiting rules</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-11122" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-attends-after-school-club/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/AS-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz attends after school club" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-attends-after-school-club/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz attends after school club</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-949" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/949/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/liz-at-bus-stop2web-150x150.jpg" alt="More action to tackle anti-social behaviour" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/949/" class="wp_rp_title">More action to tackle anti-social behaviour</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-10614" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-circuit-break-on-peston/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/IMG_2922-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz calls for a circuit break on Peston" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-circuit-break-on-peston/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz calls for a circuit break on Peston</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-4791" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/glenfield-has-some-of-the-best-survival-rates-in-the-country/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/4.jpg" alt="&#8216;Glenfield has some of the best survival rates in the country&#8217;" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/glenfield-has-some-of-the-best-survival-rates-in-the-country/" class="wp_rp_title">&#8216;Glenfield has some of the best survival rates in the country&#8217;</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-calls-for-a-real-plan-for-growth-after-the-chancellors-autumn-statement/">Liz calls for a real plan for growth after the Chancellor&#8217;s Autumn Statement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/BBC-east-mids.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="0" type=""/>
<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Itv-clip-for-FB.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="0" type=""/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3358</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:46:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Constituent, Welcome to my November&#160;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&#160; Autumn Statement: Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my November&nbsp;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Autumn Statement:</h1>



<p>Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. In which he detailed how the Government intends to restore economic stability and tackle inflation.</p>



<p>Like many countries around the world, the UK is facing profound economic challenges. Supply disruption caused by the world’s economies emerging from lockdown has been compounded by Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine and deliberate interference with Europe’s energy supply to create massive increases in the cost of energy. This has led to high inflation and high interest rates across many of the world’s major economies, and the UK is no different.</p>



<p>I welcome the proposals in the Autumn Statement. To achieve long-term, sustainable growth we need to grip inflation, balance the books, and get debt falling as a share of GDP. The plan presented by the Chancellor yesterday takes the tough decisions to face up to this situation without passing the buck onto future generations. What’s more, it protects the hard-working majority by enacting no headline tax increases, and protects the most vulnerable by maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation – something I have personally been campaigning for. All while protecting and maintaining public spending for the next two years at the levels set out in 2021.</p>



<p>The plan involves a roughly equal split between tax rises and spending cuts, with the greatest burden falling on those who can afford it most. Specifically, the plan:</p>



<p><strong>Increases taxpayer funding for our NHS and schools by an extra £11 billion over the next two years.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Government will provide £4 billion in additional funding to schools and £7.7 billion in additional funding to the NHS and social care sector over the next two years. Prioritising the public services that matter most.</p>



<p>&#8211; £2–3 billion in additional funding for the NHS in each of the next two years so we can bring down ambulance waiting times, tackle the Covid backlog, and improve access to GPs. Also providing £2.8 billion next year and £4.7 billion the year after for adult social care, which aims to double the number of people leaving hospitals on time and into care by 2024, addressing unmet needs and boosting low pay in the sector.</p>



<p>&#8211; £4 billion in additional funding for schools over the next two years. We are increasing the schools budget by £2 billion this year and £2 billion next year to help schools with rising costs as a result of inflation. Which is more than Labour has pledged to give schools.</p>



<p><strong>Introduces no headline tax increases.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Autumn Statement raises £25 billion in additional taxes over the forecast period but there are no increases in the headline rates of tax. By targeting tax rises toward businesses, wealthier households, and the oil and gas industry, the Government has ensured that it can honour its manifesto commitment not to increase Income Tax, National Insurance, or VAT.</p>



<p>&#8211; Instead of raising rates, the Government is freezing personal tax thresholds for a further two years. There are also reforms to the Additional Rate threshold, so that a taxpayer who earns more than £150,000 will pay £1,200 more in tax per year.</p>



<p>&#8211; It is only fair that companies who have made genuine windfall profits as a result of the war in Ukraine make an additional contribution to pay for the support we have outlined. So from 2023, the Energy Profits Levy rate will rise from 25per cent to 35per cent and will continue until the end of March 2028. A 45per cent Levy will be applied to extraordinary returns made by electricity generators. In total these windfall taxes will raise £52 billion over six years. This is more ambitious than Labour’s proposal.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting and maintaining public spending.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; For the next two years public spending will remain at the levels set out in 2021 and then increase by one per cent in real terms each year until 2027–28.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting every household with their energy bills.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Energy Price Guarantee will continue to support everyone for another year. This winter, the price households pay for the energy they use will be capped, so that a typical household will pay £2,500. From April 2023, the price cap will rise so that a typical household will pay £3,000. The Energy Price Guarantee will then end in April 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting the most vulnerable through maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; I have been publicly campaigning for benefits and pensions to be increased in line with inflation for some time now, and so was very pleased to see the Chancellor yesterday confirm that this would be part of the Government’s plan.</p>



<p>&#8211; To protect the most vulnerable, benefits will now be increased in line with inflation for 2023–24. More than 10 million households in receipt of working-age and disability benefits will see an increase in their benefit payments.</p>



<p>&#8211; The pensions triple lock will also be protected. Because of the difficult but necessary decisions the Government has taken elsewhere, the triple lock for pensions will be protected in full. This means that in April, the State Pension will increase in line with inflation, which is the biggest cash increase in the State Pension ever.</p>



<p><strong>Additional support for the most vulnerable.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Over £12 billion of additional targeted support is assigned to help the most vulnerable households. The Government will continue providing this year’s cost of living payments and next year it will provide extra one-off payments of £900 for the 8 million households on means-tested benefits, £300 to pensioners, and £150 for disability benefit recipients. The Government is also providing £1 billion of extra funding by extending the Household Support Fund for another year.</p>



<p>The OBR has confirmed that these plans will restore the public finances to a sustainable position and help reduce inflation and unemployment. And I look forward to engaging with my ministerial colleagues as these policies are rolled out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Remembrance Sunday:</h1>



<p>This year for Remembrance Sunday on 13th November, I was honoured to lay wreaths in Ripley and Kilburn in memory of those who have served our county, and in honour of those who are still serving. There are a multitude of remembrance services held across our constituency every year, so it is unfortunately impossible for me to attend all of them. However, every year I try to rotate which services I attend. This year it was a memorial service at Ripley War Memorial in the morning and another in Kilburn in the afternoon.</p>



<p>This has been a particularly important period of remembrance as we mark 40 years since the end of the Falkland’s war, and we commemorate the 255 British personnel who lost their lives in defence of the islands. Their courage and sacrifice must never be forgotten. Thank you to everyone who organised or supported the remembrance services and parades across Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Alfreton Solar Farm Update:</h1>



<p>On 21st October, I spoke at the public inquiry into plans from Kronos Solar to build a 50-megawatt solar farm between Alfreton and Oakerthorpe. Many of you will remember that Amber Valley Borough Council’s (AVBC) planning authorities rejected the proposal last December, stating that the project’s scale and impact on the landscape outweighed any environmental benefits the site would provide. However, Kronos Solar have since filed an appeal to overturn the decision of AVBC and get the site approved, resulting in this enquiry.</p>



<p>I have been opposing the project on behalf of local residents and businesses throughout the process, a great many of whom have contacted me about the proposals. I very much support the expansion of our clean energy network, and in the right place a solar farm would be an asset. However, there are good reasons why this site was refused planning permission. We all want renewable energy expansion but not at any cost.</p>



<p>To begin with, much of the land is north facing, which means the site would need to be overly large. The impact on the amenity of local residents, the impact on the countryside area, and the impact on the various heritage assets is just too great. And that is before we consider Alfreton Park and Alfreton Park Community School, which looks after children with the very highest level of need, very close in the vicinity.</p>



<p>It is clear to me that this is a totally unsuitable site for this intensity of development. Frankly, I believe this proposal was not based on a thorough search for suitable land for a solar farm, instead, it looks to me to be based on a search for a suitable sub-station, with the proposal then trying to force some land to suit.</p>



<p>I will continue to keep residents updated on any developments. And at present, a decision is expected at some point in the next few months.</p>



<h1>Pollution and our waterways:</h1>



<p>I have recently welcomed the Department for Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs’ (DEFRA) plans to raise the civil penalty for water companies who pollute our environment by one thousand times, from £250,000 up to £250 million. I am hopeful that increasing the penalties the Environment Agency can enforce without a lengthy and costly court process will enable swifter and stronger action to be taken against water companies that illegally pollute our environment.</p>



<p>Many residents have contacted me about pollution and the use of storm drains in our sewage system. There has also been a great deal of misinformation circulating on social media regarding the Government’s campaign to address these issues.</p>



<p>Last year, the Government introduced the Environment Act 2021 which was a bill designed to tackle this problem and reduce sewage pollution ignored by previous Governments. When the Environment Act was going through Parliament the Duke of Wellington, a hereditary peer, introduced an amendment that would legislate the complete elimination of storm drains and therefore of storm overflow sewage into our waterways. This of course sounds admirable, and indeed is something I support in principle. However, this amendment came without a plan for how it could be delivered and how such a vast project could be funded.</p>



<p>Initial assessments suggested elimination would cost between £150 &#8211; £650 billion. To put those figures in perspective, £150 billion was more than the entire schools, policing, and defence budgets put together. Therefore, the Government did not support the amendment, and I did not vote for it. In my view, the last thing people wanted was for their water bill to go through the roof.</p>



<p>Twitter mis-informers seized this opportunity and claimed we had all voted in favour of water companies dumping raw sewage into our rivers. Which was totally false, and ironically punished the Government for actually trying to do something about the problem ignored by previous Governments.</p>



<p>With this most recent announcement by DEFRA, I am glad to see the Government continuing the campaign to improve the quality of our waterways. To hold water companies to account, and ensure any polluter pays for the environmental harm they cause, the Environment Agency must take advantage of these new powers.</p>



<h1>Illegal crossings over the Channel:</h1>



<p>Many of you have contacted me about the number of small boats illegally crossing the English Channel in recent months. I appreciate the strength of feeling on this alarming issue and want to outline my position to you and explain some of the challenges we face in tackling this problem.</p>



<p>The number of illegal entries into the United Kingdom via small boats crossing the English Channel is too high. It endangers the lives of those making the journey, puts money into the pockets of ruthless and brutal people smuggling gangs, and puts undue pressure on our existing asylum system as well as our public services. I remain committed to an immigration policy that welcomes people to the UK through safe and legal routes, and an immigration policy that allows us to provide asylum to those in genuine need. However, it is clear many of those arriving in small boats are not here in genuine need of asylum, and as a result, the current situation cannot go on.</p>



<p>One reason for small boat crossings increasing in frequency is the success the Government has had in tackling other forms of illegal immigration. Such as increased checks and security for lorries and freight crossing the channel, effectively reducing the number of illegal entries into the UK through these means, and increasing the number of people turning to small boats as a way to enter the UK. The problem that now presents itself is how to police and secure hundreds of miles of coastline 24/7.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Parliament passed the Nationality and Borders Act which overhauled our approach to asylum and illegal migration. The legislation includes fairness towards those who need our help, and in welcoming people through safe and legal routes, but firmness in tackling abuse of the system and expediting the removal of those who have no legitimate claim for protection. It is worth noting that Labour opposed this Act designed to toughen our immigration system.</p>



<p>Further to changing the law in this country, the Government has recently signed a joint UK-France arrangement on tackling small boat crossings in the Channel which includes a 40% increase in the number of UK-funded officers patrolling French beaches. The new agreement lays the foundations for deeper UK-French co-operation to tackle illegal migration. The arrangement means, for the first time, specialist UK officers will be able to observe French officials at work in control rooms and on the ground patrolling the coastline.</p>



<p>It is clear, however, that big challenges still lie ahead, and that the number of small boats currently crossing the channel is unacceptable. The Prime Minister speaking recently on GB News said that tackling illegal immigration was a huge priority for his Government, and that while the recent joint UK -France arrangement was a big step in the right direction there was more that needs to be done. I share the Prime Minister’s view, and will continue engaging with my ministerial and Parliamentary colleagues to make the case for further measures to reduce cross channel migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maria calls on Barratt Homes to urgently progress fire safety remedial works at Crown Heights</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-calls-barratt-homes-urgently-progress-fire-safety-remedial-works-crown-heights" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Basingstoke MP, Maria Miller, chaired a meeting of the Crown Heights Residents Association, and Barratt Homes, the developer responsible for fire safety remedial works at Crown Heights. 
 
Maria said: “Crown Heights residents have been under untold pressure, as a result of the uncertainty around…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-calls-barratt-homes-urgently-progress-fire-safety-remedial-works-crown-heights</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Card Competition 2022 Finalists</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/VoteChristmas2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Since I launched my Christmas Card Competition for this year earlier last month, I have received hundreds of designs from children across Bassetlaw. These designs show off the sheer amount of artistic talent our children here in Bassetlaw have.
You can now cast your vote on who should win this year…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/VoteChristmas2022</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP asks Beverley and Holderness: Where is Your Favourite Curry?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-asks-beverley-and-holderness-where-your-favourite-curry" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
Graham Stuart MP is asking residents of Beverley and Holderness to nominate their favourite curry house.
 
The winner of the competition will be entered into the Tiffin Cup, a nationwide curry competition which has been running since 2005.
 
With many brilliant curry houses in Beverley and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-asks-beverley-and-holderness-where-your-favourite-curry</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg opens new early years facilities at Grendon Underwood Combined School</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-opens-new-early-years-facilities-grendon-underwood-combined-school" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP visited Grendon Underwood Combined School this morning to formally open their fantastic new early years facilities.
Greg said, "I know from my own children how important early years education is and it was uplifting to see such first class facilities and professional support in…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-opens-new-early-years-facilities-grendon-underwood-combined-school</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bring on the transport revolution – my monthly article for the Heatons Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/bring-on-the-transport-revolution-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bring-on-the-transport-revolution-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235858" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/heatons-post.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>Last month, I was delighted to hear that Transport for Greater Manchester had intervened to save over 60 bus routes and services linking communities across Greater Manchester.</p>
<p>Crucially, this means that the 7/7A route serving Heaton Chapel, Reddish and right through to Dane Bank will be saved. I know that this news came as a real relief to residents across Reddish and the <span class="markz7688x3w1" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heatons</span> who had got in touch with my office to express their concerns.</p>
<p>The bus routes had been earmarked for closure after national funding was due to end on the 4 of October. The local Labour team across the <span class="markz7688x3w1" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heatons</span> and Reddish worked exceptionally hard to prevent this closure from happening, with Cllr David Sedgwick launching a petition to highlight local strength of feeling. I have no doubt that work like this contributed to the decision to protect the 7/7A bus route.</p>
<p>With the 7/7A bus route saved, residents across Reddish and the <span class="markz7688x3w1" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heatons</span> can look forward to the full franchising of the Greater Manchester bus service. This plan, spearheaded by Greater Manchester Mayor Andy Burnham, starts next year. It means that prices can be capped, and services can be improved and better regulated.</p>
<p>I can’t wait for this pioneering work to get under way. For too long, people across Reddish and the <span class="markz7688x3w1" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heatons</span> have had to put up with a splintered bus network, where different providers charge different prices and operate unreliable services. We deserve to have a properly integrated and efficient system – and the franchising of the bus service will do just that. It is really transformative stuff.</p>
<p>So, I’d like to take a moment to thank local campaigners for working to save the 7/7A bus route, and I look forward to seeing Greater Manchester lead the way with our innovative public transport plan next year!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/bring-on-the-transport-revolution-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Bring on the transport revolution – my monthly article for the Heatons Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last month, I was delighted to hear that Transport for Greater Manchester had intervened to save over 60 bus routes and services linking communities across Greater Manchester. Crucially, this means that the 7/7A route serving Heaton Chapel, Reddish and right through to Dane Bank will be saved. I know that this news came as a […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/bring-on-the-transport-revolution-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Bring on the transport revolution – my monthly article for the Heatons Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235857</id>
    <published>2022-11-18T09:15:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-18T09:15:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne welcomes Government target to reduce energy demand</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/parliament/dunne-welcomes-government-target-reduce-energy-demand" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="7299" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;17 November 2022&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dunne welcomes Government target to reduce energy demand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Responding to the Autumn Statement, Philip Dunne welcomes the setting of a target to reduce energy demand in this country by 15% by 2030 and calls on the Government to ensure that the energy efficiency taskforce adequately engages with industry to ensure that the scheme will work and deliver reductions at a household level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-29200" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/rR7kzzpyoUc?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1542"&gt;Philip Dunne (Ludlow) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I congratulate my right hon. Friend on the exceptionally skilful delivery and content of his statement. I point particularly to the work that he was just touching on in response to the question from my right hon. Friend the Member for South Northamptonshire (Dame Andrea Leadsom) about energy efficiency. He has today set an interim target to reduce energy demand in this country by 15% by 2028. That is the first time that we have done that, as far as the Environmental Audit Committee, which I chair, is aware. It plugs a gap in the energy security strategy, which did not address reducing demand. I urge him, in his discussions with the Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy, to ensure that when the work of the energy efficiency taskforce is designed, there is engagement with the industry that has to deliver the reduction—unfortunately, neither the Treasury nor his predecessors in BEIS have done that adequately in previous schemes—to ensure that the scheme will endure, and actually work and deliver reductions at a household level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1572"&gt;The Chancellor of the Exchequer (Jeremy Hunt)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My right hon. Friend understands this extremely well, and he has done very good work with his Committee. This is a national ambition, which means that the Government and every family in the country need to work together to reduce our national energy bill by tens of billions of pounds, to meet our climate change commitments, and to reduce the average bill in this country at today’s prices by nearly £500. It is really worth doing, and we are putting our money where our mouth is with billions of pounds more investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-11-17/debates/fd6a4161-fa02-41d6-b4bd-a80d0f17a712/CommonsChamber#contribution-E4FE3E0E-D0E7-476C-809B-8341F1C881F4"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7299 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T22:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T22:20:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nothing new for a country in crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/nothing-new-for-a-country-in-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Responding to the Chancellor’s Autumn Statement, Newcastle North MP, Catherine McKinnell, commented: “Families are grappling with the biggest wage squeeze in a generation. Twelve years of Conservative failure exacerbated by twelve weeks of mini budget chaos has left our economy stagnant, borrowing costs up, prices skyrocketing, and ordinary people unable to meet their most basic … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/nothing-new-for-a-country-in-crisis/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Nothing new for a country in crisis</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7773</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T16:45:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T16:45:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Families"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Health and Social Care"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP demands DEFRA Secretary halts cuts to Cumbrian farmers</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437849/mp-demands-defra-secretary-halts-cuts-to-cumbrian-farmers"/>
  <updated>2022-11-17T16:33:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437849/mp-demands-defra-secretary-halts-cuts-to-cumbrian-farmers</id>
  <summary type="text">On the floor of the House of Commons this morning, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron urged the DEFRA Secretary to pause the phasing out of basic payments for farmers to stop them going out of business this winter.
Tim also asked for the Secretary of State to meet with Baroness Rock to discuss her recent review which has recommended more support for tenant farmers.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the floor of the House of Commons this morning, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron urged the DEFRA Secretary to pause the phasing out of basic payments for farmers to stop them going out of business this winter.</p>
<p>Tim also asked for the Secretary of State to meet with Baroness Rock to discuss her recent review which has recommended more support for tenant farmers.</p>
<p>Speaking during DEFRA Oral Questions in Parliament, Tim said<em>: "We will produce less food if we have fewer farmers.</em></p>
<p><em>"In just a few weeks' time, the Government plan to take 20% of the basic payment away from farmers, at the same time that barely 2% have got themselves into the new sustainable farming incentive.</em></p>
<p><em>"Will the Secretary of State consider delaying the reduction in the basic payment scheme to keep farmers farming while she sorts out the mess in her Department on the environmental land management schemes?</em></p>
<p><em>"Will she also meet Baroness Rock at the earliest opportunity to discuss her important tenant review?"</em></p>
<p>Responding, DEFRA Secretary Thérèse Coffey said: "<em>It has been well trailed for several years that we will shift from the EU common agricultural policy for distributing money to our farmers and landowners to using public money for public goods.</em></p>
<p><em>"That is why we have been working on the environmental land management schemes and will continue to make sure we get them right. We will make further announcements in due course."</em></p>
<p>Speaking afterwards, Tim said: <em>"The minister's woeful reply shows that the Government has their fingers in their ear when it comes to the plight of Cumbrian farmers.</em></p>
<p><em>"Moving to a new system where farmers are rewarded for the environmental work they do is undoubtedly a good thing - but not if the Government botch up the transition and farms are forced to go out of business in the process."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP questions Chancellor about additional payment for off-grid energy customers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/17/isles-mp-questions-chancellor-about-additional-payment-for-off-grid-energy-customers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Isles SNP MP Angus MacNeil has today asked the Chancellor of the Exchequer when off-grid households will receive the additional £200 support payment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3986" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/?attachment_id=3986" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg" data-orig-size="1024,571" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="WhatsApp Image 2022-11-17 at 14.49.32" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-3986" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/whatsapp-image-2022-11-17-at-14.49.32.jpeg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, The Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy confirmed to Mr Angus MacNeil that the additional support payment for people will be applied as a credit on electricity bills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Many constituents have been in touch with me to ask how and when this additional payment will be received.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is good that we now have confirmation from the UK government that the money will be credited to electricity bills.&amp;nbsp; However, we still don’t know when this credit will be applied and I took the opportunity to raise this with the Chancellor at the Autumn Statement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Chancellor told me that they are working on it and the money will be paid as quickly as possible.&amp;nbsp; This is not good enough; it is already mid-November and this scheme was announced two months ago!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is yet another example of how Westminster is failing Scotland, an energy-rich country.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Isles SNP MP Angus MacNeil has today asked the Chancellor of the Exchequer when off-grid households will receive the additional …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/17/isles-mp-questions-chancellor-about-additional-payment-for-off-grid-energy-customers/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3991</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T16:02:59Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T16:02:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Lest We Forget]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6538</id>
		<updated>2022-11-17T15:10:18Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-17T15:10:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="armistice day"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="remembrance day"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Remembrance Sunday"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve been attending Remembrance Sunday events since I was a youngster in the Boys Brigade. It’s one of those things I still look forward to all these years later, unlike some who see world wars as having happened a long time ago and ignore such traditions as belonging in the past and nothing to do<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Lest We Forget</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6540" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-5/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6540" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I’ve been attending Remembrance Sunday events since I was a youngster in the Boys Brigade. It’s one of those things I still look forward to all these years later, unlike some who see world wars as having happened a long time ago and ignore such traditions as belonging in the past and nothing to do with them.</p>



<p>Armistice Day first took place after the First World War, to commemorate the end of that awful conflict, on the 11th hour of the 11th day of the 11th month. Many people still observe it today, stopping for a two-minute silence to remember those who made the ultimate sacrifice. This year I was proud to spend it with staff and pupils at Swanshurst Girls School and a dwindling but determined bunch of veterans who have served this country well. The respect shown by those girls was something of which we should all feel proud.</p>



<p>A former Archbishop of Westminster is credited with conceiving of Remembrance Sunday which he saw as an opportunity to honour the dead of two world wars as well as other conflicts. There’s so much sacrifice and bravery to remember, including the Falklands (40th anniversary this year), Iraq, Afghanistan, Northern Ireland, and various peace keeping missions around the globe.</p>



<p>This year has taken on a new significance as British troops, although not currently committed to any conflict, are on high alert as we witness the horrors of Putin’s invasion of Ukraine. It was a topic of conversation among several of those I joined for West Midlands Travel (Birmingham) Sports &amp; Social Society’s Remembrance Sunday. I enjoyed spending the day with these people. Their history is rich in tales of bravery, lost comrades, and local feats of derring-do as they fought to protect buses at Yardley Wood depot from Luftwaffe bombs.</p>



<p>It’s easy to take freedom for granted but different if the tanks roll in and take it from you. Wearing a poppy, observing the 2-minute silence and commemorating those who gave their todays for our tomorrows is a small price to pay. I look forward to many more Remembrance Sundays.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/17/lest-we-forget/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mid November e-newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/mid-november-e-newsletter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to read my Mid-November e-newsletter
 
I weld yr e-gylchlythyr hwn yn Gymraeg cliciwch yma
 </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/mid-november-e-newsletter</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Autumn Statement to ‘restore economic stability’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/autumn-statement-restore-economic-stability" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local politicians have commented on the Chancellor’s Autumn statement delivered earlier today.
John Lamont MP said:
“The UK Government has produced a robust plan to restore economic stability, tackle inflation and boost economic growth.
“The Prime Minister and Chancellor are delivering for Scotland…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/autumn-statement-restore-economic-stability</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton welcomes plan to drive down inflation, as the Conservative Government invests £11 billion extra into schools and the NHS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-plan-drive-down-inflation-conservative-government-invests-ps11-billion" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Conservative Government is supporting every household with the cost of energy by extending the Energy Price Guarantee until April 2024, while uprating benefits and pensions in line with inflation, and providing £12 billion extra support for the most vulnerable.
To deliver on the people’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-plan-drive-down-inflation-conservative-government-invests-ps11-billion</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government Financial Statement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/government-financial-statement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Later today the Chancellor of the Exchequer will deliver his fiscal statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course of the last few weeks, I have been contacted by a number of my constituents from across Aldridge-Brownhills with regards to the Triple Lock and the uprating of benefits in the next financial year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me be quite clear, whilst we have to be fiscally responsible, &lt;strong&gt;I will not support an end to the Triple Lock for pensioners &lt;/strong&gt;and I expect the Chancellor of the Exchequer to increase benefits by inflation to help both vulnerable groups at this difficult time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2019 I stood on a manifesto commitment to protect pensioners in my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency, and I will ensure that I fulfil that commitment to them all.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Later today the Chancellor of the Exchequer will deliver his fiscal statement. Throughout the course of the last few weeks, I have been contacted by a number of my constituents […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4394</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T07:00:01Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T07:00:01Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex seeks assurances on future of Hanover Point following sale to Hanover Social Housing Ltd]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/11/alex-seeks-assurances-on-future-of-hanover-point-following-sale-to-hanover-social-housing-ltd/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14546</id>
		<updated>2022-11-16T14:10:42Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-16T13:54:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After news of its sale this week, Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham has written to the new owner of Hanover Point, a housing scheme for older people on the Glebe estate, to seek assurances about the future of the building. Anchor Hanover, a housing provider in the North of England, had been looking to sell [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/11/alex-seeks-assurances-on-future-of-hanover-point-following-sale-to-hanover-social-housing-ltd/">Alex seeks assurances on future of Hanover Point following sale to Hanover Social Housing Ltd</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on why Iran should be removed from UN commission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP visits new Town Council office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-visits-new-town-council-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Anne-Marie recently visited the new Town Council office that recently opened on Marygate in Berwick.  The new facility is situated on Marygate along from Anne-Marie's office in the town. 
The MP was invited to go along and see the new facility and catch up the Mayor Mike Greener, Gareth Davies the …</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-visits-new-town-council-office</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Britain’s Industrial Future</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/parliament/britains-industrial-future" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="2554" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;15 November 2022&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Britain’s Industrial Future&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister of State for Science, Technology, Research and Innovation George Freeman responds to an Opposition Day debate on Britain’s industrial future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-73006" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/3gaSLRFWuzk?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister of State, Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a great pleasure to serve in this debate and to have my first outing at the Dispatch Box as the returned Minister for science research, innovation and technology at the Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy—a name written proudly on the side of the building—in order to refute the litany of woe and failure that those on the Opposition Benches love to reel out, to paint a picture of a British economy that the businesses around this country would recognise and understand, and to set out in some detail the plans we have to support not only the industries of today, but the industries of tomorrow, for which this country is leading in creating the framework globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to a good debate, not least about the depression of the Opposition’s motion, which says very little about their own positive plans to develop an industrial sector for the 21st century, but simply looks to print a cheap leaflet for distribution on the doorstep. We can do better than that, and I hope that we will this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Minister for science, research and innovation in technology, my mission is to make the strategic shift in this country’s economy. The Labour party, in its long period in office, seemed to delight in—I remember the “Deputy Prime Minister” saying he was profoundly relaxed—all the deregulation in the City, the move to a service economy and deindustrialisation. This Government are absolutely committed to taking the crash of 2007-8 under the Labour Government, the difficult fiscal situation afterwards, the pandemic and the emergency in Ukraine as the wake-up call that they are to invest more in our industries of tomorrow and today, to develop our industrial resilience, to support the R&amp;D for tomorrow’s sectors, and to support our leadership in net zero. I would like to think that the Labour party would celebrate that. The truth is that British industry is leading the way in net zero in this country, and that is something we should be proud of. I will come to the detail of that in due course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3973"&gt;Grahame Morris (Easington) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the Minister give way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will make some progress in my opening remarks and then I will give way to the hon. Gentleman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my specific role and portfolio, my job is to support the industries of tomorrow. In life sciences, I set out with the then Minister the first 10-year life science strategy in this country. We launched the genomics programme, NHS digital and accelerated access, and we laid a lot of the foundations for this country’s success in the pandemic. Last year, we launched a 10-year space strategy for commercial leadership in the space sector, and we are now in the process of implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have set out a 10-year plan for fusion, and we are investing, through the UK Atomic Energy Authority, in the ground-breaking technology at the Culham Centre for Fusion Energy. We announced this summer that we are moving that to Nottinghamshire and creating the world’s first industrial deployment of fusion technology at commercial scale over the next 10 to 15 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are setting out a quantum strategy. On Friday, I was with the quantum industry, which is applauding us; we are No. 1 in Europe in the quantum industry and investment. That is a partnership between big companies—Toshiba, BT, BAE Systems and many others—and our very fertile ecosystem of small companies and universities. Similarly, I was proud, as the then Minister, to launch the UK’s first industrial strategy for agri-tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forgive me, then, if I do not take any lectures from the Labour party on the lack of an industrial strategy. Far from it, the former Member for Hartlepool and “Deputy Prime Minister” paid tribute to the Conservative party, to me, the then Chancellor and the then Minister, David Willets—who is now in the other place—for leading the thinking on a modern industrial strategy for a modern economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth, in the last few years that work has inevitably been interrupted, first by the pandemic—I am proud that the Conservative party put in £400 billion of business support for industry—and secondly by Ukraine, which has been a wake-up call to the world about the resilience of industrial supply chains. We have worked head and shoulders in the last year to beef up those industrial supply chains to protect British industry from that vulnerability, and we continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3973"&gt;Grahame Morris &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;rose—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4122"&gt;Alex Cunningham (Stockton North) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;rose—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me finish this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, the tightening of the global energy markets has hit many energy-intensive industries hard. We have announced £25 billion of support for the next six months. That is far from the doom and gloom of the motion, which, for anyone who reads it, paints a picture of this Government having no strategy or policy for industry, which is complete rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3973"&gt;Grahame Morris &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to the Minister for giving way on doom and gloom. There was a mention earlier of fleet solid support ships, which we on this side of the House have argued for many years should be built here for strategic reasons, with steel manufactured here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May I ask about rail and the home of the railways in the north-east? In my constituency, Vivarail—a world-beating, self-charging all-electric train manufacturer—is starved of Government support and investment. It could be a beacon for the future, so why is it not on the Minister’s list of shining examples?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason it was not on the list is that I was listing all the industries of tomorrow. I will come to the specific points he makes. The biggest customer for steel in this country is our rail sector, and we are proud that the UK rail industry, into which we are pouring an unprecedented level of investment, is a major user of British steel. I will come to the steel industry in a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motion paints a picture of doom and gloom and the collapse of manufacturing. It is time to put that stale old Labour trope to bed. The UK is still the ninth biggest manufacturing country in the world. Manufacturing this year contributed £205 billion in gross value added to the UK economy. We are the fourth largest manufacturing economy in Europe, supporting almost 2.5 million jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the last Labour Government, manufacturing jobs had been haemorrhaging. We stopped that in 2010 and, through major investment of the sort that I just set out, we have turned around this country’s manufacturing sector, which is now much more advanced. Again, I am surprised that Labour Members are not congratulating us on that. Manufacturing jobs were collapsing in this country, but 84% of manufacturing now takes place throughout the country, outside London, not just in the old industrial belt, but in the space economy in Cornwall and in Glasgow—I thought that Scottish National party Members would cheer that. There is the north Wales energy corridor, the south Wales compound semiconductor cluster and the Warwick robotics cluster. Our manufacturing economy is highly advanced, highly competitive and decentralised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3973"&gt;Grahame Morris &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;rose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will come to steel, shipbuilding and automotive shortly. I had not mentioned the hon. Gentleman’s rail point because I was highlighting the industries of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4359"&gt;Stephen Kinnock (Aberavon) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does the Minister know how many tonnes of British steel there are in a single wind turbine, onshore or offshore, in our country?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not have that figure at my fingertips, but I have a funny feeling that the hon. Gentleman does. The Under-Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy, my hon. Friend the Member for Thirsk and Malton (Kevin Hollinrake) will respond on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4830"&gt;Paul Howell (Sedgefield) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minister has talked about the space and science-led businesses around the country. On the north-east, in response to the hon. Member for Easington (Grahame Morris), we should not forget the tremendous things that are happening at NETPark in Sedgefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, fantastic things are happening at NETPark. One would think that the Labour party, which dominated County Durham politics for decades and seemed to indulge in the poverty up there, would celebrate the phenomenal turnaround in the north-east. It is one of our leading manufacturing regions. NETPark is home to Kromek and Newcastle is home to QuantuMDX. That is a great story of British manufacturing driving an advanced economy in the areas that were blighted by painful deindustrialisation. I am proud that the Conservative party is in the vanguard of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4122"&gt;Alex Cunningham &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt that we have new manufacturing to celebrate in the north-east, but Teesside’s steel industry is a shadow of its former self. It has a few hundred jobs, instead of the many thousands that existed a few years ago, before the Government abandoned us. Does the Minister agree that we should invest in Teesside steel now and use its product for the new industry jobs that we are promised?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to steel, and the hon. Gentleman makes an important point. There has been real pressure on the steel industry in the past 15 to 20 years. Global economic conditions are hugely challenging for all domestic steel sectors. There has been massive overcapacity, unfair overseas subsidies and steel dumping. The real issue is that global steel production has more than doubled since 1995 and China is by far the biggest contributor to that growth. In 1995, China accounted for 13% of the world’s steel production. By 2019, that had risen to 53%. There has been a phenomenal change in the global steel market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4264"&gt;Stephen Doughty (Cardiff South and Penarth) (Lab/Co-op)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been in this place 10 years today and I have worked with my local steel company since I was first elected. It has consistently raised the same issues with me: competitive electricity prices for the green steel it produces and ensuring that the industries of the future, particularly green industries, use UK steel. What exactly have the Government done to ensure that prices are competitive and that UK steel is used in those green industries? They have not done enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hon. Gentleman makes an important point about the challenge. We have done a lot—let me share that with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4264"&gt;Stephen Doughty &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the specific point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will deal with the specific point. Our ongoing support for the steel industry this year includes more than £800 million in relief for electricity costs, in addition to the energy bills relief scheme. The sector can apply for help with all sorts of energy efficiency, with decarbonisation and low-carbon infrastructure. More than £1 billion is available in competitive funding for the industry in that sector alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Several hon. Members rose—&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me just deal with this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are investing more than £600 billion to transform our country’s infrastructure—roads, rail, broadband and more—and we plan to procure 8.5 million tonnes of steel as part of that over the next decade; the hon. Member for Cardiff South and Penarth (Stephen Doughty) touched on procurement. We published an updated steel pipeline in June 2020, to help the industry plan ahead. The value of UK steel procured by the Government for major public projects in 2021, which I checked before coming to the debate, was £268 million—an increase of £160 million from the previous year. The steel procurement taskforce, which we set up as a joint working group between Government and the steel industry, published seven recommendations in February this year, and those are being implemented through updating the Cabinet Office procurement policy note. As the hon. Member will see—he asked a good question—we are taking serious steps on procurement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2021, the Secretary of State for Defence acquired specialist steel producer Sheffield Forgemasters, with £400 million of investment over the next 10 years, and Sheffield Forgemasters is working with other companies, including Rolls-Royce and the Canadian company General Fusion, on the development of nuclear power generation. In March this year, we successfully secured an expansive removal of US section 232 tariffs on UK steel and aluminium products, which means that UK steel and aluminium exports to the US can return to levels not seen since before 2018. We have also extended our steel safeguard measures for a further two years. I simply do not accept, and I do not think anyone listening to the debate would say, that the Government have done nothing and are doing nothing on procurement. It is simply not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4269"&gt;Andy McDonald (Middlesbrough) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am grateful to the Minister for giving way. I have heard what he has to say, but what does he say to the people of Teesside about his Government’s inaction in 2015? The Italian Government intervened at the Ilva plant in Taranto and came to the rescue of 25,000 workers. The French did the same in Florange, but this Government did absolutely nothing to protect our core industries at Redcar—and we have not forgotten it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would point out that last week, Green Lithium announced the UK’s first large-scale merchant lithium refinery and the first such refinery in Europe, to be built in Teesport, supported by the automotive transformation fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1584"&gt;John Penrose &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to ask the Minister the same question that I asked the hon. Member for Sefton Central (Bill Esterson) about a potential solution to the problems of high electricity costs faced by energy-intensive industries such as steel, which we have been hearing about from Opposition Members. Would a carbon border adjustment mechanism, which the Government have already consulted on and committed to in principle, help to level the playing field between British energy costs and those abroad, therefore making British heavy industry—particularly energy-intensive industries—far more competitive on the international stage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hon. Friend, as ever, makes a very interesting policy observation; as Minister for science, I will not accept it at the Dispatch Box, but I will raise it with the Ministers for industry and for energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4470"&gt;Alan Brown &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minister mentioned nuclear power. He heard what I said about costs earlier, but it is also reported that the Government are taking a 20% share in Sizewell C. Does that mean the Government are going to borrow £5 billion or £6 billion to pay for their 20% share of Sizewell C?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How interesting to hear the SNP take issue with—&lt;em&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interruption.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;]&lt;/em&gt; The hon. Member asked the question, so I will answer it. We are determined to make sure that, unlike parties on the Opposition Benches, we invest properly in new nuclear in this country, so that we have a resilient, clean and secure energy system. If that means an active industrial strategy to ensure we are able to do it, we are doing it. It would be nice to hear the SNP Government in Scotland take a similar approach to their future and to nuclear in this country, which is vital for the next few years as we get through this global tightening in energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4466"&gt;Peter Grant (Glenrothes) (SNP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will the Minister give way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I shall make some progress on this point about the automotive sector, which is also mentioned in the motion. The UK’s auto sector is hugely competitive globally. It is export-focused and has a very strong research and development base. In the last 20 to 30 years, it has transformed from what it was in the 1970s to a highly competitive and technologically advanced R&amp;D-based sector. It is also in the vanguard of the transition to net zero, and the UK is well placed to seize those opportunities because of the Government’s efforts, as we are pursuing an active industrial strategy for net zero in industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The automotive-related manufacturing sector is worth £58 billion to the economy and typically invests around £3 billion each year in R&amp;D—£3 billion in R&amp;D from the sector alone. There are 155,000 people employed in automotive manufacturing in the UK in 2021. That is 6% of total UK manufacturing. &lt;em&gt;[&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interruption.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;]&lt;/em&gt; Opposition Members may laugh about the success of the British automotive sector, but this is a tribute to business and industry adaptability and the Government’s partnership in setting out a framework for the net zero transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decarbonising transport is already starting to create thousands of jobs in green industries. The production of net zero road transport vehicles is on track to support the development of 72,000 jobs worth up to £9 billion to the economy. The Government have proven loud and clear that we can deliver a green transition and growth—something that all Opposition parties bitterly insisted was not possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4420"&gt;Gavin Newlands (Paisley and Renfrewshire North) (SNP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Minister talks about the decarbonisation of transport. Of the 4,000 buses that the former Prime Minister, the right hon. Member for Uxbridge and South Ruislip (Boris Johnson), promised nearly three years ago, how many are currently on the road in England?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will have to check the exact number. I am surprised that the hon. Gentleman did not mention Aberdeen’s leadership. With our support, Aberdeen is a hydrogen hub and there has been the creation of hydrogen hubs in Teesside, Harwich and all around the country. We are investing in another industry of tomorrow—green and blue hydrogen. His question is revealing. The motion suggests that the Government are doing nothing at all about hydrogen, but far from it. We are investing in the infrastructure for the hydrogen of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=14"&gt;John Redwood &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a danger that the UK could end diesel and petrol vehicle production too early compared with competitors—before we have a large electric car industry up and running? Would that not be bad news for our industry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My right hon. Friend makes an important point about ensuring that, as we lead on the delivery of the net zero automotive sector, we get the balance right, so that we are not unrealistically expecting consumers to make the transition too fast or, indeed, undermining our leadership in that sector. That is a fine balance that the Government are committed to striking. We are determined to lead the way in demonstrating green growth in pursuit of net zero, but we want to ensure that we capture the industrial leadership in that sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the automotive sector, we have again made significant investments. We have invested more than £1.2 billion to support innovative projects through the Advanced Propulsion Centre. The projects that it has funded have helped to create more than 50,000 jobs and save 277 million tonnes of carbon dioxide. Last month, we announced a record £200 million for the Faraday battery challenge. We have worked closely with Nissan and just announced a £1 billion investment to create a north of England electric vehicle hub in Sunderland that will safeguard 6,500 jobs. There have been investments of £227 million in Ford in Halewood, more than £100 million in Stellantis at the Vauxhall plant in Ellesmere Port, and £2.5 billion in Bentley—those are major investments from an industry that is growing in this country with Government support. It would have been nice to hear the Opposition at least pay tribute to some of that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the EV supply chain, we are actively investing in pursuit of our industrial strategy for green growth. The active travel fund has supported that £1 billion electric vehicle hub. We have also supported Pensana’s £145 million investment in East Yorkshire. Through the ATF, we recently supported a £60 million investment to develop hydrogen technologies with Johnson Matthey. Far from the Government abandoning our commitment to industry, we are doubling down on our commitment to help the existing industries of today to make the transition, and to support the industries of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shipbuilding industry in this country, which Opposition Members suggest has been decimated, actually employs 42,500 people and is worth £2.8 billion. It is a major sector. Naval orders through the Government remain an important driver of its prosperity. In 2020, the Ministry of Defence spent £3.8 billion on shipbuilding and repair, which directly supported 22,000 jobs around the economy. Over the last decade, we have seen once great names in shipbuilding, such as Harland &amp; Wolff, struggle, which puts that heritage at risk. Under the ownership of InfraStrata, however, Harland &amp; Wolff is now strong again; that resurgence is part of a general trend of global consolidation in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have seen how the symbiosis between MOD, naval and commercial buildings brings improved competitiveness, as businesses such as Cammell Laird deliver large commercial vessels alongside the Royal Fleet Auxiliary commitments. I am proud, as the Minister for Science, that the royal research ship Sir David Attenborough is one of the ships that has been built of British steel. The commissioning and delivery of the new aircraft carriers has been a massive shot in the arm. At the same time, we have seen big advances in key technologies, such as aluminium hull design and the application of robots for automated welding. That programme is also driving technological leadership. In 2019, ship boat repair maintenance was worth £2.6 billion to the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not think it is fair to suggest, as the motion does, that this Government have neither an interest in industry nor a policy for industry, and that we are abandoning industry—far from it. Not only are we helping our key industries deal with massive global challenges—the pandemic and the energy crisis—but we are actively pursuing an industrial strategy for the industries of tomorrow, and that is actively supporting clusters all around the country to drive levelling up and opportunity. It would be nice to hear the Opposition parties at least pay some tribute to the success of that private-public partnership and to the success and resilience of British industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-11-15/debates/c24b2ead-5339-42d5-bdc4-b9c05a5bb023/CommonsChamber#contribution-A6FD46C9-4291-485A-AE2B-6F181C7EA868"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2554 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T22:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T22:20:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/11/15/speech-conflict-in-ukraine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martin spoke in the House of Commons debate on the conflict in Ukraine (14 November 2022). Here is the speech in full transcribed from Hansard&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire)&lt;/strong&gt;: First, let me associate myself both with the Minister’s words about the armed forces supporting the training of the men and women of the Ukrainian armed forces, and with the words of the shadow Minister, the hon. Member for Plymouth, Sutton and Devonport (Luke Pollard), about Remembrance Sunday. I am very mindful that my brother, who is a veteran of Iraq and Afghanistan, attended the Cenotaph in Whitehall for the first time at the weekend with former comrades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is welcome to be standing here following the statement about the liberation of Kherson. Like so many people, it has been a joy to watch the videos and accounts of the liberation over the weekend. Unfortunately, there is a pattern in this conflict of the elation after the liberation of towns and villages being followed by revulsion and anger as we discover the litany of crimes committed by the Russian armed forces and administrators during their occupation. I shudder to think of what happened to those who were brave enough to resist the invasion during the early days of February, as was so memorably caught on camera for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;None the less, forcing the invading force off the west bank of the Dnieper should be celebrated for the triumph that it is, along with the liberation of the last remaining regional capital under renewed occupation. The decision of the retreating forces to blow bridges and mine the lines of the withdrawal demonstrates the direction in which they believe the conflict to be moving. We must hope, however, that it can move as quickly as possible in that direction to avoid Kherson facing the same sort of retribution that Russia has visited on the likes of Kharkiv and Mykolaiv.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that the targeting and destroying of civilian infrastructure has become such a feature of the Russian military handbook again demonstrates the weakness of its position and its repeated inability to abide by, as I think the whole House will agree, the key tenets of the Geneva convention—namely, its failure to avoid unnecessary suffering and to distinguish between civilians and combatants. That is as damning an indictment of its “Russkiy mir”, which it claims to be defending, as we are ever likely to see. I am sure that the Minister and others across the House will join me in beseeching the Russian Federation to withdraw from the rest of the country that it has illegally occupied since 2014, so that the suffering does not continue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The liberation of such a large port also brings into focus, as the Minister touched on, the global consequences of continuing this unnecessary conflict, not only because Kherson’s famous watermelons can now be exported, but because that applies to a whole host of other agricultural products of Ukraine’s famous black soil. Those grains and vegetable oils have effectively been held hostage by the Kremlin, by Vladimir Putin, as part of a strategy of resource terrorism that seeks to punish some of the poorest people in the world as a way of putting pressure on those who would support Ukraine. As the G20 summit comes to a close, overshadowed by this coercive diplomacy, I am sure we all hope that we will not face the same issue come the next summit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we talk about exports, we must also think about the health of the Ukrainian economy as a whole. Let us not forget the importance of providing, as the Minister mentioned, long-term economic guarantees to Ukraine to ensure that it can rebuild when the end of the conflict comes, as it must. The incredible potential that it has hitherto been unable to fully realise can be released only with a generous range of measures and with full integration into western economic networks—as Ukraine would wish—including the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the military and economic support that we give Ukraine and its people, we cannot forget the human element in all this and the fact that those people are fighting for so much more than economic growth or European security; they are fighting simply for the right to exist—that is, the right to exist not only as Ukrainians, but as who they are as people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am glad to have the opportunity to acknowledge the contribution made by the LGBTQ+ Ukrainians in this conflict. Their struggle is emblematic of what it is at stake, and not only because Putin and other Kremlin talking heads have specifically made their increasing prominence in that society a major plank of their spurious rationale for invasion. We know very well in this country that the realities of a wartime society can bring about large-scale social change, as previously under-represented groups come forward to demonstrate the role that they can play in society. It is through this conflict that we have seen how LGBTQ+ Ukrainians—known as the Pride brigade—have come forward to serve in their droves at every level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am very grateful for the work done by people such as Maksym Eristavi, who has documented the contribution that those Ukrainians have made to the defence of their common homeland. There is evidence that that is changing Ukrainian society for the better. Thanks to Maksym, I found out this summer that almost 60% of Ukrainians now have more positive attitudes to their LGBTQ+ siblings, a massive increase since 2016 when they were last asked the question. These people know what it is that they are fighting for: the possibility to live in a country where they are free from the dystopian control and coercion that we see too often in Putin’s Russia.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me bring my remarks to an end by thanking Ministers and the Government for ensuring that Ukraine can continue to push the invaders out of their country. They can be assured of the support from everyone on the SNP Benches, and essentially everyone across the House, in making sure that that continues to be the case. Here is hoping we will be marking the liberation of Ukraine sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://martindocherty.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/House_of_Commons_14_11_22_19_32_10.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Martin spoke in the House of Commons debate on the conflict in Ukraine (14 November 2022). Here is the speech in full transcribed from Hansard… Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): First, let me associate myself both with the Minister’s words about the armed forces supporting the training of the men and women of the ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/11/15/speech-conflict-in-ukraine/#more-1821449" aria-label="More on SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821449</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T16:39:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T16:39:45Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="House of Commons"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Speech"/>
    <category term="Ukraine Conflict"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Publicly owned renewable energy the way forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/11/publicly-owned-renewable-energy-the-way-forward/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/221109-COP27-Statement-Question-SUBTITLED.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the Prime Minister just coming back from COP27 last week, I reminded him that the Welsh Labour Government is investing in on-shore wind, thus reducing emissions, increasing energy security and using the profit for public good.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I asked him when he will lift the ban on on-shore wind in England and invest in this, the cheapest form of renewable energy. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">With the Prime Minister just coming back from COP27 last week, I reminded him that the Welsh Labour Government is investing in on-shore wind, thus reducing emissions, increasing energy security and using the profit for public good. I asked him when he will lift the ban on on-shore wind in England and invest in this, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8637</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T15:56:34Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T15:56:34Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New UK-France Agreement on Illegal Immigration</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/new-uk-france-agreement-on-illegal-immigration/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Home Secretary Suella Braverman has signed an agreement with her counterpart in France, Interior Minister, Gérald Darmanin to increase efforts on the French coast to prevent small boats bringing migrants across the Channel to the UK. This will increase the number of French police patrolling along their coast to 300, and for the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kieran Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6179</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T15:11:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T15:11:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-39" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I notice that last week The Chad dedicated a lot of column space to yet more attacks on my type of politics. The latest outburst coming from Councillor Hennigan who has accused me of ‘dog whistle politics’ over my comments on illegal immigrants. Ashfield’s Independent Councillor Hennigan stated…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-39</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-178" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">COP27 reaffirmed the UK’s commitments to deliver on the climate promises that were established at COP26 in Glasgow last year. And as the Prime Minister told the House last week, climate security and energy security go hand in hand. By committing £30 billion to support green industries in our…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-178</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2146-protecting-education-funding-is-not-a-hard-decision-to-make"/>
		<published>2022-11-14T10:02:36+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-11-14T10:02:36+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2146-protecting-education-funding-is-not-a-hard-decision-to-make</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Letter to Chancellor accepting difficult choices need to be made, but protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make. We owe it to the children of our country to put them first even in times of financial hardship, as many families already do every day. &lt;a href="https://t.co/hY6IftAEH6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hY6IftAEH6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1592095094580318209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Letter to Chancellor accepting difficult choices need to be made, but protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make. We owe it to the children of our country to put them first even in times of financial hardship, as many families already do every day. &lt;a href="https://t.co/hY6IftAEH6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hY6IftAEH6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1592095094580318209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Kind Fest <span style="color:#06396a;">Compassion in Politics?</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>It’s a pleasure to be speaking with you today as the co-Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Compassionate Politics. For those of you not familiar with our Parliamentary system, APPGs consist of members from different parties and from both Houses. We aim to work collaboratively together to address specific issues; in this case we want to shift the culture of politics to one that’s more compassionate.</p>
<h4><strong>WHAT’S WRONG WITH OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM?</strong></h4>
<p>My co-Chair Baroness Sayeeda Warsi and I convened the APPG on Compassionate Politics with the support of Matt &amp; Jennifer and the Compassion in Politics team back in 2019 as we shared the same concerns, as did many of our colleagues, about the increased divisiveness in politics which had steadily grown since 2016.</p>
<p>Many of us recognised that the division and discord being played out in Parliament, and also in some local authorities, was negatively impacting on our communities and how people were treating each other. A climate of fear, hostility and blame has been emanating from our politics. There was another effect: an escalating lack of trust in politics and politicians. A recent CiP poll showed that <a href="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/cip/pages/304/attachments/original/1663327185/OP19111_Compassion_in_Politics_Trust_and_Civility_-_Final_Tables.xlsx?1663327185">7 in 10 people don’t trust anything politicians say</a>. <a href="https://www.opinium.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/OP12494-Compassion-in-%20Politics-tables.xlsx">9 in 10 don’t think politicians have their interests at heart</a> and <a href="https://www.electoral-reform.org.uk/new-polling-reveals-just-how-powerless-people-feel-over-westminster/">2 in 3 feel completely powerless over the decisions being made at Westminster</a>. This incredibly disturbing for the health of our democracy.</p>
<p>However, as much as there are kindred spirits across the political spectrum, we’ve had a party-political system for centuries in this country which has been largely based on tribalism and narrow party rivalries, on making the electorate believe that each party has the answers to make their life better/fairer/safer for them and, unfortunately, negative campaigning has been seen by some to be part of that.</p>
<p>Negative campaigning has been successfully aided by a negative and partisan media, again, over many years. But over the last 16 years or so we’ve had another dimension: the wild west that is social media, where there is little policing of unlawful content by either the platforms or law enforcement agencies, let alone disinformation or misinformation; even legal but harmful content which includes platforms pushing information on suicide to school-age children is apparently off limits. Collectively, these exponentially ramp up the negativity, and even the hate.</p>
<h4><strong>SO WHAT SHOULD WE DO ABOUT IT? </strong></h4>
<p>Many of you will already know that as human beings we have an immense and innate capacity for compassion &amp; kindness: it’s what drives us to care for our family, look out for our friends, and help our neighbours. Within our communities, it can be nurtured and enabled, or it can be stifled and suppressed. The key to cultivating this compassion and kindness is leadership: leadership in our schools, leadership at work and, fundamentally leadership by politicians.</p>
<p>Again, as many of you will also know, ‘Compassion’ as defined by psychologists, involves an awareness of suffering with a commitment to alleviate and prevent it. Compassion is built on empathy, sympathy, and understanding – a tuning into the experience of self and others. Secondly, it requires commitment. Compassion doesn’t zero-in on the distress of others only to turn away, castigate, or blame. It seeks to understand and learn. Thirdly, it requires action – and action not only to alleviate the symptoms of suffering but to uproot their cause.</p>
<p>The recent pledges from the new Prime Minister and Chancellor for compassion and compassionate Conservatism are welcome but what do they mean?</p>
<p>To govern effectively through compassion will require a commitment to not only help those who are suffering today but also create conditions in which everyone can thrive tomorrow. Those instincts need to be activated and championed because, right now, we live according to quite alternate values. Refugees, social security users, and others are being decried, vilified, and shamed. This approach not only weakens us as a society, but it is also injurious to political engagement, to our very democracy.</p>
<p>A compassionate Government would recognise our common humanity, and that all human beings are equal. And within this, a compassionate immigration system in a country which upholds the rule of law, would abide by our obligations under the UN Refugee Convention which the UK is not only a signatory to, but helped to develop, after the horrors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As a Labour politician I would argue that the market doesn’t have all the answers to the economic crisis millions are facing, and that the immediate compassionate response to this crisis would be to recognise and address the fact that the <strong>richest 1% of individuals</strong> <strong>pay 12.5% of their income in tax</strong> compared with the <strong>50% lowest earners who pay 25.5% of their income in tax</strong>. Similarly, I would argue that the tax from corporations has flatlined over the last 12 years at about 2% and that some companies, for example, energy companies like BP have reported their highest quarterly profits for 14 years. Their figures are eclipsed by Shell who delivered second quarter profits of over £9bn.</p>
<p>I have argued that a compassionate Government would reflect this in their Autumn Statement next week.</p>
<p>There’s so much more policy-wise that could reflect compassion in the Government’s response to these very real issues and hardships so many in our country face.</p>
<p>But hand-in-hand with this, is an effort to reform the culture of our politics. Good policies can only come from good politics and if our government is truly committed to a compassionate future, it needs to create the right environment for such a future to grow and prosper. That has to start with the conduct of those in high office. We need to put the Ministerial and Members’ codes on a statutory footing so that they can be universally read and be properly enforced. The Prime Minister needs to appoint and then empower the government ethics advisor to launch independent investigations into ministerial conduct and strengthen the rules to prevent politicians from wilfully lying to the public.</p>
<p>Compassionate governance also means working alongside those we seek to serve, not dictating policies from the centre. We need to look at how we can reconnect politicians to the people we serve by shifting power away from Westminster. Establishing citizen and constituency assemblies as part of developing active and empowered citizens would be an important start.</p>
<p>Finally, this crisis in politics is not just a UK phenomenon; democracies across the world are facing the same issues. The last year’s insurrection at the Capitol is just one example of this. I would urge the like-minded to work together internationally for a new and compassionate politics.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7065</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remembrance Sunday 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/remembrance-sunday-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">They shall grow not old, as we that are left grow old. Age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn.
It was an honour to attend the Bicester Remembrance Service today on what is such an important day of reflection for so many. We must never forget those who have made the ultimate sacrifice for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/remembrance-sunday-2022</id>
    <published>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill plants a Remembrance stake in the Constituency Garden of Remembrance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday, Sir Bill Wiggin MP planted a wooden cross to pay tribute to service personnel from his constituency of North Herefordshire who have died in service to our country.  The Speaker of the House of Commons, Sir Lindsay Hoyle... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/#more-4548">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4548</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Opposition Day Debate on the Triple Lock for Pensions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/opposition-day-debate-triple-lock-pensions" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am not the first Member of the House to recognise that this motion is not a serious request of the Government, because we have the autumn statement in just nine days’ time. It is blatantly a political stunt to gain headlines.
I am surprised that Labour wants to draw attention to pensions policy,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/opposition-day-debate-triple-lock-pensions</id>
    <published>2022-11-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Network Rail Confirm Beckenham Junction Foot Bridge Repairs Timetable </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following pressure from Member of Parliament Bob Stewart, jointly with local Councillor Michael Tickner and London Assembly Member Peter Fortune; Network Rail have set out the timetable to replace the footbridge at Beckenham Junction. 
 
Bob, Michael and Peter wrote to Network Rail in October to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable</id>
    <published>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP secures key commitment on visas for international GPs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/11/04/matt-warman-mp-secures-key-commitment-on-visas-for-international-gps/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li>In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS.<br/>
• To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve this challenge’, for example working with the sector to explore umbrella sponsors for international GPs and holding meetings with the sector to encourage more GP surgeries to become visa sponsoring practices.</li>
</ul>
<p>On Wednesday (2nd November), a Westminster Hall debate took place in which the House<br/>
considered visas for international doctors.</p>
<p>Matt Warman MP raised the point that under current legislation, GPs who have come from abroad to train in the UK are in a position whereby it is difficult to obtain employment after they graduate. This is mainly because, in order for a General Practice to hire an international graduate, they must be registered as a ‘sponsoring practice’. This requires a large amount of complicated engagement with the Home Office, both on the international GP’s behalf and that of the practice hoping to sponsor them.</p>
<p>Following a discussion of members from different parties, the Minister for Immigration, Robert<br/>
Jenrick MP, acknowledged the issues raised and agreed to look at ways to make this process easier. The Minister assured that the Home Office will ‘reflect carefully on the points raised’ and stated that he will ‘task Home Office officials to work with stakeholders in the sector to give greater consideration to the central question of whether there is a simpler way in which GP practices can apply for relevant visas.’</p>
<p>The Minister for Immigration also pledged to ‘ask my officials to work with the sector to see whether there is a way forward to create umbrella bodies, if there is mutual support on both sides’, as well as agreeing to run further engagement events with the sector to discuss the process of becoming a sponsor.</p>
<p>Commenting on the positive outcome of this debate, Matt Warman said: <em>‘The Minister has </em><br/>
<em>demonstrated more progress on this important issue in the commitment that he has made to us </em><br/>
<em>today than we have seen in some years … I am immensely grateful to all Members who have brought the issue to life, and I look forward to continuing to work with the Minister on the outcome of the review, which will make a real difference to our constituents, and to doctors up and down the country.’</em></p>
<p>Matt will continue to liaise with the Home Office, the NHS and the Royal Colleges in order to turn this promise into action as quickly as possible.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS. • To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4133</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Families in St Helens North worried about the Tory-made economic crisis.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/11/04/families-in-st-helens-north-worried-about-the-tory-made-economic-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7553</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T11:15:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T11:15:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Jobs and recruitment </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-jobs-and-recruitment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Amid the political turmoil of the last few weeks, which hopefully will now start to calm down, there has been a tendency to assume that all the economic background is equally dreadful. But conversations with Ashford businesses suggest that one of the various economic problems discussed on the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-jobs-and-recruitment</id>
    <published>2022-11-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Facebook Meta Boosts Support Fund for Wildfire Victims</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/facebook-meta-boosts-support-fund-wildfire-victims" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Facebook Meta Boosts Support Fund for Wildfire Victims</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-11-03T10:51:00+00:00">Thu, 11/03/2022 - 10:51</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1165 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-03T10:51:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-03T10:51:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10619</id>
		<updated>2022-11-02T14:30:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-02T13:54:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday, I spoke in the House of Commons after several whistleblowers and victims of sexual harassment came forward to speak of their traumatic experiences whilst serving in the Royal Navy. Many woman have spoken out about the continued sexual harassment that they experienced over a number of years, at the hands of colleagues at ... <a title="Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/" aria-label="More on Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/final_6360f1545675000011d02fda_764768-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="6873214" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span class="searchHighlight">Halloween</span> is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for years, picking up speed in the past weeks and months as breathless newscasters break the news of more dark intrigue and betrayal. Make no mistake, this may look like a rollercoaster ride, but it is a dirty old carousel with the same old dangerously unfit horses going round and round in ever-decreasing circles.</p>
<p>Of course, seeing the first Asian Hindu take office is truly welcome, but this isn’t a new broom with Prime Minister Rishi Sunak. The Tories have been in office for over 12 years. He’s the ‘Party gate Chancellor” who broke his own laws. He isn’t going to make things better; he’s continuing their long-running austerity programme, degrading public services and growing food bank dependency. As a Brexiteer, he happily wedded us all to the deeply toxic Brexit ideology harming our businesses, starving them of vital staff and turbocharging inflation – especially basic food items, now running at up to 60% more.</p>
<p>Westminster’s hall of mirrors also shows Labour wedded to “make Brexit work”. It’s a nonsensical stance that, hand in hand with their stated belief that the Tories are not deporting enough people quickly enough is a chilling reflection.</p>
<p>And just when you thought that one of the most frightening apparitions had been removed, it is back where it was. Suella Braverman, the Home Secretary, whose dream is *not* of a brighter future for families, or a reduced skills shortage or even an end to people trafficking. No, it is her stated “dream and obsession” to see a flight take asylum seekers to Rwanda. Sacked only 6 days earlier having broken the ministerial code, she is back in the job tasked with upholding law and order and breached national security. She is back alongside colleagues at the helm of the ghostly pirate ship that is the Tory Government.</p>
<p>It’s a horror show we should be done with. The UK is substantially poorer than independent counties comparable to Scotland, with wider inequality, higher child and pensioner poverty and lower productivity. It is time for Scotland to choose a better path.</p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Halloween is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6525</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill of Rights Bill]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1704</id>
		<updated>2022-10-31T11:16:52Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-31T07:00:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bill of Rights Bill"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="European Convention on Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="legislation"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Parliament"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith wants Bradford at the centre of the next Rugby League World Cup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-wants-bradford-at-the-centre-of-the-next-rugby-league-world-cup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities in her Bradford South constituency:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Week in, week out, local communities come together to support their clubs, their local kids’ teams and young players.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, levels of investment and opportunities haven’t always matched the pride we feel in our towns and cities, but it’s moments like the world cup that will give communities the opportunities to stand tall and showcase where they live to the world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A compelling levelling-up bid has been submitted to government for a world-class stadium and training complex for elite sports with a Rugby League Skills, Training and Education centre in Odsal to serve the people of Yorkshire and the North. I can’t wait to host the world cup again in a decade’s time and be standing in our very own Odsal stadium in Bradford cheering England on!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding to Judith’s invitation to visit Odsal, Sports Minister Stuart Andrew MP said: “If I’m still in post by the end of the week I’ll still come but, if not, I’ll leave a note to my successor that their first trip needs to be to Bradford!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2022 Cup’s world-leading social impact programme has invested more than £26 million in equipment and facilities, volunteering, mental health, culture and education, to transform clubs into hubs for their communities. And, for the first time, the men’s, women’s and wheelchair tournaments will be held concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study from the Sheffield Hallam University shows that investment in sport and physical activity gives back four times the investment in social value, equivalent to around £72 billion each year across the UK, improving people’s health and wellbeing, creating jobs and stimulating local economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith is fighting for Bradford to have its share:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When the competition is over and the winning teams raise their trophies, it is only the start of the story for communities, not the end. With the Rugby League world cup in full swing, Bradford’s year as capital of culture in 2025, and Bradford’s bid for a world-class stadium and sports complex that will bring over a billion pounds of benefits to Bradford, now is the time to ensure that people of Bradford benefit from this legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3c9.png" alt="🏉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;The Rugby League World Cup &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLWC2021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@RLWC2021&lt;/a&gt; is more than just a competition – it’s a force for good that can transform the fortunes and unlock the potential of towns and cities like Bradford.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; Today I led a debate in Parliament celebrating this fantastic sport. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheRFL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheRFL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ysM6QHjEO9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ysM6QHjEO9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1584880580881063937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, culture, sports, stadium, odsal, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/santander-picture.jpg.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" alt="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has said that banking provision in the constituency has been totally wiped out. "People will have to travel over three miles to get to a bank,” she said, adding that the bank has “failed to take into account the social costs to the local area of removing this vital&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, will, local, bradford, people, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, people, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford. Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2685</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Constituent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing to do so if they contact me directly. But these emails are designed to be informative about local matters, and go to everyone who wants them, regardless of political persuasion, and I do not want to change their local focus even at times when there are significant events at a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charity Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a reminder that the Charity Volunteer Fair, which was postponed because of the sad death of Her Majesty the Queen, is being held between 4pm and 6pm this Friday, 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; October at the Dell Centre, St Giles Church, Park Lane, Ashtead, KT21 1EJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 20 charities will be there, and there will be a wide range of volunteering opportunities. So please do come along. If you can’t make it but are interested in volunteering, please let me know and I will steer you towards the right opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom Methodist Church &amp;#8211; Warm Wednesdays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epsom Methodist Church is launching a programme of Warm Wednesdays for the winter if people are struggling with their bills and need a place to go and warm up and get some company. The events will be held every Wednesday from November 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; until the end of February. From 9am &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be complimentary hot drinks served in their café, from  12.30 &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be Hot and tasty soup and a roll, from 2pm onwards complimentary hot drinks and homemade cakes, and from 3pm &amp;#8211; 6pm a family after-school club with space for homework, story time, games, films and a free hot meal for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church is in Ashley Road, Epsom, KT18 5AQ. People are welcome just to drop in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom &amp;amp; Ewell Energy Relief Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally thank you to everyone who has supported the Epsom and Ewell Energy Efficiency Programme. The appeal has already raised more than £12,000. If you do not need the £400 Government contribution towards bills this winter, please do donate it to the programme and help those locally who are already struggling with higher bills make their homes more energy efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of how to give are at &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/98eeCRO3xsv5ggnEf9CRxP?domain=justgiving.com"&gt;https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best wishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/"&gt;Local Update&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Constituent I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things. A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6321</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Zahawi guests at Conservative Annual Dinner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nadhim Zahawi, Chancellor of the Duchy of Lancaster, Minister for Intergovernmental Relations and Minister for Equalities, was the guest speaker at the Bexleyheath and Crayford Conservative Association on Thursday evening (13 October) held at Stuzzichini restaurant in Bexleyheath. In the Chair was…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner</id>
    <published>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking with Business South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Great to speak with Business South about the work they are doing to support businesses in our region, encouraging new start-ups and increasesing apprenticeship opportunities across Southampton. The pressures of increasing energy costs and staff shortages are a big worry for Southampton businesses and I will continue to push for more action to help these [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/">Speaking with Business South</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5068</id>
    <published>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP welcomes Prime Minister Liz Truss speech to Conservative Party Conference 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning the Prime Minister set out our Conservative vision for the future. A country focussed on growth, aspiration and enterprise. Turning away from those who say much and do little, the anti-growth coalition we are so used to seeing on our screens and in the hall today.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[CHECKMATE!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=467</id>
		<updated>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/september-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5588" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" data-type="URL" data-id="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for September 2022.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for September 2022.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5587</id>
    <published>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="September"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bust Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/09/27/bust-budget/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</p>



<p>The tax cuts in this mini budget, are mainly for the super wealthy, for corporations and for the bankers. The top tax rate of 45p (%) has been completely removed, which is great news for those lucky few that earn over £150,000 a year. Corporation tax increases have been discarded, and the cap on bankers’ bonuses brought in after the financial crisis of 2008 have been scrapped.</p>



<p>But the Tories aren’t content with just giving handouts to the rich, they have also increased the number of Universal Credit recipients who have to actively search for work and attend weekly or fortnightly job centre appointments, if they are working up to 15 hours a week. If they don’t then their benefits will be reduced. Unsurprisingly the mini-budget also attacks trade union rights further, making it harder for working people to strike for the pay and conditions they deserve.</p>



<p>While they have suspended National Insurance increases and cut stamp duty, this support is minute compare to the support for those best off in society. Even in terms of energy bill support, prices being frozen where they are now, simply means they are only twice what they were last year, at the same time that the price for everything else from food to transport is increasing, while wages and benefits remain completely stagnant.</p>



<p>This budget does not serve the needs of the people of Nottingham, it does not help those who need help the most. People earning £20,000 will only save £167 a year. What it will do is drive Britain into an inflationary spiral. It will cause the prices of the goods that residents need to survive to increase further, at a time where benefits and wages are not rising. This will wipe out any gains that residents in the city see from this mini-budget.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg"><img src="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2931" width="398" height="271" srcset="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg 1024w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-768x524.jpg 768w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1536x1047.jpg 1536w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px"/></a><figcaption>the Tory mini-budget will only give most people small change</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Tories say their budget will stimulate growth; it remains to be seen if it will. What is certain though is that growth in the economy is pointless if it does not lead to increased wages for the average person, if people are not supported to re-skill and obtain jobs in growing sectors, and if people do not have access to suitable affordable housing, whether that’s via home ownership or renting.</p>



<p>The mini budget does nothing to help achieve these aims, Nottingham Labour strongly believe that the budget will not help the people of Nottingham, it will only help a tiny minority of people. A Labour government is needed nationally to give the people of this country and of Nottingham the support and help that they need, and that they deserve.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</updated>
    <category term="east midlands"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Cuts"/>
    <category term="debt"/>
    <category term="inflation"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="taxes"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mum’s Here With Us, Yet Already Gone</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/mums-here-with-us-yet-already-gone/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3151</id>
    <published>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom</h2>



<p>The availability of free education is a gift, but only if it can come with high quality. Google Classroom has given students in classrooms around the country an online option to supplement their learning. A potential downside to these options is the inability to meet with professors and apply classroom learning. As a part of the University of Washington system, we have found the use of Google Classroom during the quarter distance courses produced good results for both parties. Distance learning is here to stay and has only grown over time. If you want to make sure you aren’t left behind in a digital world, you may want to consider your options and how they will help or hurt your future professional prospects.</p>



<p>Google Classroom is a reliable one-stop-shop for managing all of your coursework and communication. It is definitely worth checking out if you are in a distance learning program, or even just want to streamline some of your everyday communication tasks.</p>



<h3>Benefits and Drawbacks</h3>



<p>There are several other features that set Google Classroom apart from the competition. It is a free tool and it works on computers and mobile devices through the GAFE platform. The discussion features of Google Classroom do an excellent job at encouraging interaction between students and teachers, making it a very effective tool for working with groups of all sizes. The major drawback to Google Classroom is that it is a relatively new tool, so it does not work with iPads, Android tablets or Kindle Fires. The lessons created within Google Docs can be exported directly into Google Classroom on the computer, but in order to view or edit those documents or upload them onto the iPad tablet, students will have to use other third-party tools such as Documents 5 and iBooks Author.</p>



<h2>Integration</h2>



<p>If you are using Google Classroom for your teaching and learning, it is important to note that it does require integration with Google Apps for Education. This means that you are using Gmail along with Calendar and Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides) etc., so the other school faculty members need to have access to all of these tools. The obvious way to do this is through the use of a domain. It is required that you have a domain in order to use Google Classroom or any other GAFE tool/application.</p>



<p>By going through a step by step process, one can easily move one’s entire digital repository into Google Classroom for easy organization and management; therefore, allowing access to all student work without having to worry about losing any data or files that are not needed for a current class engagement.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom Future Prospects</h2>



<p>According to the Scholastic Parent &amp; Child list of the most popular educational apps , in 2015 Classroom wasn’t one of them, indicating that this tool is still relatively new and also relatively unknown. While the design is nothing particularly innovative, the new Google Classroom 2022 is a promising step towards more effective and efficient learning, especially in a classroom setting. Though it appears to be geared towards teachers, students will benefit from having access to Google Classroom, whether they’re in an online or a traditional classroom. With that said, it should be noted that it may take some time before this update fully penetrates into secondary schools and universities. But nonetheless, Google Classroom is off on the right foot, leaning further into an online world which we’ll all have to face sooner or later.</p>



<h2>Bottom Line</h2>



<p>Google Classroom has made a huge impact in the world of educational technology, especially for teachers who don’t have face-to-face access to students. It’s a powerful tool that will likely continue to be developed and improved upon, as educators keep gravitating towards it.</p>



<p>In the end, there is no one best way to teach and learn, but instead many valid options. Whether you are interested in the low-cost education of a MOOC or the high-end technology of Sketchfab virtual reality tours, it’s exciting to see that educational technology is progressing at a rapid rate. Let’s hope that as more schools begin to adopt innovative techniques like Google Classroom, we will continue to see positive changes in how students learn around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission. Google […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=211</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=XdL2KTMV" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-637878ebac9fb" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-637878ebac9fb').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"637878ebac9fb","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-637878ebac9fb" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-637878ebac9fb" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="637878ebac9fb" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_637878ebac9fb" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_637878ebac9fb" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_637878ebac9fb" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_637878ebac9fb" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_637878ebac9fb" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_637878ebac9fb" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_637878ebac9fb_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-637878ebac9fb script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxxQm2BDd2CPLtuN-DSztYVRZdiNy_aHrIdOhC-8GCsbEmTw9UyOhOHpg7QxHn4m0eboGUcjpTAyzXxsLMddg' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
