<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-11-15T18:35:42Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/11/15/speech-conflict-in-ukraine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Martin spoke in the House of Commons debate on the conflict in Ukraine (14 November 2022). Here is the speech in full transcribed from Hansard&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire)&lt;/strong&gt;: First, let me associate myself both with the Minister’s words about the armed forces supporting the training of the men and women of the Ukrainian armed forces, and with the words of the shadow Minister, the hon. Member for Plymouth, Sutton and Devonport (Luke Pollard), about Remembrance Sunday. I am very mindful that my brother, who is a veteran of Iraq and Afghanistan, attended the Cenotaph in Whitehall for the first time at the weekend with former comrades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is welcome to be standing here following the statement about the liberation of Kherson. Like so many people, it has been a joy to watch the videos and accounts of the liberation over the weekend. Unfortunately, there is a pattern in this conflict of the elation after the liberation of towns and villages being followed by revulsion and anger as we discover the litany of crimes committed by the Russian armed forces and administrators during their occupation. I shudder to think of what happened to those who were brave enough to resist the invasion during the early days of February, as was so memorably caught on camera for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;None the less, forcing the invading force off the west bank of the Dnieper should be celebrated for the triumph that it is, along with the liberation of the last remaining regional capital under renewed occupation. The decision of the retreating forces to blow bridges and mine the lines of the withdrawal demonstrates the direction in which they believe the conflict to be moving. We must hope, however, that it can move as quickly as possible in that direction to avoid Kherson facing the same sort of retribution that Russia has visited on the likes of Kharkiv and Mykolaiv.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact that the targeting and destroying of civilian infrastructure has become such a feature of the Russian military handbook again demonstrates the weakness of its position and its repeated inability to abide by, as I think the whole House will agree, the key tenets of the Geneva convention—namely, its failure to avoid unnecessary suffering and to distinguish between civilians and combatants. That is as damning an indictment of its “Russkiy mir”, which it claims to be defending, as we are ever likely to see. I am sure that the Minister and others across the House will join me in beseeching the Russian Federation to withdraw from the rest of the country that it has illegally occupied since 2014, so that the suffering does not continue.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The liberation of such a large port also brings into focus, as the Minister touched on, the global consequences of continuing this unnecessary conflict, not only because Kherson’s famous watermelons can now be exported, but because that applies to a whole host of other agricultural products of Ukraine’s famous black soil. Those grains and vegetable oils have effectively been held hostage by the Kremlin, by Vladimir Putin, as part of a strategy of resource terrorism that seeks to punish some of the poorest people in the world as a way of putting pressure on those who would support Ukraine. As the G20 summit comes to a close, overshadowed by this coercive diplomacy, I am sure we all hope that we will not face the same issue come the next summit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we talk about exports, we must also think about the health of the Ukrainian economy as a whole. Let us not forget the importance of providing, as the Minister mentioned, long-term economic guarantees to Ukraine to ensure that it can rebuild when the end of the conflict comes, as it must. The incredible potential that it has hitherto been unable to fully realise can be released only with a generous range of measures and with full integration into western economic networks—as Ukraine would wish—including the European Union.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the military and economic support that we give Ukraine and its people, we cannot forget the human element in all this and the fact that those people are fighting for so much more than economic growth or European security; they are fighting simply for the right to exist—that is, the right to exist not only as Ukrainians, but as who they are as people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am glad to have the opportunity to acknowledge the contribution made by the LGBTQ+ Ukrainians in this conflict. Their struggle is emblematic of what it is at stake, and not only because Putin and other Kremlin talking heads have specifically made their increasing prominence in that society a major plank of their spurious rationale for invasion. We know very well in this country that the realities of a wartime society can bring about large-scale social change, as previously under-represented groups come forward to demonstrate the role that they can play in society. It is through this conflict that we have seen how LGBTQ+ Ukrainians—known as the Pride brigade—have come forward to serve in their droves at every level.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am very grateful for the work done by people such as Maksym Eristavi, who has documented the contribution that those Ukrainians have made to the defence of their common homeland. There is evidence that that is changing Ukrainian society for the better. Thanks to Maksym, I found out this summer that almost 60% of Ukrainians now have more positive attitudes to their LGBTQ+ siblings, a massive increase since 2016 when they were last asked the question. These people know what it is that they are fighting for: the possibility to live in a country where they are free from the dystopian control and coercion that we see too often in Putin’s Russia.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me bring my remarks to an end by thanking Ministers and the Government for ensuring that Ukraine can continue to push the invaders out of their country. They can be assured of the support from everyone on the SNP Benches, and essentially everyone across the House, in making sure that that continues to be the case. Here is hoping we will be marking the liberation of Ukraine sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://martindocherty.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/House_of_Commons_14_11_22_19_32_10.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Martin spoke in the House of Commons debate on the conflict in Ukraine (14 November 2022). Here is the speech in full transcribed from Hansard… Martin Docherty-Hughes MP (SNP, West Dunbartonshire): First, let me associate myself both with the Minister’s words about the armed forces supporting the training of the men and women of the ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/11/15/speech-conflict-in-ukraine/#more-1821449" aria-label="More on SPEECH: CONFLICT IN UKRAINE">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821449</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T16:39:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T16:39:45Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="House of Commons"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Speech"/>
    <category term="Ukraine Conflict"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Future Breckland Board</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/future-breckland-board-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2553" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">15 November 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Future Breckland Board</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span><span>All of our market towns face the familiar challenge of balancing new growth and development with the needs of the communities living in, and around, them – all the while preserving the unique rural heritage and way of life that we all cherish, and that makes our part of the world such an attractive place to visit.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>That’s why, alongside my support for Breckland Council’s ‘Future Breckland Plan’ initiative (see more </span></span></span><span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/future-breckland-plans"><span><span><span>here</span></span></span></a></span><span><span><span>), I was pleased to be involved in the latest ‘Future Breckland Board’ meeting this afternoon – hosted by Cllr Sam Chapman-Allen (Leader of Breckland Council) and Maxine O’Mahony (Chief Executive of Breckland Council).</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>This group is a collection of leaders from across Breckland’s public and private sectors, straddling a wide variety of industries and sections of society and already inspiring the work of other district councils across the country. </span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>I am delighted to continue playing my part in the conversation and look forward to working with local councillors, businesses, community groups and many others as we all look to ensure Breckland remains a thriving and vibrant place to live and work in, as well as visit.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>To see more on my work with the ‘Future Breckland Board’, please click </span></span></span><span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/future-breckland-board"><span><span>here</span></span></a>.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>To see more on my work on ‘Planning and Protecting Our Rural Landscape and Heritage’, please click </span></span></span><span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/planning-and-protecting-our-rural-landscape-and-heritage"><span><span>here</span></span></a></span>.</span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2553 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T16:14:20Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T16:14:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Publicly owned renewable energy the way forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/11/publicly-owned-renewable-energy-the-way-forward/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/221109-COP27-Statement-Question-SUBTITLED.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the Prime Minister just coming back from COP27 last week, I reminded him that the Welsh Labour Government is investing in on-shore wind, thus reducing emissions, increasing energy security and using the profit for public good.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I asked him when he will lift the ban on on-shore wind in England and invest in this, the cheapest form of renewable energy. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">With the Prime Minister just coming back from COP27 last week, I reminded him that the Welsh Labour Government is investing in on-shore wind, thus reducing emissions, increasing energy security and using the profit for public good. I asked him when he will lift the ban on on-shore wind in England and invest in this, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8637</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T15:56:34Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T15:56:34Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP congratulates award-winning Barra hospitality</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/15/isles-mp-congratulates-award-winning-barra-hospitality/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="3975" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/15/isles-mp-congratulates-award-winning-barra-hospitality/tigh/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg" data-orig-size="2000,1200" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="tigh" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-3975" width="363" height="217" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=363 363w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=723 723w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/tigh.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 363px) 100vw, 363px"/></a></figure>



<div class="is-layout-constrained wp-block-group"><div class="wp-block-group__inner-container">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg"><img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="3977" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/15/isles-mp-congratulates-award-winning-barra-hospitality/heathbank/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg" data-orig-size="300,210" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;14&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5DS&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1650540007&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;24&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;100&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.004&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="heathbank" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg?w=300" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg?w=300" alt="" class="wp-image-3977" width="388" height="272" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/heathbank.jpeg?w=150 150w" sizes="(max-width: 388px) 100vw, 388px"/></a></figure>
</div></div>



<p>Angus Brendan MacNeil, SNP MP for Na h-Eileanan an Iar, has praised two Barra businesses for winning awards from SME News (Small Medium Enterprise News) in the Family Business Awards 2022.</p>



<p>Tigh-Na-Mara Guest House was awarded “Best Traditional Stone Cottage Accommodation” in Scotland while the Heathbank Hotel won “Best Family-Run Hotel” in the Hebrides.</p>



<p>Commenting Mr MacNeil said:</p>



<p>“Congratulations to Linda and Archie MacLean, Tigh-Na-Mara Guest House and Marion MacNeil and her team at the Heathbank Hotel.</p>



<p>“Linda has run the Guest House in Castlebay for a number of years, and I of course might be biased as it was my granny’s house and Linda is my cousin and I can’t forget that Marion is my neighbour. But of course the judges of this competition weren’t biased, so like many others, I am absolutely delighted that they are both winners in their categories.</p>



<p>“Both are very deserving of such an award. The fact that the Guest House is the best in Scotland says something not just for Linda but for Barra as well similarly for the Heathbank team. It is congratulations all round or “slainte” as they say in Heathbank.”</p>



<p/>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Angus Brendan MacNeil, SNP MP for Na h-Eileanan an Iar, has praised two Barra businesses for winning awards from SME …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/11/15/isles-mp-congratulates-award-winning-barra-hospitality/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3973</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T15:47:48Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T15:47:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[No one should die in poverty, says Alex as he proposes new law to strengthen employment rights and financial support for the terminally ill]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/11/no-one-should-die-in-poverty-says-alex-as-he-proposes-new-law-to-strengthen-employment-rights-and-financial-support-for-the-terminally-ill/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14537</id>
		<updated>2022-11-15T15:20:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-15T15:20:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A bill (Terminal Illness [Support and Rights] Bill) proposed by Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham to strengthen employment rights of terminally ill people, and stop people with terminal illnesses falling into fuel poverty will be debated in the House of Commons on Friday 18 November. Alex, who came twelfth in the draw for Private Members’ [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/11/no-one-should-die-in-poverty-says-alex-as-he-proposes-new-law-to-strengthen-employment-rights-and-financial-support-for-the-terminally-ill/">No one should die in poverty, says Alex as he proposes new law to strengthen employment rights and financial support for the terminally ill</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New UK-France Agreement on Illegal Immigration</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/new-uk-france-agreement-on-illegal-immigration/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Home Secretary Suella Braverman has signed an agreement with her counterpart in France, Interior Minister, Gérald Darmanin to increase efforts on the French coast to prevent small boats bringing migrants across the Channel to the UK. This will increase the number of French police patrolling along their coast to 300, and for the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kieran Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6179</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T15:11:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T15:11:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins MP: statement regarding East-West Cycle Path proposals and permanent closure of Crow Lane</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/15/toby-perkins-mp-statement-regarding-east-west-cycle-path-proposals-and-permanent-closure-of-crow-lane/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/15/toby-perkins-mp-statement-regarding-east-west-cycle-path-proposals-and-permanent-closure-of-crow-lane/">Toby Perkins MP: statement regarding East-West Cycle Path proposals and permanent closure of Crow Lane</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/15/toby-perkins-mp-statement-regarding-east-west-cycle-path-proposals-and-permanent-closure-of-crow-lane/">Toby Perkins MP: statement regarding East-West Cycle Path proposals and permanent closure of Crow Lane</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5131</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T13:54:49Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T13:54:49Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Campaign"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>‘A RACE TO THE BOTTOM IN WHICH OUR CHILDREN WILL BE THE BIGGEST LOSERS’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/a-race-to-the-bottom-in-which-our-children-will-be-the-biggest-losers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine led a debate on behalf of 109,000 petitioners against the Government’s proposals to reduce minimum staff-child ratios in England for 2-year-olds from 1:4 to 1:5. The debate followed a petition started by Zoe and Lewis Steeper, whose 9-month-old son, Oliver, tragically died after a medical emergency in a nursery. Opening the debate, Catherine paid … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/a-race-to-the-bottom-in-which-our-children-will-be-the-biggest-losers/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">‘A RACE TO THE BOTTOM IN WHICH OUR CHILDREN WILL BE THE BIGGEST LOSERS’</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7774</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T12:43:17Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T12:43:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Children and Young People"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="childcare"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maria joins Salvation Army ‘As One’ community brunch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-joins-salvation-army-one-community-brunch" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Basingstoke MP, Maria Miller, dropped into the local Salvation Army branch at their community brunch to share information on Borough Council support schemes with the cost of living. 
 
Maria said: “Our community has always worked hard to support those most in need, and it is doing so now. That’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-joins-salvation-army-one-community-brunch</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Outwood Academy Valley in Worksop</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/outwood-academy-valley-worksop" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Thank you to Mr Cavill and the pupils at Outwood Academy Valley in Worksop for inviting me to their poignant Armistice Day performance last week
It was lovely to see our local youngsters paying their respects and recognising the sacrifices of our armed forces. They are a credit to our community.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/outwood-academy-valley-worksop</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Invites Students From Beverley and Holderness To Visit Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-invites-students-beverley-and-holderness-visit-parliament" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, is inviting students across his constituency to visit Parliament or for teachers to invite him to visit their school.
UK Parliament week runs between 14th-20th November and is designed to spread the word about how Parliament works. To…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-invites-students-beverley-and-holderness-visit-parliament</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>Conservative trade deals will put Cumbrian farmers out of business, MP tells Minister</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437750/conservative-trade-deals-will-put-cumbrian-farmers-out-of-business-mp-tells-minister"/>
  <updated>2022-11-15T11:16:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437750/conservative-trade-deals-will-put-cumbrian-farmers-out-of-business-mp-tells-minister</id>
  <summary type="text">On the floor of the House of Commons last night, local MP Tim Farron warned ministers that the Conservative Government's trade deals with Australia and New Zealand threaten the future of farmers in Cumbria.
It comes after the Conservatives' former DEFRA Secretary George Eustice said that the deal with Australia negotiated by the Government was "not actually a very good deal for the UK" and that it "gave away far too much for far too little in return".</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the floor of the House of Commons last night, local MP Tim Farron warned ministers that the Conservative Government's trade deals with Australia and New Zealand threaten the future of farmers in Cumbria.</p>
<p>It comes after the Conservatives' former DEFRA Secretary George Eustice said that the deal with Australia negotiated by the Government was "not actually a very good deal for the UK" and that it "gave away far too much for far too little in return".</p>
<p>Speaking during a debate in Parliament, Tim said: "<em>The Liberal Democrats are very strongly in favour of free trade, but we also believe that free trade has to be fair. Let me take him back to his earlier comments about the strategic value of this. Does he understand that trade deals must have strategic value when it comes to protecting our ability to feed ourselves as a country?</em></p>
<p><em>"Does he understand why those of us who represent rural communities are deeply concerned about the imbalance that exists between farm standards on this side of the world and those in New Zealand and Australia on the other? We think that might undermine our ability to feed ourselves because it will put British farmers out of business."</em></p>
<p>In response, the Trade Minister Greg Hands said: <em>"I look forward to the honourable member actually supporting one of these trade deals.</em></p>
<p><em>"I have already pointed out the safeguards that exist in both deals: the long transition period and the substantial tariff-rate quotas. I am talking about all of the protections and safeguards that are in those deals for British farmers - the non-regression clauses on animal welfare, for example, which will prevent Australia or any other country from seeking to gain a trade advantage if they were to weaken their animal welfare rules.</em></p>
<p><em>"I will be frank, though; I have seen no evidence that Australia will be looking to do that, but the deal does have protection for our farmers and our consumers."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Walsall Manor Hospital Progress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/walsall-manor-hospital-progress/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;table style="height: 288px;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr style="height: 288px;"&gt;
&lt;td style="height: 288px; width: 1516.35px;"&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;I was delighted to accept an invitation from the Chief Executive of the Manor Hospital to see the continuing progress on the new Urgent and Emergency Care Centre. It was good to see at first-hand the excellent progress on the reconfiguration of the current department following the Government’s commitment of £36 million of capital funding towards the new Emergency Care Department.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;Throughout the visit I was once again struck by the incredible professionalism of the people we are fortunate enough to have working in our National Health Service and the clear team approach to developing and delivering these new facilities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;Once complete this will benefit patients across Walsall, including Aldridge-Brownhills, whilst also benefitting the staff working in our local emergency services.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_s9"&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;I would like to thank the staff at the Manor and contractors Tilbury Douglas for taking the time to facilitate my visit and I look forward to visiting again &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;in the near future&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="x_s10"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4389" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/DSC_0933-FAVE-scaled.jpg" alt="" width="2560" height="1708" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/DSC_0933-FAVE-scaled.jpg 2560w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/DSC_0933-FAVE-1280x854.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/DSC_0933-FAVE-980x654.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/DSC_0933-FAVE-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 2560px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was delighted to accept an invitation from the Chief Executive of the Manor Hospital to see the continuing progress on the new Urgent and Emergency Care Centre. It was […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4386</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T10:08:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T10:08:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tameside coming together to help those in need – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/tameside-coming-together-to-help-those-in-need-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tameside-coming-together-to-help-those-in-need-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235846" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Tameside-COming-together.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">The temperature is beginning to fall, Michael Bublé is defrosting, and we’re slowly but surely approaching the festive season.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">Christmas is a time for joy, family, friends and kindness. But for many people this year, Christmas will feel very different. The cost-of-living crisis, soaring energy bills and the continuing catastrophic consequences of the Tory minibudget will be worrying people right across the UK, who will be wondering how on earth they will afford to get food on the table, let alone enjoy the festivities.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">We are going through hard times. As is always the case here in <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span>, however, local people are stepping up and doing their utmost to help those who are struggling. Recently, Action Together launched its <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> Toy Appeal 2022. This initiative has been running for many years, and through donations gives gifts to children most in need. Last year, over 7,000 toys and gifts were donated to children right across <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span>.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">The <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> <span class="mark06r159on6" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Reporter</span> have a very handy list of all the drop-off points right across <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> at<span class="x_ContentPasted0"> </span><a class="x_ContentPasted0" href="http://www.questmedianetwork.co.uk/tameside-toy-appeal" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="0">www.questmedianetwork.co.uk/<span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">tameside</span>-toy-appeal</a>. The appeal will be accepting donations up until the 9<sup class="x_ContentPasted0">th</sup><span class="x_ContentPasted0"> </span>of December.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">We’re also seeing local-led food banks doing an extraordinary amount to help those in need. St Mary’s Church in Haughton Green and <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> East Food Bank in Dukinfield are just some of the brilliant food bank access points. There’s also The Bread and Butter Thing, which provides families and individuals with food banks for £7.50-a-week (the packs themselves often contain over £35 of food in them).</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">For a full list of food banks and local pantries visit<span class="x_ContentPasted0"> </span><a class="x_ContentPasted0" href="http://www.tameside.gov.uk/healthyeatingandnutrition/foodbanks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="1">www.<span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">tameside</span>.gov.uk/healthyeatingandnutrition/foodbanks</a>. You can also call <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> Council on 0161 342 8355 for more support.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">It goes without saying that I wish we lived in a world where food banks were not necessary; where people across <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> had access to high-quality, affordable meals and the Government made sure that those who needed support could access it. It’s a sad indictment of 12 years of Tory rule that the number of people accessing food bank support has increased by 2 million since 2010.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">However, where the Government is failing the <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> community is stepping up, and that is something we should be incredible proud of.</p>
<p class="x_ContentPasted0">I’ll keep supporting this work in whatever way I can locally and in Parliament and would like to take a moment to sincerely thank all the people across <span class="markuu1bycht8" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Tameside</span> who are working hard to make a difference over these tough winter months.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/tameside-coming-together-to-help-those-in-need-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Tameside coming together to help those in need – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The temperature is beginning to fall, Michael Bublé is defrosting, and we’re slowly but surely approaching the festive season. Christmas is a time for joy, family, friends and kindness. But for many people this year, Christmas will feel very different. The cost-of-living crisis, soaring energy bills and the continuing catastrophic consequences of the Tory minibudget […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/tameside-coming-together-to-help-those-in-need-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Tameside coming together to help those in need – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235845</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T09:26:13Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T09:26:13Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A budget to beat recession? (from Conservative Home)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/11/15/a-budget-to-beat-recession-from-conservative-home/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div> <b>The Autumn Statement will be one of the most crucial budgets ever delivered. Rishi and Jeremy have in their hands the opportunity to rescue the Uk economy from poor performance and recession if they wish, or they can accept the depressing official advice and double down with austerity. Tax rises and the wrong spending cuts now will turn a downturn into a nasty and long recession. This will lead to job losses, struggling businesses and a bigger state deficit. </b></div>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b>          Their challenge should be to put forward a budget and plan for growth as Liz Truss proposed, but one with forecasts, numbers and sensible controls over spending and borrowing which in his haste Kwasi left out. This is important for the whole country, and for MPs’ constituents. It is also important for the Conservative party whose reputation for economic competence hinges on it.</b></div>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b>          Over the last fifty years we have seen Labour lose badly on two occasions and Conservatives lose twice, once badly, thanks to presiding over recessions</b></div>
<div>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0 x_x_x_ContentPasted1">Edward Heath presided over the 1973-4 recession. His 1970-2 policies of competition and credit control were inflationary</span><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0 x_x_x_ContentPasted1"> leading to a borrowing binge . The inflation was worsened by the  energy crisis when OPEC hiked the oil price. He tightened too much in response and lost the 1974 election. </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0 x_x_x_ContentPasted1">Harold Wilson lost control of the economy  in 1974-5, created a recession and left office. Labour lost the next election under his successor.  </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0 x_x_x_ContentPasted1">John Major on official advice put us into the Exchange rate Mechanism. As I warned it took us through a very predictable  violent boom/bust cycle with a five quarter recession. This led to a huge defeat in 1997 which took the Conservatives  13 years to recover from. </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0 x_x_x_ContentPasted1">Gordon Brown created his own disaster, leading and encouraging the wrong official advice. He put us through a banking and credit boom, only to collapse it too fast through severe policy. The five quarter recession took the economy down by more than 6% . Labour have still not won an election in the 12 years that followed, with their reputation for economics in tatters.<span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted1"> </span> </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b> </b></p>
</div>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoListParagraph"><b> </b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">          It was a pity  Boris did not use the advice he was offered to cut out the money creation and bond buying  and tighten money policy last year to keep inflation down. We have more inflation now than we needed. Japan and China remind us with their low inflation rates it was not all  caused by oil and gas prices.  It was a tragedy  Liz did not present a rounded and costed Growth Plan within an economic  framework that would have worked as some proposed.  These mistakes must not lead the new team to conclude they must impose more austerity. The prime task today is fighting recession. Inflation will come down rapidly next year thanks to the  monetary stringency now  being applied. The Bank itself sees inflation down to 2%  in a couple of years time. </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">          If government  accepts all the OBR and Bank advice to tighten too much into a downturn it will be bad economics and worse politics. We will end up with a deeper and longer downturn than we need, and with a bigger deficit than if we had been more willing to offset some of the recessionary forces.  You cannot tax your way into growth and recovery. A fractious and unhappy party is in  no mood for tax rises nor for spending cuts that harm individual incomes and front line services in health, law and order  and education. </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">          Of course there is a need to rein in wasteful and less essential public spending. In recent years the purse strings have been loosened across a  very wide field. The Chancellor should s</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">top the Bank of England taking losses on bonds. There is no need to do this. This will produce an immediate saving of £11bn this year. This has always been a joint control policy where the Bank needs the Chancellor’s approval.  </span></b></p>
<p class="x_x_x_MsoNormal"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">          The Department of Work and pensions should promote more employment for the many on benefits that could do some work. Remove the 16 hours rule for working whilst on benefit, and improve mentoring and assistance into employment  as we need to fill many more job vacancies from people already settled here. There is an unfinished part to Iain Duncan Smith’s excellent benefit reforms.  </span></b></p>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">            The government could suspend the Smart meter programme saving more than £1bn a year , as everyone who really wants a free smart meter now has one. The Treasury should s</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">top Councils borrowing to buy up property . The Cabinet Office can i</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">mpose a recruitment freeze on public sector jobs other than uniformed roles, teachers and medics . This will give more opportunities for promotion to those already working in the civil service, and assist in increasing productivity after a period of no progress. They can r</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">educe the central London office estate to reflect more home working and transfers out of London. There should be a privatisation programme including the sale of </span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0"> Channel 4 , the British Business Bank and more Nat West shares to the private sector .</span></b></div>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">             The Transport department should cut rail subsidies which are funding far too many near empty train services following the collapse of commuting . The Business  and Energy Department should t</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">rim the energy support package. They could limit cut price energy to a normal family amount so larger users pay full price for the extra they buy . We should not accept the need to provide more overseas aid for net zero or any other purpose other than a new disaster where we want to  help generously and energetically.</span></b></div>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">            We also need to boost tax revenues. Often the way to increase tax revenues from capital gains, profits, transactions and incomes is to lower the rate, not raise it. Every time we lowered Income tax and Corporation tax rates revenues rose.  The government should a</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">ccelerate licences for North Sea oil and gas fields. Every extra barrel we produce ourselves switches substantial tax from a foreign country to ourselves as home production replaces imports. It also cuts the CO2.  </span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">Government should allow the private sector to finance production of oil and gas from the large Falklands islands discovery which would also displace foreign imports and help with expenditures. It could u</span></b><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">se more of the Defra grant money to boost home food production backed by more mechanisation/glasshouses. This will boost taxable farm incomes. </span></b></div>
<div class="x_x_elementToProof"><b><span class="x_x_x_ContentPasted0">           Any amelioration of the downturn will be revenue rich. The UK figures are very sensitive to the growth rate. As we saw last year, a bit higher growth rate gave us a central government borrowing requirement £120bn below the budget OBR forecast. Let’s have that budget for growth . It would help unite the party, it would help restore our economy and would cheer people up. It would be good economics and even better politics. It would also be quite a surprise. </span></b></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> The Autumn Statement will be one of the most crucial budgets ever delivered. Rishi and Jeremy have in their hands the opportunity to rescue the Uk economy from poor performance and recession if they wish, or they can accept the depressing official advice and double down with austerity. Tax rises and the wrong spending cuts…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33839</id>
    <published>2022-11-15T05:00:35Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-15T05:00:35Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Geoff Palmer receives the Edinburgh Award 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13590/sir-geoff-palmer-receives-the-edinburgh-award-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Professor Emeritus and Chancellor of Heriot-Watt University Sir Geoff Palmer has been presented with the prestigious Edinburgh Award 2022 in a ceremony at the City Chambers this evening. </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13590/sir-geoff-palmer-receives-the-edinburgh-award-2022</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T19:39:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T19:39:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz pays her respects on Remembrance Sunday]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-pays-her-respects-on-remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11852</id>
		<updated>2022-11-14T18:20:01Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-14T18:08:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160;<br />
I was honoured to pay my respects to the fallen at Leicester&#8217;s Remembrance Day service and parade in Victoria Park on Sunday. It was a deeply moving occasion as always.<br />
It was also a huge privilege to see the recently installed memorial to commemorate Sikhs who fought in both World Wars and other global conflicts for the UK. The statute of a Sikh World War One soldier will now permanently stand alongside existing memorials in Peace Walk.<br />
Artist Taranjit Singh designed the statue which was funded by donations from Sikh congregations, the ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-pays-her-respects-on-remembrance-day/">Liz pays her respects on Remembrance Sunday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-pays-her-respects-on-remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-11853 size-large" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-405x540.jpg" alt="" width="405" height="540" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-405x540.jpg 405w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-195x260.jpg 195w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-138x184.jpg 138w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Rememberance-sunday.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 405px) 100vw, 405px" /><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-11854 size-large" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-405x540.jpg" alt="" width="405" height="540" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-405x540.jpg 405w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-195x260.jpg 195w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-138x184.jpg 138w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-768x1024.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/RS-2.jpg 1440w" sizes="(max-width: 405px) 100vw, 405px" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I was honoured to pay my respects to the fallen at Leicester&#8217;s Remembrance Day service and parade in Victoria Park on Sunday. It was a deeply moving occasion as always.</p>
<p>It was also a huge privilege to see the recently installed memorial to commemorate Sikhs who fought in both World Wars and other global conflicts for the UK. The statute of a Sikh World War One soldier will now permanently stand alongside existing memorials in Peace Walk.</p>
<p>Artist Taranjit Singh designed the statue which was funded by donations from Sikh congregations, the wider public and Leicester City Council ward funding.</p>
<p>It is great that there is a fitting tribute to the sacrifices made by so many Sikhs in service of our country.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">&#8220;They shall grow not old, as we that are left grow old;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">At the going down of the sun and in the morning</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">We will remember them&#8221;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" ><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-1924" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-leadership/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/DM_Stride_22-150x150.jpg" alt="Labour Leadership" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-leadership/" class="wp_rp_title">Labour Leadership</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-8036" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/helping-support-families-with-every-day-challenges/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/centre-150x150.jpg" alt="Helping support families with every day challenges" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/helping-support-families-with-every-day-challenges/" class="wp_rp_title">Helping support families with every day challenges</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-6867" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/backing-local-businesses-to-boost-jobs-and-growth/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Capture-150x150.png" alt="Backing local businesses to boost jobs and growth" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/backing-local-businesses-to-boost-jobs-and-growth/" class="wp_rp_title">Backing local businesses to boost jobs and growth</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-11274" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-backs-local-efforts/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/22.jpg" alt="Liz backs local efforts" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-backs-local-efforts/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz backs local efforts</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-10117" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/how-the-uks-care-homes-were-abandoned-to-coronavirus/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/4.jpg" alt="How the UK’s care homes were abandoned to coronavirus" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/how-the-uks-care-homes-were-abandoned-to-coronavirus/" class="wp_rp_title">How the UK’s care homes were abandoned to coronavirus</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-pays-her-respects-on-remembrance-day/">Liz pays her respects on Remembrance Sunday</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin hosts advice and support event in Llanfairfechan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-hosts-advice-and-support-event-llanfairfechan" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last Friday over 15 local organisations were represented at a drop in event in Llanfairfechan hosted by Aberconwy MP Robin Millar. Following the successful Worried About Winter event in September in Llandudno, this was the second event in this series hosted by Robin. Organisations including Conwy…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-hosts-advice-and-support-event-llanfairfechan</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-39" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I notice that last week The Chad dedicated a lot of column space to yet more attacks on my type of politics. The latest outburst coming from Councillor Hennigan who has accused me of ‘dog whistle politics’ over my comments on illegal immigrants. Ashfield’s Independent Councillor Hennigan stated…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-39</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wishing His Majesty The King a very happy birthday today.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/wishing-his-majesty-king-very-happy-birthday-today" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy Birthday to his Royal Highness King Charles III. 
Today marks the King's 74th birthday, and the first since he became our sovereign. To commemorate such an occasion, the King has officially become Park Ranger of Windsor Great Park, 70 years after his father, The Duke of Edinburgh, was…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/wishing-his-majesty-king-very-happy-birthday-today</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-178" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">COP27 reaffirmed the UK’s commitments to deliver on the climate promises that were established at COP26 in Glasgow last year. And as the Prime Minister told the House last week, climate security and energy security go hand in hand. By committing £30 billion to support green industries in our…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-178</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2146-protecting-education-funding-is-not-a-hard-decision-to-make"/>
		<published>2022-11-14T10:02:36+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-11-14T10:02:36+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2146-protecting-education-funding-is-not-a-hard-decision-to-make</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Letter to Chancellor accepting difficult choices need to be made, but protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make. We owe it to the children of our country to put them first even in times of financial hardship, as many families already do every day. &lt;a href="https://t.co/hY6IftAEH6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hY6IftAEH6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1592095094580318209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Letter to Chancellor accepting difficult choices need to be made, but protecting education funding is not a hard decision to make. We owe it to the children of our country to put them first even in times of financial hardship, as many families already do every day. &lt;a href="https://t.co/hY6IftAEH6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hY6IftAEH6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1592095094580318209?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 14, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Kind Fest <span style="color:#06396a;">Compassion in Politics?</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>It’s a pleasure to be speaking with you today as the co-Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Compassionate Politics. For those of you not familiar with our Parliamentary system, APPGs consist of members from different parties and from both Houses. We aim to work collaboratively together to address specific issues; in this case we want to shift the culture of politics to one that’s more compassionate.</p>
<h4><strong>WHAT’S WRONG WITH OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM?</strong></h4>
<p>My co-Chair Baroness Sayeeda Warsi and I convened the APPG on Compassionate Politics with the support of Matt &amp; Jennifer and the Compassion in Politics team back in 2019 as we shared the same concerns, as did many of our colleagues, about the increased divisiveness in politics which had steadily grown since 2016.</p>
<p>Many of us recognised that the division and discord being played out in Parliament, and also in some local authorities, was negatively impacting on our communities and how people were treating each other. A climate of fear, hostility and blame has been emanating from our politics. There was another effect: an escalating lack of trust in politics and politicians. A recent CiP poll showed that <a href="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/cip/pages/304/attachments/original/1663327185/OP19111_Compassion_in_Politics_Trust_and_Civility_-_Final_Tables.xlsx?1663327185">7 in 10 people don’t trust anything politicians say</a>. <a href="https://www.opinium.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/OP12494-Compassion-in-%20Politics-tables.xlsx">9 in 10 don’t think politicians have their interests at heart</a> and <a href="https://www.electoral-reform.org.uk/new-polling-reveals-just-how-powerless-people-feel-over-westminster/">2 in 3 feel completely powerless over the decisions being made at Westminster</a>. This incredibly disturbing for the health of our democracy.</p>
<p>However, as much as there are kindred spirits across the political spectrum, we’ve had a party-political system for centuries in this country which has been largely based on tribalism and narrow party rivalries, on making the electorate believe that each party has the answers to make their life better/fairer/safer for them and, unfortunately, negative campaigning has been seen by some to be part of that.</p>
<p>Negative campaigning has been successfully aided by a negative and partisan media, again, over many years. But over the last 16 years or so we’ve had another dimension: the wild west that is social media, where there is little policing of unlawful content by either the platforms or law enforcement agencies, let alone disinformation or misinformation; even legal but harmful content which includes platforms pushing information on suicide to school-age children is apparently off limits. Collectively, these exponentially ramp up the negativity, and even the hate.</p>
<h4><strong>SO WHAT SHOULD WE DO ABOUT IT? </strong></h4>
<p>Many of you will already know that as human beings we have an immense and innate capacity for compassion &amp; kindness: it’s what drives us to care for our family, look out for our friends, and help our neighbours. Within our communities, it can be nurtured and enabled, or it can be stifled and suppressed. The key to cultivating this compassion and kindness is leadership: leadership in our schools, leadership at work and, fundamentally leadership by politicians.</p>
<p>Again, as many of you will also know, ‘Compassion’ as defined by psychologists, involves an awareness of suffering with a commitment to alleviate and prevent it. Compassion is built on empathy, sympathy, and understanding – a tuning into the experience of self and others. Secondly, it requires commitment. Compassion doesn’t zero-in on the distress of others only to turn away, castigate, or blame. It seeks to understand and learn. Thirdly, it requires action – and action not only to alleviate the symptoms of suffering but to uproot their cause.</p>
<p>The recent pledges from the new Prime Minister and Chancellor for compassion and compassionate Conservatism are welcome but what do they mean?</p>
<p>To govern effectively through compassion will require a commitment to not only help those who are suffering today but also create conditions in which everyone can thrive tomorrow. Those instincts need to be activated and championed because, right now, we live according to quite alternate values. Refugees, social security users, and others are being decried, vilified, and shamed. This approach not only weakens us as a society, but it is also injurious to political engagement, to our very democracy.</p>
<p>A compassionate Government would recognise our common humanity, and that all human beings are equal. And within this, a compassionate immigration system in a country which upholds the rule of law, would abide by our obligations under the UN Refugee Convention which the UK is not only a signatory to, but helped to develop, after the horrors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As a Labour politician I would argue that the market doesn’t have all the answers to the economic crisis millions are facing, and that the immediate compassionate response to this crisis would be to recognise and address the fact that the <strong>richest 1% of individuals</strong> <strong>pay 12.5% of their income in tax</strong> compared with the <strong>50% lowest earners who pay 25.5% of their income in tax</strong>. Similarly, I would argue that the tax from corporations has flatlined over the last 12 years at about 2% and that some companies, for example, energy companies like BP have reported their highest quarterly profits for 14 years. Their figures are eclipsed by Shell who delivered second quarter profits of over £9bn.</p>
<p>I have argued that a compassionate Government would reflect this in their Autumn Statement next week.</p>
<p>There’s so much more policy-wise that could reflect compassion in the Government’s response to these very real issues and hardships so many in our country face.</p>
<p>But hand-in-hand with this, is an effort to reform the culture of our politics. Good policies can only come from good politics and if our government is truly committed to a compassionate future, it needs to create the right environment for such a future to grow and prosper. That has to start with the conduct of those in high office. We need to put the Ministerial and Members’ codes on a statutory footing so that they can be universally read and be properly enforced. The Prime Minister needs to appoint and then empower the government ethics advisor to launch independent investigations into ministerial conduct and strengthen the rules to prevent politicians from wilfully lying to the public.</p>
<p>Compassionate governance also means working alongside those we seek to serve, not dictating policies from the centre. We need to look at how we can reconnect politicians to the people we serve by shifting power away from Westminster. Establishing citizen and constituency assemblies as part of developing active and empowered citizens would be an important start.</p>
<p>Finally, this crisis in politics is not just a UK phenomenon; democracies across the world are facing the same issues. The last year’s insurrection at the Capitol is just one example of this. I would urge the like-minded to work together internationally for a new and compassionate politics.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7065</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remembrance Sunday 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/remembrance-sunday-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">They shall grow not old, as we that are left grow old. Age shall not weary them, nor the years condemn.
It was an honour to attend the Bicester Remembrance Service today on what is such an important day of reflection for so many. We must never forget those who have made the ultimate sacrifice for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/remembrance-sunday-2022</id>
    <published>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Remembering those who made the ultimate sacrifice for our country and our freedom</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/remembering-those-who-made-ultimate-sacrifice-our-country-and-our-freedom" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today Greg laid two wreaths - firstly in Princes Risborough and then in Monks Risborough - to remember those who made the ultimate sacrifice for our country and our freedom.
Commenting, Greg said, "It was particularly humbling and moving to read the names of those from Princes Risborough who lost…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/remembering-those-who-made-ultimate-sacrifice-our-country-and-our-freedom</id>
    <published>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Tories aren’t serious about science</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/11/12866/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science minister resigns. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No science minister for three months. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New PM, new science minister.    &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another new PM, now 2 science ministers. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Their roles unclear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chi Onwurah&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Tory short-termism is wrecking UK science&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not content with their catastrophic trickle-down experiment with the nation’s economy the Tories are now trialling Heisenberg’s “uncertainty principle” — for the last few months it has been impossible to know both the position and number of science ministers at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://thetimes.co.uk/article/94de13fc-612c-11ed-80da-2c56e60527b0?shareToken=a07c112737aa3830ee0877862e0fc778"&gt;https://thetimes.co.uk/article/94de13fc-612c-11ed-80da-2c56e60527b0?shareToken=a07c112737aa3830ee0877862e0fc778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-family: Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;The Tories aren&amp;#8217;t serious about science &amp;#8211; that&amp;#8217;s why we don&amp;#8217;t convert our rich science base into the high-skill, high-wage, high-productivity economy we want. Cuts to R&amp;amp;D spending would be disastrous for not only our science base but also our economy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-family: Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a style="font-size: 14px;" href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-63583663"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-63583663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> Science minister resigns. No science minister for three months. New PM, new science minister.    Another new PM, now 2 science ministers. Their roles unclear.   The Times Chi Onwurah Tory short-termism is wrecking UK science Not content with their… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12866</id>
    <published>2022-11-12T15:49:41Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-12T15:49:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up 11 November 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/11/weekly-round-up-11-november-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-11-november-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>I am pleased to be a member of the UK-EU Parliamentary Assembly (PPA) as part of our post-Brexit institutional framework to ensure a good and productive relationship with the EU. This group aims to maintain dialogue over trade so that we can build security and prosperity across Europe. This week we hosted our European partners in Westminster for the first time, hearing from the UK Minister for Europe, Leo Doherty MP, Maros Sefcovcic, from the European Commission, former European Commissioner, Lord Hill, and the EU Ambassador to the UK, Joao Vale de Almeida. The main items of discussion were the Northern Ireland Protocol and the importance of maintaining peace. We also discussed Russia’s war on Ukraine and the security implications for the rest of Europe from energy and cyber security to food security and our support for Ukraine’s military and refugees. We are in a new phase in our relationship with Europe but we have to find constructive ways to engage and continue working together on issues of global and regional security from climate change to economic prosperity. I look forward to future meetings.</p>
<p>Labour secured an Opposition Day debate on the Pension Triple Lock this week. This debate ended with a vote to tell the Government to protect the Triple Lock. The Triple Lock promises to ensure pensions rise with inflation, earnings or 2.5% – whichever is the highest. Pensioner poverty is up by a shocking 450,000 since the Tories came into power in 2010. Something Labour had nearly abolished when in government with our policies of free TV licences for the over-75s and Winter Fuel Payments during cold snaps to name but a few. The soaring cost of living is putting further pressure on pensions with 3.5 million pensioners already this year having to spend less on food and essentials. Over half of the UK’s pensioners are cutting back on gas and electricity, with Age UK suggesting that 2.8 million older households are set to be in fuel poverty this winter – 1.8 million more than in previous years. We want to see the UK be a decent place in which to raise families and grow old. That can only happen if our pensions are able to offer a good standard of living. </p>
<p>I was also able to speak in Northern Ireland Questions. Having recently met members of East Border Region, a cross-party, cross-border local authority-led organisation delivering peace and prosperity across the border, I called on the Minister to meet them himself in order to hear first-hand the work that is happening in Northern Ireland and the importance of our supporting it from here in Westminster. The Secretary of State referred to the three strands of the Good Friday agreement, and he needs to make sure those three strands are fully implemented to help us through both this crisis and the forthcoming crisis. The three strands are the status and system of government of Northern Ireland within the United Kingdom, the relationship between Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland, and the relationship between the Republic of Ireland and the United Kingdom. It is paramount that all three strands are worked on and that relationships are maintained.</p>
<p>It was a pleasure to meet German Ambassador Miguel Berger in Bristol this week. We spoke about plans to strengthen ties between the British and German societies, in particular youth mobility and cultural and academic exchanges. It is so important that both our young peoples get to experience different cultures and learn more about the differences in the world but also the ways in which we are fundamentally the same – we all have families we care about and want to help move forward, we all have interests that we follow, we all want to find work to support our families. Visiting other countries and talking to other people is such an interesting and joyous experience, I really want to make sure that our young people have those chances after Brexit and I am pleased that Germany shares that view. </p>
<p>This weekend we mark Armistice Day and Remembrance Sunday. It is a time of reflection – of those in our family who may have served in past conflicts, of those who have lost their lives in serving their country, and of those who continue to serve today. Our Armed Forces are phenomenal. They work in the toughest of circumstances, leaving their families for long periods of time, and sometimes, not knowing whether they will return to them. Bristol’s Remembrance Day Parade and Service will take place on Sunday at City Hall and the Cenotaph. We will remember them.<br/>
If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/11/weekly-round-up-11-november-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 11 November 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I am pleased to be a member of the UK-EU Parliamentary Assembly (PPA) as part of our post-Brexit institutional framework […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/11/11/weekly-round-up-11-november-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 11 November 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3375</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T16:57:17Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T16:57:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton MP welcomes £40 million Levelling Up package for Blackpool</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-ps40-million-levelling-package-blackpool" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Blackpool South MP, Scott Benton, has welcomed the announcement that Blackpool is to receive £40 million in funding from government to help ‘level up’ Blackpool. The Department for Levelling Up, Housing and Communities has confirmed that Blackpool will be given £40 million to relocate the court…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-ps40-million-levelling-package-blackpool</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill plants a Remembrance stake in the Constituency Garden of Remembrance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday, Sir Bill Wiggin MP planted a wooden cross to pay tribute to service personnel from his constituency of North Herefordshire who have died in service to our country.  The Speaker of the House of Commons, Sir Lindsay Hoyle... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/#more-4548">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4548</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[MP Welcomes Investment in Weston’s Local Artists]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/11/10/mp-welcomes-investment-in-westons-local-artists/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5551</id>
		<updated>2022-11-10T16:57:48Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-10T16:57:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Local Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Regenerating Weston"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weston’s MP, John Penrose, has welcomed news that Arts Council England has chosen two Weston-based arts organisations, Theatre Orchard and Trigger Productions, to receive grants of over £600,000 pounds. The money is to support, develop, and champion the work of local artists, and both Theatre Orchard and Trigger Productions have a strong history of delivering imaginative [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/11/10/mp-welcomes-investment-in-westons-local-artists/"><![CDATA[
<p>Weston’s MP, John Penrose, has welcomed news that Arts Council England has chosen two Weston-based arts organisations, Theatre Orchard and Trigger Productions, to receive grants of over £600,000 pounds. The money is to support, develop, and champion the work of local artists, and both Theatre Orchard and Trigger Productions have a strong history of delivering imaginative events in public spaces.<br><br>John said: &#8220;Funding from Arts England is hugely competitive, so the fact we have two local organisations winning their bids for significant amounts of cash says a lot about the quality of their plans and of the artists they have involved too. We&#8217;ve had huge cultural events in Weston over recent years, going back to Banksy and more recently See Monster. New, interesting, regular events put on by organisations such as Theatre Orchard and Trigger build on this legacy, continue entertaining locals and give tourists an ever-changing program of culture and heritage worth their time (and money) to visit!&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-82/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">Of the many Urgent Questions (UQs) and Government Statements in the Commons Chamber last week, I’ve singled out three that were of particular importance. Since her re-appointment, the Home Secretary had not appeared in the Chamber, but the seriousness of the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-31/debates/F189CA88-FDF3-4018-905C-1CC8A1B76E28/WesternJetFoilAndManstonAsylumProcessingCentres">Western Jet Foil, Manston and Asylum processing centres</a> made it imperative that she delivered the U.K. Government statement in person, and not delegate it to one of her ministers. On Sunday police were called to Western because two to three incendiary devices had been thrown at Home Offices premises. The suspect was later found dead at a local petroleum station, and at that time, Kent Police decided that it was not a terrorist incident. Ms Braverman said that several hundred migrants had been transferred to Manston, but Western was now operational again. And she needs to meet statutory duties around detention, provide accommodation, and conduct security checks, on anyone entering the UK illegally. Manston is in Sir Roger Gale’s constituency and he had been interviewed extensively on the media over the weekend. The Home Secretary did not appear on the media. Her Minister Robert Jenrick gave interviews and he also met Sir Roger at Manston. In the Chamber, Ms Braverman defended her actions, and said that 40,000 people have illegally crossed the channel in small boats this year…she did not say that only 4% of applications to stay had been processed by her department. She said there had been an invasion of the coast, a surge of Albanians, and used this inflammatory language repeatedly when answering MPs’ questions. She spoke about the Rwanda Partnership, but it is a fact that not one person has been sent to Rwanda, because of the many legal challenges against this discriminatory U.K. Government policy that are awaiting court hearings. She said that when she became Home Secretary (assuming she meant the first time, from 6th September until she was sacked by Liz Truss on 19th September) she was appalled to discover there were over 35,000 migrants in hotel accommodation costing £6.8billion a day, but she didn’t say that her Government has been in power for over 12 years, so they’ve created this problem. She denied that she has blocked using hotels to house migrants, and so contributed to the Manston situation. There was no other UK Government Minister on the front bench apart from Minister Jenrick, and he sat beside her in stony silence. Yvette Cooper appeared for the Official Opposition and Ms Braverman did not answer any of the points she raised. Sir Roger asked the first question from the back benches, and shook his head in disappointment at the Home Secretary’s answer. That set the pattern for the rest of the statement; more questions and no answers.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Foreign Secretary James Cleverly made a <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-31/debates/96A2ADE5-7829-43C2-9E46-F14A5C86AADA/Ukraine">statement on the situation in Ukraine</a> following recent developments when Russian missiles striking Kyiv, depriving people of water and electricity, and Putin suspending the agreed export of 100,000 tonnes of grain every day from the Black Sea. Over 60% had gone to Ethiopia, Yemen and Afghanistan and these are made to suffer because of Putin’s setbacks in Ukraine. Russia’s suicide drones and cruise missiles are killing Ukrainian civilians, spreading terror and depriving people of heat, light and shelter as winter sets in. Ukraine has 143 UN countries in support, whilst Russia has only 4 supporters – Syria, Belarus, Nicaragua, and North Korea. The UK has given Ukraine £2.3 billion in military support, only the US has given more, and committed £220 million in humanitarian aid. Putin has spoken about using nuclear weapons, and that Ukraine plans to use a “dirty bomb” on its own territory, but we’ve seen Putin’s tactics before. Mr Cleverly pledged to support Ukraine until it prevails.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The new Security Minister Tom Tugendhat provided MPs with an update on <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-11-01/debates/13B42D2D-C358-4BF9-827F-A58CAFBE3851/NationalSecurity">National Security and Safeguarding our Democracy</a>. He said that Dictatorships are trying to write the rules for a new world, for example Russia. Technological integration has deepened connections, opened doors into areas of our lives we once thought closed, and made us vulnerable. Unfriendly states have tried to influence our politics. The National Security Bill will provide powers to combat threats. Mr Tugendhat told us that the PM has asked him to lead a Task Force to drive forward work to defend the democratic integrity of our country. It will work cross party with parliament, departments, security and intelligence agencies, devolved administrations, and the private sector. It will look at all threats, and report to the National Security Council.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended 3 All-Party Parliamentary Groups (APPGs) last week. I was honoured to be elected as chair of the APPG for Wales in the World. The former chair Craig Williams MP stood down after being promoted to be the Private Parliamentary Secretary for the PM. We had a presentation from Noel Mooney, CEO of the FAW, about the strategy for development of football in Wales, and the preparations for the World Cup in Qatar next month. Our Welsh ambassadors will be Jess Fishlock and Ian Rush. The squad will be launched on Wednesday 9th November in Tylorstown Welfare Hall, which is the home town of the Welsh Team Manager, Rob Page. Tickets for the event are already sold out and the proceeds will go to refurbish the Hall which was damaged in flooding. The announcement will be broadcast simultaneously on BBC 1 Wales and S4C. They will launch the Wales World Cup Song on Monday 7th November, and the “Our Wales” strategy had already nearly doubled staff and increased gender parity. Noel said that he had asked FIFA for information about the Migrant Centre and the Migrant Fund in Qatar, but hadn’t received a response. The Wales FA will be erecting 10 feet by 10 feet replica bucket hats in six city locations throughout Wales: Swansea, Cardiff, Caernarfon, Bangor, Wrexham and Aberystwyth. All the members of the APPG wished Wales every success, and I expect that we will be wearing our bucket hats.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Western Gateway APPG held its AGM and elected co-chairs Jess Morden MP and Sir Robert Buckland MP. I was re-elected as a vice chair.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The AGM of the APPG for Prevention of Flooding re-elected chair Rachel Maskell MP and I was re-elected vice chair.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I dropped-in to some Parliamentary events.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.dogstrust.org.uk/dog-advice/life-with-your-dog/seasonal/fireworks">Dogs Trust</a> and 11 charities hosted a coalition event to discuss the impact of fireworks on human and animal welfare. The UK law is failing to protect those affected by the unpredictable and loud noise of fireworks and contributes to the unnecessary number of children, young people, and adults injured every year by a firework. The coalition is calling for a review to introduce further restrictions on where and when fireworks can be used. This year many councils have cancelled fireworks events because of costs, and the coalition is very concerned that there may be an increase in families holding events at home with no fireworks restrictions.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Anna McMorrin MP hosted the <a href="https://www.centreforwomensjustice.org.uk/news/2022/8/15/daisys-law-new-research-commissioned-by-centre-for-womens-justice-demonstrates-why-children-born-from-rape-should-be-recognised-as-victims-in-law">Children Born of Rape: “Daisy’s Law” Centre for Women’s Justice</a> (CWJ) drop-in and I had the immense privilege of meeting Daisy. A very brave woman who discovered in the 1990s that she has been born as a result of rape. As a child she was raised by an adoptive family, shielded from the circumstances of her birth. After turning 18 she requested her adoption file and was horrified to discover that her mother had became pregnant at 13. Her father aged 29 had allegedly forced himself on her mother. But no criminal action had been taken. Daisy contacted her birth mother, offered her DNA as evidence. The man was prosecuted and convicted in 2020, and sentenced to 11 years in prison. Daisy’s case raises many issues, including whether individuals conceived by rape should be regarded as secondary victims and complainants in their own right. The CWJ is supporting Daisy’s call for individuals born of rape to be recognised in the Victim’s Bill as secondary victims of crime for the first time, and counter the dearth of safeguards for rape-conceived children and adults. Daisy’s Law will significantly improve these offences being recorded, and prosecuted, in cases where the pregnancy is evidence of the crime. There is a data gap regarding rape-related pregnancies and births in the UK, so legislation will improve recognition. But the CWJ found that between 2017 and 2020, at least 900 mothers in the UK relied on the “rape clause” exception to the “two child cap” rule to claim child tax credit over and above the cap. Women claimants have to prove that the conception is non-consensual.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I supported <a href="https://childbraininjurytrust.org.uk/campaigns/gloweek/">GloWeek, The Child Brain Injury Trust</a> (CBIT) raising awareness week in Parliament, sponsored by Liz Twist MP. CBIT has identified road traffic collisions as the leading cause of acquired brain injury (ABI) in the many children they support across the UK and make up 20% of all the referrals through the country in the last 12 months. In Wales, 9% of children referred to the charity last year are receiving support for an ABI that occurred from a road traffic collision. CBIT is calling for increased road safety and vigilance from vulnerable road users particularly through winter months. CBIT’s message is “Be Seen Not Hurt”, and are asking those most vulnerable on the roads to wear brightly coloured clothes when out and about. I spoke to the charity’s staff, its Chief Executive, an ABI coordinator, and the parent of a child the charity is supporting.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the <a href="https://www.bva.co.uk/news-and-blog/news-article/bva-urges-cross-party-collaboration-on-crucial-animal-welfare-issues-at-westminster-event/">British Veterinary Association briefing</a> and spoke with Malcolm Morley about their key focuses for the year ahead, which included Putting pressure on the UK Government to deliver the long overdue Animal Welfare (Kept Animals) Bill; improved regulation and labelling; a ban of exports of Non-stun Slaughter meat; the anticipated shortage of veterinary medicines in Northern Ireland as a result of post-Brexit regulation; support the campaign by the Royal College of Veterinary Surgeons for veterinary legislative reform; post-Brexit trade and the veterinary profession; Bovine TB; gene-editing of animals for food; and regulating canine fertility clinics.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined an online webinar hosted by the British American Parliamentary Group, of which I’m a life member, to receive a presentation about the US 2022 Mid-Term Elections which are on 8th November from <a href="https://iop.harvard.edu/about/staff/john-della-volpe">John Della Volpe, Harvard University’s Director of Polling</a>. Voters will be choosing 35 senators, 36 state governors, and all 435 members of the House of Representatives. The outcome will shape the second half of Joe Biden’s Presidential Term, and the political landscape of the US. John looked at the pivotal swing states of North Carolina, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Michigan, Georgia, Arizona, and Florida with respect to demographic voting changes, and found that in 2000 there was no demographic difference but in 2020, 60% of the Democratic vote came from younger people, whilst 36% of the Republican vote came from older voters. A number of Republican-leaning Polling Groups are flooding the media with results showing 13 of 14 polls favour Republican candidates, but when all polls and the “generic ballot” are taken together it shows that if the younger vote turns out, the result would be 217 Republicans and 218 Democrats. The suspicion is that the “flooding” will set up the Trump narrative that the election outcome is rigged, when the results do not match the Republican prediction.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined the Cardiff University Public Policy Affairs webinar to discuss the new book by Professor Richard Wyn Jones and Dr Rob Jones “<a href="https://www.uwp.co.uk/book/the-welsh-criminal-justice-system/">The Welsh Criminal Justice System – On the Jagged Edge</a>” which has examined the Welsh criminal justice system and its unique position – how Wales has its own devolved Government and Parliament, and yet, there is no Welsh equivalent of the Scottish or Northern Irish justice systems. Professor Jones said that the Welsh Government is responsible for health and education in prisons, police funding, and all social policy apart from welfare, so needs its own approach to criminal justice. The Home Office and Ministry of Justice are in Whitehall, therefore staff are centralised in London. There is a rapid turnover of staff in these departments, and Wales counts for little. He quoted Nye Bevan “responsibility without power” and that Wales is a policy taker not a policy maker. Neither the Home Affairs nor the Justice Select Committees scrutinise justice in Wales, so it’s left to the Welsh Affairs Select Committee, which carries little weight in Westminster. The “wicked” problems are the extra complexity produced by 2 Governments with different priorities and no joined up policy making. Between 2010 and 2019, 21 Magistrates and Crown Courts in Wales were closed, producing “access to justice deserts” across Wales. There are now only 6 combined Magistrates and Crown Courts and 8 Magistrates only Courts remaining in Wales. I recommend reading the book.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Of the many Urgent Questions (UQs) and Government Statements in the Commons Chamber last week, I’ve singled out three that were of particular importance. Since her re-appointment, the Home Secretary had not appeared in the Chamber, but the seriousness of the Western Jet Foil, Manston and Asylum processing centres made it imperative that she delivered the U.K. Government […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2695</id>
    <published>2022-11-10T09:50:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-10T09:50:28Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne calls for rivers to achieve bathing water quality status</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/parliament/dunne-calls-rivers-achieve-bathing-water-quality-status" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="7291" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;9 November 2022&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dunne calls for rivers to achieve bathing water quality status&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philip Dunne intervenes in a debate on rivers achieving bathing water quality status to highlight the Environmental Audit Committee’s view that achieving such status should be an objective of every water company to allow more people to enjoy swimming in all weathers in more and more rivers around the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-59582" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/epBinLaMdC8?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1542"&gt;Philip Dunne (Ludlow) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inadvertently or not, my hon. Friend is making almost precisely the points that the Environmental Audit Committee made in its inquiry into water quality in rivers: that bathing water quality status should be an objective of every water company over the next pricing period, so that we can radically improve the quality of our rivers and allow more people to take great pleasure from swimming in all weathers in more and more rivers around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3996"&gt;Andrew Jones &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My right hon. Friend is absolutely spot on. I have to say that I had not picked up all the output of his Select Committee, so apologies for that, but I strongly agree with everything he has said this evening. He is right that it should be an objective, but to achieve that objective, a team approach is needed, and one that involves the local community, local businesses, Government agencies, local government and national Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-11-09/debates/5a2b6d9e-36c0-4545-8bf1-654e065369d9/CommonsChamber#contribution-2CE44959-3074-4299-A779-E47E968A92AC"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7291 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-11-09T22:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-09T22:30:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Opposition Day Debate on the Triple Lock for Pensions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/opposition-day-debate-triple-lock-pensions" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am not the first Member of the House to recognise that this motion is not a serious request of the Government, because we have the autumn statement in just nine days’ time. It is blatantly a political stunt to gain headlines.
I am surprised that Labour wants to draw attention to pensions policy,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/opposition-day-debate-triple-lock-pensions</id>
    <published>2022-11-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost-of-living support paid to more than 11,000 families in Scottish Borders</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/cost-living-support-paid-more-11000-families-scottish-borders" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The UK Government has today started paying hundreds of pounds in cost-of-living support to more than 11,000 families in the Scottish Borders.
Payments of £324 from the UK Department for Work and Pensions have started to be paid today (Tuesday). They will reach the bank accounts of approximately 10,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/cost-living-support-paid-more-11000-families-scottish-borders</id>
    <published>2022-11-08T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Network Rail Confirm Beckenham Junction Foot Bridge Repairs Timetable </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following pressure from Member of Parliament Bob Stewart, jointly with local Councillor Michael Tickner and London Assembly Member Peter Fortune; Network Rail have set out the timetable to replace the footbridge at Beckenham Junction. 
 
Bob, Michael and Peter wrote to Network Rail in October to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable</id>
    <published>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>LP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Costly Scandal Needs Sorting]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/03/costly-scandal-needs-sorting/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6513</id>
		<updated>2022-11-04T17:52:12Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-03T16:00:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Housing"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Policing, Justice and the Fight Against Crime"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="exempt accommodation"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="housing"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Events at asylum centres have made the headlines this week, drawing attention to the cost of government funded accommodation. They’re now spending millions on hotels. &#160; That story rather overshadowed a report on exempt accommodation by the Levelling up, Housing and Communities Select Committee.&#160; Exempt accommodation is so called because its exempt from usual housing<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/03/costly-scandal-needs-sorting/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Costly Scandal Needs Sorting</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/03/costly-scandal-needs-sorting/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6478" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/20/its-time-for-change/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6478" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>Events at asylum centres have made the headlines this week, drawing attention to the cost of government funded accommodation. They’re now spending millions on hotels. &nbsp;</p>



<p>That story rather overshadowed a report on exempt accommodation by the Levelling up, Housing and Communities Select Committee.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Exempt accommodation is so called because its exempt from usual housing benefit restrictions. &nbsp;</p>



<p>That makes it very lucrative for private providers. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The report identifies a number of problems for residents and neighbours and points out that concentrations of such property often results in anti-social behaviour, rubbish, and vermin as well as noise, violence, and drugs. &nbsp;</p>



<p>West Midlands Police say organised crime is involved.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The committee came to Birmingham where I was pleased to sit in on a couple of sessions and hear what constituents have been telling me for years. Despite two separate attempts on my part, to legislate on this, the government has turned a blind eye. &nbsp;</p>



<p>They’ve also largely ignored a brilliant Birmingham Mail campaign and demands for action from almost every Birmingham MP.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The chair of the committee, Clive Betts MP, acknowledged that I was the first to raise it with him and suggest an enquiry. You can view our exchange on Facebook. His report confirms my worst fears.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It calls for councils to be given powers to limit the number of ‘hostels’ per area, to regulate referrals so that children and victims of domestic abuse aren’t forced to share with people who’ve committed violent offences or have serious drink and drug problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Home Secretary has now given a figure for the cost of her failed asylum strategy but when the committee asked for similar information, the government said it didn’t know how many people were living in exempt accommodation or what it was costing. &nbsp;</p>



<p>A report, back in 2016, to the Comptroller and Auditor General suggested it might be around £2.15 billion, money that could be used to build homes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I write this, there’s been such upheaval in government that, I’m not yet clear who the new housing minister is but I’m sure he or she must act quickly to end this scandal.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-video wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-videopress"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="VideoPress Video Player" aria-label='VideoPress Video Player' width='870' height='489' src='https://videopress.com/embed/w2WFxaFm?cover=1&amp;posterUrl=https%3A%2F%2Fvideos.files.wordpress.com%2Fw2WFxaFm%2Fexempt-accom-final-1_mp4.scrubthumb.jpg&amp;preloadContent=metadata&amp;useAverageColor=1&amp;hd=1' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen data-resize-to-parent="true" allow='clipboard-write'></iframe><script src='https://v0.wordpress.com/js/next/videopress-iframe.js?m=1658470809'></script>
</div><figcaption>Steve McCabe MP speaking in the House of Commons debate on exempt accommodation</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/03/costly-scandal-needs-sorting/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/11/03/costly-scandal-needs-sorting/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP secures key commitment on visas for international GPs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/11/04/matt-warman-mp-secures-key-commitment-on-visas-for-international-gps/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li>In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS.<br/>
• To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve this challenge’, for example working with the sector to explore umbrella sponsors for international GPs and holding meetings with the sector to encourage more GP surgeries to become visa sponsoring practices.</li>
</ul>
<p>On Wednesday (2nd November), a Westminster Hall debate took place in which the House<br/>
considered visas for international doctors.</p>
<p>Matt Warman MP raised the point that under current legislation, GPs who have come from abroad to train in the UK are in a position whereby it is difficult to obtain employment after they graduate. This is mainly because, in order for a General Practice to hire an international graduate, they must be registered as a ‘sponsoring practice’. This requires a large amount of complicated engagement with the Home Office, both on the international GP’s behalf and that of the practice hoping to sponsor them.</p>
<p>Following a discussion of members from different parties, the Minister for Immigration, Robert<br/>
Jenrick MP, acknowledged the issues raised and agreed to look at ways to make this process easier. The Minister assured that the Home Office will ‘reflect carefully on the points raised’ and stated that he will ‘task Home Office officials to work with stakeholders in the sector to give greater consideration to the central question of whether there is a simpler way in which GP practices can apply for relevant visas.’</p>
<p>The Minister for Immigration also pledged to ‘ask my officials to work with the sector to see whether there is a way forward to create umbrella bodies, if there is mutual support on both sides’, as well as agreeing to run further engagement events with the sector to discuss the process of becoming a sponsor.</p>
<p>Commenting on the positive outcome of this debate, Matt Warman said: <em>‘The Minister has </em><br/>
<em>demonstrated more progress on this important issue in the commitment that he has made to us </em><br/>
<em>today than we have seen in some years … I am immensely grateful to all Members who have brought the issue to life, and I look forward to continuing to work with the Minister on the outcome of the review, which will make a real difference to our constituents, and to doctors up and down the country.’</em></p>
<p>Matt will continue to liaise with the Home Office, the NHS and the Royal Colleges in order to turn this promise into action as quickly as possible.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS. • To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4133</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Families in St Helens North worried about the Tory-made economic crisis.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/11/04/families-in-st-helens-north-worried-about-the-tory-made-economic-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7553</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T11:15:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T11:15:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Jobs and recruitment </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-jobs-and-recruitment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Amid the political turmoil of the last few weeks, which hopefully will now start to calm down, there has been a tendency to assume that all the economic background is equally dreadful. But conversations with Ashford businesses suggest that one of the various economic problems discussed on the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-jobs-and-recruitment</id>
    <published>2022-11-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Facebook Meta Boosts Support Fund for Wildfire Victims</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/facebook-meta-boosts-support-fund-wildfire-victims" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Facebook Meta Boosts Support Fund for Wildfire Victims</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-11-03T10:51:00+00:00">Thu, 11/03/2022 - 10:51</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1165 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-03T10:51:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-03T10:51:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10619</id>
		<updated>2022-11-02T14:30:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-02T13:54:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday, I spoke in the House of Commons after several whistleblowers and victims of sexual harassment came forward to speak of their traumatic experiences whilst serving in the Royal Navy. Many woman have spoken out about the continued sexual harassment that they experienced over a number of years, at the hands of colleagues at ... <a title="Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/" aria-label="More on Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/final_6360f1545675000011d02fda_764768-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="6873214" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on the two-year anniversary of the arrest of Karim Ennarah </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_two_year_anniversary_of_the_arrest_of_karim_ennarah" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_two_year_anniversary_of_the_arrest_of_karim_ennarah</id>
    <published>2022-11-02T11:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-02T11:53:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span class="searchHighlight">Halloween</span> is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for years, picking up speed in the past weeks and months as breathless newscasters break the news of more dark intrigue and betrayal. Make no mistake, this may look like a rollercoaster ride, but it is a dirty old carousel with the same old dangerously unfit horses going round and round in ever-decreasing circles.</p>
<p>Of course, seeing the first Asian Hindu take office is truly welcome, but this isn’t a new broom with Prime Minister Rishi Sunak. The Tories have been in office for over 12 years. He’s the ‘Party gate Chancellor” who broke his own laws. He isn’t going to make things better; he’s continuing their long-running austerity programme, degrading public services and growing food bank dependency. As a Brexiteer, he happily wedded us all to the deeply toxic Brexit ideology harming our businesses, starving them of vital staff and turbocharging inflation – especially basic food items, now running at up to 60% more.</p>
<p>Westminster’s hall of mirrors also shows Labour wedded to “make Brexit work”. It’s a nonsensical stance that, hand in hand with their stated belief that the Tories are not deporting enough people quickly enough is a chilling reflection.</p>
<p>And just when you thought that one of the most frightening apparitions had been removed, it is back where it was. Suella Braverman, the Home Secretary, whose dream is *not* of a brighter future for families, or a reduced skills shortage or even an end to people trafficking. No, it is her stated “dream and obsession” to see a flight take asylum seekers to Rwanda. Sacked only 6 days earlier having broken the ministerial code, she is back in the job tasked with upholding law and order and breached national security. She is back alongside colleagues at the helm of the ghostly pirate ship that is the Tory Government.</p>
<p>It’s a horror show we should be done with. The UK is substantially poorer than independent counties comparable to Scotland, with wider inequality, higher child and pensioner poverty and lower productivity. It is time for Scotland to choose a better path.</p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Halloween is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6525</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill of Rights Bill]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1704</id>
		<updated>2022-10-31T11:16:52Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-31T07:00:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bill of Rights Bill"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="European Convention on Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="legislation"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Parliament"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith wants Bradford at the centre of the next Rugby League World Cup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-wants-bradford-at-the-centre-of-the-next-rugby-league-world-cup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities in her Bradford South constituency:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Week in, week out, local communities come together to support their clubs, their local kids’ teams and young players.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, levels of investment and opportunities haven’t always matched the pride we feel in our towns and cities, but it’s moments like the world cup that will give communities the opportunities to stand tall and showcase where they live to the world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A compelling levelling-up bid has been submitted to government for a world-class stadium and training complex for elite sports with a Rugby League Skills, Training and Education centre in Odsal to serve the people of Yorkshire and the North. I can’t wait to host the world cup again in a decade’s time and be standing in our very own Odsal stadium in Bradford cheering England on!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding to Judith’s invitation to visit Odsal, Sports Minister Stuart Andrew MP said: “If I’m still in post by the end of the week I’ll still come but, if not, I’ll leave a note to my successor that their first trip needs to be to Bradford!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2022 Cup’s world-leading social impact programme has invested more than £26 million in equipment and facilities, volunteering, mental health, culture and education, to transform clubs into hubs for their communities. And, for the first time, the men’s, women’s and wheelchair tournaments will be held concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study from the Sheffield Hallam University shows that investment in sport and physical activity gives back four times the investment in social value, equivalent to around £72 billion each year across the UK, improving people’s health and wellbeing, creating jobs and stimulating local economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith is fighting for Bradford to have its share:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When the competition is over and the winning teams raise their trophies, it is only the start of the story for communities, not the end. With the Rugby League world cup in full swing, Bradford’s year as capital of culture in 2025, and Bradford’s bid for a world-class stadium and sports complex that will bring over a billion pounds of benefits to Bradford, now is the time to ensure that people of Bradford benefit from this legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3c9.png" alt="🏉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;The Rugby League World Cup &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLWC2021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@RLWC2021&lt;/a&gt; is more than just a competition – it’s a force for good that can transform the fortunes and unlock the potential of towns and cities like Bradford.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; Today I led a debate in Parliament celebrating this fantastic sport. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheRFL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheRFL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ysM6QHjEO9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ysM6QHjEO9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1584880580881063937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, culture, sports, stadium, odsal, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/santander-picture.jpg.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" alt="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has said that banking provision in the constituency has been totally wiped out. "People will have to travel over three miles to get to a bank,” she said, adding that the bank has “failed to take into account the social costs to the local area of removing this vital&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, will, local, bradford, people, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, people, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford. Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2685</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3349</id>
		<updated>2022-10-21T16:54:04Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-21T16:46:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="All News"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="In Parliament"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This has been another tumultuous period in British politics culminating with the resignation of the Prime Minister. This had looked inevitable once her mini-budget had to be reversed following the loss of market confidence. The Prime Minister’s diagnosis of the need to do more to increase the growth rate was correct, but sadly the policies [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/">Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/"><![CDATA[
<p>This has been another tumultuous period in British politics culminating with the resignation of the Prime Minister. This had looked inevitable once her mini-budget had to be reversed following the loss of market confidence. The Prime Minister’s diagnosis of the need to do more to increase the growth rate was correct, but sadly the policies she prescribed made the situation worse and it’s right that she has resigned.</p>



<p>We knew that Liz Truss was inheriting a difficult position a few weeks ago with the ongoing cost of living crisis, the significant NHS backlogs, the war in Ukraine and the resulting serious issues with energy prices and supply. To those crises we can now add the market turmoil and the increases in interest rates which are so painful for those with mortgages and will worsen the public finances given the amount of debt we owe – and our ongoing need to borrow.</p>



<p>We should have a new Prime Minister in place by the end of next week, in time for the critical statement by the Chancellor on 31 October setting out the details of the public finances and proposed measures to bring borrowing under control. Regrettably it looks very likely that this will include some difficult measures including tax rises and spending cuts. We will need the new Prime Minister and their team to present a coherent plan that we can unite behind to avoid any further market turmoil.</p>



<p>There has been speculation that these measures should include restricting the increases in the state pension and benefits next April to less than the inflation rate of 10.1%. While increases of this level will represent a significant cost, we cannot seek to balance the books on the backs of the least well off and those unable to work to earn extra money. The state pension has never increased by less than inflation and I’m glad the outgoing Prime Minister confirmed the increase would indeed be 10.1%. We should do the same for benefits too. We can’t expect people livings on the least to get through next winter with less money in real terms than this one.</p>



<p>There have been encouraging signs that global gas prices have started to fall. I hope that this continues and signals that efforts to boost supply and reduce demand around the world have stabilised the position. There are however significant risks this winter and next that in the event of a lengthy period of cold weather we might run out of gas. In the short term we all need to be careful with our use – to reduce our bills and protect supply.</p>



<p>In the longer term we need to do more to obtain secure domestic sources of energy including nuclear, wind solar – and fracking for our own gas. None of these are easy – and very often applications are unpopular. The key thing is to ensure we develop these in areas where they have the least impact and that all applications are properly considered through the planning process with local people consulted. We’ve gone further on fracking and proposed requiring actual local consent which is not required for other planning issues. Again, none of this is easy or popular but relying on cheap imports from abroad is no longer a viable strategy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" alt=""/></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/">Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Constituent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing to do so if they contact me directly. But these emails are designed to be informative about local matters, and go to everyone who wants them, regardless of political persuasion, and I do not want to change their local focus even at times when there are significant events at a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charity Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a reminder that the Charity Volunteer Fair, which was postponed because of the sad death of Her Majesty the Queen, is being held between 4pm and 6pm this Friday, 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; October at the Dell Centre, St Giles Church, Park Lane, Ashtead, KT21 1EJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 20 charities will be there, and there will be a wide range of volunteering opportunities. So please do come along. If you can’t make it but are interested in volunteering, please let me know and I will steer you towards the right opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom Methodist Church &amp;#8211; Warm Wednesdays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epsom Methodist Church is launching a programme of Warm Wednesdays for the winter if people are struggling with their bills and need a place to go and warm up and get some company. The events will be held every Wednesday from November 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; until the end of February. From 9am &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be complimentary hot drinks served in their café, from  12.30 &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be Hot and tasty soup and a roll, from 2pm onwards complimentary hot drinks and homemade cakes, and from 3pm &amp;#8211; 6pm a family after-school club with space for homework, story time, games, films and a free hot meal for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church is in Ashley Road, Epsom, KT18 5AQ. People are welcome just to drop in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom &amp;amp; Ewell Energy Relief Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally thank you to everyone who has supported the Epsom and Ewell Energy Efficiency Programme. The appeal has already raised more than £12,000. If you do not need the £400 Government contribution towards bills this winter, please do donate it to the programme and help those locally who are already struggling with higher bills make their homes more energy efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of how to give are at &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/98eeCRO3xsv5ggnEf9CRxP?domain=justgiving.com"&gt;https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best wishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/"&gt;Local Update&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Constituent I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things. A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6321</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Zahawi guests at Conservative Annual Dinner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nadhim Zahawi, Chancellor of the Duchy of Lancaster, Minister for Intergovernmental Relations and Minister for Equalities, was the guest speaker at the Bexleyheath and Crayford Conservative Association on Thursday evening (13 October) held at Stuzzichini restaurant in Bexleyheath. In the Chair was…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner</id>
    <published>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking with Business South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Great to speak with Business South about the work they are doing to support businesses in our region, encouraging new start-ups and increasesing apprenticeship opportunities across Southampton. The pressures of increasing energy costs and staff shortages are a big worry for Southampton businesses and I will continue to push for more action to help these [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/">Speaking with Business South</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5068</id>
    <published>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP welcomes Prime Minister Liz Truss speech to Conservative Party Conference 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning the Prime Minister set out our Conservative vision for the future. A country focussed on growth, aspiration and enterprise. Turning away from those who say much and do little, the anti-growth coalition we are so used to seeing on our screens and in the hall today.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[CHECKMATE!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=467</id>
		<updated>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/september-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5588" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" data-type="URL" data-id="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for September 2022.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for September 2022.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5587</id>
    <published>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="September"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bust Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/09/27/bust-budget/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</p>



<p>The tax cuts in this mini budget, are mainly for the super wealthy, for corporations and for the bankers. The top tax rate of 45p (%) has been completely removed, which is great news for those lucky few that earn over £150,000 a year. Corporation tax increases have been discarded, and the cap on bankers’ bonuses brought in after the financial crisis of 2008 have been scrapped.</p>



<p>But the Tories aren’t content with just giving handouts to the rich, they have also increased the number of Universal Credit recipients who have to actively search for work and attend weekly or fortnightly job centre appointments, if they are working up to 15 hours a week. If they don’t then their benefits will be reduced. Unsurprisingly the mini-budget also attacks trade union rights further, making it harder for working people to strike for the pay and conditions they deserve.</p>



<p>While they have suspended National Insurance increases and cut stamp duty, this support is minute compare to the support for those best off in society. Even in terms of energy bill support, prices being frozen where they are now, simply means they are only twice what they were last year, at the same time that the price for everything else from food to transport is increasing, while wages and benefits remain completely stagnant.</p>



<p>This budget does not serve the needs of the people of Nottingham, it does not help those who need help the most. People earning £20,000 will only save £167 a year. What it will do is drive Britain into an inflationary spiral. It will cause the prices of the goods that residents need to survive to increase further, at a time where benefits and wages are not rising. This will wipe out any gains that residents in the city see from this mini-budget.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg"><img src="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2931" width="398" height="271" srcset="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg 1024w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-768x524.jpg 768w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1536x1047.jpg 1536w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px"/></a><figcaption>the Tory mini-budget will only give most people small change</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Tories say their budget will stimulate growth; it remains to be seen if it will. What is certain though is that growth in the economy is pointless if it does not lead to increased wages for the average person, if people are not supported to re-skill and obtain jobs in growing sectors, and if people do not have access to suitable affordable housing, whether that’s via home ownership or renting.</p>



<p>The mini budget does nothing to help achieve these aims, Nottingham Labour strongly believe that the budget will not help the people of Nottingham, it will only help a tiny minority of people. A Labour government is needed nationally to give the people of this country and of Nottingham the support and help that they need, and that they deserve.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</updated>
    <category term="east midlands"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Cuts"/>
    <category term="debt"/>
    <category term="inflation"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="taxes"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mum’s Here With Us, Yet Already Gone</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/mums-here-with-us-yet-already-gone/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3151</id>
    <published>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-26T08:54:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom</h2>



<p>The availability of free education is a gift, but only if it can come with high quality. Google Classroom has given students in classrooms around the country an online option to supplement their learning. A potential downside to these options is the inability to meet with professors and apply classroom learning. As a part of the University of Washington system, we have found the use of Google Classroom during the quarter distance courses produced good results for both parties. Distance learning is here to stay and has only grown over time. If you want to make sure you aren’t left behind in a digital world, you may want to consider your options and how they will help or hurt your future professional prospects.</p>



<p>Google Classroom is a reliable one-stop-shop for managing all of your coursework and communication. It is definitely worth checking out if you are in a distance learning program, or even just want to streamline some of your everyday communication tasks.</p>



<h3>Benefits and Drawbacks</h3>



<p>There are several other features that set Google Classroom apart from the competition. It is a free tool and it works on computers and mobile devices through the GAFE platform. The discussion features of Google Classroom do an excellent job at encouraging interaction between students and teachers, making it a very effective tool for working with groups of all sizes. The major drawback to Google Classroom is that it is a relatively new tool, so it does not work with iPads, Android tablets or Kindle Fires. The lessons created within Google Docs can be exported directly into Google Classroom on the computer, but in order to view or edit those documents or upload them onto the iPad tablet, students will have to use other third-party tools such as Documents 5 and iBooks Author.</p>



<h2>Integration</h2>



<p>If you are using Google Classroom for your teaching and learning, it is important to note that it does require integration with Google Apps for Education. This means that you are using Gmail along with Calendar and Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides) etc., so the other school faculty members need to have access to all of these tools. The obvious way to do this is through the use of a domain. It is required that you have a domain in order to use Google Classroom or any other GAFE tool/application.</p>



<p>By going through a step by step process, one can easily move one’s entire digital repository into Google Classroom for easy organization and management; therefore, allowing access to all student work without having to worry about losing any data or files that are not needed for a current class engagement.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom Future Prospects</h2>



<p>According to the Scholastic Parent &amp; Child list of the most popular educational apps , in 2015 Classroom wasn’t one of them, indicating that this tool is still relatively new and also relatively unknown. While the design is nothing particularly innovative, the new Google Classroom 2022 is a promising step towards more effective and efficient learning, especially in a classroom setting. Though it appears to be geared towards teachers, students will benefit from having access to Google Classroom, whether they’re in an online or a traditional classroom. With that said, it should be noted that it may take some time before this update fully penetrates into secondary schools and universities. But nonetheless, Google Classroom is off on the right foot, leaning further into an online world which we’ll all have to face sooner or later.</p>



<h2>Bottom Line</h2>



<p>Google Classroom has made a huge impact in the world of educational technology, especially for teachers who don’t have face-to-face access to students. It’s a powerful tool that will likely continue to be developed and improved upon, as educators keep gravitating towards it.</p>



<p>In the end, there is no one best way to teach and learn, but instead many valid options. Whether you are interested in the low-cost education of a MOOC or the high-end technology of Sketchfab virtual reality tours, it’s exciting to see that educational technology is progressing at a rapid rate. Let’s hope that as more schools begin to adopt innovative techniques like Google Classroom, we will continue to see positive changes in how students learn around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission. Google […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=211</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=XdL2KTMV" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6373db56bbee9" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6373db56bbee9').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6373db56bbee9","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6373db56bbee9" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6373db56bbee9" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6373db56bbee9" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6373db56bbee9" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6373db56bbee9" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6373db56bbee9" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6373db56bbee9" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6373db56bbee9" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6373db56bbee9" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6373db56bbee9_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6373db56bbee9 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dzxTr4EftnQ_0rr2g6DwLxSz_hA7GRTvkoCdUNFnnu0d4h90rNfGDA3-lQf3WMLhqXKZUKSIaCEHkZLCNDajw' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
