<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-01-12T14:16:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Harriett: ‘UK Aid helped Covid response’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-%E2%80%98uk-aid-helped-covid-response%E2%80%99" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The UK’s work helping to combat the ebola virus in Africa helped us improve our response to Covid-19, according to West Worcestershire MP Harriett Baldwin. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-%E2%80%98uk-aid-helped-covid-response%E2%80%99" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5025 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T13:57:17Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T13:57:17Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Government’s “we need more time” response to question about timeframes leaves Alex “frustrated”]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/governments-we-need-more-time-response-to-question-about-timeframes-leaves-alex-frustrated/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13864</id>
		<updated>2021-01-12T12:01:58Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-12T12:01:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP, Alex Cunningham, has expressed his frustration at the length of time it’s taking to get answers from the Government for his constituents. Following constituents’ concerns over the Track and Trace scheme – and the time the team takes to provide answers, Alex submitted a Written Parliamentary Question (WPQ) to the Health Secretary [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/governments-we-need-more-time-response-to-question-about-timeframes-leaves-alex-frustrated/">Government’s “we need more time” response to question about timeframes leaves Alex “frustrated”</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Channel 4 Production Training Scheme </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/channel-4-production-training-scheme" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interested in a career in TV? Channel 4's Production Training Scheme is now open to applications. To find out more visit careers.channel4.com/4jobs
Channel 4’s Production Training Scheme is now open for applications. This scheme has long supported entry level talent who are passionate about TV…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/channel-4-production-training-scheme</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jon Cruddas MP Responds to Spring Farm GP Closure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/jon-cruddas-mp-responds-spring-farm-gp-closure" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/DSC_1478_0.JPG?itok=Wo-18cZu" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p> </p>
              <p>In November 2020 Jon Cruddas MP was contacted by patients of the Spring Farm GP surgery, which has operated for 30 years on Upminster Road North in Rainham, concerned about rumours the practice would close in 2021.</p>
              <p>Jon Cruddas has now learned that the surgery is due to close in the next few weeks. Since November Jon has been running a campaign calling on the Government and NHS England to invest more into healthcare provision for south Havering. You can sign the petition here: <strong><a href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/hands-off-our-healthcare">https://joncruddas.org.uk/hands-off-our-healthcare</a></strong></p>
              <p>
                <strong>Jon’s response to confirmation of Spring Farm GP surgery closure</strong>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>“At a time when the health emergency brought about by Covid is at its most intense, the news of the closure of the Spring Farm GP surgery in Upminster Road North in the next few weeks is particularly hard to accept.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>“I have been tirelessly making the case for improvements to primary health care services across Rainham and South Hornchurch over the past few years. But rather than improvements we have seen repeated closures in the area – Mungo Park GP surgery, Mardyke, services in Rainham and now Spring Farm.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>“I have called upon NHS England and the local Clinical Commissioning Group to invest in GP and primary health care services in our area and am continuing to do so. This has never been more vital when you see the pressure on Queens Hospital.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>“In particular I am calling for:</em>
              </p>
              <ul>
                <li>
                  <em>       - Bringing forward the proposed Beam Park health centre, providing the full range of GP and community health services.</em>
                </li>
                <li>
                  <em>       - Provision of outreach and localised surgeries across Rainham and South Hornchurch so that older and vulnerable residents do not have to face difficult journeys.</em>
                </li>
                <li>
                  <em>       - Arrangements be put in place for residents who require repeat prescriptions to save them needing to visit the replacement health centres.</em>
                </li>
              </ul>
              <p>
                <em>“In the meantime, residents can show their support by signing my petition calling for the above by clicking here: <strong><a href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/hands-off-our-healthcare">https://joncruddas.org.uk/hands-off-our-healthcare</a></strong>”</em>
              </p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/nhs" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">NHS</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/rainham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Rainham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/spring-farm" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Spring Farm</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/healthcare" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Healthcare</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-5">
              <a href="/tags/services" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Services</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-6">
              <a href="/tags/campaign" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Campaign</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-7">
              <a href="/tags/petition" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Petition</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-8">
              <a href="/tags/investment" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Investment</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1445 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T10:42:25Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T10:42:25Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP presses Minister for COVID Vaccine Deployment to add school staff to vaccination priority list</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389466/mp-presses-minister-for-covid-vaccine-deployment-to-add-school-staff-to-vaccination-priority-list"/>
  <updated>2021-01-12T10:21:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389466/mp-presses-minister-for-covid-vaccine-deployment-to-add-school-staff-to-vaccination-priority-list</id>
  <summary type="text">Last night in Parliament, local MP Tim Farron praised the 'immense service' of people working in schools, and made the case for them to be added on to the priority list for vaccinations.
Tim was speaking in a Westminster Hall debate on a national petition which called on the Government to prioritise teachers, school and childcare staff for COVID-19 vaccination.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last night in Parliament, local MP Tim Farron praised the 'immense service' of people working in schools, and made the case for them to be added on to the priority list for vaccinations.</p>
<p>Tim was speaking in a Westminster Hall debate on a national petition which called on the Government to prioritise teachers, school and childcare staff for COVID-19 vaccination.</p>
<p>The petition has received over 460,000 signatures, including over 3,000 signatures from Cumbria. 589 people have signed the petition in Tim's Westmorland and Lonsdale constituency.</p>
<p>Speaking during the debate, Tim said: <em>"People talk about the reopening of schools, but they are open: far more children are being taught in our schools and in school settings today than during the April-May phase of the earliest lockdown, for lots of very good reasons.</em></p>
<p><em>"One reason why schools have been otherwise closed as part of the lockdown is that we recognise that the science shows that although children do not get badly affected by the disease, they clearly spread it.</em></p>
<p><em>"We are asking teachers, teaching assistants and other school staff to put themselves in harm's way for good reason, so it is right that they be considered as part of the priority vaccination list alongside others.</em></p>
<p><em>"No one wants to muscle their way to the front of the queue, but we recognise that these are people who are doing an immense service for our children and our country, and who are putting themselves at risk at the same time."</em></p>
<p>In response, the Minister for COVID Vaccine Deployment, Nadhim Zahawi said: <em>"Schools, as the hon. Member for Westmorland and Lonsdale reminded us, are open.</em></p>
<p><em>"Primary and secondary schools are open, delivering both online education and education in school for the most vulnerable children and the children of NHS and social care workers, who look after the people who are most vulnerable and whom we are trying to protect from dying.</em></p>
<p><em>"I understand the sentiment behind the petition and pay tribute to the vital work that teachers in schools and childcare workers do to see us through this difficult time.</em></p>
<p><em>"However, I believe that our strategy of putting the most vulnerable first is the right one, morally, ethically and practically, but I recognise that even with such brilliant work in full swing the next few weeks will be difficult, especially in education settings."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Great to catch up with constituents, I am very clear leaseholders should not have to pay for historic fire safety defects</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1741-great-to-catch-up-with-constituents-i-am-very-clear-leaseholders-should-not-have-to-pay-for-historic-fire-safety-defects"/>
		<published>2021-01-12T09:52:28+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-12T09:52:28+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1741-great-to-catch-up-with-constituents-i-am-very-clear-leaseholders-should-not-have-to-pay-for-historic-fire-safety-defects</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It was great to catch up with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SophieLB1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SophieLB1&lt;/a&gt; and other constituents affected by the cladding scandal. I am very clear that leaseholders should not have to pay for historic fire safety defects. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ukcag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ukcag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EOCS_Official?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@EOCS_Official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndOurCladdingScandal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndOurCladdingScandal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/n2DkHG1FUc"&gt;https://t.co/n2DkHG1FUc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1348927137663889409?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;It was great to catch up with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SophieLB1?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@SophieLB1&lt;/a&gt; and other constituents affected by the cladding scandal. I am very clear that leaseholders should not have to pay for historic fire safety defects. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ukcag?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ukcag&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EOCS_Official?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@EOCS_Official&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/EndOurCladdingScandal?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#EndOurCladdingScandal&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/n2DkHG1FUc"&gt;https://t.co/n2DkHG1FUc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1348927137663889409?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 12, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debbie Abrahams MP’s update on Dovestone</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/debbie-abrahams-update-on-dovestone/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>Last summer I convened a meeting with the owners of the site, United Utilities (UU), the site’s leaseholder, the RSPB, other partners and concerned residents to discuss the antisocial and frankly dangerous behaviour of visitors to Dovestone. UU and the partners agreed to draft proposals for a new visitors’ strategy to address these issues and we reconvened to discuss these in November. At this meeting it was agreed to put these proposals out for wider community consultation in January 2021 which, as the legal owners of the site, UU will be co-ordinating.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, with the third lockdown announced last week by the Prime Minister, once again we’ve seen more antisocial behaviour and flagrant flouting of Covid restrictions at Dovestone with social distancing being ignored, and people clearly exercising with more than one person outside their household and not exercising locally. This is hugely disappointing given the seriousness of the pandemic and the new, more infectious Covid variant that we are also seeing here in Oldham and Saddleworth.</p>
<p>The consultation for a ‘community led visitor strategy’ includes many elements which are designed to address the issues identified by many residents, including the potential for electronic signage, CCTV and modified car parking in a bid to tackle anti-social behaviour, inconsiderate parking, and increased littering. Clearly a long term solution to this ongoing problem for people living near Dovestone needs to be found.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the problem with so many people visiting the area, because it’s so beautiful, is clearly being exacerbated by the vagaries of the Government’s guidelines during this new lockdown, and in particular what constitutes ‘not travelling [sic] outside your local area’ for exercise. As Derbyshire Police are finding to their cost.</p>
<p>As such I will be writing to the Home Office, the Department of Health and Social Care, and the Ministry of Housing and Local Government, asking that as part of their regular review of their guidelines, they give the public, and the police who have to enforce the rules, clearer guidance on what is and what is not acceptable during the pandemic, as they did in the first lockdown last March.</p>
<p>I’ll also be asking United Utilities, as the owners of the private land around the reservoir, as well as other organisations, to look closely at the messaging on their websites and other social media platforms, which could inadvertently be contravening the guidelines by encouraging people who don’t live locally to visit the area.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/debbie-abrahams-update-on-dovestone/">Debbie Abrahams MP’s update on Dovestone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/debbie-abrahams-update-on-dovestone/">Debbie Abrahams MP’s update on Dovestone</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6734</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T09:51:42Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T09:51:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Crime &amp; Policing"/>
    <category term="Environment"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/rugby-league-clubs-social-impact-worth-185m-a-year/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Rugby League’s response to the Covid-19 pandemic has been highlighted by a groundbreaking report which concludes that Rugby League clubs contribute £185m in social value each year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins, chair of the All Party-Parliamentary Group on Rugby League said: &amp;#8220;This proves that Rugby League is more than just a sport. Rugby League Clubs including their staff, players and volunteers should be recognised for the impact they have had and continue to have in supporting our communities through lockdowns and restrictions. They have often been the glue keeping communities together.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read the full article &lt;a href="https://www.nwemail.co.uk/sport/19003069.rugby-league-clubs-social-impact-worth-185-million/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;by clicking here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;89&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, social, including, staff, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy."&gt;Judith tells Government 'the people of the north will hold you to account' on rebalancing the economy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;87&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy."&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy." alt="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy." /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864 Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, restrictions, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;66&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" alt="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has welcomed the latest proposals for tougher sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving and urges the government to act on them without delay Responding in Parliament, Leader of the House Jacob-Rees Mogg said: " “I thank the hon. Lady for the campaigning she's done on this very&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, cummins, read, full, article, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-welcomes-re-opening-of-bradfords-businesses/" title="Judith welcomes re-opening of Bradford&amp;#039;s businesses"&gt;Judith welcomes re-opening of Bradford's businesses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;64&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-welcomes-re-opening-of-bradfords-businesses/" title="Judith welcomes re-opening of Bradford&amp;#039;s businesses"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/thumbnail_IMG_20200731_100014-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith welcomes re-opening of Bradford&amp;#039;s businesses" alt="Judith welcomes re-opening of Bradford&amp;#039;s businesses" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith Cummins has welcomed the reopening of&amp;nbsp;business&amp;nbsp;across Bradford which had been shut by local coronavirus restrictions. A number of businesses - including gyms, swimming pools, skating rinks, bowling alleys and indoor play areas – are now allowed to re-open You can read the full article here in the T&amp;amp;A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, article, full, read, including, restrictions, local, cummins, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rugby League’s response to the Covid-19 pandemic has been highlighted by a groundbreaking report which concludes that Rugby League clubs contribute £185m in social value each year. Judith Cummins, chair of the All Party-Parliamentary Group on Rugby League said: “This proves that Rugby League is more than just a sport. Rugby League Clubs including their […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2454</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T09:31:32Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T09:31:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Recovering from the virus</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/01/12/recovering-from-the-virus/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The ever tightening lockdowns increase the  damage to businesses requiring social contact. They  delay the start of recovery and make the loss of more small businesses and supply capacity more likely.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yesterday’s statement from the Chancellor did not update the  forecasts for the economy and did not answer the question of why some small businesses that have to shut are left out of the compensation or assistance schemes. Getting through one lock down by borrowing more or drawing down on savings or reserves may be possible but doing it all over again in a second lock down is more difficult. Setting up and running  your own business is hard enough without successive bans on trading lasting for the best part of a year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The government’s strategy to get out of this is heavily dependent on rapid roll outs of vaccines. It would also help to redouble efforts to reduce the  spread of infection  in health settings. The loss of staff from illness and the need to self isolate is adding  to the strains. Redoubling  efforts  to find a wider range of treatments would help, as the treatments cut the time the serious illness lasts.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today there is another debate on CV 19 in Parliament. It would be good to hear from Ministers progress on providing more support for closed small businesses, more news on infection control and treatments, and some report on how air flow and extraction can be improved to reduce infection spread. We need to get more back to work and more businesses trading as safely as possible. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The ever tightening lockdowns increase the damage to businesses requiring social contact. They delay the start of recovery and make the loss of more small businesses and supply capacity more likely. Yesterday’s statement from the Chancellor did not update the forecasts for the economy and did not answer the question of why some small businesses […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29408</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T07:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T07:05:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Looking forwards – my article for the Heatons Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/looking-forwards-my-article-for-the-heatons-post/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=looking-forwards-my-article-for-the-heatons-post" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233211" src="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Looking-forwards.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p class="xmsonormal">As the clock strikes midnight on 31st December each year, amidst all the hugging, drinking and Auld Lang Syne-ing, we all collectively hope that the year to come will be better than the last. For once, we can all be fairly confident that these hopes will be realised. Put bluntly, 2020 was a pig of a year and I’m fairly sure that we’re all delighted to see the back of it.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">We’ve all faced difficulties, whether it’s not seeing our families, losing jobs or businesses, feeling isolated and lonely or losing loved ones to the virus. As a community, the events that are normally such highlights – like ReddFest or Friends of Reddish Vale’s seasonal events – have been cancelled, along with countless birthday parties, weddings and religious festivals.</p>
<p class="xmsonormal">In all these dark times though, 2020 did give us one very positive thing indeed and that was the launch of the newspaper that you hold in your hands (or are scrolling down online) right now! The Heatons Post has been a delight to read through these difficult times, full of positive stories about the brilliant things going on in Reddish and the Heatons despite the pandemic and the lockdown. Thanks to the Heatons Post team for all their hard work keeping the community connected and informed during this time!<span class="apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p class="xmsonormal">Just because we’re in 2021, the challenges that we face won’t magically disappear, but there is much to be hopeful about in this new year. Vaccines are being rolled out which will allow social distancing to be phased out, businesses will be able to reopen and we’ll be able to spend time with friends and family again. What’s more, if there’s one thing that 2020 taught us all, it’s how fantastic the community is we have here – together I believe we can support each other to make sure we all have a happier, healthier 2021.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/looking-forwards-my-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Looking forwards – my article for the Heatons Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>As the clock strikes midnight on 31st December each year, amidst all the hugging, drinking and Auld Lang Syne-ing, we all collectively hope that the year to come will be better than the last. For once, we can all be fairly confident that these hopes will be realised. Put bluntly, 2020 was a pig of […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/looking-forwards-my-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Looking forwards – my article for the Heatons Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233210</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T18:16:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T18:16:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne welcomes Government support to help children access remote learning</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-welcomes-government-support-help-children-access-remote-learning" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="6868" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">11 January 2021</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne welcomes Government support to help children access remote learning</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span>Philip Dunne MP has welcomed measures the Government has put in place to help students receive remote education while schools are closed, including laptops and tablets for schools to allocate locally to students who need them, 4G routers for internet access, and video lessons made available via the Oak National Academy.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Throughout the pandemic, education has been a national priority, and thanks to the efforts of teachers and school staff across Shropshire, schools remain the best, and safest place for our children to learn. However, with the whole country in alert level 5, the highest it has ever been, the closure of schools is now necessary to keep the new variant of the virus under control. </span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><strong><span><span>Philip Dunne said: </span></span></strong></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>“The difficult decision to close schools and colleges was not taken lightly but is necessary if we are to keep the new variant of the virus at bay across the country. While nothing can ever replace the benefits of learning in a classroom for our children and young people, I am pleased the Government is again helping to make sure young people and children have access to high-quality remote learning so they can receive continuing education that they deserve and need.” </span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>As part of the Government’s commitment that no child is left behind, it is providing a million laptops and tablets for schools to allocate locally to students who need them most. To date, it has delivered over 560,000 devices to councils in England, with students benefitting from the 560,000 devices provided to schools and colleges and a further 100,000 arriving this week nationally.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>In tackling the barriers to remote learning for our most vulnerable students, over 54,000 4G routers to have been delivered to schools and colleges in England, helping children access the internet. The Government is building on this work through its partnership with the UK’s leading mobile phone providers, including EE, Three, O2 and Vodafone, to deliver free internet access for these students until July 2021.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The Government has also supported provision of video lessons made available via the Oak National Academy, and strengthened remote education requirements for schools, monitored by Ofsted, so parents can be reassured that their children will benefit from a set number of hours of high-quality remote learning a day. </span></span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6868 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T17:43:24Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T17:43:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK Government must set up Brexit Adjustment Fund</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/11/uk-government-must-set-up-brexit-adjustment-fund/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Chair of the International Trade Committee, Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil is writing to Chancellor of the Exchequer Rishi Sunak stressing the need for the UK Government to set up a Fund to assist those adversely affected by Brexit.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil is suggesting a Fund similar to the Brexit Adjustment Reserve set up by the European Union.</p>



<p>He said: “It has been long known that the worst impacted part of the whole of Europe by Brexit will be the Highlands andn Islands of Scotland.</p>



<p>“The impacts of Brexit are of course worse in the UK but there will be impacts on the European Union too obviously. There is no good Brexit, the economic story is bad for everybody.</p>



<p>“Realising this, the EU have set up a Brexit Adjustment Reserve worth about 5 billion Euros. The lion share of that is expected to go to Ireland whose economy will be impacted greatly.</p>



<p>“However, being impacted far more percentage wise will be the economy of the Highlands and Islands and perhaps most of Scotland.</p>



<p>“Therefore, I think the Chancellor of the Exchequer should set up a similar fund to what the Europeans are doing, commencing it with the economic damage Brexit is going to do to help those affected.</p>



<p>“We see already the effect on fish processors and fishermen who cannot get their catch to the valuable and lucrative market.</p>



<p>“Brexit was not the choice of Scotland but the choice of a Tory Government in a faraway Westminster.</p>



<p>“As a result, they should now ensure there is a Fund in place to compensate for the damage that they have started and continue to do as a result of the policies.</p>



<p>“If Europe can do it for the citizens of the European Union, surely the UK Government can do this for the citizens of this current Union.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="3023" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/ab3-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg" data-orig-size="640,481" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="ab3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-3023" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg 640w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab3.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px"/></a></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chair of the International Trade Committee, Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil is writing to Chancellor of the Exchequer …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/11/uk-government-must-set-up-brexit-adjustment-fund/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3295</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:54:07Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T14:54:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP congratulates Hornsea School and Language College for their remote learning success</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-congratulates-hornsea-school-and-language-college-for-their-remote-learning-success/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-congratulates-hornsea-school-and-language-college-for-their-remote-learning-success/meeting-with-headteacher-and-chair-of-govenors-at-hornsea-school-and-language-college-jan-21/" rel="attachment wp-att-10885"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-10885" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Meeting-with-Headteacher-and-Chair-of-Govenors-at-Hornsea-School-and-Language-College-Jan-21-740x393.jpg" alt="" width="740" height="393" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Meeting-with-Headteacher-and-Chair-of-Govenors-at-Hornsea-School-and-Language-College-Jan-21-740x393.jpg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Meeting-with-Headteacher-and-Chair-of-Govenors-at-Hornsea-School-and-Language-College-Jan-21-300x159.jpg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Meeting-with-Headteacher-and-Chair-of-Govenors-at-Hornsea-School-and-Language-College-Jan-21.jpg 1380w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness, virtually met with Headteacher of Hornsea School and Language College, Steve Ostler, and the Chair of Governors, Graham McDonald, to congratulate Steve and find out how he and his staff successfully prepared for remote learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the Prime Minister’s announcement about the new national lockdown on 4 January 2021, it was confirmed that only the children of critical workers, vulnerable children and young people who do not have access to a device should attend school or college. All other pupils and students should not attend and should receive remote learning instead. Schools are expected to provide a minimum of 3-5 hours of remote learning per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham said, “I am delighted to hear about the incredible efforts Steve Ostler and his staff have made to ensure the success of remote learning for their pupils, as well as their admirable commitment to supporting their students’ overall wellbeing. I want to congratulate Steve and his staff for taking such a positive and pragmatic approach and all the work they have done to ensure that their students’ education continues smoothly during this period of national restrictions. I am quite certain that pupils (or at least their parents) will appreciate their effort – it is hard not to be impressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The past year has provided us with unprecedented challenges to be met, and these clearly continue into 2021. It is great to hear about teachers and school staff working together effectively and meeting those challenges in this way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Headteacher, Steve Ostler, said “I really appreciate Graham’s time and interest in all the work that my staff and I have put in to ensure that our students are supported and provided with the best education that we can offer at this difficult time. I think it is really important to have these types of conversations so that schools can feedback the challenges they are experiencing, and the Government can understand what is happening on the ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chair of Governors, Graham McDonald, said “It was great to chat with Graham and share with him the immense efforts Steve and his staff have made to continue our students&amp;#8217; education during the new lockdown. Staff overwhelmingly decided to come into school to support the distance learning process, and we are assisting those children who need to be in school, in a safe controlled environment. The work they have done is exemplary, and they deserve every congratulation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham is looking forward to working with the Headteacher and the Chair of Governors in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness, virtually met with Headteacher of Hornsea School and Language College, Steve Ostler, and the Chair of Governors, Graham...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10884</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:32:43Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T14:32:43Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Hornsea"/>
    <category term="Schools"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[VACCINE CENTRE VISIT]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=343</id>
		<updated>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Oak Park Leisure Centre to act as Covid-19 Vaccination Hub!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/oak-park-leisure-centre-to-act-as-covid-19-vaccination-hub/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On Friday I visited Oak Park Leisure Centre as it was about to go live as one of the Covid-19 vaccination hubs in the Walsall Borough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walsall Council has provided this site and combined with the local Primary Care Network and Walsall Together to create the hub for the East of the Borough.   NHS staff, GPs, Council Staff, leisure centre staff and volunteers are all working extremely hard vaccinating local residents from my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency, and the organisation and logistics are incredible. I pay tribute to all those involved in making this happen.  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate that people want to receive their vaccinations but it is really important that as residents you wait until you are contacted by your GP practice, or the NHS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Covid-19 vaccination programme is the largest in our history, but it will ensure that we can steadily return to a more normal way of life after a year of unprecedented restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3496" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210108_112228-scaled.jpg" alt="" width="2560" height="1920" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210108_112228-scaled.jpg 2560w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210108_112228-1280x960.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210108_112228-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210108_112228-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 2560px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday I visited Oak Park Leisure Centre as it was about to go live as one of the Covid-19 vaccination hubs in the Walsall Borough. Walsall Council has provided this site and combined with the local Primary Care Network and Walsall Together to create the hub for the East of the Borough.   NHS staff, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3494</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:42:19Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:42:19Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP joins wedding industry roundtable</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-joins-wedding-industry-roundtable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP Maria Miller joined a meeting of the UK Wedding Taskforce today to offer her support to the businesses involved in this sector that have been impacted by the Coronavirus pandemic. The UK Wedding Taskforce is a Government supported industry group to ensure the full impact of the pandemic on…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-joins-wedding-industry-roundtable</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Galashiels testing centre welcomed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/new-galashiels-testing-centre-welcomed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The UK Government has opened a new walk through testing centre in Galashiels. The centre opened on Saturday 9th January at Langlee Community Centre.
The centre will operate seven days a week, with appointments available from 8am to 8pm.
In Scotland, the UK Government is providing all COVID testing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/new-galashiels-testing-centre-welcomed</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-102" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The government has taken a twin track approach to Covid - finding the medicines and cures as fast as possible and reducing infection spread while this work goes on. The current lockdown is until 31 March. The vaccine seems so tantalisingly close, but even by the end of February we will not have…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-102</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour Councillors call on Government to retain £20 a week increase for Universal Credit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/11/nottingham-labour-councillors-call-on-government-to-retain-20-a-week-increase-for-universal-credit/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today Nottingham Labour councillors call on the Government to  retain the £20 a week increase to Universal Credit made at the beginning of the pandemic and extend the payment to claimants of legacy benefits who are currently excluded from the additional support.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There are roughly 35,000 people on Universal Credit in Nottingham. These are people that were already struggling before the pandemic and  the economic consequences of the lockdown has made life harder for them. The Government was right to help mitigate the this hardship last year with an increase  to Universal Credit payments of £20 a week. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Reversing this  will hit those already most in need and result in more debt, more rent arrears and  greater reliance on food banks for many people in Nottingham. As unemployment across the country hits record highs and incomes are increasingly stretched, it is essential there is an adequate support system for those that need it. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The government needs to urgently reconsider its planned cut.&lt;br&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/11/nottingham-labour-councillors-call-on-government-to-retain-20-a-week-increase-for-universal-credit/"&gt;Nottingham Labour Councillors call on Government to retain £20 a week increase for Universal Credit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Today Nottingham Labour councillors call on the Government to  retain the £20 a week increase to Universal Credit made at the beginning of the pandemic and extend the payment to claimants of legacy benefits who are currently excluded from the additional support. There are roughly 35,000 people on Universal Credit in Nottingham. These are people...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/11/nottingham-labour-councillors-call-on-government-to-retain-20-a-week-increase-for-universal-credit/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/11/nottingham-labour-councillors-call-on-government-to-retain-20-a-week-increase-for-universal-credit/">Nottingham Labour Councillors call on Government to retain £20 a week increase for Universal Credit</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2573</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T11:19:09Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T11:19:09Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Utility Week: Regulatory appeals, the Penrose review, and the case for change]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/03/utility-week-regulatory-appeals-the-penrose-review-and-the-case-for-change/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4543</id>
		<updated>2021-01-11T08:47:51Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-03T08:44:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fingleton’s Simon Oates discusses the potential implications for regulated companies of the Penrose Review of UK competition policy. Is the system of regulatory appeals in the UK about to be overhauled? In September last year, the prime minister asked&#160;John Penrose&#160;to examine UK competition policy with a view to identifying how it should evolve to meet [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/03/utility-week-regulatory-appeals-the-penrose-review-and-the-case-for-change/"><![CDATA[
<p>Fingleton’s Simon Oates discusses the potential implications for regulated companies of the Penrose Review of UK competition policy. Is the system of regulatory appeals in the UK about to be overhauled?</p>



<p>In September last year, the prime minister asked&nbsp;<strong>John Penrose</strong>&nbsp;to examine UK competition policy with a view to identifying how it should evolve to meet the government’s policy aim of promoting a dynamic, innovation-driven economy. The ‘Penrose review’, as it is called, is timely. The country has left the European Union and at the same time is urgently exploring a route out of the economic turmoil caused by coronavirus.</p>



<p>The Penrose review is broad in scope. And there are good reasons for this. Parts of the competition regime hitherto handled by Brussels are now being handed back to the UK to manage and own, such as large mergers and state aid. According to the government,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/terms-of-reference-for-john-penrose-mp-report-on-competition-policy/terms-of-reference-john-penrose-mp-report-on-competition-policy#fn:7" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the scope</a>&nbsp;of the review will include antitrust and consumer protection policy, including tackling consumer rip-offs, bad business practices, and “supporting disruptors taking risks on new ideas”.</p>



<p>The review will also consider reform ideas advanced by outgoing Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) chairman Lord Andrew Tyrie, set out in his&nbsp;<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/781151/Letter_from_Andrew_Tyrie_to_the_Secretary_of_State_BEIS.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">letter to then BEIS secretary Greg Clark</a>&nbsp;in February 2019.</p>



<p>One eye-catching – and potentially controversial – suggestion in Lord Tyrie’s letter is his statement that, “there is a strong case for removing review of economic regulatory decisions from the CMA. These could be consolidated in the Courts … this would simplify appeal arrangements across the regulatory landscape.”</p>



<p>This statement signals a major change to the way appeals could work. It suggests a removal of the current right to a “merit based review” of sector regulator’s decisions by the CMA – which exists in one form or another across most regulated sectors. His suggestion is to establish an alternative process where appeal cases would go straight to the Courts on judicial review grounds.</p>



<p>Is there justification for such a radical move, should regulated businesses and their investors care about such changes, and if so what can they do?</p>



<p>Today’s regulatory environment</p>



<p>UK regulators are responsible for setting the allowed: revenues, level of returns, and the scale and scope of investment for companies of considerable size and value. Critical pipes and infrastructure businesses – water, energy, and telecoms – alone represent over £35 billion of annual revenues. If we add in the revenues of other major UK regulated businesses, Royal Mail, NATS, Heathrow Airport and Network Rail, the combined annual turnover rises to more than £50 billion.</p>



<p>With the oversight of such significant economic activity vested in the hands of non-elected institutions, it’s essential that sector regulators are held accountable for their decisions through a range of clear and robust processes. At present, a range of methods combine to provide accountability, including:</p>



<ul><li>•Corporate Governance requirements (notably: Boards with Independent Chairs / Non-Executives)</li><li>•Consumer representation (for example via statutory consumer bodies such as Citizens Advice Bureaux and Consumer Council for Water)</li><li>•Transparency arrangements (notably: a statutory requirement to consult on licence modifications)</li><li>•The ability for regulated companies to request references to the CMA / CAT for merits based review / appeals of major regulatory decisions (e.g. licence changes such as price reviews)</li><li>•Judicial Review</li><li>•Parliamentary Scrutiny via Select Committees</li></ul>



<p>Two things leap out from this list. The first is that the only way a sector regulator’s decision can be reviewed – and potentially removed and replaced by an alternative outcome – is by reference to the CMA. Whilst the other processes provide strong incentives for high quality decision making, reference to the CMA is the only means by which the regulator’s final decision can be subjected to a merits based review – an assessment of whether the decision was ‘right and preferable’ based on evidence which supports a high quality decision.</p>



<p>The second is that, whilst most accountability measures are applied consistently, the approach to a merits based review varies significantly from sector to sector. This may explain Lord Tyrie’s call to simplify appeal arrangements across regulated sectors.</p>



<p>The table below summarises the current landscape (merits based reviews and appeals):</p>



<p>Is there a case for change?</p>



<p>The variation across sectors (illustrated in the table above) means that there are material differences in the detail of how each sector regulator is held accountable for the quality of their decisions.</p>



<p>These sector specific differences are largely a relic of history. Each one linked to the stage of maturity of their industry – when their sector specific legislation was established. The variation is not driven by any specific rationale, such as sector specific needs.</p>



<p>The Penrose review provides an ideal opportunity to re-evaluate the regulatory appeals framework and the CMA’s role within it. Full harmonisation across all sectors may not be desirable, but a fresh assessment of whether the existing differences across sectors remain appropriate – targeting simplification where possible – would provide welcome clarity for regulated businesses.</p>



<p>What also seems clear is that any dilution in regulatory accountability, specifically the removal of a merits based review of decisions by an independent body, is unlikely to be the right answer. Any move to do so should be troubling to regulated businesses, their investors, and also the boards of independent sector regulators who value their credibility.</p>



<p>History shows regulators don’t always get it right the first time. There are many examples over the last two decades of sector regulators decisions being referred to the CMA, (or its predecessors the CC or MMC) and of errors being identified as part of the merits based review. Sometimes in the favour of companies, sometimes customers.</p>



<p>This year has been no different on that front. In February 2020, four water companies disputed their regulator’s, decision relating to the price review settlement, seeking a redetermination at the CMA. At the time of writing, the CMA, in its provisional findings, found some aspects of Ofwat’s decisions wanting. The CMA is currently consulting on upping the rate of allowed return for the water companies 0.54bps above Ofwat’s original figure as well as allowing each company a higher expenditure allowance (on average about 15 per cent above Ofwat’s settlement). Without scope for a merits based review, a judicial review would be the only basis for appeal. And, the courts are limited in scope. They can only consider if the method by which a regulator took a decision was robust, not if the regulator was correct. Simply put, moving away from a merits based review process would leave companies unable to seek a review of whether the level of allowed return or expenditure allowances had been set at the right level, by their regulator, to underpin financeability.</p>



<p>Adopting a judicial review process is not just a bold move, it could hurt businesses, industries and consumers. Further still, it could undermine the accountability of independent regulators as well as trust in the sectors they oversee. All of which is problematic as the UK seeks to attract investment in critical infrastructure, the government charts a path to economic recovery following the Covid pandemic and seeks to tackle the major societal challenges to achieve net zero.</p>



<p>So what should happen?</p>



<p>We need sector regulators to continue to be accountable and we need a framework to make this happen. Any changes to the system must avoid dilution of accountability. A move away from a merits based review of regulators’ decisions would be a clear dilution.</p>



<p>Our hope is that Penrose will take this opportunity to provide businesses with additional clarity, and propose a harmonised appeal process across the industry sectors.</p>



<p>What this appeals process looks like in practice is not a decision to be taken lightly. The CMA has the central role in ensuring consumers get a good deal when buying goods and services, and that businesses operate within the law. We know that its primary focus is to investigate mergers and entire markets, to take action against businesses and individuals involved in cartels or anti-competitive behaviour, and to protect consumers from unfair trading practices. But come January 2021, its plate will be full, as the effects of Brexit start to bite. Inclusion in its remit to act as an appellate body for sector regulators price review decisions does seem an odd bed fellow in this context.</p>



<p>And, removing the review of sector regulators’ price review decisions from CMA’s remit would clarify its role as a decision taker rather than appellate body. What then for merits based review of regulator’s decisions? One option would be to channel them to the Competition Appeal Tribunal – a body which is well-versed in appeals based on the merits (the clue’s in the name).</p>



<p>Penrose’s report is expected this month and regulated companies and their investors are watching closely. At this stage, the Penrose review has not explicitly gone out to consultation or asked for responses from industry. Instead, it has opted to speak directly to deemed experts to gather views and insight. This does not stop a concerned company or its investors from writing to the review team to express their views, make their voice heard and help shape their regulatory future.</p>



<p>Simon Oates is the head of the infrastructure practice at Fingleton. Prior to joining the consultancy last year he spent seven years at Southern Water, latterly as director of corporate strategy, regulation and corporate affairs. He also spent two years at Thames Water.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Jack Gebhard</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Government provides devices for students to support remote learning]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/government-provides-devices-for-students-to-support-remote-learning/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2124</id>
		<updated>2021-01-10T17:59:30Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-09T12:10:24Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Education"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Robin Walker has welcomed the measures the Government has put in place to ensure every student across Worcester receives a high-quality remote education while schools are closed. Throughout the pandemic, education has been a national priority, and thanks to the efforts of teachers and school staff across the country, schools remain the best, and safest [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/government-provides-devices-for-students-to-support-remote-learning/"><![CDATA[<p>Robin Walker has welcomed the measures the Government has put in place to ensure every student across Worcester receives a high-quality remote education while schools are closed.</p>
<p>Throughout the pandemic, education has been a national priority, and thanks to the efforts of teachers and school staff across the country, schools remain the best, and safest place for our children to learn.</p>
<p>However, with our country in alert level 5, the highest it has ever been, the closure of schools is now necessary to keep the new variant of the virus under control. While there is no substitute for learning in a classroom, the Government has strengthened measures to ensure every child has access to a high-quality remote education.</p>
<p>As part of the Government’s commitment that no child is left behind, it is providing a million laptops and tablets for schools to allocate locally to students who need  them most. To date, it has delivered over 560,000 devices to councils in England, with students in Worcester benefitting from the 525 devices provided to schools and colleges across Worcestershire with a further 100,000 arriving this week nationally.</p>
<p>In tackling the barriers to remote learning for our most vulnerable students, over 54,000 4G routers to have been delivered to schools and colleges in England, ensuring every child has internet access. The Government is building on this work through its partnership with the UK’s leading mobile phone providers, including EE, Three, O2 and Vodafone, to deliver free internet access for these students until July 2021.</p>
<p>The Government has also strengthened remote education requirements for schools, which will be enforced by Ofsted, so parents can be reassured that their children will benefit from a set number of hours of high-quality remote learning a day.</p>
<p><strong>Commenting, Robin said: </strong></p>
<p>“Having taken the difficult decision to close schools and colleges it is right that the government is providing support for students to ensure they can continue their learning from home.”</p>
<p>“I am meeting with headteachers in Worcester this week to discuss the challenges they are facing with accommodating face to face education for the students of key workers while providing remote learning for the majority of students.”</p>
<p><strong> </strong><strong>Commenting, Education Secretary, Gavin Williamson said:</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong>“The last thing any Education Secretary wants to do is close schools and this is not a decision that the government ever wanted to take. But the closing of schools for the majority of pupils does not mean the end of their education.”</p>
<p>“Schools and colleges are much better prepared to deliver online learning – with the delivery of a million devices well underway, data support and high-quality video lessons available via the Oak National Academy.”</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/government-provides-devices-for-students-to-support-remote-learning/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/government-provides-devices-for-students-to-support-remote-learning/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Stay away from planned demonstration at the Scottish Parliament tomorrow</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13077/stay-away-from-planned-demonstration-at-the-scottish-parliament-tomorrow" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is the message from our Council Leader who is urging members of the public to stay at home and not attend a planned demonstration at the Scottish Parliament tomorrow.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13077/stay-away-from-planned-demonstration-at-the-scottish-parliament-tomorrow</id>
    <published>2021-01-10T17:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-10T17:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update following discussions regarding vaccinations in Chesterfield and Derbyshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/94H1vQroyDU/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4761</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T18:30:29Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T18:30:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 8 January 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/8jan21" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>From this week, the Government are introducing new national lockdown measures<span><strong>. </strong>I know how frustrating and disheartening this news will be after an incredibly challenging year, b</span>ut these restrictions are necessary to save lives and to prevent our NHS from becoming overwhelmed. We’ve seen alarming increases in cases in recent weeks, with rates of infection and hospitalisation now rising extremely quickly in every region of the UK. The new variant of the virus is 50% to 70% more infectious and transmissible. Hundreds of people are losing their lives on a daily basis. Every day without decisive action means more will die and our hospitals will be unable to care for those who are desperately ill. It’s devastating for families and businesses to start the New Year with tighter restrictions – but this is the only way we will save lives; protect our NHS; and get through the toughest winter we have ever faced.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/8jan21</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T15:36:24Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T15:36:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>*Attention Schools and Parents*</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/attention-schools-and-parents/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=attention-schools-and-parents" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>While they are sadly closed during lockdown, schools can use this link to request free increases in mobile data allowances for families who don’t have broadband and can’t afford it themselves, so that the kids can access online education. Three, Smarty, Virgin Mobile, EE, Tesco Mobile &amp; Sky Mobile are all taking part in the scheme.<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://get-help-with-tech.education.gov.uk/about-increasing-mobile-data?fbclid=IwAR1cM8ld8nwRpR4xOVhFHQhntqoOx1rbzlfIl0BQB4v7ORB4AAHZ0nlPsY8" target="_blank">https://get-help-with-tech.education.gov.uk/about…</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Information for parents on home learning.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2827</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T14:25:27Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T14:25:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This week I participated in the Public Health debate concerning the implementation of new Covid restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the third wave of Covid intensifies and we are back under lockdown, it is critical the UK Government agree to a &amp;#8216;Zero Tolerance&amp;#8217; approach to community transmission, as sought last summer by the three Devolved Governments.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also crucial that the UK Government restrict international travel both too and from the UK.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only by following such a strict approach will our domestic economy and society eventually be able to open up fully and safely as we have seen in countries like New Zealand, Singapore and South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The impact of new restrictions will be tough on families and businesses who will need financial support to get through it and so it was hugely disappointing to hear that the £375 million of support for businesses in Scotland promised by the Chancellor has since been rescinded.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the public health debate here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Qx8FeTZmkk"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7Qx8FeTZmkk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="06/02 Public Health Debate" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Qx8FeTZmkk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford MP&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A year ago, when the SARS-Cov-2 virus emerged, there was no handbook on covid. All Governments had to feel their way, but there is little excuse for repeating the same mistakes a year on. “Go early and go hard” has been public health experts’ consistent advice. Michael Ryan of the World Health Organisation said at the start of the pandemic:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The virus will always get you if you don’t move quickly”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet just last week, the Health Secretary still refused to put England into tier 4, despite surging case numbers and the devolved nations already being under tight restrictions since Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the late lockdown in March and rushed reopening in May, the Government allowed rates of infection in England to run seven times higher than in Scotland or Northern Ireland over the summer, and at the time, chose not to agree a zero-tolerance covid policy to eliminate community spread of the virus on a UK-wide basis. The gains of lockdown were gradually lost, as eat out to help out drove up cases in August and September, thus beginning the second wave.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UK is one of the few countries that never closed its borders and many new strains of covid were imported by people travelling to Europe on summer holidays.&amp;nbsp;Even now, in the middle of the second wave, the UK does not have strict testing and residential or monitored quarantine for arrivals. On the contrary, the Government have sought to grant further exemptions from quarantine rules.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In September, the Prime Minister ignored the tenfold rise in covid cases and his own advisory group to listen yet again to the proponents of disease-driven rather than vaccine-based herd immunity, leading to a six-week delay in instigating the autumn lockdown. Herd immunity can be safely achieved only through the use of a vaccine, and even then, only if the vaccine prevents transmission of the virus and thus also protects the unvaccinated. That is the hope, but we do not yet know if either of the vaccines used in the UK will achieve that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is understandable that Governments are wary about the use of tight covid restrictions and their impact on our economy and society, but it is a false dichotomy to set public health against the economy and lives against livelihoods. People simply choose not to endanger themselves or their families and need to have confidence that the risk of catching the virus is very low. Allowing increased levels of spread—and, therefore, high rates of viral replication—also contributes to more frequent mutations, and increases the risk of generating yet more problematic new variants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;With cases growing exponentially, it simply is not possible to vaccinate our way out of the current surge so I welcome the decision for this lockdown, but it is tough on everyone, and both individuals and businesses will need support to get through it. That is why it is bitterly disappointing to hear that the £375 million of support for businesses in Scotland promised by the Chancellor just yesterday has now been rescinded, leaving Scotland with no new funding to deal with the economic impact of the current shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Government must also consider what strategy they will follow at the end of the lockdown. It should be maintained long enough to achieve suppression of community transmission and to establish a more systematic approach to test, trace and isolate. It is critical to provide both financial and practical support to those who need to isolate, as it is only isolation that actually breaks the chains of infection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strict controls at external borders would avoid importing more covid cases and new variants. Such a covid-secure approach would allow the domestic UK economy to reopen fully, with the Government then able to target financial support at the industries associated with international travel, such as aviation and aerospace, which have been so badly impacted by the pandemic. Countries such as New Zealand, Singapore and Korea, which have tight travel restrictions and quarantines, have eliminated community transmission and been able fully to open up their economies and societies, including schools, hospitality and domestic tourism. We only have to look at their Christmas and new year celebrations to see what could be on offer to us here if we get things right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F08%2Fpublic-health%2F&amp;#038;title=Public%20Health%20Debate%20%E2%80%93%20Covid%20Restrictions%2006%2F01%2F21" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/" data-a2a-title="Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/"&gt;Public Health Debate &amp;#8211; Covid Restrictions 06/01/21&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week I participated in the Public Health debate concerning the implementation of new Covid ... <a title="Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/08/public-health/">Public Health Debate – Covid Restrictions 06/01/21</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2023</id>
    <published>2021-01-08T14:06:10Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-08T14:06:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Health, Wellbeing, &amp; Social Justice"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="Financial-Support"/>
    <category term="Health &amp; Social Care"/>
    <category term="Public Health"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>BTEC, vocational and technical exams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/01/07/btec-vocational-and-technical-exams/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6410</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T09:52:52Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T09:52:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on New National Lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/statement-on-new-national-lockdown/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Parliament was recalled today for a vote on the Government’s new lockdown measures and a statement on education. I put myself forward to speak in the proceedings but unfortunately did not get selected, therefore I wanted to update constituents on what is happening. The situation is clearly incredibly serious. Covid-19 is spreading rapidly across the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/statement-on-new-national-lockdown/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Statement on New National Lockdown</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7039</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T15:47:54Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T15:47:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lockdown 3</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/lockdown-3/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This is not the Happy New Year we were hoping for. Before Christmas the daily data produced by the Government, showing the numbers of new cases of coronavirus in Kent, was starting to look more positive. In Folkestone and Hythe there had been a sustained fall in the rolling seven-day average of new cases, from […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5489</id>
    <published>2021-01-06T05:26:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-06T05:26:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Local MP, Karin Smyth, is encouraging all constituents to follow the rules laid down by the Government this week in order to protect those vulnerable to this virus and to support the work of NHS staff. This comes after the UK Government finally acted upon the SAGE documents published before Christmas.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Government has now implemented a national lockdown in England, and everyone must now stay at home to try to slow the spread of the virus; that means, working from home where possible and only go out for essential reasons: to shop for basic necessities, to exercise, to seek or provide medical assistance, and to attend education for those eligible. Most children and university students will now learn remotely until February half term.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">For greater detail on the rules and exceptions, check the UK Government website at: <a href="http://gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNFLiV7obsfUO_K8WoTzkvmzXLrfJQ">gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home</a>.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Karin Smyth MP said:</strong></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“2020 was an incredibly difficult year for many and this was not the start we wanted to the New Year, but the third lockdown announced this week is vital to prevent the NHS from being overwhelmed and to protect those most at risk from this virus. It’s important that we all act quickly on Government advice as we need to make up for time lost through dither and delay.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">“The vaccine is being rolled out, but until sufficient numbers have been vaccinated, we need to continue to pull together and protect our family and friends, and all those we come into contact with. I know it’s difficult, that we all miss seeing those we love, and that we are weary of the frequently changing rules, but there is light at the end of the tunnel, and we must not stop now.”</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Support for constituents can be found on the Bristol Council website at <a href="https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGnuP4YCjbRT0MAvCOYX50KuJjtJw">https://www.bristol.gov.uk/coronavirus/what-you-need-to-know</a> and from the local Citizens Advice Bureau at <a href="http://bristolcab.org.uk/" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://bristolcab.org.uk&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1609947550551000&amp;usg=AFQjCNGKa93gq4aVSLQZwsamnHRlO8xtHQ">bristolcab.org.uk</a> or on the phone at 0808 278 7957.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">In accordance with the lockdown rules and public health guidance, Karin’s office is working remotely but are still available for constituents to contact via email at <a href="mailto:Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk">Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk</a> or on the phone at 0117 953 3575.</p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/" target="_blank">“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/05/it-is-vitally-important-that-we-follow-lockdown-rules-to-stop-the-spread-of-this-virus-karin-smyth-mp/" target="_blank">“It is vitally important that we follow lockdown rules to stop the spread of this virus” – Karin Smyth MP</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2833</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T15:43:59Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T15:43:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UPDATE: SCOTLAND IN LOCKDOWN</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On 4th January 2021 the Scottish Government announced a new national lockdown in mainland Scotland to prevent the spread of the new, highly contagious strain of coronavirus (Covid-19). The new measures make it a legal requirement to stay at home … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/update-scotland-in-lockdown/">UPDATE: SCOTLAND IN LOCKDOWN</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1490424</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:24:28Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:24:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign Emails"/>
    <category term="Latest Issues"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>National Lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/national-lockdown" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Please see below the Prime Minister's address to the nation from yesterday evening.  The full guidance is below and HERE.
The key differences to the March lockdown is that support and childcare bubbles remain in place, and early years childcare remains open.  Please do all you can to limit your…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/national-lockdown</id>
    <published>2021-01-05T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-05T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New National Lockdown Restrictions – Stay At Home</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/new-national-lockdown-restrictions-stay-at-home/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Prime Minister has announced this evening new national lockdown restrictions which will come into force tonight. As back in March this year, everyone must stay at home.  I know even tougher restrictions than under Tier 4 are disappointing. All schools which haven’t already will move to online learning from tomorrow, except for vulnerable [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/new-national-lockdown-restrictions-stay-at-home/">New National Lockdown Restrictions – Stay At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3029</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T20:57:11Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T20:57:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Axing the Tampon Tax – I am glad to set the record straight</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/01/axing-the-tampon-tax/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My letter to constituents on my role in axing the Tampon Tax follows below. Thank you for writing to me about the abolition of the “Tampon Tax”.  Having fought for it, I am very pleased a zero rate of VAT now applies to women’s sanitary products.  This is part of wider action by this Conservative Government to end period poverty, which includes free sanitary products in schools, colleges and hospitals.  You can find the Government’s announcement here: https://www.gov.uk/government/news/tampon-tax-abolished-from-today In particular, “The Chancellor […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18340</id>
    <published>2021-01-04T09:57:11Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-04T09:57:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Tampon Tax"/>
    <category term="Tax"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 vaccines update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/covid-19-vaccines-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Good news but please be patient.</p>



<p>Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. </p>



<p>Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect to get 4,000 Pfizer and 2,800 Oxford by next week, but understand that the main roll-out of the vaccine to our 45,000 over 80s and health / care workers will be from 11th January. Then it will be all systems go ……. </p>



<p>Please make sure you are registered with  GP, and you will get your invitation. But also please remember the vaccine takes time to be effective and gives no guarantee you will not pass the disease on to others. </p>



<p>In the meantime, please stay at home unless you have to go out. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Good news but please be patient. Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7941</id>
    <published>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job Vacancy: Chi Seeks to Appoint New Caseworker for Newcastle Central</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/job-chi-seeks-to-appoint-new-caseworker-for-newcastle-central/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below:</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Job Title</strong>: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31 March 2021</p>
<p><strong>Working For</strong>: Chi Onwurah MP</p>
<p><strong>Location</strong>: Internet</p>
<p><strong>Salary</strong>: £21,529- 24,000</p>
<p><strong>Job Details: </strong></p>
<p>Chi Onwurah MP (Newcastle Central) has a vacancy for a caseworker/admin officer. The most important factor is a willingness to learn and work together with the senior caseworker. Training will be provided.</p>
<p>(This post is currently until March 31st 2021, potential for extension dependant on IPSA funding)</p>
<p>The successful candidate will be well-organised with excellent IT and communication skills and attention to detail. Ideally s/he will have some knowledge of welfare benefits and public services including Universal Credit and experience of managing casework, confidential and sensitive information; and of drafting complex letters.</p>
<p>Experience of a similar role and CaseworkerMP would be beneficial. A good understanding of the political environment is advantageous, and a knowledge of local issues in the constituency is desirable. The successful candidate will demonstrate their enthusiasm to play a key role in a small team supporting Chi in her constituency work.</p>
<p><strong>Key Tasks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Provide advice and support to constituents on a range of financial, health, housing and other issues variety of issues through liaison with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve matters.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Responsibilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deal with queries by phone/in person, taking appropriate action to resolve, by gathering information or evidence; then document or escalate their concerns or enquiries in order to progress or close the case.</li>
<li>Manage own caseload and progress of casework, prioritising, logging and updating any actions taken and following up any outstanding queries; with urgent cases reported to the Member.</li>
<li>Draft responses or respond to constituents on any issues raised on behalf of the Member.</li>
<li>Maintain an up-to-date knowledge of relevant guidelines/legislation as appropriate in dealing with casework.</li>
<li>Analyse patterns of enquiries and produce reports.</li>
<li>Ensure records are kept adhering to the Data Protection Act principles Undertake general administrative tasks.</li>
<li>Assist with the work of other colleagues as required and communicate appropriately with internal and external contacts.</li>
<li>Competent use of IT including casework management systems, Microsoft Of ce package, email and internet to support the above.</li>
<li>Attending surgeries and meetings as appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Chi values inclusivity and diversity, and welcomes applications from candidates of all backgrounds.</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Interview/Start Dates: </strong></p>
<p>Closing time for applications 5pm.</p>
<p>Interviews scheduled via zoom Monday 18th January 2021</p>
<p>Start date Monday 25th January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Application Details: </strong></p>
<p>Please send an email with the subject line “Caseworker application – YOURNAME” to <strong>Anthony.bone@parliament.uk</strong> Please attach a CV, a covering letter and a report (max 2 sides A4) which presents a complex situation you have dealt with.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong>: 0191 233 5838</p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="http://chionwurahmp.com/">http://chionwurahmp.com</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below: Closing Date: 15 January 2021 Job Title: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10769</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK-EU Trade deal press release</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">‘I am currently reading through the 1246 pages of the new UK-EU Trade Deal, announced by the Prime Minister on Christmas Eve. I believe this deal makes good on the promises that were made, by the Prime Minister, myself and... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/#more-3749">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3749</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EU (Future Relationship) Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was sorry, along with scores of other MPs, not to be called to speak on this vital but all too short debate. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5019 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Brexit to coronavirus and everything in between - Ashfield MP reflects on eventful first year in office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From sending Boris Johnson into isolation, to being trolled on social media, dealing with coronavirus and Brexit, it’s been a busy year for former miner Lee Anderson who has clocked up one year representing his home turf as Ashfield MP.
The married dad of two, raised in Huthwaite, is the area’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s December Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3047</id>
		<updated>2020-12-30T11:33:26Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-30T11:32:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters here</p>
<p></p>
<p>Dear Constituent,</p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" /></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. Under these challenging circumstances, I nevertheless wish you a very safe and happy new year in 2021.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Heanor Future High Streets Fund bid success &#8211; £8.5 million:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following Heanor&#8217;s bid towards the Government&#8217;s £830 million Future High Streets Fund, I&#8217;m delighted that Heanor has been successful and has been awarded over £8.5 million to help transform its town centre and recover from the pandemic. You can find the full details of the Borough Council&#8217;s bid <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/">here</a>, which focuses on plans to regenerate the Market Place and Grammar School site. The Council now have a few months to confirm the final version of their plans, and I look forward to continuing to support and work with them to ensure we can maximise this funding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit deal latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister reached a deal with the EU regarding our future relationship after the end of the transition period, from the 1st January 2021. Parliament has been recalled today, on the 30th December, to consider the deal and vote on it. You can read the deal <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union">here</a> and the legislation enabling it <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf" data-cke-saved-href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf">here</a>. The select committee on the Future Relationship with the EU on which I serve has published a report on the deal this morning, which you can read <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/">here</a>.</p>
<p>I can confirm I will be supporting the deal when it comes to a vote later.</p>
<p>Many constituents have contacted me throughout the negotiation period, and I think this deal delivers on the key areas whilst also providing certainty and security for businesses and residents already impacted by Covid-19.</p>
<p>This deal delivers on Brexit, the referendum and last year&#8217;s election result by taking back control of our laws, borders, money, trade and fisheries.</p>
<p>&#8211; there is no role for the European Court of Justice and no requirement for the UK to follow EU law, so <strong>regaining parliamentary sovereignty</strong>;</p>
<p>&#8211; we will <strong>trade with the EU on the basis of zero tariffs and zero quotas</strong>, which will allow businesses to be able to trade smoothly and continue to access EU markets;</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Allows us to introduce our own modern subsidy system. </strong>This new subsidies system will operate in a that best suits the interests of UK industries &#8211; outside the EU State Aid regime.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> offers streamlined <strong>co-operation on law enforcement</strong>, ensuring we continue to effectively tackle serious organised crime and counter terrorism, protecting the public, and bringing criminals to justice. It also provides for future cooperation between the UK and EU on emerging security challenges, such as cyber and health security, including continuing to work together on tackling the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p><strong>- Recognises UK sovereignty over our fishing waters and puts us in a position to rebuild our fishing fleet and increase quotas, overturning the inequity that British fishermen have faced for over four decades. </strong>By the end of the five year transition we will have full control of our waters and the amount of fish available to UK fishermen will have risen from half to two-thirds.</p>
<p><strong><strong>- Provides for the UK’s participation in certain EU programmes, furthering our commitment to making the UK a science and research superpower. </strong></strong>This deal will fulfil our manifesto commitment to participate in the Horizon Europe programme, but also the Euratom Research and Training programme, and the space programme, Copernicus.</p>
<p>The deal also includes arrangements for airlines and hauliers that provides them with certainty, and gives people the ability to travel to and from the EU easily for work and holidays; a social security agreement that has practical benefits for UK citizens including accessing healthcare when travelling in the EU; and agreements on energy which will benefit consumers by helping to keep prices down.</p>
<p>As I set out in previous newsletters, compromises were necessary to achieve a deal, especially on fishing and the level playing field. Having been through the deal I am satisfied that these compromises are acceptable in the context of the importance of tariff free access to the EU market. This is a good deal achieved at great speed and gives us the best possible platform to make a success of Brexit.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus guidance latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following the last review of the tier restrictions on 16 December, Amber Valley and all of Derbyshire remained in the tier 3 restrictions. The next review takes place today. Amber Valley currently has a high case rate, of 332 cases per 100k, which is one of the highest in Derbyshire, and up 44% on the previous week. This is a very concerning situation and may lead to further restrictions being out in place locally.</p>
<p>On the positive side, mass testing has started in Swadlincote in the south of the County and will spread further in the county, including to Amber Valley early in the new year. This programme, along with similar roll outs in health, care and school settings will help identify cases earlier and slow the spread.</p>
<p>Vaccines are also now starting to be rolled out across the County, and I&#8217;m pleased that Ripley is one of the first primary care centres to begin rolling out the vaccine, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/">here</a>. Now that the Oxford vaccine has been approved for us, the roll out of vaccination should increase rapidly at dedicated centres as well as local GPs and pharmacies. Please do wait to be contacted about the vaccine though rather than asking your GP.</p>
<p>We are now at a critical point in this pandemic with cases rising rapidly and the problems of 2 new variants. But the end is in sight now we can rapidly vaccinate the most vulnerable. At this time we all need to show as much caution as possible to reduce the number of cases and minimise the new restrictions needed. We’ve got this far, let’s not ease off now.</p>
<p>I will continue to engage with ministers, the public health team and the local NHS to ensure that this area sees the full roll out of the vaccines and mass testing as soon as possible and that support is in place for those who can’t work and those businesses forced to close as a result of the tier measures.</p>
<p>You can read my contributions in Parliament here including on highlighting the need to roll out the vaccine to people who are unable to leave their homes as soon as logistics allow <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4">here</a> and about consideration of more localised geography for tier restrictions <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As always, you can find the latest Covid-19 guidance, and support available, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus &#8211; support for local businesses &amp; high streets:</span></strong></p>
<p>In Parliament, I&#8217;ve continued to highlight the difficulties faces by our local businesses, such as the events industry and conference centres (you can read my question to the Secretary of State for Business on this <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4">here</a>), and supporting local high streets (which you can read more on <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4">here</a>).</p>
<p>I welcome the Chancellor&#8217;s announcement of the extension of the furlough scheme until the end of April 2021, and the extension of the business loan schemes until the end of March. You can find more information on the support and grants available for you or your business <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></span></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills" data-cke-saved-href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like me on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" /></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Johnson’s deal ‘social and economic disaster’ for Argyll &amp; Bute</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/12/29/johnsons-deal-social-and-economic-disaster-for-argyll-bute/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I can’t vote for a ‘deal’ that undermines our farmers, fishermen and future opportunities for young people Tomorrow (Wednesday) I will vote against Boris Johnson’s post-Brexit EU trade deal. I will do so because the deal we are being asked to support is woefully deficient, as it undermines our farmers, our fishing communities and the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9118</id>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas cheer for the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/christmas-cheer-for-the-friends-of-neath-abbey-iron-company/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Hard-working volunteers with the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have pulled another iron from the fund-raising fire – a £9,300 grant from the National Lottery Heritage Fund to take the project to a new level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Part of the cash will be used to create a digital guide to the history of Neath Abbey – including not only the world-famous ironworks but the impressive remains of the Cistercian monastery close by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;And with open days, guided tours and personal presentations all off-limits while the corona virus pandemic continues, digital outreach has become an essential tool in raising awareness of the project by allowing people to visualise the ironworks at its world-beating peak – when it powered the industrial revolution of the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;Data will be posted on Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and People’s Collection Wales, creating a virtual guided tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;In addition, new interpretive panels at the ironworks will explain the history and function of the various structures and buildings on site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;The remainder of the money will be used to renovate an old BT telephone kiosk – which cost £1 – and convert it into a heritage centre at the nearby Longford housing estate where local people can, via a display book and works of art, discover the area’s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;The artworks will be created by children of the local Dwr y Felin Comprehensive School. Other community groups such as Bryncoch Environment Group, Dyffryn Clydach Community Council, Dyffryn Clydach and Bryncoch Historic Group will also display community news, events and information in the kiosk.&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2344"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2344" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/8DCDF1DF-42F0-4CD0-97E0-3676E4E7186B-560x297.png" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hard-working volunteers with the Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have pulled another iron from the fund-raising fire – a £9,300 grant from the National Lottery Heritage Fund to take the project to a new level. Part of the cash will be used to create a digital guide to the history of Neath Abbey – […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2343</id>
    <published>2020-12-23T08:53:03Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T08:53:03Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>David Evennett and Bexley Conservatives supporting local pubs, sports and social clubs this winter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bexley Council with funding support from the government has announced further Covid-19 support packages for local businesses across Bexleyheath and Crayford. 
These new grant schemes include a special winter support package of just under £1 million being made available for local independent pubs,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chippenham High Street Closure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19.</p>



<p>High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market Place. Alternative route: via Market Place – The Causeway – A4 – Bath Road and vice versa.</p>



<p>The closure and diversion route will be clearly indicated by traffic signs and access will be maintained for residents and businesses where possible throughout the works period.</p>



<p>These works will commence on 21 December 2020 and are anticipated to be required for one day. This Notice will have a maximum duration of 21 days. </p>



<p>For further information regarding these works please contact Tracy Howell on behalf of Chippenham Town Council on 01249446699. Sustainable Transport Group, County Hall, Bythesea Road, Trowbridge BA14 8JN Ref: SH/DEC2020</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="722" src="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33865" srcset="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg 1024w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-300x212.jpg 300w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-768x542.jpg 768w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-710x501.jpg 710w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1030x726.jpg 1030w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg 1316w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19. High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33864</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Chippenham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=loneliness-and-our-communities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="5663" class="elementor elementor-5663" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-27b274df elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="27b274df" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-71d5ac96" data-id="71d5ac96" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3b39d78c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3b39d78c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"><p><!-- wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p>
<p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances none of us would have imagined. As we look to the light provided by new vaccines and as we approach a new year, there is yet another nasty legacy sting in the tail of 2020 – a rise in feelings of loneliness.</p>
<p>Research from Age UK has shown that this Christmas is set to be the loneliest yet for older people. Over 160,000 people over the age of 65 will suffer from feeling lonely this festive season, with nearly 60% of them fearing that they won’t see any family and friends. Those are heartbreaking numbers, even one person feeling like this is one too many.</p>
<p>Our communities can carry another more positive legacy from 2020. The Age UK research also highlighted that over 100,000 older people were helped to get through the pandemic by the kindness of strangers. The simple act of checking on people made a life-enhancing difference for so many, we can never know for sure, but it’s probably safe to assume that in some instances, it was life-saving.</p>
<p>Of course, loneliness and isolation don’t discriminate; young people are also affected. The Office of National statistics were able to point out that, during the first month of the pandemic, 7. 4 million people, across the nations of the UK said that their wellbeing was affected through feeling isolated.</p>
<p>We all knew that these restrictions were essential to protect lives, but the collateral effect was, as predicted, substantial. Recently, we have become more aware of a problem that has existed for some time but rarely brought into public debate. Work undertaken for the charities MIND and Mental Health UK confirmed that young people are particularly affected by loneliness.</p>
<p>During the pandemic almost half of 18-24-year-olds experienced, and those aged 25-34 are twice – yes twice – as likely to be lonely at Christmas than older people. That’s a lot of lonely people out there feeling isolated.</p>
<p>While we cannot visit indoors, there are many other ways we can help people feel less isolated. Given that a third of people are too embarrassed to admit that they are lonely, it is small acts that make a difference; it might be a note through the door or a phone call to someone you haven’t spoken to in a while. Simple offers of contact, help with shopping, a chat a few steps back from the doorstep could mean a big deal to reassure folk that they are valued and to feel a little less alone.</p>
<p>If you need to talk to someone over the festive period, or any other time, the below contacts offer free and non-judgemental help;</p>
<p>MikeysLine 01463 729000</p>
<p>Breathing Space 0800 83 85 87</p>
<p>Samaritans 116 123</p>
<p>Mind 0300 123 3393</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
<p><!-- /wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5663</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Over 100 Parliamentarians urge the UK Government to take action to protect the Rohingya against genocide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p style="background: white;">
          <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: black;">104 Parliamentarians from across parties are calling on the UK Government to take urgent action to protect the Rohingya Muslim minority from persecution from the Myanmar Government and military. </span>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meeting Father Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I met Father Christmas in Marks and Spencers' Car Park on Sunday 13 December. He had been invited there by the Beckenham Roatary Club of which I an also a member. It was the first time I have seen him this year and he said would be delivering presents to children as normal what ever happened over…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas</id>
    <published>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/23/lambed/07/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - Brexit </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we approach the end of this terrible year I suspect I will not cheer anyone up by reminding them that the end of the Brexit transition period is very close. It is a matter of huge interest to the whole country but is of course of particular concern to us in Kent because of the possibility of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0</id>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WGC Becomes Location for First Ever Green Number Plate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Transport Secretary Grant Shapps recently visited Halfords autocentres in Welwyn Garden City to have the first ever ‘green number plate’ fitted. This comes as the country prepares for the mass adoption of electric vehicles ahead of the UK ending its contribution to climate change by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number plate consists of a green coloured flash on the left-hand side of the plate to designate the vehicle as having zero emissions at tailpipe. The plates are now available to the general public and will be included with all new zero-emissions-vehicles unless customers choose to opt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said the move “Underlined the Government’s commitment to tackling poor air quality in the UK’s towns and cities. It builds on last month’s announcement to end the sale of new petrol and diesel cars and vans in the UK by 2030, putting the UK on course to be the fastest G7 country to decarbonise these vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the new plates on UK roads will raise awareness of the growing number of zero emission vehicles, as well as helping motorists benefit from possible local initiatives such as special parking spaces and cost-free entry into zero-emission zones such as the one in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said: “A green recovery is key to helping us achieve our net zero carbon commitments while also promoting economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Green number plates could unlock a number of incentives for drivers and increase awareness of cleaner vehicles on our roads, showing people that a greener transport future is within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re supporting small businesses to develop the transport tech of the future through a multi-million-pound investment, ensuring that&amp;nbsp;UK&amp;nbsp;businesses remain at the forefront of low carbon innovation and research.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video was produced during the visit, which can be viewed below:&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0  et_pb_text_align_center"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F719013365401804%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=476" width="476" height="476" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30910</id>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Green Number Plates"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Garden City"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
