<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-01-15T21:11:28Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Update following discussions regarding vaccinations in Chesterfield and Derbyshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/Sb80brfxry8/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4765</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T19:21:34Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T19:21:34Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/01/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy-Anne Hickey</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18349</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T18:27:18Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T18:27:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shaping communities – my article for the Stockport Express</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/shaping-communities-my-article-for-the-stockport-express/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=shaping-communities-my-article-for-the-stockport-express" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233229" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Shaping-communities.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;With the country heading into a third national lockdown as COVID infections soar, we are again all rightly focused on how we can work together to bring infections down and prevent our NHS from being overwhelmed. At times like this, it can be hard to look beyond the immediate crisis, but I think it is vital that we carry on thinking seriously about what we want our country and our communities to look like in a post-crisis world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Here in Stockport, we recently saw the council vote against the Greater Manchester Spatial Framework (GMSF). This was a plan for homes, jobs and the environment across the whole of Greater Manchester, which attempted to balance development across the ten boroughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Now that the GMSF is dead for the borough, the Council needs to produce a local plan. This will pose some significant challenges. For example, the GMSF involved cooperation between boroughs, meaning that Manchester and Salford could take on extra housing targets, easing the pressure on Stockport. With this cooperation now rejected, Stockport will need to find space to accommodate more housing than had been expected. We all know how difficult that might be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;However, this can also be an opportunity for a coherent master plan to be developed for and by the borough that champions affordable and social housing. I’m very proud that, under the current Labour administration, Stockport already has a very good record on this through the Viaduct Housing Partnership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;I’d also like to see good design championed, proper urban regeneration (as we’re seeing under the Mayoral Development Corporation) and a renewal of the District Centres, like Reddish and the Heatons. It is essential that regeneration in Stockport reaches out beyond the town centre and its surroundings and into every corner of the borough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Another key element will, of course, be protecting and improving our river valleys for nature and recreation, and tackling air quality (a process begun by the Greater Manchester Council more than 45 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Whilst it is vital that we focus, as a community, on dealing with the COVID crisis – following regulations to reduce transmission, looking out for the most vulnerable in our communities and getting vaccinated when we get the chance – we also need to make sure that we do not lose sight of what comes next. With the GMSF off the table, I’d encourage everyone to think how they would like to see our communities reshaped over the coming months and years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/shaping-communities-my-article-for-the-stockport-express/"&gt;Shaping communities &amp;#8211; my article for the Stockport Express&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>With the country heading into a third national lockdown as COVID infections soar, we are again all rightly focused on how we can work together to bring infections down and prevent our NHS from being overwhelmed. At times like this, it can be hard to look beyond the immediate crisis, but I think it is […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/shaping-communities-my-article-for-the-stockport-express/">Shaping communities – my article for the Stockport Express</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233228</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T18:12:02Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T18:12:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE’S MP SLAMS TORIES OVER PLANS TO RIP-UP WORKERS’ RIGHTS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshires-mp-slams-tories-over-plans-to-rip-up-workers-rights/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Martin Docherty-Hughes, MP for West Dunbartonshire, has hit out at the Westminster government over reports the Tories are preparing to rip-up key worker protections enshrined in EU law. According to reports in the Financial Times, the UK Government business department … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshires-mp-slams-tories-over-plans-to-rip-up-workers-rights/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshires-mp-slams-tories-over-plans-to-rip-up-workers-rights/">WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE’S MP SLAMS TORIES OVER PLANS TO RIP-UP WORKERS’ RIGHTS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1495355</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T17:25:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T17:25:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP welcomes pandemic insurance ruling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/mp-welcomes-pandemic-insurance-ruling" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;West Worcestershire MP Harriett Baldwin has welcomed a Supreme Court ruling which will mean insurance companies will have to pay out to dozens of local companies who paid for pandemic insurance. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/mp-welcomes-pandemic-insurance-ruling" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5026 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T16:26:05Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T16:26:05Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">		&lt;div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="5677" class="elementor elementor-5677" data-elementor-settings="[]"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-inner"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-section-wrap"&gt;
							&lt;section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-330dca1e elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="330dca1e" data-element_type="section"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-row"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-4660dffb" data-id="4660dffb" data-element_type="column"&gt;
			&lt;div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-widget-wrap"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4fe4aa24 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="4fe4aa24" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"&gt;
				&lt;div class="elementor-widget-container"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish you all a good and perhaps most importantly, a healthy New Year. This year begins with a shared goal; for us, all to get through it safely together. As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know our villages, towns and the city centre will be different and that now is the time to reflect on how we want to live and treat people locally in the future. The world has changed, and although the fabric that holds our communities together is stronger than ever, we have learned that what was paramount yesterday could now be a barrier to progress. While there are new and exciting endeavours that need our support, existing challenges outside the pandemic bubble remain pressing – globally, nationally and locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still a climate emergency, and we still need to provide a place fit for people of all ages, for the 21st Century. Finding a way to bring all of this together into a cohesive plan involving the most impacted people has to be a collective, local priority. I am already reaching out to businesses, community groups, charities and a wide range of organisations to work towards this common goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new, more contagious strain of the virus has pushed back many people&amp;#8217;s hopes and expectations for the early months of 2021. Of course, this is hard to take, especially for those whose jobs or livelihoods are affected directly by the lockdown. My team and I continue to support hundreds of families and businesses going through extreme hardship; for them right now, it&amp;#8217;s hard to see any light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this new strain is a setback, it is not the virus winning; we can get through this—rapid deployment of the vaccine underway. As hard as it is, we need to keep the faith, hunker down, stay home, go out for only essential purposes or exercise and keep out of other homes unless included in a specifically identified exemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that because of our efforts to follow the rules, rates of infection here have been lower, but we also now face rising numbers of infections fuelled by mixing over the festive period. A reminder of just how vulnerable we all are and how quickly our fortunes can change. Please keep staying at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up to date with new articles at &lt;a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;www.drewhendrymp.scot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about my work in parliament at &lt;a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com"&gt;www.theyworkforyou.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/"&gt;As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;Drew Hendry MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This year begins with a shared goal; for us, all to get through it safely together. As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/">As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5677</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T16:12:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T16:12:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Community"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Tourism"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 15 January 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron15jan" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>One of the most worrying aspects of the Coronavirus pandemic is the impact on cancer care, with an estimated 100,000 people in the UK affected by the backlog in cancer services. Whilst essential cancer treatments have continued throughout the pandemic, it is clear that the pressures of Covid on our NHS have had a significant knock-on effect. I know from my own experience the devastation cancer causes to families, which is why the Government need a laser-like focus on ensuring that our cancer care services are supported to clear this backlog.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron15jan</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T16:07:27Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T16:07:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-39/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I began the week in Westminster, chairing a Delegated Legislation committee. The committee discussed the temporary measures designed to help UK companies and other entities during difficult times caused by Coronavirus. The reason these temporary measures are being extended is to continue to protect companies from aggressive creditor enforcement whilst the adverse effects from the coronavirus pandemic continue and the related social distancing restrictions remain in place, including regional tiered arrangements which affect normal trading. The provisions cover England, Scotland and Wales. There was cross party support and the provisions were extended <u>until 31st March 2021</u>.</p>
<p>The following day, I was fortunate to secure a Westminster Hall debate entitled “Squash and the Olympics”. I have been playing squash since the mid-seventies and have represented Wales over a hundred times. I was a former Squash Wales National Coach. The world squash family has been campaigning for squash to be included in the Olympic Games programme since 1986, but unfortunately other sports have been included ahead of squash. Squash is dynamic, physically and mentally challenging, strategic, tactical – like chess on legs. A heathy sport for all ages. I am not in any way criticising other sports who have been included ahead of squash, because it is the aspiration of any sport to be able to grandstand its players on the Olympic stage. To play for your country is a tremendous honour, but to have the opportunity to take part in the Olympics is the ultimate honour. If squash had been included in the Tokyo Olympics now scheduled for July 2021, our International Stars, Joel Makin, from Aberdare, and Tesni Evans from Prestatyn, ranked number one and two in Great Britain, and both ranked number nine in the January 2021 World Rankings, would have been automatically included in the GB Olympic Team. And rated as probable gold and silver medalists. Such a shame. But we won’t give up campaigning.</p>
<p>At the end of the week, the Speaker of the House of Commons, Lindsay Hoyle, made an announcement ahead of a debate, emphasising that the Commission of the House has a duty of care to all members and to all staff that work on the Parliamentary Estate. Public Health England has continuously provided advice regarding working practices on the Estate, which sought to limit physical attendance, especially during lockdown. But members have been able to take part virtually in debates in the Chamber. However the Grand Committee Room where Westminster Hall debates take place does not have capacity for virtual participation and Friday Sittings for Private Members’ Bills require 100 members to be in attendance for votes on closure motions, because proxy voting does not cover PMBs and we do not have virtual voting. The Leader of the House proposed that changes to Parliamentary procedures be made immediately. Westminster Hall debates were suspended from 14th January until a virtual participation system can be set up and Friday Sittings have been suspended. Members were assured that Westminster Hall debates and Friday Sittings would resume as soon as alternative arrangements are in place.</p>
<p>Many constituents have been getting in touch this week to ask about the vaccination process in Neath, wondering where and when they can expect to receive the jab.  The main advice I can give is to continue to be patient and await contact from the NHS regarding the vaccine.  I do understand how difficult a time this is for everyone, however, and how anxious people are to know when they will be contacted.  The Welsh Government announced their vaccination strategy this week, laying out how they plan to vaccinate our communities.  All care home residents and staff should have been vaccinated by mid-February, as well as frontline health and social care staff, everyone over 70 and everyone who is clinically extremely vulnerable. This will be followed by everyone over 50 and all those at risk due to underlying health conditions by the spring, and all other eligible adults in Wales by the autumn.  I hope this will help to give some reassurance that there is a light at the end of the tunnel, and progress is being made on rolling out the vaccine.  Vaccine figures will now be published daily.</p>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch about any matters that fall under my role as an MP, please do not hesitate to drop us an email on christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call us on 01639 630152. My staff are working from home to comply with the social distancing measures, but, as always, we remain there should you need to get in contact with us.</p>
<p>I hope you stay well, and remember – observe social distancing, wash your hands regularly and keep Wales safe.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I began the week in Westminster, chairing a Delegated Legislation committee. The committee discussed the temporary measures designed to help UK companies and other entities during difficult times caused by Coronavirus. The reason these temporary measures are being extended is to continue to protect companies from aggressive creditor enforcement whilst the adverse effects from the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2355</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T15:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T15:05:00Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>Supreme Court decision gives welcome relief to local businesses – MP</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389915/supreme-court-decision-gives-welcome-relief-to-local-businesses-mp"/>
  <updated>2021-01-15T14:20:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1389915/supreme-court-decision-gives-welcome-relief-to-local-businesses-mp</id>
  <summary type="text">Commenting on today's news that a Supreme Court ruling is set to force insurers to pay out on disputed coronavirus claims, local MP Tim Farron said: "It's almost a year since my office was inundated with desperate local businesses who were being thrown to the wolves by insurance companies refusing to pay out.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Commenting on today's news that a Supreme Court ruling is set to force insurers to pay out on disputed coronavirus claims, local MP Tim Farron said: <em>"It's almost a year since my office was inundated with desperate local businesses who were being thrown to the wolves by insurance companies refusing to pay out.</em></p>
<p><em>"It was one of the biggest scandals of this entire crisis that the Government failed to do their duty and let wealthy insurance companies get off scot-free whilst local small businesses were hung out to dry.</em></p>
<p><em>"So I massively welcome this decision from the Supreme Court and hope that these businesses will now get the pay-outs that they deserve."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercury Article: No one wanted to start 2021 with a third lockdown&#8230;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/15/mercury-article-no-one-wanted-to-start-2021-with-a-third-lockdown/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4548</id>
		<updated>2021-01-15T14:19:43Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-15T14:19:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[O hell, here comes another one. No one wanted to start 2021 with a third lockdown but, as the new and&#160;more-infectious strain of Covid spread, it proved too strong for the local tier system. And with the NHS starting to fill up under the strain, even though covid treatments are getting better and the vaccine [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/15/mercury-article-no-one-wanted-to-start-2021-with-a-third-lockdown/"><![CDATA[
<p>O hell, here comes another one. No one wanted to start 2021 with a third lockdown but, as the new and&nbsp;more-infectious strain of Covid spread, it proved too strong for the local tier system. And with the NHS starting to fill up under the strain, even though covid treatments are getting better and the vaccine rollout is picking up speed, here we are again.</p>



<p>A lot of us (me included) had been hoping we could just &#8216;ride it out&#8217; by keeping elderly and vulnerable people safe while everybody else carried on fairly normally. But last autumn showed that, no matter how careful they’ve been, sooner or later&nbsp;grandparents catch it too, particularly with the new and more-infectious strain of the disease. For a retirement town like Weston with plenty of elderly folk, but where lots of local jobs depend on hard-hit hospitality and tourism too, it’s a no-win dilemma. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it’s a rubbish start to 2021. But even though&nbsp;a full-scale lockdown is only&nbsp;a temporary ‘reset’ rather than a long-term answer to the problem, this time is different because there’s hope. The vaccines mean there’s a decent chance of normality returning in a few months. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The challenge is getting through until then: keeping jobs and firms alive, and not letting up on ‘hands, face, space’ in the meantime. The most difficult stretch of all will be the few weeks after we’ve each been vaccinated, before our immune systems are fully booted up. The temptation to go back to normal before we’re really safe will be super-strong, but we’ll all have to resist it. It would be awful to catch covid right at the end of the pandemic, after we’d stayed safe for so long. Roll on the jabs, and then perhaps we can have a normal summer!</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Updated Guidelines for Lockdown Fishing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/updated-guidelines-lockdown-fishing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/107040310_2999724350096719_6517924700809217461_o.jpg?itok=dMBwPlav" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p>
                <em>Image left to right; Jon Cruddas MP, Angling Trust CEO Jamie Cook, Charles Walker MP</em>
              </p>
              <p> </p>
              <p>After a hectic and successful week navigating the consequences for angling of the government’s decision to impose a third National Lockdown in England in response to the rise in coronavirus infections, the Angling Trust has published new comprehensive guidelines and FAQs to help anglers fish safely, locally and responsibly without falling foul of the law.</p>
              <p>The news that fishing was to continue, when most other sports could not, was greeted enthusiastically by anglers with over 2,000 new members signing up as members of the Angling Trust in the last week (a new record) and staff working long hours responding to the mass of enquiries.</p>
              <p>As well as the updated FAQs, which now includes advice on interactions with the police, Angling Trust Policy Chief Martin Salter, who has been at the centre of our campaign to keep us fishing during lockdown, has published a new blog telling the full story on ‘how we got angling over the line’, together with some essential reading on how to stay the right side of the rules.</p>
              <p>
                <strong>The key messages are:</strong>
              </p>
              <ul>
                <ul>
                  <li>- This is a strictly limited resumption of LOCAL fishing and very different to how we have been allowed to operate since May.</li>
                  <li>- Read the government guidance here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home</a></li>
                  <li>- Angling is a ‘reasonable excuse’ recognised by Government as evidenced by Sport England.</li>
                  <li>- You should be able to show that your travel to go fishing is in accordance with the government’s instruction to stay local and you are following the Angling Trust’s travel guidelines.</li>
                  <li>- We are in a National Lockdown and this must be respected. The law requires a ‘reasonable excuse’ to leave your home or penalties will apply.</li>
                  <li>- Should a police officer decide to issue you with a direction order or fixed penalty notice you should accept it and pack up immediately and return home if so instructed.</li>
                  <li>- Organised sporting gatherings are prohibited so no match fishing.</li>
                  <li>- The exercise is limited to once a day so no overnight fishing whatsoever.</li>
                  <li>- To remain within the law you should follow the travel guidance and only fish locally.</li>
                  <li>- Avoid fishing in crowded places where social distancing could be difficult and might give rise to concerns over public health.</li>
                  <li>- We are once again able to enjoy the sport we love at a time when many others cannot and we must ensure that every angler adheres to the rules.</li>
                </ul>
              </ul>
              <p><strong>Jon Cruddas MP, a keen angler said:</strong> <em>“Throughout the pandemic we have seen the positive impact angling has had on people’s mental health. There were some areas that needed clarification such as how far people can reasonably travel for fishing, but the updated guidance is clear that anglers must stay local for it to be considered a ‘reasonable excuse’ to be travelling. We have some fantastic fishing lakes in Dagenham, and I hope that constituents will continue to enjoy them responsibly.”</em></p>
              <p><strong>Jamie Cook, Angling Trust CEO, added:</strong> <em>“I couldn’t be prouder of the leadership role played by the Angling Trust throughout the Covid crisis. We have acted responsibly, professionally and effectively, much to the envy of many other sports, as has been acknowledged by Sport England, the Environment Agency, government ministers and officials and the thousands of anglers who have sent us messages of support or joined us in record numbers. But I must stress that the spotlight is on us like never before and we must all conduct ourselves responsibly and fish safely. Please remember we are extremely fortunate to be able to fish at all and we must all act as ambassadors for our sport.”</em></p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/dagenham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Dagenham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/fishing" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Fishing</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/angling" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Angling</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/angling-trust" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Angling Trust</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-5">
              <a href="/tags/lockdown" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Lockdown</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-6">
              <a href="/tags/covid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Covid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-7">
              <a href="/tags/mental-health" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Mental Health</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1449 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T13:55:14Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T13:55:14Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Business Interruption Insurance must be paid.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/business-interruption-insurance-must-be-paid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Business Interruption Insurance must be paid.
Many of you have contacted me over the last few months regarding your Business Interruption Insurance.  I am sure you will be as pleased as I am with the result of the test case brought by the FCA.  The link to the BBC News article is below.  Please do…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/business-interruption-insurance-must-be-paid</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Maria Miller meets with experts to call for change in law on image-based sexual image abuse</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/mp-maria-miller-meets-experts-call-change-law-image-based-sexual-image-abuse" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Wednesday, MP Maria Miller held an expert led Parliamentary briefing, and renewed her call for a change in the law, as part of the Government’s Online Harms Bill, following a significant increase in online intimate sexual image abuse cases during the Covid-19 pandemic. The making and sharing of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/mp-maria-miller-meets-experts-call-change-law-image-based-sexual-image-abuse</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p><b><span data-contrast="none">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Gov</span></b><b><span data-contrast="auto">ernment over vaccinations rollout </span></b><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has this week demande</span><span data-contrast="auto">d more clarity and transparency from the Government over the rollout </span><span data-contrast="none">of the Covid-19 vaccination programme.  The call comes as it </span><span data-contrast="auto">was revealed that although </span><span data-contrast="none">Ashton Gate Stadium is ready to go as a regional vaccine hub, working in partnership with the Clini</span><span data-contrast="none">cal Commissioning Group,  the Government have not yet explicitly set out their expectations for the </span><span data-contrast="auto">hub, or let those involved know when they will begin to receive supplies of vaccines to use.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Bristol GPs have also expressed concern that recent Government</span><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><span data-contrast="none">announcements regarding the number of weekly vaccinations and the fluctuating period between people accessing the first and second dose of the vaccine are </span><span data-contrast="auto">creating m</span><span data-contrast="none">ore confusion</span><span data-contrast="auto"> both for those </span><span data-contrast="none">delivering the </span><span data-contrast="auto">vaccine and those receiving it.  </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><b><span data-contrast="none">Karin Smyth</span></b><b><span data-contrast="none">, MP f</span></b><b><span data-contrast="auto">or Bristol South,</span></b><b><span data-contrast="none"> said:</span></b><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">“We will always be indebted to the researchers, volunteers and NHS professionals who have worked at incredible pace to bring us a vaccine so rapidly – but we now find ourselves with a new set of challenges.  The Covid-19 vaccination programme will be the m</span><span data-contrast="auto">ost complex task ever undertaken by our NHS, and it is vital that this Tory Government – which has been found wanting at so many points during this pandemic – do not let down the incredible NHS staff who continue to go above and beyond to tackle this pande</span><span data-contrast="auto">mic.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">“The</span><span data-contrast="auto"> Government must provide more details on who will be given what vaccine, where and when, so that those administering the vaccine and those receiving it can have confidence in the safety and efficacy of the rollout.  I’ll continue to press for more clarity so that together we can roll out the vaccine and rebuild our country”.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout   Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has this week demanded […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2839</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T11:49:39Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T11:49:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Long Covid Debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/long-covid-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;"&gt;Read Debbie Abrahams&amp;#039; &lt;span style="color:#06396a;"&gt;speech on Long Covid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_empty_space"   style="height: 20px" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_empty_space_inner"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " &gt;
		&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I took part in a Long Covid debate secured by my colleague Layla Moran MP.  It&amp;#8217;s important that we recognise that we need a societal not just a healthcare response to Long Covid. Working age people with Long Covid must be provided with support by their employer and the Government through the Department for Work Pensions and not stigmatised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my speech in full below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is perhaps understandable that in the middle of this Covid pandemic the focus has been on primary prevention, managing the acute symptoms of those who become infected and preventing death.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But given that the Covid-tracker survey suggests more than 4 million people (~12% population) have symptoms beyond the 4-week acute phase with 1 in 10 experiencing symptoms beyond 12 weeks, we also need to develop healthcare management responses that recognise Covid can have effects way beyond the acute phase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On top of this we need to have appropriate societal response to Long Covid, one where people are supported during the chronic and fluctuating stage of this illness, and don’t feel stigmatised.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m pleased at the speed with which NICE – the National Institute of Health &amp;amp; Care Excellence – have brought forward their guidelines for managing Long Covid. I particularly liked the recommended holistic healthcare approach when assessing a patient with symptoms beyond 4 and 12 weeks, with the emphasis on empathy and acknowledging the impact the symptoms may be having on the patient’s day to day lives, including their ability to work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;However, I was surprised that there was no reference to immunology or immune therapies.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I hope that we have learnt from the mistakes made in how we prevent, treat and care for people suffering from Chronic Fatigue Syndrome also known as ME, as well as Post Viral Syndrome. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We know that Covid-19 like other viruses, attacks multiple systems – respiratory, cardiovascular, nervous, gastrointestinal – as it attaches to epithelial cells which are distributed throughout the body.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But our bodies ability to fight the virus depends on our immune systems reacting appropriately, and not over-reacting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The British Society for Immunology and several research units have suggested that it in addition to long term damage to multiple organs, the pain, muscle weakness, fatigue and even brain fog often associated with Long Covid may be due to inflammatory issues associated with our immune response rather than with Covid itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is still so much we don’t know about this virus, and we really need to be investigating this as a matter of urgency. The prevalence of Long Covid in the population strongly points to the need for a Long Covid disease register with effective treatment regimens.   &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More research is desperately needed to understand the long-term effects of Covid on all body systems including our immune response. As a strong advocate of evidence-based medicine, I recognise the need for longitudinal studies, but it’s also important that we never let the perfect be the enemy of the good: we cannot wait decades for therapies. And we must learn from previous mistakes in relation to CFS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have seen how quickly we can develop vaccines in response to Covid-19 when there is the will, and we should be demanding this investment in research now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally, I reiterate, we must make sure that this is a societal response and not just a healthcare response – working age people in particular must be supported by their employers, and the Government, through the DWP, if they are unable to work. Stigmatising those with Long Covid will not be tolerated.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;                                                                                                                                 Debbie Abrahams MP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AN ANONYMOUS CASE STUDY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I assume I had a mild Covid infection last April. I had a temperature and flu-like symptoms. My whole body was stiff and ached, making it difficult to walk. I also felt exhausted, with waves of nausea which woke me up when I was asleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those symptoms lasted a few days and then eased, apart from the joint and muscle pain, loss of muscle strength and tiredness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to work after 5 days but shortly after I remember being out on a walk by myself one Friday evening, and suddenly feeling very dizzy. I made it back home – just – but for the next few weeks I could barely move – I shuffled. The joint and muscle pain were constant affecting my sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I foolishly carried on working from home – I didn’t want to let people down – but had to knock the volunteering I’d been doing on the head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the summer the symptoms subsided, with the pain and stiffness becoming confined to my left side and now it’s just in my left leg and hip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed my pain as best I can and have tried to do exercises to regain my muscle strength. Some days are worse than others. It does affect your mental health…comparing what I could do a few months ago to what I can do now.”&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"&gt;&lt;h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;"&gt;Feel strongly about this article? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"&gt;&lt;a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact"&gt;Contact Debbie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/long-covid-debate/"&gt;Long Covid Debate&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk"&gt;Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/long-covid-debate/">Long Covid Debate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6738</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T09:50:03Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T09:50:03Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Jobs"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Speeches"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government borrowing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/01/15/government-borrowing/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>A contributor asked for an update on government debt.</p>



<p>The UK had a difficult borrowing problem in the IMF crash of the mid 1970s when the country ran out of foreign currency to borrow and had to make emergency cuts. The IMF   supervised a programme of lower public spending in return for loans. </p>



<p> It had a bit of a domestic borrowing problem in the 1980s as a Conservative government tackled the large inherited borrowings. Interest rates rose to high levels to persuade people to take state debt as investments.  As spending came under better control so rates came down, helping economic recovery. </p>



<p> It had a worse borrowing problem during and after the banking crash of 2008. State debt was high going into the crash alongside very high levels of private  sector borrowing. Both sectors reined in in the last months of the Labour government. The incoming Coalition, contrary to media reports, raised the levels of state borrowing over their tenure. </p>



<p>On each of these occasions debt interest was over 3% of GDP or  6-7% of total public spending. It was considerably higher immediately after the war when state debt was 250% of GDP reflecting the need to spend and borrow to win the war. Patient work  brought the debt under better control in the 1950s.</p>



<p>People ask me if we can afford the sharp build up in gross debt brought on by the policies chosen to deal with the pandemic. I am pleased to report that we can afford it, because interest rates have tumbled so much and because the Bank of England is buying in substantial quantities of the debt. The latest official predictions show net debt interest as a percentage of GDP falling to a tiny 0.8% of GDP next year as debts are rolled over at low rates and as the Bank completes its buying programme. This means debt interest will be at its lowest for the post 1945 period. There is no need to count the interest paid on the debt owned by the Bank of England, as taxpayers and government get that receipt. </p>



<p>The Uk government today can borrow money for 10 years at 0.29%. The stated debt is a large 105% of GDP, but the state itself will  own £875bn of that so the true figure for the actual net debt owed by the state is around two thirds of GDP.</p>



<p>These are unusual times when the US, UK, leading EU countries and Japan can all borrow at around zero very large sums of money. It is still not a good idea to go on borrowing at scale for too long, and never  a good idea to waste money borrowed. The immediate need for high borrowing is necessary to subsidise people and companies that are prevented from working by lock downs. The sooner we can unlock, the sooner we can get our finances under better control. </p>



<p>The good news is there is no need to worry yet. Markets are allowing all the major countries to borrow plenty at ultra low rates of interest, underpinned by Central Banks buying up a lot of  the debt. This only has to change were inflation to pick up, which so far it has not. Japan has been doing this now for several decades with  no inflation, with gross state debt at 250% of GDP but net state debt around half that and the interest burden very low. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A contributor asked for an update on government debt. The UK had a difficult borrowing problem in the IMF crash of the mid 1970s when the country ran out of foreign currency to borrow and had to make emergency cuts. The IMF supervised a programme of lower public spending in return for loans. It had […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29427</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T05:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T05:21:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NEWCASTLE NORTH MP PRESENTS CALL FOR A DEDICATED HOSPITALITY MINISTER IN PARLIAMENT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/newcastle-north-mp-presents-call-for-a-dedicated-hospitality-minister-in-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, Member of Parliament for Newcastle North and Chair of the influential House of Commons Petitions Committee has led a debate in Parliament calling for the creation of a dedicated Minister for Hospitality. The debate was called in response to an online petition started by Claire Bosi, editor of ‘Chef and Restaurant’ Magazine, and … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/newcastle-north-mp-presents-call-for-a-dedicated-hospitality-minister-in-parliament/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">NEWCASTLE NORTH MP PRESENTS CALL FOR A DEDICATED HOSPITALITY MINISTER IN PARLIAMENT</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7052</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:51:41Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:51:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MacNeil calls for compensation for fishing industry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/14/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-fishing-industry/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"&gt;&lt;img src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/04/a1b5c66c-64cd-4de6-8cc5-d2cd48c1794c.jpeg?w=864" alt="" width="614" height="345" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to the UK Prime Minister following Boris Johnson&amp;#8217;s acknowledgment of the difficulties faced by the Scottish fishing industry as a result of his Brexit deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Commenting, Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP MacNeil said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;I have contacted Downing Street following the Prime Minister&amp;#8217;s appearance at the Liaison Committee where he talked about compensation. I am hearing from the fishing industry who are telling me scallop fishing has stopped, prawn boats are also tied up, white fish prices have crashed, and we know from DFDS that they are not taking any consignments to the continent for yet another 5 days.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;At the route of all this is people&amp;#8217;s jobs, in processing and on boats, who are affected by this and affected badly. This situation is a catastrophe. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;The Republic of Ireland has been promised €1.051 billion in help from the European Union, as a result Irish politicians have been commenting about the result of it &amp;#8216;consistent solidarity&amp;#8217; from the European Union towards Ireland, in what is even for them a difficult Brexit process. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;For us in Scotland, the Brexit process is far far worse than anything Ireland is facing. The best we have had so far is to share a £100 million between England, Wales and Northern Ireland, a tenth of what Ireland alone is getting. It is time for the UK Government, who have caused this situation, to up their game and make sure that billions are coming into Scotland, particularly the Highlands and Islands which are the worst affected area in Europe due to Brexit. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;People&amp;#8217;s lives should not be damaged because of the choices of Tory Westminster, Scotland clearly needs to be independent, the damage being done by being in the UK is very much on our doorsteps right now.&amp;#8221; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has written to the UK Prime Minister following Boris Johnson’s acknowledgment of …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/14/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-fishing-industry/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3313</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:37:23Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:37:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210112-Donelan-Whitehead.pdf" class="pdfemb-viewer" style="" data-width="max" data-height="max" data-mobile-width="500" data-scrollbar="none" data-download="on" data-tracking="on" data-newwindow="on" data-pagetextbox="off" data-scrolltotop="off" data-startzoom="100" data-startfpzoom="100" data-toolbar="bottom" data-toolbar-fixed="on">20210112-Donelan-Whitehead<br/></a>
<p class="wp-block-pdfemb-pdf-embedder-viewer"/>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/">My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/">My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33911</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:34:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:34:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Wiltshire Council"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex pushes for support to save chemical industry £1 billion in post-Brexit costs]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/alex-pushes-for-support-to-save-chemical-industry-1-billion-in-post-brexit-costs/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13873</id>
		<updated>2021-01-14T14:40:53Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-14T14:40:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The chemical industry, which supports thousands of jobs across Teesside, will face post-Brexit costs of £1 billion per year unless the Government takes action to align the UK’s chemical regulatory regime with that of the EU.&#160; The industry is the UK’s biggest manufacturing exporter &#8211; with 60% of its total exports destined for EU member [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/alex-pushes-for-support-to-save-chemical-industry-1-billion-in-post-brexit-costs/">Alex pushes for support to save chemical industry £1 billion in post-Brexit costs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Free School Food Parcels</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/update-on-free-school-food-parcels/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Images have been circulating online of some unacceptable food parcels which have been given to students entitled for free school meals but are not able to attend school. Some were claiming that the food parcels were supposed to feed children for two weeks and were costing the taxpayer £30. Both of these claims are not [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/update-on-free-school-food-parcels/">Update on Free School Food Parcels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3038</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T14:03:21Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T14:03:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccination information</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/vaccination-information" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Vaccine delivery plan
The Government has published the Vaccine Delivery plan outlining the strategy for vaccinating the public against covid-19 in the largest mass vaccination the UK has ever seen. You can read the plan HERE.
Vaccination statistics
You can view the daily statistics on the number of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/vaccination-information</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP seeks urgent clarity on fishing exports</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/mp-seeks-urgent-clarity-fishing-exports" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Borders MP, John Lamont, has raised issues facing Berwickshire fishermen in the House of Commons.
Mr Lamont has been in contact with representatives of the industry in the Borders and heard the issues they are facing. He has been discussing the issues with DEFRA and Scotland Office ministers since…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/mp-seeks-urgent-clarity-fishing-exports</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Jack Gebhard</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[High praise for Worcester Talking News]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/high-praise-for-worcester-talking-news/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2127</id>
		<updated>2021-01-14T11:01:59Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-13T11:01:08Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Coronavirus"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Local MP Robin Walker has praised the volunteers at Worcester Talking News for their work over the past year to help blind and visually impaired people stay in touch with local and national news. The charity, based at Colin Chance House in Worcester, has existed since 1978, and their work has been particularly valuable over [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/high-praise-for-worcester-talking-news/"><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal">Local MP Robin Walker has praised the volunteers at Worcester Talking News for their work over the past year to help blind and visually impaired people stay in touch with local and national news. The charity, based at Colin Chance House in Worcester, has existed since 1978, and their work has been particularly valuable over the past year as many people have been forced to stay at home due to the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Volunteers at Worcester Talking News provide regular recordings of current affairs and community news stories. In addition to this, they host a large collection of audiobooks which service users are able to borrow free of charge. They also offer advice and signpost to other services available to assist people who are blind and visually impaired.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Robin has previously visited Colin Chance House to meet the volunteers and has provided a recording so that listeners could hear a report directly from their local MP. Robin said:</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“Worcester Talking News has been a great tool for people who are blind or visually impaired since it began over forty years ago. Without their sight people can understandably feel isolated from the rest of the community, but this resource ensures regular access to news and current affairs.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“Coronavirus has added to everyone’s feeling of isolation, including people who are blind and partially sighted. That is why the service Worcester Talking News provides is more important now than ever. The service is only possible thanks to the committed team of volunteers who deserve praise for their work which improves lives in Worcester and the wider area.”</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/high-praise-for-worcester-talking-news/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2021/01/high-praise-for-worcester-talking-news/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Community vaccination to commence in South West Shropshire </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/community-vaccination-commence-south-west-shropshire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="6870" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">14 January 2021</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Community vaccination to commence in South West Shropshire </span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span>Philip Dunne MP for the Ludlow constituency today confirmed his understanding of the rollout of the COVID vaccination programme in South Shropshire.  </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>In a statement released today he confirmed: </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>“South East Shropshire Primary Care Network was chosen to pilot community vaccination some two weeks before Christmas as soon as the Pfizer BioNTech vaccine became available. This has gone well with strong cooperation and support from all nine GP practices and a majority of residents over 80s are expected to have received their first dose vaccine by this weekend. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>The vaccination programme in the South West Shropshire Primary Care Network area around Ludlow has been underway with the Pfizer BioNTech vaccine for those in Priority Group 1 (care homes and NHS staff) sequentially since 2nd January. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>I am assured by NHS leaders in Shropshire that the programme for Priority Group 2 (over 80s) will commence <span>on 25th Januar</span>y as supplies of the vaccine become available. Vaccination pods will open at Ludlow Racecourse and local residents across South West Shropshire will be contacted by their medical practice by email or letter to be offered a date and time to attend. Please do not contact your GP, they will contact you. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>If vaccine supplies are maintained as planned, the programme is expected to complete all care homes in South Shropshire by the end of next week, all Priority Group 2 (over 80s) by the end of January and all Priority Group 3 (over 75s) and Priority Group 4 (over 70s and clinically extremely vulnerable) by mid-February. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>I know there has been frustration that vaccines have not been deployed earlier. This has been due to logistical challenges in supplying the Pfizer BioNTech vaccine to such a large and sparsely populated geography as the whole of South West Shropshire through a single hub. As more vaccine becomes available and with the Oxford Astra Zeneca vaccine requiring less challenging handling practices, it is now possible to deploy with all the very willing vaccinators and volunteers from the GP surgeries and others in the area. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>GP practices will be in a position to administer the Oxford Astra Zeneca vaccine much like they do the flu vaccine, since it can be transported more readily and has a shelf life of 6 months in a fridge whereas the Pfizer BioNTech has only a few days use following removal from freezer storage at -70C which made it very difficult to deploy for mass vaccination in a rural setting. </span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span>I also have to add that there has been some most unhelpful commentary and speculation suggesting the vaccines would not be available to reach the top four Priority Groups until the end of March. I have been assured by NHS leaders in Shropshire responsible for the vaccination programme that this is wrong and inappropriately misleading for local residents. I am appalled to learn that anyone should be stoking anxiety by spreading such ill informed speculation at this difficult time.” </span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6870 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T09:43:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T09:43:04Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Council welcomes government decision to reject short term let appeals</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13080/council-welcomes-government-decision-to-reject-short-term-let-appeals" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Convener and Vice Convener of our Planning Committee respond to the welcome announcement. </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13080/council-welcomes-government-decision-to-reject-short-term-let-appeals</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T08:44:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T08:44:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Take a peek inside the newly opened vaccine centre in Stevenage that can do over 2000 people a day</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1742-take-a-peek-inside-the-newly-opened-vaccine-centre-in-stevenage-that-can-do-over-2000-people-a-day"/>
		<published>2021-01-13T19:47:32+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-13T19:47:32+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1742-take-a-peek-inside-the-newly-opened-vaccine-centre-in-stevenage-that-can-do-over-2000-people-a-day</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Take a peek inside the newly opened vaccine centre in Stevenage that can do over 2000 people a day. Great addition to the amazing Lister Hospital &amp;amp; 2 GP surgeries already vaccinating local people. Proud Stevenage is leading the way on vaccinations nationally &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ENHertsCCG?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ENHertsCCG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/enherts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@enherts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Ynw6GuhVzD"&gt;https://t.co/Ynw6GuhVzD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1349429486824038400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Take a peek inside the newly opened vaccine centre in Stevenage that can do over 2000 people a day. Great addition to the amazing Lister Hospital &amp;amp; 2 GP surgeries already vaccinating local people. Proud Stevenage is leading the way on vaccinations nationally &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ENHertsCCG?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@ENHertsCCG&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/enherts?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@enherts&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/Ynw6GuhVzD"&gt;https://t.co/Ynw6GuhVzD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1349429486824038400?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Column: Failure on vaccine rollout is not an option</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/column-failure-on-vaccine-rollout-is-not-an-option/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;#8217;s Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus, Judith speaks on the importance of getting the coronavirus vaccination programme right, and calls on the Government to do more to support people with the economic effects of the pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read here article by &lt;a href="http://I have repeatedly called on the Government to do more to support people with the economic effects of the pandemic."&gt;clicking here to go the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;93&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, people, support, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy."&gt;Judith tells Government 'the people of the north will hold you to account' on rebalancing the economy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;93&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy."&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy." alt="Judith tells Government &amp;#039;the people of the north will hold you to account&amp;#039; on rebalancing the economy." /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864 Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, support, judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;92&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, people, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/rugby-league-clubs-social-impact-worth-185m-a-year/" title="Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year"&gt;Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;89&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/rugby-league-clubs-social-impact-worth-185m-a-year/" title="Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/SDP3245-0795-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year" alt="Rugby League Clubs Social Impact worth £185m a year" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Rugby League’s response to the Covid-19 pandemic has been highlighted by a groundbreaking report which concludes that Rugby League clubs contribute £185m in social value each year. Judith Cummins, chair of the All Party-Parliamentary Group on Rugby League said: "This proves that Rugby League is more than just a sport.&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: read, article, clicking, pandemic, judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;72&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/imgID149097243-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" alt="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A version of this article was first published in The Times Ever since I heard Matt Hancock, in a recent interview, extol the virtues of getting seven hours sleep a night through this pandemic, I’ve been thinking about what keeps me awake at night. At the top of my list&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: local, government, support, people, economic, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In this week’s Telegraph &amp; Argus, Judith speaks on the importance of getting the coronavirus vaccination programme right, and calls on the Government to do more to support people with the economic effects of the pandemic.  You can read here article by clicking here to go the Telegraph &amp; Argus website. Related PostsJudith raises World […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2458</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T14:09:36Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T14:09:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Supporting Victims of Domestic Abuse!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/supporting-victims-of-domestic-abuse/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Covid-19, together with Lockdown, has brought about an increased sense of community spirit right across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency. However, at the same time the pandemic has highlighted some of the worst aspects of our day to day life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic violence and abuse is a pernicious crime, and can affect us all. It is important to remember that even during the current lockdown restrictions you can still leave your home if you are experiencing domestic abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Domestic Abuse Helpline is staffed 24 hours a day and can be reached on 0808 2000 247 alternatively they are available at &lt;a href="https://www.nationaldahelpline.org.uk/Chat-to-us-online?fbclid=IwAR2uGmFhWG_MRsiC4231HZDnMEMdh8OopI4KdSbWCJfIGoq0O6p_frprzGo"&gt;https://www.nationaldahelpline.org.uk/Chat-to-us-online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covid-19, together with Lockdown, has brought about an increased sense of community spirit right across my Aldridge-Brownhills constituency. However, at the same time the pandemic has highlighted some of the worst aspects of our day to day life.   Domestic violence and abuse is a pernicious crime, and can affect us all. It is important […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3501</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T12:45:02Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T12:45:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP echoes calls for patience as Covid-19 vaccine rollout continues at pace in East Riding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-echoes-calls-for-patience-as-covid-19-vaccine-rollout-continues-at-pace-in-east-riding/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-echoes-calls-for-patience-as-covid-19-vaccine-rollout-continues-at-pace-in-east-riding/sheila-page/" rel="attachment wp-att-10892"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-10892" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sheila-Page-740x493.jpg" alt="" width="740" height="493" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sheila-Page-740x493.jpg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sheila-Page-300x200.jpg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sheila-Page-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Sheila-Page-2048x1365.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"/></a></p>
<p>(Photo credit: Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust)</p>
<p>Local MP for Beverley and Holderness, has echoed clinicians’ calls for patience as the long-anticipated Covid-19 vaccine continues to be rolled out across the East Riding of Yorkshire, after seeking updates on the progress of its distribution</p>
<p>The UK’s independent regulator, the Medicines &amp; Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA), has now granted approval to three different vaccines shown to be effective against Covid-19 in clinical trials – the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine, the Oxford/AstraZeneca vaccine and the Moderna vaccine. Both the Pfizer and Oxford vaccines are already being distributed to hospitals and GP practices across the country, while deliveries of Moderna doses are expected in the spring.</p>
<p>All seven Primary Care Networks (groups of GP surgeries) in the East Riding are now live vaccination sites, following news that Holderness Health had been chosen as a hub in December. In Beverley and Holderness, vaccines are being administered from Church View Surgery in Hedon, while Beverley PCN has begun vaccinating from Beverley Racecourse.</p>
<p>Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust is also administering the jabs, using the Pfizer vaccine – which must be stored between -80°C and -60°C – to reach NHS and care home staff as well as those over the age of 80. Meanwhile, GP surgeries are leading on immunising care home residents and other housebound patients using the Oxford vaccine.</p>
<p>Graham said, “Vaccines are key to exiting these restrictions and returning to a semblance of normality, so I can understand why people are so keen to see their friends and loved ones get the jab as soon as possible.</p>
<p>“But I think the key message at the moment is for people to be patient and not add to surgeries’ workloads by phoning up to ask when you’ll be getting yours. This is the biggest vaccination programme in the country’s history, so it’s impossible to fit everyone in within the first few days alone. Especially with the Pfizer vaccine, because of its storage requirements, GPs only have a short period of time in which to take delivery of the vaccine, book vulnerable patients in, and administer it before it expires.</p>
<p>“I contacted both the NHS Trust and the Clinical Commissioning Group to see if there was anything I could do to help at a political level, and I was very pleased to hear that vaccination sites in the East Riding are working hard to ensure that every last drop is being used to protect people from this terrible virus.”</p>
<p>Over 2.6 million Covid-19 jabs have been given out to people in the UK as of 12th Janaury, with around 200,000 doses a day being administered at current rates. Government data indicates that over one-third of people aged 80 and over have received their first jab.</p>
<p>Graham added, “The UK has vaccinated more people than anywhere else in Europe – but the programme is still in its early stages. It’s only going to get better as more of the vaccines become available and more hospitals, GP surgeries and pharmacies join up.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">(Photo credit: Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust) Local MP for Beverley and Holderness, has echoed clinicians’ calls for patience as the long-anticipated Covid-19 vaccine...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10891</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T11:43:31Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T11:43:31Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="Beverley Racecourse"/>
    <category term="Castle Hill Hospital"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="Covid-19"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Hedon"/>
    <category term="Holderness"/>
    <category term="Holderness Health"/>
    <category term="Hospital"/>
    <category term="Hull Royal Infirmary"/>
    <category term="Hull University Teaching Hospitals NHS Trust"/>
    <category term="NHS"/>
    <category term="Vaccine"/>
    <category term="Vaccines"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local COVID testing and vaccines</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/local-covid-testing-and-vaccines/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Our NHS is leading the world in the rollout of the coronavirus vaccine. We were the first country to use the Pfizer vaccine, and we now have regulatory approval for the Oxford AstraZeneca vaccine, and the Moderna vaccine. We have vaccinated more people against coronavirus as a proportion of our population than any other country […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5504</id>
    <published>2021-01-13T08:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-13T08:12:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Following Lockdown Rules</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/following-lockdown-rules/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=following-lockdown-rules" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I used my slot on BBC Breakfast today to stress the importance of following the rules and making this lockdown the last.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="Following Lockdown Rules (BBC Breakfast)" width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dUKCvw-tz7c?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I used my slot on BBC Breakfast today to stress the importance of following the rules and making this lockdown the last.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2835</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T18:55:23Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T18:55:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Deputy Leader Urges Divestment from Fossil Fuels of Pension Fund</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/12/deputy-leader-urges-divestment-from-fossil-fuels-of-pension-fund/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the Nottinghamshire Local Government Pension Fund  AGM, Deputy Leader of Nottingham City Council. Cllr Sally Longford, has called on the fund to ensure the long term sustainability of the Fund and play its part in addressing climate change by divesting from fossil fuel to more sustainable, low carbon and renewable investments.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Pension Fund covers over 300 members including Nottingham City Council, Nottinghamshire County Council, the District Councils and many other organisations who are generally non-profit making, or are undertaking a service which was, or could be carried out by the Local Authority. It is controlled by County Councillors and the City Council has no voting rights on the Pension Fund.  Interested parties are able to submit questions to the AGM though which Cllr Longford has done on behalf of City members of the scheme&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Currently Nottinghamshire Pension Fund holds at least £170m in fossil fuel company shares and has no investments in sustainable, low carbon or renewable energy equity funds. Divestment from any fossil fuel related investments is part of Nottingham City Council’s &lt;a href="https://www.nottinghamcity.gov.uk/media/2619917/2028-carbon-neutral-action-plan-v2-160620.pdf"&gt;Carbon Neutral Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; which is aiming to make Nottingham carbon neutral by 2028.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Outlining her argument at January Full Council, Cllr Longford said “We know that the primary responsibility of the pension fund is to protect the financial benefits of the scheme, and now that there is growing evidence that fossil fuel investments are performing less well than comparators it is the time to grasp the divestment nettle.”&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; “Over 1300 institutions worldwide have committed to divestment, including at least 10 UK local government pension funds and a large number of UK universities and faith organisations and so I have submitted a question to the Pension Fund AGM asking them to agree to consult with its members on a divestment strategy and timeline before the next AGM, in order to ensure the long term sustainability of the Fund and to play it’s part in the prevention of catastrophic climate change.”&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;The Pension Fund is set to have its AGM on 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/12/deputy-leader-urges-divestment-from-fossil-fuels-of-pension-fund/"&gt;Deputy Leader Urges Divestment from Fossil Fuels of Pension Fund&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Ahead of the Nottinghamshire Local Government Pension Fund  AGM, Deputy Leader of Nottingham City Council. Cllr Sally Longford, has called on the fund to ensure the long term sustainability of the Fund and play its part in addressing climate change by divesting from fossil fuel to more sustainable, low carbon and renewable investments. The Pension...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/12/deputy-leader-urges-divestment-from-fossil-fuels-of-pension-fund/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/12/deputy-leader-urges-divestment-from-fossil-fuels-of-pension-fund/">Deputy Leader Urges Divestment from Fossil Fuels of Pension Fund</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2578</id>
    <published>2021-01-12T16:12:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-12T16:12:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>support for on line learning for all our childeren</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/01/11/support-for-on-line-learning-for-all-our-childeren/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6413</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:23:21Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T14:23:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[VACCINE CENTRE VISIT]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=343</id>
		<updated>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-102" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The government has taken a twin track approach to Covid - finding the medicines and cures as fast as possible and reducing infection spread while this work goes on. The current lockdown is until 31 March. The vaccine seems so tantalisingly close, but even by the end of February we will not have…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-102</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Funding Sources</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/11/covid-19-funding-sources/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><h3 style="text-align: center">COVID-19 funding sources</h3>
<p>Below is an updated list of COVID-19 funding for Voluntary Organisations, Charities and Businesses as of 8th January 2021.</p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/New-COVID-19-Funds-communities-as-at-8-Jan-2021.docx">New COVID-19 Funds communities as at 8 Jan 2021</a></p>


<p/>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;linkname=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F11%2Fcovid-19-funding-sources%2F&amp;title=COVID-19%20Funding%20Sources" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/11/covid-19-funding-sources/" data-a2a-title="COVID-19 Funding Sources"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/11/covid-19-funding-sources/">COVID-19 Funding Sources</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 funding sources Below is an updated list of COVID-19 funding for Voluntary Organisations, Charities ... <a title="COVID-19 Funding Sources" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/11/covid-19-funding-sources/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/11/covid-19-funding-sources/">COVID-19 Funding Sources</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=1644</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T10:51:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T10:51:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="charities"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="voluntary groups"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - A look at 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-look-2021" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy New Year, although that was no one’s idea of a quiet and peaceful Christmas, and the next few months are unlikely to be any easier.
Starting with the roads, the late addition of the French demand for Covid tests from everyone travelling across the Channel to the plans for the post-Brexit…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-look-2021</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 vaccines update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/covid-19-vaccines-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Good news but please be patient.</p>



<p>Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. </p>



<p>Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect to get 4,000 Pfizer and 2,800 Oxford by next week, but understand that the main roll-out of the vaccine to our 45,000 over 80s and health / care workers will be from 11th January. Then it will be all systems go ……. </p>



<p>Please make sure you are registered with  GP, and you will get your invitation. But also please remember the vaccine takes time to be effective and gives no guarantee you will not pass the disease on to others. </p>



<p>In the meantime, please stay at home unless you have to go out. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Good news but please be patient. Thanks to Hywel Dda health board for sharing with us today plans to share as much of the vaccine as they can get hold of ASAP. Great that Wales &amp; Hywel Dda have received their fair share, &amp; you’ll have given 8,416 vaccine doses by this weekend, &amp; expect […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7941</id>
    <published>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-31T20:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job Vacancy: Chi Seeks to Appoint New Caseworker for Newcastle Central</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/job-chi-seeks-to-appoint-new-caseworker-for-newcastle-central/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below:</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Job Title</strong>: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31 March 2021</p>
<p><strong>Working For</strong>: Chi Onwurah MP</p>
<p><strong>Location</strong>: Internet</p>
<p><strong>Salary</strong>: £21,529- 24,000</p>
<p><strong>Job Details: </strong></p>
<p>Chi Onwurah MP (Newcastle Central) has a vacancy for a caseworker/admin officer. The most important factor is a willingness to learn and work together with the senior caseworker. Training will be provided.</p>
<p>(This post is currently until March 31st 2021, potential for extension dependant on IPSA funding)</p>
<p>The successful candidate will be well-organised with excellent IT and communication skills and attention to detail. Ideally s/he will have some knowledge of welfare benefits and public services including Universal Credit and experience of managing casework, confidential and sensitive information; and of drafting complex letters.</p>
<p>Experience of a similar role and CaseworkerMP would be beneficial. A good understanding of the political environment is advantageous, and a knowledge of local issues in the constituency is desirable. The successful candidate will demonstrate their enthusiasm to play a key role in a small team supporting Chi in her constituency work.</p>
<p><strong>Key Tasks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Provide advice and support to constituents on a range of financial, health, housing and other issues variety of issues through liaison with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve matters.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Responsibilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deal with queries by phone/in person, taking appropriate action to resolve, by gathering information or evidence; then document or escalate their concerns or enquiries in order to progress or close the case.</li>
<li>Manage own caseload and progress of casework, prioritising, logging and updating any actions taken and following up any outstanding queries; with urgent cases reported to the Member.</li>
<li>Draft responses or respond to constituents on any issues raised on behalf of the Member.</li>
<li>Maintain an up-to-date knowledge of relevant guidelines/legislation as appropriate in dealing with casework.</li>
<li>Analyse patterns of enquiries and produce reports.</li>
<li>Ensure records are kept adhering to the Data Protection Act principles Undertake general administrative tasks.</li>
<li>Assist with the work of other colleagues as required and communicate appropriately with internal and external contacts.</li>
<li>Competent use of IT including casework management systems, Microsoft Of ce package, email and internet to support the above.</li>
<li>Attending surgeries and meetings as appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Chi values inclusivity and diversity, and welcomes applications from candidates of all backgrounds.</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Interview/Start Dates: </strong></p>
<p>Closing time for applications 5pm.</p>
<p>Interviews scheduled via zoom Monday 18th January 2021</p>
<p>Start date Monday 25th January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Application Details: </strong></p>
<p>Please send an email with the subject line “Caseworker application – YOURNAME” to <strong>Anthony.bone@parliament.uk</strong> Please attach a CV, a covering letter and a report (max 2 sides A4) which presents a complex situation you have dealt with.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong>: 0191 233 5838</p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="http://chionwurahmp.com/">http://chionwurahmp.com</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below: Closing Date: 15 January 2021 Job Title: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10769</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK-EU Trade deal press release</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">‘I am currently reading through the 1246 pages of the new UK-EU Trade Deal, announced by the Prime Minister on Christmas Eve. I believe this deal makes good on the promises that were made, by the Prime Minister, myself and... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/#more-3749">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3749</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EU (Future Relationship) Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was sorry, along with scores of other MPs, not to be called to speak on this vital but all too short debate. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/eu-future-relationship-bill" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5019 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T13:50:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Brexit to coronavirus and everything in between - Ashfield MP reflects on eventful first year in office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From sending Boris Johnson into isolation, to being trolled on social media, dealing with coronavirus and Brexit, it’s been a busy year for former miner Lee Anderson who has clocked up one year representing his home turf as Ashfield MP.
The married dad of two, raised in Huthwaite, is the area’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s December Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3047</id>
		<updated>2020-12-30T11:33:26Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-30T11:32:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters here</p>
<p></p>
<p>Dear Constituent,</p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" /></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. Under these challenging circumstances, I nevertheless wish you a very safe and happy new year in 2021.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Heanor Future High Streets Fund bid success &#8211; £8.5 million:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following Heanor&#8217;s bid towards the Government&#8217;s £830 million Future High Streets Fund, I&#8217;m delighted that Heanor has been successful and has been awarded over £8.5 million to help transform its town centre and recover from the pandemic. You can find the full details of the Borough Council&#8217;s bid <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/">here</a>, which focuses on plans to regenerate the Market Place and Grammar School site. The Council now have a few months to confirm the final version of their plans, and I look forward to continuing to support and work with them to ensure we can maximise this funding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit deal latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister reached a deal with the EU regarding our future relationship after the end of the transition period, from the 1st January 2021. Parliament has been recalled today, on the 30th December, to consider the deal and vote on it. You can read the deal <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union">here</a> and the legislation enabling it <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf" data-cke-saved-href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf">here</a>. The select committee on the Future Relationship with the EU on which I serve has published a report on the deal this morning, which you can read <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/">here</a>.</p>
<p>I can confirm I will be supporting the deal when it comes to a vote later.</p>
<p>Many constituents have contacted me throughout the negotiation period, and I think this deal delivers on the key areas whilst also providing certainty and security for businesses and residents already impacted by Covid-19.</p>
<p>This deal delivers on Brexit, the referendum and last year&#8217;s election result by taking back control of our laws, borders, money, trade and fisheries.</p>
<p>&#8211; there is no role for the European Court of Justice and no requirement for the UK to follow EU law, so <strong>regaining parliamentary sovereignty</strong>;</p>
<p>&#8211; we will <strong>trade with the EU on the basis of zero tariffs and zero quotas</strong>, which will allow businesses to be able to trade smoothly and continue to access EU markets;</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Allows us to introduce our own modern subsidy system. </strong>This new subsidies system will operate in a that best suits the interests of UK industries &#8211; outside the EU State Aid regime.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> offers streamlined <strong>co-operation on law enforcement</strong>, ensuring we continue to effectively tackle serious organised crime and counter terrorism, protecting the public, and bringing criminals to justice. It also provides for future cooperation between the UK and EU on emerging security challenges, such as cyber and health security, including continuing to work together on tackling the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p><strong>- Recognises UK sovereignty over our fishing waters and puts us in a position to rebuild our fishing fleet and increase quotas, overturning the inequity that British fishermen have faced for over four decades. </strong>By the end of the five year transition we will have full control of our waters and the amount of fish available to UK fishermen will have risen from half to two-thirds.</p>
<p><strong><strong>- Provides for the UK’s participation in certain EU programmes, furthering our commitment to making the UK a science and research superpower. </strong></strong>This deal will fulfil our manifesto commitment to participate in the Horizon Europe programme, but also the Euratom Research and Training programme, and the space programme, Copernicus.</p>
<p>The deal also includes arrangements for airlines and hauliers that provides them with certainty, and gives people the ability to travel to and from the EU easily for work and holidays; a social security agreement that has practical benefits for UK citizens including accessing healthcare when travelling in the EU; and agreements on energy which will benefit consumers by helping to keep prices down.</p>
<p>As I set out in previous newsletters, compromises were necessary to achieve a deal, especially on fishing and the level playing field. Having been through the deal I am satisfied that these compromises are acceptable in the context of the importance of tariff free access to the EU market. This is a good deal achieved at great speed and gives us the best possible platform to make a success of Brexit.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus guidance latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following the last review of the tier restrictions on 16 December, Amber Valley and all of Derbyshire remained in the tier 3 restrictions. The next review takes place today. Amber Valley currently has a high case rate, of 332 cases per 100k, which is one of the highest in Derbyshire, and up 44% on the previous week. This is a very concerning situation and may lead to further restrictions being out in place locally.</p>
<p>On the positive side, mass testing has started in Swadlincote in the south of the County and will spread further in the county, including to Amber Valley early in the new year. This programme, along with similar roll outs in health, care and school settings will help identify cases earlier and slow the spread.</p>
<p>Vaccines are also now starting to be rolled out across the County, and I&#8217;m pleased that Ripley is one of the first primary care centres to begin rolling out the vaccine, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/">here</a>. Now that the Oxford vaccine has been approved for us, the roll out of vaccination should increase rapidly at dedicated centres as well as local GPs and pharmacies. Please do wait to be contacted about the vaccine though rather than asking your GP.</p>
<p>We are now at a critical point in this pandemic with cases rising rapidly and the problems of 2 new variants. But the end is in sight now we can rapidly vaccinate the most vulnerable. At this time we all need to show as much caution as possible to reduce the number of cases and minimise the new restrictions needed. We’ve got this far, let’s not ease off now.</p>
<p>I will continue to engage with ministers, the public health team and the local NHS to ensure that this area sees the full roll out of the vaccines and mass testing as soon as possible and that support is in place for those who can’t work and those businesses forced to close as a result of the tier measures.</p>
<p>You can read my contributions in Parliament here including on highlighting the need to roll out the vaccine to people who are unable to leave their homes as soon as logistics allow <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4">here</a> and about consideration of more localised geography for tier restrictions <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As always, you can find the latest Covid-19 guidance, and support available, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus &#8211; support for local businesses &amp; high streets:</span></strong></p>
<p>In Parliament, I&#8217;ve continued to highlight the difficulties faces by our local businesses, such as the events industry and conference centres (you can read my question to the Secretary of State for Business on this <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4">here</a>), and supporting local high streets (which you can read more on <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4">here</a>).</p>
<p>I welcome the Chancellor&#8217;s announcement of the extension of the furlough scheme until the end of April 2021, and the extension of the business loan schemes until the end of March. You can find more information on the support and grants available for you or your business <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></span></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills" data-cke-saved-href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like me on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" /></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Johnson’s deal ‘social and economic disaster’ for Argyll &amp; Bute</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/12/29/johnsons-deal-social-and-economic-disaster-for-argyll-bute/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I can’t vote for a ‘deal’ that undermines our farmers, fishermen and future opportunities for young people Tomorrow (Wednesday) I will vote against Boris Johnson’s post-Brexit EU trade deal. I will do so because the deal we are being asked to support is woefully deficient, as it undermines our farmers, our fishing communities and the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9118</id>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Speaks Up for Traveling Showmen and Women</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-speaks-up-for-traveling-showmen-and-women/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2969" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-980x653.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled &lt;strong&gt;Future of fairs and Showgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and showmen community and steps in to provide vital support before it is too late. As a longstanding supporter and advocate for show people and a member of the All Party Parliamentary Group for Fairs and Showgrounds, I will continue to be a voice for this community and press the Government at every opportunity for better support and recognition. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the outset of the pandemic, many fairs were either cancelled or postponed – from summer fetes to Christmas Markets. As a result of the closures and postponing of fairs, many show people suffered huge financial loss, plunging them into financial insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The heart of the issue is that the financial support offered to the tourism industry during COVID-19 continually excluded the fairground community. Showmen and women also did not qualify for the assistance announced in the recent budget for retail, leisure and hospitality firms relating to business rates in the coming year, due to the way that the Show people operate, which falls outside the scope of static leisure providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Show people across the UK and particularly those here in South Shields, now face losing their businesses and livelihoods if the UK Government does not step in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read my speech by clicking &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2020-12-17/debates/3B335883-D800-426D-ACAD-2204734ED4F7/FairsAndShowgrounds#contribution-374A337C-9576-467B-95F1-505F40A37FE0"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled Future of fairs and Showgrounds. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2971</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>David Evennett and Bexley Conservatives supporting local pubs, sports and social clubs this winter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bexley Council with funding support from the government has announced further Covid-19 support packages for local businesses across Bexleyheath and Crayford. 
These new grant schemes include a special winter support package of just under £1 million being made available for local independent pubs,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Over 100 Parliamentarians urge the UK Government to take action to protect the Rohingya against genocide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p style="background: white;">
          <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: black;">104 Parliamentarians from across parties are calling on the UK Government to take urgent action to protect the Rohingya Muslim minority from persecution from the Myanmar Government and military. </span>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meeting Father Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I met Father Christmas in Marks and Spencers' Car Park on Sunday 13 December. He had been invited there by the Beckenham Roatary Club of which I an also a member. It was the first time I have seen him this year and he said would be delivering presents to children as normal what ever happened over…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas</id>
    <published>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/23/lambed/07/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WGC Becomes Location for First Ever Green Number Plate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Transport Secretary Grant Shapps recently visited Halfords autocentres in Welwyn Garden City to have the first ever ‘green number plate’ fitted. This comes as the country prepares for the mass adoption of electric vehicles ahead of the UK ending its contribution to climate change by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number plate consists of a green coloured flash on the left-hand side of the plate to designate the vehicle as having zero emissions at tailpipe. The plates are now available to the general public and will be included with all new zero-emissions-vehicles unless customers choose to opt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said the move “Underlined the Government’s commitment to tackling poor air quality in the UK’s towns and cities. It builds on last month’s announcement to end the sale of new petrol and diesel cars and vans in the UK by 2030, putting the UK on course to be the fastest G7 country to decarbonise these vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the new plates on UK roads will raise awareness of the growing number of zero emission vehicles, as well as helping motorists benefit from possible local initiatives such as special parking spaces and cost-free entry into zero-emission zones such as the one in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said: “A green recovery is key to helping us achieve our net zero carbon commitments while also promoting economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Green number plates could unlock a number of incentives for drivers and increase awareness of cleaner vehicles on our roads, showing people that a greener transport future is within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re supporting small businesses to develop the transport tech of the future through a multi-million-pound investment, ensuring that&amp;nbsp;UK&amp;nbsp;businesses remain at the forefront of low carbon innovation and research.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video was produced during the visit, which can be viewed below:&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0  et_pb_text_align_center"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F719013365401804%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=476" width="476" height="476" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30910</id>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Green Number Plates"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Garden City"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rubbish dumping survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="caldera-grid" id="caldera_form_1" data-cf-ver="1.9.2" data-cf-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;&lt;div id="caldera_notices_1" data-spinner="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-admin/images/spinner.gif"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;form data-instance="1" class="CF5f8c811d77adc caldera_forms_form cfajax-trigger" method="POST" enctype="multipart/form-data" id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1" data-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc" aria-label="Flytipping on Cotterills Lane" data-target="#caldera_notices_1" data-template="#cfajax_CF5f8c811d77adc-tmpl" data-cfajax="CF5f8c811d77adc" data-load-element="_parent" data-load-class="cf_processing" data-post-disable="0" data-action="cf_process_ajax_submit" data-request="https://liambyrne.co.uk/cf-api/CF5f8c811d77adc" data-hiderows="true"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" id="_cf_verify_CF5f8c811d77adc" name="_cf_verify" value="c20e8890e2"  data-nonce-time="1610744787" /&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_wp_http_referer" value="/feed/" /&gt;&lt;div id="cf2-CF5f8c811d77adc_1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_id" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_ct" value="1"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="cfajax" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_cr_pst" value="7970"&gt;
&lt;div class="hide" style="display:none; overflow:hidden;height:0;width:0;"&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Order Number&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="text" name="order_number" value="" autocomplete="off"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-1"  class="row  first_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_949637" class="form-group" id="fld_949637_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_949637Label" for="fld_949637_1" class="control-label"&gt;First name &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_949637" class=" form-control" id="fld_949637_1" name="fld_949637" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_949637Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3720579" class="form-group" id="fld_3720579_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3720579Label" for="fld_3720579_1" class="control-label"&gt;Surname &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_3720579" class=" form-control" id="fld_3720579_1" name="fld_3720579" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_3720579Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_377714" class="form-group" id="fld_377714_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_377714Label" for="fld_377714_1" class="control-label"&gt;Postcode &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_377714" class=" form-control" id="fld_377714_1" name="fld_377714" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_377714Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8339186" class="form-group" id="fld_8339186_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8339186Label" for="fld_8339186_1" class="control-label"&gt;Email &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="email" data-field="fld_8339186" class=" form-control" id="fld_8339186_1" name="fld_8339186" value="" data-type="email" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_8339186Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id="fld_3670460_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8286015" class="form-group" id="fld_8286015_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8286015Label" for="fld_8286015_1" class="control-label"&gt;Has the dumping and littering problem in the area reduced recently?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_8286015" value="" data-field="fld_8286015" class="form-control" id="fld_8286015_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_8286015Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Not Sure"  data-calc-value="Not Sure" &gt;
						Not Sure					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_5317914" class="form-group" id="fld_5317914_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_5317914Label" for="fld_5317914_1" class="control-label"&gt;What further steps would you like to see taken?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;textarea name="fld_5317914" value="" data-field="fld_5317914" class="form-control" id="fld_5317914_1" rows="4"    aria-labelledby="fld_5317914Label" &gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_7237774" class="form-group" id="fld_7237774_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_7237774Label" for="fld_7237774_1" class="control-label"&gt;Would you be willing to join a residents’ group?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_7237774" value="" data-field="fld_7237774" class="form-control" id="fld_7237774_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_7237774Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Maybe"  data-calc-value="Maybe" &gt;
						Maybe					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3572997" class="form-group" id="fld_3572997_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3572997Label" for="fld_3572997_1" class="control-label"&gt;Can Liam email you about news and campaign updates? &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_3572997" value="" data-field="fld_3572997" class="form-control" id="fld_3572997_1"  required="required"  aria-labelledby="fld_3572997Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Liam can email me					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						Liam cannot email me					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_4555323" class=" form-control" id="fld_4555323_1" name="fld_4555323" value="1" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_3061013" class=" form-control" id="fld_3061013_1" name="fld_3061013" value="2020 Oct Flytipping Survey" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;hr id="fld_6111107_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_432351" class="form-group" id="fld_432351_1-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class=""&gt;
	&lt;input  class="btn btn-default" type="submit" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1" value="Submit" data-field="fld_432351"  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;input class="button_trigger_1" type="hidden" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1_btn" value="" data-field="fld_432351"  /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-2"  class="row  last_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/"&gt;Rubbish dumping survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/">Rubbish dumping survey</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=7970</id>
    <published>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Flytipping"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Written Answers — Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs: Gun Sports: Coronavirus (22 May 2020)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.cliftonbrown.co.uk/content/written-answers-%E2%80%94-department-environment-food-and-rural-affairs-gun-sports-coronavirus-22" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Clifton-Brown: To ask the Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, what steps his Department is taking to enable the early resumption of shooting after the covid-19 outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/wrans/?id=2020-05-13.46528.h&amp;amp;s=geoffrey%20clifton-brown%20section%3Awrans#g46528.q0" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.theyworkforyou.com/wrans/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>1332 at https://www.cliftonbrown.co.uk</id>
    <published>2020-05-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Steve Reed joins Labour’s Shadow Cabinet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2020/04/07/steve-reed-joins-labours-shadow-cabinet/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1586274800955">

<div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- ">

	
	<p>Labour’s new leader Keir Starmer has appointed Steve Reed MP into the Shadow Cabinet. Steve is now Labour’s Shadow Secretary of State for Communities and Local Government. Steve has a strong local government background having previously served as shadow local government minister and was leader of Lambeth Council where he oversaw dramatic improvements in key services.</p>
<blockquote>
<h5>Steve said:</h5>
<p>I’m honoured that Keir has asked me to be Labour’s spokesperson on communities and local government.   Councillors and council workers are responding heroically to coronavirus, and I want to make sure they have all the resources they need to succeed.</p>
<p>We’ve never needed good councils more than we do today, and I’m proud to stand up for local government in Parliament
</p></blockquote>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	<div class="templatera_shortcode">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"/>

<div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center"><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span><div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"><div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey"><span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"/></div></div><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span>
</div></div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-">
	<ul>

	
		<li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7">
			<div class="item-holder">
				<div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true">
							<img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-owwwgkdrjtxtzs5i2ll8hok1khkbl72gz2cnu2gj3s.png" data-mk-image-src-set="{&quot;default&quot;:&quot;https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg&quot;,&quot;2x&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;mobile&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;responsive&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}"/>


					
				</div>

				<div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">
						<span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333">Steve Reed</span>
					<span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1">Member of Parliment for Croydon North</span>
					
					<div class="clearboth"/>

					
<ul class="mk-employeee-networks">
			<li><a target="_blank" href="mailto:steve.reed.mp@parliament.uk" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-600203fb03971" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-600203fb03b13" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-600203fb03c71" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-600203fb03d50" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/></svg></a></li>
	</ul>
				</div>
			</div>
		</li>

					<div class="clearboth"/>
			</ul>
<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>
</div>

<div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155">

<div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text">

	
	<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steven Reed</a> is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/">reducing violent mental health restraint</a> became law. In June 2019 he launched <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/">Labour’s civil society strategy</a> outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>
</div></div>
	</div>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2020/04/07/steve-reed-joins-labours-shadow-cabinet/">Steve Reed joins Labour’s Shadow Cabinet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2020/04/07/steve-reed-joins-labours-shadow-cabinet/">Steve Reed joins Labour’s Shadow Cabinet</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Reed MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10480</id>
    <published>2020-04-07T15:55:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-04-07T15:55:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hull MP reacts to the Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/hull-mp-reacts-budget" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10.5755px;"&gt;Diana Johnson spoke in the Commons debate on the Chancellor's Budget Statement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10.5755px;"&gt;The Hull North MP's remarks ranged across several key issues for Hull North, including support for workers over the Coronavirus, the NHS and public health, flood resilience and devolution for the Humber.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/14"&gt;Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item odd"&gt;&lt;a href="/tags/devolution"&gt;devolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/7"&gt;Fair deal for Hull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Morton</name>
    </author>
    <id>884 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-3822029382927366640</id>
    <published>2020-03-06T13:22:00.003+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-06T13:22:42.576+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Raise the rate"/>
    <title type="text">Raise the Rate debate</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="true" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" height="313" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FYvonneFovargue4Makerfield%2Fvideos%2F613975099449506%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/3822029382927366640/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html" title="Raise the Rate debate"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-600204d06f2d6" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-600204d06f2d6').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"600204d06f2d6","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-600204d06f2d6" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-600204d06f2d6" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="600204d06f2d6" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_600204d06f2d6" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_600204d06f2d6" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_600204d06f2d6" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_600204d06f2d6" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_600204d06f2d6" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_600204d06f2d6" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_600204d06f2d6_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-600204d06f2d6 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dwTjZESFQA1QSAk2xcOZG4KaeVcnKm-NkMXtPqlqSi43F4ZIiZ6n9NbcNZzX5YMd13Dg4ouxSUz1LoBiFPwaw' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~3/QVJ5Ukdon9g/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~4/QVJ5Ukdon9g" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>118389 - George Freeman - 08-Dec-2017 (Tabled)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/content/118389-george-freeman-08-dec-2017-tabled" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;George Freeman&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To ask the Secretary of State for International Development, what recent discussions she has had with her counterpart in the Lebanese Government on the potential forced return of refugees to Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-statements/written-question/Commons/2017-12-08/118389" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-stateme…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2472 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thank you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" rel="attachment wp-att-281"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="281" data-permalink="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" data-orig-size="640,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 09-06-2017, 10 43 04 (2)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=300%2C186" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" src="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=640%2C396" alt="" width="640" height="396" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?w=640 640w, https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=300%2C186 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will be closing down shortly, but you can keep up to date with my work on my &lt;a href="http://www.carolynharris.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;main webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Google+" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;#038;title=Thank%20you" data-a2a-url="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" data-a2a-title="Thank you"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  We did it! Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me. I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East. This website will be closing down shortly, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>linzi_isaac</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/?p=279</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>37017 - Mr Keith Simpson - 11-May-2016 (Tabled)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.keithsimpson.com/content/37017-mr-keith-simpson-11-may-2016-tabled" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mr Keith Simpson&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To ask the Prime Minister, if he will clarify his recent remarks concerning President Ghani made on Tuesday 10 May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-statements/written-question/Commons/2016-05-11/37017" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-stateme…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>156 at https://www.keithsimpson.com</id>
    <published>2016-05-11T18:58:20Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-11T18:58:20Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcoming the Fantastic Ryanair Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/2016/01/11/welcoming-the-fantastic-ryanair-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport.<br/>
Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result.<br/>
The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here.<br/>
The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well.<br/>
It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have been ongoing for a considerable length of time now, have resulted in success for both Ryanair and the Northern Ireland economy.<br/>
We have a very proud aerospace industry here in Northern Ireland and it is very much engrained in our manufacturing heritage with the likes of Shorts Brothers, now Bombardier, having been established in Northern Ireland since the end of the Second World War.<br/>
We have gone through an extremely difficult 18 months in County Antrim with the announced closures of both the JTI Gallaher tobacco plant and the Michelin tyre factory bringing about almost 1800 redundancies and this investment is a huge step forward in finding new jobs and new opportunities for the people of this area.<br/>
Ryanair’s investment of £300 million will boost our local wage economy enormously and all of our local businesses and town centres will reap the benefits as a result.<br/>
Ryanair are also in discussions with Tourism Ireland to explore the possibility of introducing five new routes and I have every faith that Tourism Ireland and all other sectors who would benefit from such an arrangement will do everything they can to ensure its successful delivery.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport. Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result. The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here. The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well. It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/?p=1623</id>
    <published>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795</id>
    <published>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
