<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2020-12-03T17:52:25Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP welcomes the Spending Review – helping Basingstoke to fight coronavirus, and investing in recovery</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-welcomes-spending-review-helping-basingstoke-fight-coronavirus-and-investing-recovery" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP Maria Miller has welcomed the Spending Review which provides billions of pounds in the fight against coronavirus, and invests in the UK’s recovery.
On Wednesday, the Government set out an ambitious plan that focuses on levelling up across the country, investing in vital infrastructure that…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-welcomes-spending-review-helping-basingstoke-fight-coronavirus-and-investing-recovery</id>
    <published>2020-12-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne signs Commons motion marking International Day of People with Disabilities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-signs-commons-motion-celebrating-international-day-of-people-with-disabilities/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-signs-commons-motion-celebrating-international-day-of-people-with-disabilities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233112" src="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/IDPWD.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has signed an Early Day Motion that celebrates International Day of People with Disabilities, which takes place today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Day of People with Disabilities was launched by the United Nations in 1992 and takes place on 3 December every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the day is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="sc-fHxwqH gVvrSi pf-f3a36848" data-pf-type="Text"&gt;Celebration – to recognize and value the diversity of our global community, and to cherish the role we all play, regardless of our abilities;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i class="sc-kxynE kHrSas pf-ed9b5a89 fa fa-star" data-pf-type="Icon"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="sc-fHxwqH gVvrSi pf-b4d0d78b" data-pf-type="Text"&gt;Learning – to understand and learn from the experiences of people with living with a disability;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i class="sc-kxynE kHrSas pf-c1d37e40 fa fa-star" data-pf-type="Icon"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="sc-fHxwqH gVvrSi pf-5ea5cc05" data-pf-type="Text"&gt;It is a day for optimism – to look towards the future and the creation of a world where a person is not characterised by their disabilities, but by their abilities;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i class="sc-kxynE kHrSas pf-05b37e9e fa fa-star" data-pf-type="Icon"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="sc-fHxwqH gVvrSi pf-7133bbd5" data-pf-type="Text"&gt;Action – where all people, organisations, agencies and charities not only show their support for International Day of People with Disabilities, but take on a commitment to create a world characterised by equal human rights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme for 2020 is ‘Not all Disabilities are Visible’. This focuses on spreading awareness and understanding of disabilities that are not immediately apparent, such as mental illness, chronic pain or fatigue, sight or hearing impairments, diabetes, brain injuries, neurological disorders, learning differences and cognitive dysfunctions, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwynne put his name to a Commons motion tabled by Dr Lisa Cameron MP (East Kilbride, Strathaven and Lesmahagow), which states the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That this House recognises 3 December is the International Day of People with Disabilities, a day to celebrate disabled people and champion their abilities; supports the United Nation’s work surrounding this campaign, notes this year’s theme is entitled not all disabilities are visible, which aims to spread awareness and understanding of disabilities that are not immediately apparent such as mental illness, learning difficulties, head injury and other non-visible conditions; acknowledges that over 15 per cent of the world’s population live with a disability and that during these unprecedented times, they are likely to be disproportionately affected; acknowledges the work the all-party Parliamentary group on Disability has done to raise the profile of disability across the House; further acknowledges the fantastic work charities have done to support disabled people globally, including Leonard Cheshire, Sense and Sense International; encourages the wider promotion and protection of disability rights; understands the importance of combatting the stigma surrounding disability; and urges parliamentarians to work for an inclusive, accessible, and sustainable society for people with disabilities leaving no one behind in line with United Nations Sustainable Development Goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Gwynne said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It has been a particularly difficult year for those with disabilities, so I think that the International Day of People with Disabilities is perhaps particularly important year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I think it&amp;#8217;s fantastic that this year&amp;#8217;s theme focuses on non-visible disabilities. Those living with these disabilities can have difficulty receiving support or face abuse because many people think only about visible disabilities.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-signs-commons-motion-celebrating-international-day-of-people-with-disabilities/"&gt;Gwynne signs Commons motion marking International Day of People with Disabilities&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has signed an Early Day Motion that celebrates International Day of People with Disabilities, which takes place today. The International Day of People with Disabilities was launched by the United Nations in 1992 and takes place on 3 December every year. The purpose of the day is: Celebration […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-signs-commons-motion-celebrating-international-day-of-people-with-disabilities/">Gwynne signs Commons motion marking International Day of People with Disabilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233111</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T16:44:56Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T16:44:56Z</updated>
    <category term="National"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Agricultural Transition Plan offers path to sustainable farming says MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/agricultural-transition-plan-offers-path-sustainable-farming-says-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="6849" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;3 December 2020&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Agricultural Transition Plan offers path to sustainable farming says MP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne has welcomed publication this week of the government’s long awaited Agricultural Transition Plan, to prepare farmers for moving away from the Common Agricultural Policy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;As the UK leaves the EU transition period each nation of the UK is able to take a unique approach to replacing the previous method of support. In England, the government will support farmers to improve the environment, improve animal health and welfare and reduce carbon emissions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Plan includes incentives for environmentally sustainable farming, local nature recovery, and recovery of landscape and ecosystems. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.philipdunne.com/sites/philipdunne.com/files/2020-12/philip_dunne_dairy_farm.jpg" width="1000" height="600" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
            &lt;svg xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:cc="http://creativecommons.org/ns#" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" id="svg1633" version="1.1" viewbox="0 0 9.260417 9.260417" height="9.260417mm" width="9.260417mm"&gt;&lt;defs id="defs1627"&gt;&lt;/defs&gt;&lt;metadata id="metadata1630"&gt;&lt;rdf&gt;&lt;work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;format&gt;image/svg+xml&lt;/format&gt;&lt;type rdf:resource="http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/StillImage"&gt;&lt;/type&gt;&lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;&lt;/work&gt;&lt;/rdf&gt;&lt;/metadata&gt;&lt;g transform="translate(42.427828,-119.2567)" id="layer1"&gt;&lt;path style="fill:#ffffff;stroke-width:0.26458332" id="path644" d="m -37.797619,120.02849 a 3.8584187,3.8584187 0 1 1 -3.858419,3.85841 3.8629167,3.8629167 0 0 1 3.858419,-3.85841 z m 0,-0.77179 a 4.6302083,4.6302083 0 1 0 4.630208,4.6302 4.6302083,4.6302083 0 0 0 -4.630208,-4.6302 z m 0,2.21853 a 0.48233542,0.48233542 0 1 1 -0.481806,0.48233 0.48286458,0.48286458 0 0 1 0.481806,-0.48233 z m 0.771789,4.72678 h -1.543579 v -0.38576 c 0.186796,-0.0691 0.385763,-0.0775 0.385763,-0.28364 v -1.72376 c 0,-0.20611 -0.198967,-0.23812 -0.385763,-0.30744 v -0.38577 h 1.157552 v 2.41724 c 0,0.20637 0.199496,0.21537 0.385763,0.28363 z"&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-caption field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photo predates COVID19 restrictions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The system will change between 2021 and 2024, with a phased reduction in direct support, affecting larger farmers the quickest, but intended to give farmers time to adapt. The government will also help farmers prepare for the new Environmental Land Management Scheme, due from 2024, but with pilots for up to 5,500 farmers being trialled earlier. The transition will include extensions to Countryside Stewardship and Environmental Stewardship, for those who already have an agreement, new Countryside Stewardship agreements, for those who want to undertake a wider range of more ambitious environmental activities, and core elements of the Sustainable Farming Incentive will be available to all farmers from 2022 onwards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Direct payments will be phased out from 2021, with the last Direct Payments being made in 2027. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr Dunne, who has responsibility for his family farm, said: “There is much to welcome in the Agricultural Transition Plan, including a move towards sustainable farming practices and effective lasting stewardship of the countryside, as we move away from the EU’s Common Agricultural Policy with all its idiosyncrasies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I was pleased that DEFRA Secretary of State, George Eustice, confirmed in response to my question in the House of Commons on Monday that he will work to ensure new entrants can find routes into farming, so the new scheme to allow upfront payments for farmers who wish to retire does not result solely in consolidation into larger holdings. I also expressed my concern that farming should remain viable in disadvantaged areas.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr Dunne also welcomed a separate development this week to strengthen oversight of new trade deals. The new Trade &amp; Agriculture Commission will have greater ability to ensure future Free Trade Agreements do not undermine animal welfare and environmental standards in food production. Consumer and developing country interests will be represented. New export opportunities will flow from these new trade agreements for food producers in all parts of the UK.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr Dunne added: “I abstained on some well-intentioned though impractical amendments to the Agriculture Bill, and called on Ministers to provide greater oversight of standards for new free trade deals. So I am pleased the government has listened to these concerns. This new Commission will ensure all MPs have the detail needed to judge the impact of any FTA on future standards, and we will be able to vote accordingly informed by the Commission’s advice.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The amendments brought forward by the Government to the Trade Bill place a duty on the Secretary of State to request, and lay before Parliament, advice from the TAC on the extent to which new Free Trade Agreement measures applicable to trade in agricultural products are consistent with the maintenance of domestic levels of statutory protection for:    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;animal or plant life or health;   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;animal welfare;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the environment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This will allow MPs and Peers access to independent and expert advice when reviewing the impact of free trade agreements. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6849 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T16:21:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T16:21:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Harriett calls for Ministerial intervention on college sale</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-calls-ministerial-intervention-college-sale" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;West Worcestershire MP Harriett Baldwin has held a series of meetings with senior Government Ministers following the shock decision to close Malvern Hills College. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/harriett-calls-ministerial-intervention-college-sale" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>4999 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T14:45:12Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T14:45:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>C2C Adapted Service Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/c2c-adapted-service-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/DSC_1474.JPG?itok=-pyYu2Jz" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p> </p>
              <p>Over the course of the last few months c2c have been in the process of adapting services to meet the needs of customers. Covid-19 has seen a significant drop in journeys. In October, the number of daily travellers had risen to a high of 42% of pre-Covid levels. By the end of November that figure had fallen back down to 30%.</p>
              <p>A recent update sent to Jon Cruddas MP outlined the following measures:</p>
              <ul type="disc">
                <ul>
                  <li>
                    <em>Protecting trains that arrive in central London before 08.00, and there will be more carriages running at the start of the day than at present.</em>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                    <em>Due to changing work patterns rush hour now results in a pre-18.00 peak so c2c are prioritising capacity at these new peak times.</em>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                    <em>Due to high demand from school students travelling from east London and Essex into Southend on certain trains in the morning, there will now be five successive 12-car services that will arrive in the Southend area between 07.20 and 08.40.</em>
                  </li>
                </ul>
              </ul>
              <p>At other times however, like off-peak and late-night services, demand has fallen away significantly so there will be significant reductions. However, all trains will be 8-carriages to maximise space to support social distancing.</p>
              <p>A number of residents raised their concerns and Jon Cruddas sought assurances on issues relating to staff face coverings, increase in service usage when lockdown ends and shops reopen over Christmas, and c2c were also asked when residents could expect a normal service to resume.</p>
              <p><strong>Jon said:</strong> “there were a number of concerns about the new timetable and service being run on the line through Dagenham Dock and Rainham. I feel confident that all of these issues were addressed by c2c. Their staff are exempt from face coverings as they work incredibly long shifts, but there are very strict protocols in place to protect staff and passengers. Additional services have been added to the timetable to manage anticipated journey increases over the Christmas period.”</p>
              <p>C2c stated that it is too early to give an indication of when a normal service would resume as they are currently working hard to adapt to a constantly changing environment.</p>
              <p>Find out all about the changes and how they may affect you here: <strong><a href="https://www.c2c-online.co.uk/our-network/timetables-and-service-alterations/">c2c Timetables &amp; Service Alterations | Latest timetable information (c2c-online.co.uk)</a></strong></p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/rainham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Rainham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/travel" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Travel</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/c2c" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">C2C</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/transport" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Transport</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-5">
              <a href="/tags/trains" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Trains</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-6">
              <a href="/tags/journey" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Journey</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-7">
              <a href="/tags/commute" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Commute</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1431 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T14:24:12Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T14:24:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Travel Window</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2020/12/03/christmas-travel-window/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I have received this update from the Secretary of State for Transport:</p>



<p>Dear John</p>



<p>I am writing to provide you with an update on the Government’s preparations for the Christmas period.</p>



<p>The Government recently published guidance to help families and friends see each other over the Christmas period – and to do so as safely as possible. Between 23rd and 27th of December or between 22nd and 28th of December for those travelling to and from Northern Ireland, travel restrictions across the UK and between tiers will be lifted to allow three households to come together. Once at their destination, people should follow the rules in that tier.</p>



<p>We are working with transport operators to help people see their loved ones, safely. We ask everyone to closely consider their journey, plan and book ahead, be patient, and be considerate of fellow passengers – and particularly staff who have worked so hard all year – by following the guidance carefully, including keeping space and wearing a face covering on public transport.</p>



<p>To help people travel safely and minimise disruption as far as possible over the Christmas period, we are deploying a series of measures.</p>



<ul><li>On our strategic road network of motorways and trunk roads, Highways England have <strong>cleared a total of 778 miles of roadworks</strong>, meaning that 96% of the network will be unaffected. Where essential work must continue, speed limits will be set at 60mph (rather than 50mph) where possible to keep disruption to a minimum.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Ministers have written to all Local Authorities in England with the request that they lift as many roadworks as possible and <strong>ensure bus services are running reliably </strong>over the period, to ease traffic on local roads.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Network Rail will ensure that <strong>over 95% of the network will be unaffected by engineering works </strong>over the Christmas period. Where essential works must continue, replacement buses will be available.</li></ul>



<ul><li>We are also working with train operators, a number of whom have already confirmed they will <strong>run longer trains </strong>and increase service levels. For example, longer trains will run on Anglo-Scotland and Liverpool routes to boost the number of seats at anticipated busy times on the West Coast Main Line. Chiltern Railway will also run additional services on the 27 December, and East Midlands Railway will run a full intercity timetable over the Christmas period.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Government is also <strong>waiving change of journey admin fees </strong>for Advance rail tickets sold before the announcement of new Covid tiers on 26th November, ensuring passengers are not left out of pocket for changing their tickets to comply with the guidance.</li></ul>



<p>To provide further support to passengers, Network Rail and train operators have been asked to ensure extra staff are in place at key stations to provide assistance. British Transport Police will also be deploying extra officers to help keep passengers safe.</p>



<p>All transport operators have been asked to increase the clarity and regularity of communications with passengers, to help them plan their journeys, warn of any disruption and offer support.</p>



<p>Finally, to protect and support the resilience of transport workers on the frontline, we are working closely with the Department of Health and Social Care and transport operators on rapid testing at selected sites, the first of which is going live next week.</p>



<p>Further details on these measures can be found in the annex.</p>



<p>To help provide rigorous scrutiny of these plans, the Government has appointed Sir Peter Hendy – Chair of Network Rail – who will work alongside operators and the Department for Transport. He will ensure there is a collective focus across the transport industry on minimising disruption and supporting passengers.</p>



<p>We are also continuing to work with the Devolved Administrations on our plans to ensure we take an aligned approach as far as possible.</p>



<p>I am confident that the measures set out above will ensure that people can travel as safely and reliably as possible if they choose to, and we are doing everything we can to help people see their loved ones safely this Christmas.</p>



<p>Yours ever,</p>



<p><strong>Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</strong></p>



<p><strong>SECRETARY OF STATE FOR TRANSPORT</strong></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I have received this update from the Secretary of State for Transport: Dear John I am writing to provide you with an update on the Government’s preparations for the Christmas period. The Government recently published guidance to help families and friends see each other over the Christmas period – and to do so as safely […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29149</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T14:21:05Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T14:21:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Wokingham and West Berkshire Issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP reiterates support for efforts to retain Air Traffic Control in the islands</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/03/mp-reiterates-support-for-efforts-to-retain-air-traffic-control-in-the-islands/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil has reiterated his support for Air Traffic Control staff who are continuing their battle against the plans by HIAL to move forward with the Remote Towers project.</p>



<p>Prospect union, representing staff across the Highlands and Islands, state the HIAL’s assertion that there will be no redundancies is misleading given that the plan is to close workplaces and relocate jobs to mainland locations.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil said: “From the beginning, HIAL have had an agenda of trying to undermine the economic prospects of the islands. They are not Highlands and Islands Airports but Inverness Airports. It has not been good enough. The Scottish Government should step in and take control of this and protect our islands.”</p>



<p>Prospect are currently balloting members about future industrial action and they state that this will cause as little disruption to local communities as possible starting after the holiday period.</p>



<p>It is also stressed that any industrial action with have no impact on emergency cover.</p>



<p/>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg"><img data-attachment-id="2348" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/barra-plane/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg" data-orig-size="1600,777" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Barra plane" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-2348" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2019/05/barra-plane.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil has reiterated his support for Air Traffic Control staff who are continuing their …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/03/mp-reiterates-support-for-efforts-to-retain-air-traffic-control-in-the-islands/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3243</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T12:53:45Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T12:53:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Another step forward with energy-efficient housing at Granton Waterfront </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13054/another-step-forward-with-energy-efficient-housing-at-granton-waterfront" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hart Builders appointed as work is underway to design around 150 brand new affordable homes at the former Silverlea care home in North West Edinburgh</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13054/another-step-forward-with-energy-efficient-housing-at-granton-waterfront</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T12:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T12:15:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP CALLS FOR WIDER ACCESS TO GREEN HOMES GRANT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-calls-wider-access-green-homes-grant" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MP for Berwick-upon-Tweed, Anne-Marie Trevelyan MP, has expressed her concern that few energy providers and installers in Northumberland have been able to access Trustmark status, meaning they are not able to become part of the Green Homes Grant scheme the Government has launched.
The scheme –…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-calls-wider-access-green-homes-grant</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John asks questions about Government covid contracts.]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/03/john-asks-questions-about-government-covid-contracts/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4531</id>
		<updated>2020-12-03T11:31:01Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-03T11:28:36Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Anti-Corruption"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Question by John to the Chancellor and Minister for the Cabinet Office: With reference to the National Audit Office report on Government procurement during the covid-19 pandemic, published 18 November 2020, [I would like to ask] whether the same standard of due diligence checks was carried out on potential suppliers and contracts in the (a) [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/03/john-asks-questions-about-government-covid-contracts/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Question by John to the Chancellor and Minister for the Cabinet Office:</strong></p>



<p>With reference to the National Audit Office report on Government procurement during the covid-19 pandemic, published 18 November 2020, [I would like to ask] whether the same standard of due diligence checks was carried out on potential suppliers and contracts in the (a) high priority lane and (b) normal lane.</p>



<p><strong>Answer from Ministers:</strong></p>



<p>Being able to procure at speed has been critical in providing the Government’s response to the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>We welcome the NAO report which recognises that the government ‘needed to procure with extreme urgency’ and ‘secured unprecedented volumes of essential supplies necessary to protect front-line workers’.</p>



<p>All contracts, including those designed to tackle coronavirus issues, must continue to achieve value for money for taxpayers, use good commercial judgement and the details of any awards made should be published as soon as possible in line with Government transparency guidelines.</p>



<p>Robust processes are in place for the award of government contracts. PPE offers were assessed using the same eight step process, including quality checks, price controls and other due diligence, no matter where the original referral came from. This eight step process has been published in the NAO’s report. For further details please see the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/statement-on-government-procurement-following-this-weeks-nao-report" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">statement on gov.uk.(opens in a new tab)</a></p>



<p>We are committed to transparency in public procurement. Details of central government contracts above £10,000 are published on Contracts Finder. We regret that some details have not been uploaded in a timely fashion. All will be published as soon as possible and significant information is already available online.</p>



<p>The forthcoming Green Paper on transforming the UK’s public procurement regulations will strengthen our longstanding and essential policies that are fundamental to public procurement including transparency, ensuring value for money and fair treatment of suppliers. As part of this, we will propose legislating to reinforce that contracting authorities would need to publish basic disclosure information, including the basis of award decisions.</p>



<p>We have always accepted that there are lessons to be learned from how we responded to this unprecedented global pandemic and the government is fully committed to doing so. We will address the NAO report’s recommendations in due course. As I stated in my&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2020-11-12/debates/46D252DF-18D4-40EE-9AD5-0439F9106839/OralAnswersToQuestions#contribution-ED32E98C-15B1-4BEF-A267-47FB68033CDF" target="_blank">answer on 12 November (opens in a new tab)</a>, we are engaged in both internal and external audit to review how our procurements during this period have been conducted.</p>



<p><strong><span class="has-inline-color has-heading-link-color-mariner-color">Responding to the answer from Government, John wrote on social media: &#8220;Got answers to my Questions on Government covid contracts. Good that all suppliers faced same quality checks no matter who recommended them, but publication backlog of contract details still needs fixing. Big post-brexit opportunity for faster, more digital &amp; transparent, less bureaucratic Government buying process so small firms can challenge big incumbents easily!&#8221;&nbsp;</span></strong></p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Shoppers around Neath have brought a warm glow to the hearts of the hard working volunteers of a local conservation group</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/shoppers-around-neath-have-brought-a-warm-glow-to-the-hearts-of-the-hard-working-volunteers-of-a-local-conservation-group/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt;The Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have been awarded £2,625 by the Co-op Community Fund – and they want to say a big thank-you to everyone who helped to stoke the group’s funds.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt;“Many thanks for all your kind donations,” said Friends’ secretary Peter Richards, who has already earmarked the cash for a piece of hi tech new equipment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt;“We are hoping to buy a powered wheelbarrow for the next phase of work on the site off New Road,” he added.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt;The Friends meet most Sundays &lt;a dir="ltr" href="x-apple-data-detectors://7"&gt;at 1pm&lt;/a&gt;, and welcome people of all ages. Contact &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:wernddu@gmail.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;wernddu@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-GB"&gt; or just turn up.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/shoppers-around-neath-have-brought-a-warm-glow-to-the-hearts-of-the-hard-working-volunteers-of-a-local-conservation-group/9f16b943-a8aa-42e0-8417-0dae7807c872/"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2326" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/9F16B943-A8AA-42E0-8417-0DAE7807C872-560x425.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Friends of Neath Abbey Iron Company have been awarded £2,625 by the Co-op Community Fund – and they want to say a big thank-you to everyone who helped to stoke the group’s funds. “Many thanks for all your kind donations,” said Friends’ secretary Peter Richards, who has already earmarked the cash for a piece […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2324</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T11:16:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T11:16:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 Vaccine Update – 2nd December 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/03/covid-19-vaccine-update/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Below is a Dear Colleague letter I received from Ministers following the announcement of the approval for use of Pfizer/BioNTech’s Covid-19 vaccine.</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3712</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T10:24:44Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T10:24:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Exciting Stevenage amongst first vaccination hubs following brilliant news that Government accepted MHRA's recommendation on using Pfizer/ BioNTech's Covid-19 vaccine</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1718-exciting-stevenage-amongst-first-vaccination-hubs-following-brilliant-news-that-government-accepted-mhra-s-recommendation-on-using-pfizer-biontech-s-covid-19-vaccine"/>
		<published>2020-12-03T08:54:43+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-03T08:54:43+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1718-exciting-stevenage-amongst-first-vaccination-hubs-following-brilliant-news-that-government-accepted-mhra-s-recommendation-on-using-pfizer-biontech-s-covid-19-vaccine</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning, the government accepted the recommendation from the independent Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) to approve Pfizer/BioNTech’s Covid-19 vaccine for use. This is brilliant news and very exciting Stevenage is one of the first vaccination hubs.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1334414888203120640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 3, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning, the government accepted the recommendation from the independent Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) to approve Pfizer/BioNTech’s Covid-19 vaccine for use. This is brilliant news and very exciting Stevenage is one of the first vaccination hubs.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1334414888203120640?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 3, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Thoughts on the New Tier System</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/my-thoughts-on-the-new-tier-system/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This is my take on the relative merits and weaknesses of the tier system which I voted on earlier this week. Let’s consider what happens when someone contracts Covid-19. Some people don’t show symptoms, others die. Some patients who survive coronavirus suffer from significant and long-term impacts to their health. Spending days and weeks [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/my-thoughts-on-the-new-tier-system/">My Thoughts on the New Tier System</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3000</id>
    <published>2020-12-03T08:46:43Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-03T08:46:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why we need the Online Harms Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/why-we-need-the-online-harms-bill/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Introductory remarks delivered to the 4th meeting of the International Grand Committee on disinformation and data privacy, 2 December 2020 Next year, the UK Parliament will debate a Government Bill to regulate Online Harms and establish that social media companies have a duty of care to their users, which includes the responsibility to act against […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5417</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T20:44:10Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T20:44:10Z</updated>
    <category term="My Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli’s MP and MS statement on Ysgol Gynradd Mynyddygarreg, Kidwelly closure proposal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/llanellis-mp-and-ms-statement-on-ysgol-gynradd-mynyddygarreg-kidwelly-closure-proposal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nia Griffith MP said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We encourage everyone who will be affected by this proposal
put forward by the Plaid Cymru&amp;nbsp;Carmarthenshire County Council Cabinet to
make their voice heard during the consultation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Pupils, parents and staff at the schools, as well as
everyone living nearby, have an important role to play in the future of
education provision in the area and their input will be vital when any decision
is made.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the sort of far-reaching decision which needs
proper community consultation, and a realistic appraisal of the needs in years
to come. There has been a very large number of new houses built relatively
recently on the Mynyddygarrreg side of the by-pass, and full account needs to
be taken of the impact of these new developments on future school numbers. Even
in a couple of years the situation could have changed significantly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Every child deserves the best education and the best start
in life that can be provided.&amp;nbsp; This proposal will impact on many future
generations as well and needs to be considered very carefully by everyone
involved. This consultation needs to be the start of a conversation about
what’s best for children in the area and I hope that the Council will listen to
what local people have to say about it.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lee Waters MS added:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I know this is an issue which the school Governors have
wrestled with for some time and there is clearly a delicate balance to be
struck between maintaining a strong sense of community with a school at its
heart, and allowing children access to the best facilities and a teaching body
with enough capacity to give them the best education.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s important the
Council don’t rush into making any decisions here. I’m particularly concerned
about the impact closing Mynyddygarreg will have on travel patterns. Just at
the moment when we’re trying to help people leave their cars at home more
often, the relocation of educational facilities could have the opposite effect.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue of small
rural schools and their future viability is a really difficult one. I think the
case of Mynyddygarreg is far from settled, so I hope the Council do their
upmost to listen to residents.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposal under consideration is:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discontinue Mynyddygarreg primary at the end of
August 2021.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;From September, all pupils to be registered at Gwenllian
primary, which would operate on both sites and increase its capacity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alter Gwenllian primary&amp;#8217;s catchment area to
include that of the Mynyddygarreg area.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Relocate Gwenllian primary to a new site and
increase its capacity to 210 pupil and 30 nursery places, with the new school
ready in 2023.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The consultation process on the proposal is due to commence
on 11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January 2021 for a period of six weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nia Griffith MP said: “We encourage everyone who will be affected by this proposal put forward by the Plaid Cymru Carmarthenshire County Council Cabinet to make their voice heard during the consultation. Pupils, parents and staff at the schools, as well as everyone living nearby, have an important role to play in the future of education […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7923</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T17:05:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T17:05:17Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>Government should be investing in entrepreneurs, not excluding them from support, MP tells Parliament</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1385756/government-should-be-investing-in-entrepreneurs-not-excluding-them-from-support-mp-tells-parliament"/>
  <updated>2020-12-02T15:24:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1385756/government-should-be-investing-in-entrepreneurs-not-excluding-them-from-support-mp-tells-parliament</id>
  <summary type="text">On the floor of the House of Commons this afternoon, South Lakes MP Tim Farron urged ministers to help small business owners and entrepreneurs who have so far been excluded from the Government's coronavirus financial support schemes.
Speaking during today's debate in Parliament on COVID restrictions, Tim said: "People who have been excluded from support include people who set up their own businesses 18 months ago, directors of very small limited companies, taxi drivers, hairdressers and the like.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the floor of the House of Commons this afternoon, South Lakes MP Tim Farron urged ministers to help small business owners and entrepreneurs who have so far been excluded from the Government's coronavirus financial support schemes.</p>
<p>Speaking during today's debate in Parliament on COVID restrictions, Tim said: <em>"People who have been excluded from support include people who set up their own businesses 18 months ago, directors of very small limited companies, taxi drivers, hairdressers and the like.</em></p>
<p><em>"These are the entrepreneurs we need to build Britain back as we recover from the economic wreckage of the coronavirus.</em></p>
<p><em>"We should be investing in those people, not excluding them and leaving many of them in deep and dangerous debt."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rail Minister: Beverley-York railway ‘has potential’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/rail-minister-beverley-york-railway-has-potential/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/rail-minister-beverley-york-railway-has-potential/graham-lobbying-chris-heaton-harris-rail-minister-for-minster-rail-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-10838"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-10838" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Graham-lobbying-Chris-Heaton-Harris-Rail-Minister-for-Minster-Rail-3-740x555.jpeg" alt="" width="740" height="555" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Graham-lobbying-Chris-Heaton-Harris-Rail-Minister-for-Minster-Rail-3-740x555.jpeg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Graham-lobbying-Chris-Heaton-Harris-Rail-Minister-for-Minster-Rail-3-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Graham-lobbying-Chris-Heaton-Harris-Rail-Minister-for-Minster-Rail-3-1536x1152.jpeg 1536w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Graham-lobbying-Chris-Heaton-Harris-Rail-Minister-for-Minster-Rail-3.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"/></a></p>
<p>Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness and parliamentary sponsor of a bid for funding to help restore the direct rail route from Beverley to York, has said that he remains ‘optimistic’ about the project’s future, despite the proposal being initially turned down by the Government.</p>
<p>Back in June, the MP submitted a bid to restore the 32-mile length of track from Beverley to York to the Department for Transport’s Restoring Your Railway Fund. Billed as an opportunity to reduce traffic along the A1079 – boosting job opportunities and tourism in the area – the project has been rejected at the second funding round.</p>
<p>In total, 111 bids have been submitted by 219 MPs, all of which have been evaluated by a panel chaired by the Rail Minister, Chris Heaton-Harris MP, which also included the Chair of Network Rail, Sir Peter Hendy, and Isabel Dedring – the former London Deputy Mayor for Transport.</p>
<p>Despite this setback, the Rail Minister has described the proposal as having ‘potential’, and there will be an opportunity to strengthen the bid before submitting a revised case to the next round of funding. There remains strong local backing for the scheme in the area with East Riding of Yorkshire, City of York, Hull City and North Yorkshire County Councils all expressing their support, as have York MPs Julian Sturdy and Rachael Maskell and Humber MPs Dame Diana Johnson and David Davis.</p>
<p>Graham said, “This is of course disappointing news, particularly after the hard work of the Minsters Rail Campaign and East Riding Council to work up and submit the bid back in the summer.</p>
<p>“But this is definitely not the end of the line. Support for the project is still there, and there’ll now be opportunities to strengthen our bid and submit an even better case in a future funding round with the help of feedback and workshops from the Government.</p>
<p>“I will continue to do all I can to support this bid as I want to see greater investment into infrastructure in our area.”</p>
<p>Success in the Government fund would mean the Department for Transport covering up to 75% of the costs of carrying out extensive transport and economic studies so that a comprehensive business case can be created. Future funding to develop projects would be subject to agreement of the business case.</p>
<p>The proposed Beverley-York line would branch off the existing Hull-Scarborough route which runs through Beverley, with stops at Market Weighton, Pocklington, Stamford Bridge and Haxby – which has just been successful in the Government’s New Stations Fund.</p>
<p>Graham added, “The most recent census indicated that about a quarter of East Riding residents commute to either Hull or York, so I really think this train service would provide a popular alternative to the congested roads and sparse bus services we have at the minute.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness and parliamentary sponsor of a bid for funding to help restore the direct rail route from Beverley to...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10834</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T14:52:39Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T14:52:39Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beeching"/>
    <category term="Beverley"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="Beverley-York"/>
    <category term="Council"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Jobs"/>
    <category term="Minsters Rail"/>
    <category term="Rail"/>
    <category term="Train"/>
    <category term="Trains"/>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="York"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Lachlan Skinner</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Walker welcomes approval of Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine as Worcestershire moves into Tier 2 restrictions  ]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-welcomes-approval-of-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-as-worcestershire-moves-into-tier-2-restrictions/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2081</id>
		<updated>2020-12-02T13:47:57Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-02T13:47:57Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Coronavirus"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="coronavirus"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Tier 2"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worcester MP, Robin Walker has celebrated the positive news that the UK has become the first country in the world to approve the Pfizer/BioNTech coronavirus vaccine, paving the way for nationwide vaccination, as Worcestershire moves out of national restrictions into Tier 2. The decision made by the UK Regulatory Authority (MHRA) was made with advice from [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-welcomes-approval-of-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-as-worcestershire-moves-into-tier-2-restrictions/"><![CDATA[<p>Worcester MP, Robin Walker has celebrated the positive news that the UK has become the first country in the world to approve the Pfizer/BioNTech coronavirus vaccine, paving the way for nationwide vaccination, as Worcestershire moves out of national restrictions into Tier 2.</p>
<p>The decision made by the UK Regulatory Authority (MHRA) was made with advice from the Commission on Human Medicines, the government&#8217;s independent expert scientific advisory body, after carrying out a rigorous, scientific, and detailed review of all the available data.</p>
<p>The first 800,000 doses will be available in the UK from next week and elderly people in care homes and care home staff have been placed top of the priority list, followed by over-80s and health and care staff.</p>
<p>With regular reviews of the tiered system, Robin is hopeful that the approval of the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine will be a significant step in making restrictions a thing of the past, however recognising the need to ensure that we reduce the impact on people’s lives and on the economy in the meantime by taking a careful approach.</p>
<p>The rate of infection in Worcestershire has been falling in recent weeks and Robin has spoken to Ministerial colleagues to make the point that Worcestershire’s rates are below the England average, which will give the area the best chance to get into a lower tier sooner. The roll-out of mass vaccination will help to provide a pathway for Worcestershire to move into Tier 1.</p>
<p>As well as the positive news of the approval of the vaccine, Robin is pleased that the Government has taken on-board some of the lessons of earlier approaches which needed to be reviewed, such as the 10pm curfew and the closure of gyms &amp; pools and adjusted the tiers accordingly. He has consistently pressed for support to ensure that as many people as possible keep their jobs and livelihoods and Robin will continue to do so.</p>
<p>Speaking after the news of the vaccine approval, Robin said:</p>
<p>“I strongly welcome the news that the Pfizer/BioNTech coronavirus vaccine has been approved for roll out starting next week. It is a phenomenal step forward and a moment the UK should be extremely proud of. It is a testament to the UK’s scientific expertise and commitment to produce this vaccine.”</p>
<p>“I voted for the tiered system yesterday because I think it is the best-balanced approach to support lives and livelihoods for the time being and to prepare for the roll out of vaccines and mass testing which will hopefully take us out of this situation entirely.”</p>
<p>“Hospital admissions tend to trail the peak of infections by about two weeks so whilst it is welcome news that the number of covid-19 infections has been falling locally for the last couple of weeks, it is sadly the case that the number of people in hospital with covid-19 has remained high over this period and is now higher at 82 than it was one or two weeks ago. This has been a key factor for me in accepting that a position in tier 2 is justified for Worcester at this stage.”</p>
<p>“The Opposition’s approach of abstaining on the vote in the Chamber rather than proposing any alternative shows a complete lack of conviction and whilst I respect many of the colleagues who have decided to vote against the measures for one reason or another, I note none of them have proposed a viable alternative. Governments do not have the luxury of sitting on the side lines and commenting, they must take decisions and recognise that those decisions have consequences. I can assure you that I have thought through the consequences of mine.”</p>
<p>“As the Prime Minister rightly said this morning, it is the protection of vaccines that will ultimately allow us to reclaim our lives and get our economy moving again.”</p>
<p>A Department of Health and Social Care spokesperson said:</p>
<p>“The government has today accepted the recommendation from the independent Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) to approve Pfizer/BioNTech’s COVID-19 vaccine for use. This follows months of rigorous clinical trials and a thorough analysis of the data by experts at the MHRA who have concluded that the vaccine has met its strict standards of safety, quality and effectiveness.”</p>
<p>“The Joint Committee on Vaccinations and Immunisations (JCVI) will shortly publish its final advice for the priority groups to receive the vaccine, including care home residents, health and care staff, the elderly and the clinically extremely vulnerable.”</p>
<p>“The vaccine will be made available across the UK from next week. The NHS has decades of experience in delivering large-scale vaccination programmes and will begin putting their extensive preparations into action to provide care and support to all those eligible for vaccination.”</p>
<p>“To aid the success of the vaccination programme it is vital everyone continues to play their part and abide by the necessary restrictions in their area so we can further suppress the virus and allow the NHS to do its work without being overwhelmed.”</p>
<p>MHRA Chief Executive Dr June Raine said:</p>
<p>“We have carried out a rigorous scientific assessment of all the available evidence of quality, safety and effectiveness. The public’s safety has always been at the forefront of our minds – safety is our watchword.”</p>
<p>“I’m really pleased to say that the UK is now one step closer to providing a safe and effective vaccine to help in the fight against COVID-19 – a virus that has affected each and every one of us in some way &#8211; and in helping to save lives.”</p>
<p>“We are globally recognised for requiring high standards of safety, quality and effectiveness for any vaccine. Our expert scientists and clinicians worked tirelessly, around the clock, carefully, scientifically, robustly and rigorously poring over hundreds of pages and tables of data, methodically reviewing the data.”</p>
<p>“Vaccines are the most effective way to prevent infectious diseases. They save millions of lives worldwide.”</p>
<p>ENDS</p>
<p>Notes to editors</p>
<p>For more information on the vaccine approval announcement, please see:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-authorises-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-authorises-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-medicines-regulator-gives-approval-for-first-uk-covid-19-vaccine" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">https://www.gov.uk/government/news/uk-medicines-regulator-gives-approval-for-first-uk-covid-19-vaccine</a></p>
<p>For guidance on Tier 2 restrictions please see:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/tier-2-high-alert" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">https://www.gov.uk/guidance/tier-2-high-alert</a></p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-welcomes-approval-of-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-as-worcestershire-moves-into-tier-2-restrictions/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/walker-welcomes-approval-of-pfizer-biontech-covid-19-vaccine-as-worcestershire-moves-into-tier-2-restrictions/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 Tier Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2020/12/02/covid-19-tier-restrictions/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Yesterday (01/12/20), Parliament was presented with a simple, for or against, choice to vote on the renewed ‘Tier’ restrictions which have subsequently come into place this morning and the additional financial support package on offer to businesses, workers and households across Gateshead and the North East.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I wanted to take some time to explain my position on this matter and why I voted against the imposition of this package yesterday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>At the outset, I absolutely agree with experts here in Gateshead and Nationally that we must prevent the spread of Covid-19 throughout our communities.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>I also agree that the best way to do this is through limiting social interaction especially among meetings of multiple households.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The package of restrictions are not perfect, they appear to be ever more complicated and the allocation of tiers to different regions appears to be unequal at first glance, with areas in the North and North East subjected to greater levels of restrictions compared to other parts of the UK with similar or higher rates of incidence of Covid-19.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>To this end, I have formally requested the Government publish the criteria used and set out some clarity on how regions will move between tiers while we await the rollout of a number of vaccine programmes.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The restrictions in place since the spring, closing large numbers of businesses across Gateshead and limiting the trade of so many others, have had an incredibly damaging impact on the lives and livelihoods and overall wellbeing of so many people.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The Government has a duty and the means to provide proper financial support to these businesses and their employees, and to this end, I firmly believe they have failed. While the initial business rate grant scheme and the furlough scheme seemed generous, many millions of people have been left without any support whatsoever and continue to be ignored 9 months on.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>In addition, businesses in Gateshead which have either had to remain closed or have been once again forced to close – hospitality, fitness suites and retail particularly – alongside many self employed workers; have been left with meagre amounts of support, if any, as many businesses enter what would traditionally be their busiest trading period.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The Government appear to have prioritised funnelling billions of pounds of tax payer money into, sometimes selective, elements of the private sector to provide inadequate PPE and an ineffective test, track and trace system. Instead, they should be prioritising financial support for businesses, employees and families affected.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>Failure to do so has not only had a detrimental impact on the health and wellbeing of so many people, but it has had a detrimental impact on adherence to the restrictions. The Government must understand that many people can not work from home and do not have ready access to utilities and food, and many can not afford to withstand repeated periods of self isolation without proper financial support – Statutory Sick Pay is simply totally inadequate.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>Notwithstanding the urgent need to restrict the spread of Covid-19, I voted against the motion yesterday evening, as I firmly believe the Government can and must do more to provide adequate financial support for every person and business affected.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I have raised the inadequate financial support with the Government since the spring and will continue to do so until they meet their responsibility in full.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">Now that the North East is officially subject to tier 3 restrictions, I would urge all residents to follow the rules closely, as this is the only way we can reduce the spread of the virus enough to move down the tier system. With our infection rates declining, because of everyone’s efforts and with positive news of vaccinations in the very near future, it is imperative that we all do whatever we can to further drive down the spread of Covid-19.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I hope this sets out my view clearly, however, if you have any further questions please do contact my office.</span></p>
<p>Stay safe,</p>
<p>Ian Mearns MP</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday (01/12/20), Parliament was presented with a simple, for or against, choice to vote on the renewed ‘Tier’ restrictions which have subsequently come into place this morning and the additional</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20754</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:10:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:10:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Ians votes"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Covid-19 Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/statement-covid-19-restrictions" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The move from national lockdown to the tier system is going to continue to see many people living under very severe restrictions. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/statement-covid-19-restrictions" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5016 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T09:03:47Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T09:03:47Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Press release: The PM is misleading us about how much he really knows about Covid-19 transmission.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/press-release-the-pm-is-misleading-us-about-how-much-he-really-knows-about-covid-19-transmission/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah: “the PM is misleading us about how much he really knows about Covid-19 transmission.”&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the news that Newcastle will be placed in Tier 3 restrictions, Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah has written to the PM accusing him of misleading her in how much he knows about COVID-19 transmission in Newcastle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chi Said: &lt;em&gt;In October I asked the prime minister, in an oral question, if he knew where transmission was occurring in Newcastle, he said he did, so I then addressed three written questions to ministers &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;to find out what they knew. The final question was eventually answered on Friday, over six weeks after I asked, and the responses to all three show that no, they do not know where transmission is occurring in Newcastle. Is it in bars or shops? Is it in the student community or front line workers?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It is important that we do everything we can to crush the rate of transmission of COVID-19. But the Government need to come clean with us about what they really know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The data the government is using to impose Tier 3 restrictions on Newcastle is from the 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; of November, when data leading up to the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; shows a marked decrease in Newcastle’s infection rate&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;em&gt;Why does it take them so long to process and collect the data?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“In summary the, the government don’t know where COVID-19 is transmitted, are using old data, and are misleading the country on how much they know.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Today, I am asking the Prime Minister: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why did he pretend he knew where transmission was occurring in Newcastle?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why won’t they judge us on up to date data?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why don&amp;#8217;t they give resources and data to local authorities who know local communities?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video of Oral Question to the PM: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1315939403219509248"&gt;https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1315939403219509248&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to written questions from Chi Onwurah MP to the Department of Health and Social Care:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-07-09/71760"&gt;https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-07-09/71760&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-10-12/102074"&gt;https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-10-12/102074&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-10-13/102802"&gt;https://questions-statements.parliament.uk/written-questions/detail/2020-10-13/102802&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah: “the PM is misleading us about how much he really knows about Covid-19 transmission.”   Following the news that Newcastle will be placed in Tier 3 restrictions, Newcastle Central MP Chi Onwurah has written to… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10674</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T13:56:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T13:56:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Correspondence"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I won’t be voting for Government restrictions today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/NzcI-YaqHgI/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4760</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T13:01:38Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T13:01:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cymorth £340m ar gyfer busnesau Cymru wrth i’r rheolau coronafeirws newydd gael eu cyhoeddi</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/cymorth-ps340m-ar-gyfer-busnesau-cymru-wrth-ir-rheolau-coronafeirws-newydd-gael-eu-cyhoeddi" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mae Mark Drakeford, y Prif Weinidog, wedi cyhoeddi set o gyfyngiadau newydd wedi’u targedu ar gyfer y sectorau lletygarwch a hamdden yn ogystal â phecyn cymorth gwerth £340m.
Mae’r mesurau newydd yn cael eu cyflwyno wrth i achosion o’r coronafeirws gyflymu yng Nghymru unwaith yn rhagor, gan erydu’r…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/cymorth-ps340m-ar-gyfer-busnesau-cymru-wrth-ir-rheolau-coronafeirws-newydd-gael-eu-cyhoeddi</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>£11m for Borders self employed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/ps11m-borders-self-employed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">New statistics reveal that self-employed Borderers have benefitted from the UK Government income support scheme to the tune of almost £11m.
The Self-Employed Income Support Scheme was announced at the beginning of the coronavirus pandemic to go alongside the furlough scheme for employees to help…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/ps11m-borders-self-employed</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RELEASE: MP praises CAB for their Fair Delivery Charges campaign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-mp-praises-citizens-advice-bureau-for-their-local-fair-delivery-charges-campaign/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=release-mp-praises-citizens-advice-bureau-for-their-local-fair-delivery-charges-campaign" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Highland MP, Drew Hendry has praised the Inverness, Badenoch &amp; Strathspey Citizens Advice Bureau and Nairn Citizens Advice Bureau for their local Fair Delivery Charges campaign; which seeks to raise awareness of the detriment caused to local people by delivery surcharging and the lack of transparency around the use of surcharges. The campaign led by Citizens Advice Scotland also seeks to promote the Scottish Government’s ‘Fairer Deliveries for All’ map tool, which allows consumers to explore delivery prices charged by different companies and create a more transparent system.</p>
<p>With online shopping rates growing by 129% in the U.K. during the pandemic, there is a real shift in how consumers are purchasing goods. However, consumers living in affected Highland areas still pay an average of 30-50% more for receiving items bought online than in the rest of the mainland UK. Further analysis carried out by the Scottish Government in 2019 found that consumers in Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch &amp; Strathspey paid over £7,000,000 in delivery surcharges, relative to the rest of the UK.</p>
<p>Mr Hendry has long campaigned against rip-off delivery charges and previously took a fairer delivery charges bill to the UK Parliament as part of his campaign to end excess delivery charges to rural areas. He also helped the Highland Council launch the national reporting tool it spearheaded as part of the ongoing work to end rip of delivery charges <a href="http://www.deliverylaw.uk/">http://www.deliverylaw.uk/</a>.  The SNP MP praises the CAB for their renewed efforts to support ongoing work to highlight the unfairness of excess delivery charges.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mr Hendry said:</p>
<p>“Every one of us living in the Highlands is familiar with the problem of unfair delivery charges; whether it’s surcharges being added to deliveries, or simply no delivery option available, despite offering delivery to mainland UK.</p>
<p>“Whilst I would always urge folk to support local where they can, we all know this is not always possible and consumers should not have to pay the price for companies shortcomings.</p>
<p>“I am pleased to see our local Citizens Advice teams prioritising this campaign and I would urge everyone in the Highlands to get behind it too, to raise awareness of ongoing unfair delivery surcharging faced by folk in the North of Scotland.”</p>
<p>“For my part, I will continue to press the UK government for legislation to end unfair delivery charges and take on companies charging constituents outrageous delivery charges. We can all play our part by reporting instances of excessive delivery charges at deliverylaw.uk, and folk can also make use of the Scottish Government’s Fairer Deliveries For All tool at <a href="https://fairdeliveries.scot/explore-your-postcode">https://fairdeliveries.scot/explore-your-postcode.”</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at<a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com"> www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-mp-praises-citizens-advice-bureau-for-their-local-fair-delivery-charges-campaign/">RELEASE: MP praises CAB for their Fair Delivery Charges campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Highland MP, Drew Hendry has praised the Inverness, Badenoch &amp; Strathspey Citizens Advice Bureau and...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/release-mp-praises-citizens-advice-bureau-for-their-local-fair-delivery-charges-campaign/">RELEASE: MP praises CAB for their Fair Delivery Charges campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5615</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T15:40:03Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-30T15:40:03Z</updated>
    <category term="Community"/>
    <category term="Delivery Charges"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-98" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last Wednesday, the Chancellor of the Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, set out the 2020 Spending Review. Given that we find ourselves in the middle of a pandemic, it is quite right that much of the focus was on supporting businesses and individuals through Covid-19 and our recovery the other side.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-98</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid Statement 26/11/20</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/30/test-trace-isolate-support/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today I asked the UK Secretary of State for Health a series of questions about the UK Government&amp;#8217;s response to the Covid crisis; specifically, the suitability of the new tier approach to restrictions in England and how much support is being made available for Covid contacts to isolate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A recent King&amp;#8217;s College study found the vast majority of Covid contacts are failing to isolate. Failing to improve the existing &amp;#8216;test, trace, isolate&amp;#8217; strategy risks limiting progress in suppressing new Covid cases.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He also completely ignored my question about the logic of allowing 1000 people at indoor events in high risk areas in England from next week. With only 15 allowed to attend weddings, it is hard to grasp the logic of this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the statement here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AUa_zUJIFRg"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AUa_zUJIFRg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="26/11 Covid Statement" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/AUa_zUJIFRg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many scientists have expressed concern that the easing of restrictions at Christmas could lead to another surge of&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;covid&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;cases in January. With cases still over 80% of the level at the start of lockdown, is the Secretary of State not worried that allowing outdoor events of 2,000 participants and indoor events of 1,000 in level 2 high-risk areas could drive up infection rates ahead of Christmas? Although lateral flow testing is very welcome, given how it increases capacity, the Secretary of State previously stated that the mass testing in Liverpool was a pilot and would be evaluated before being rolled out elsewhere. As the city has also been under tight restrictions and then lockdown, how will the impact of mass testing alone be evaluated? How does he plan to counter the lower uptake among deprived communities—the very ones at highest risk, as seen in Liverpool—and with no clinical evaluation yet published, how can he justify putting out contract tenders for an eye-watering £43 billion and rolling out this approach to 67 other areas? Should this strategy not be compared with investing money and energy in getting the traditional test, trace and isolate system working properly? Currently, over 40% of contacts in England are still not even informed that they should be isolating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Secretary of State knows that it is not testing, but isolation, that stops the spread of the virus. If people who are infected or could be carriers are not isolating, no amount of testing will stop viral spread. A study by King’s College London that suggested that fewer than a quarter were isolating when advised was incredibly worrying, so what assessment are the Government doing to clarify current isolation rates and understand the reasons why people may not follow the advice they are given?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt Hancock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, we are constantly evaluating the impact of people isolating, and how many people isolate when asked to. I would encourage the hon. Lady to look at a broader range of studies than just that one from King’s College, especially those dealing with the self-isolation of those who test positive, for whom the rate tends to be higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hon. Lady asked about the use of these lateral flow tests to have a negative impact on the number of cases in an area. Of course, we have been evaluating this all the way through the study in Liverpool, which is why we can have confidence in rolling out more broadly across tier 3 areas. I included in my statement a high-level assessment of this. The number of cases in Liverpool city region is down by two thirds, but in the city itself, where the testing took place—the testing was of people who live in the city and of people who work in the city and live largely in the wider city region—the number of cases is down by over three quarters. That is one piece of evidence. It is clear that it is the combination of people following the rules and community testing, with appropriate incentives to get people to take up that mass community testing, that can help to make this work. We want to work with local directors of public health to understand how this can work effectively in their areas, precisely to reach those hard-to-reach people whom the hon. Lady mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I echo the hon. Lady’s request that we be cautious this Christmas. However, I am delighted that we have agreed an approach across the whole UK, including with the SNP Administration in Edinburgh, with the Welsh Labour Administration and the cross-party Administration in Northern Ireland, because there are so many ties that bind us together and mean that we are stronger as one United Kingdom, working together to tackle this virus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F11%2F30%2Ftest-trace-isolate-support%2F&amp;#038;title=Covid%20Statement%2026%2F11%2F20" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/30/test-trace-isolate-support/" data-a2a-title="Covid Statement 26/11/20"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/30/test-trace-isolate-support/"&gt;Covid Statement 26/11/20&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Today I asked the UK Secretary of State for Health a series of questions about ... <a title="Covid Statement 26/11/20" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/30/test-trace-isolate-support/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/11/30/test-trace-isolate-support/">Covid Statement 26/11/20</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=1948</id>
    <published>2020-11-30T11:21:32Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-30T11:21:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Health, Wellbeing, &amp; Social Justice"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="Financial-Support"/>
    <category term="Lockdown"/>
    <category term="Testing"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tier 2 Lockdown Rules</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2020/tier-2-lockdown-rules/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tier-2-lockdown-rules" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;From the 2nd of December Hampshire will be in Tier 2, this means:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;you must not socialise with anyone you do not live with or who is not in your support bubble in any indoor setting, whether at home or in a public place&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you must not socialise in a group of more than 6 people outside, including in a garden or a public space&amp;nbsp;– this is called the ‘rule of 6’&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;businesses and venues can continue to operate, in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/working-safely-during-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;COVID-Secure&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;manner, other than those which remain closed by law, such as nightclubs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;pubs and bars must close, unless operating as restaurants. Hospitality venues can only serve alcohol with substantial meals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;hospitality businesses selling food or drink for consumption on their premises are required to:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;provide table service only, in premises which sell alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;close between 11pm and 5am (hospitality venues in airports, ports, transport services and motorway service areas are exempt)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;stop taking orders after 10pm&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;hospitality businesses and venues selling food and drink for consumption off the premises can continue to do so after 10pm as long as this is through delivery service, click-and-collect or drive-through&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;early closure (11pm) applies to casinos, cinemas, theatres, museums, bowling alleys, amusement arcades, funfairs, theme parks, adventure parks and activities, and bingo halls. Cinemas, theatres and concert halls can stay open beyond 11pm in order to conclude performances&amp;nbsp; that start before 10pm&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;public attendance at outdoor and indoor events (performances and shows) is permitted, limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;public attendance at spectator sport and business events can resume inside and outside, subject to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae"&gt;social contact rules&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;places of worship remain open but you must not socialise with people from outside of your household or support bubble while you are indoors there, unless a legal exemption applies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;weddings and funerals can go ahead with restrictions on numbers of attendees – 15 people can attend wedding ceremonies and receptions, 30 people can attend funeral ceremonies, and 15 people can attend linked commemorative events such as wakes&amp;nbsp; or stonesettings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;organised outdoor sport, and physical activity and exercise classes can continue&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;organised indoor sport, physical activity and exercise classes will only be permitted if it is possible for people to avoid mixing with people they do not live with (or share a support bubble with). There are exceptions for indoor disability sport, sport for educational purposes and supervised sport and physical activity for under-18s, which can take place with larger groups mixing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you can continue to travel to venues or amenities which are open, but should aim to reduce the number of journeys you make where possible&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;if you live in a tier 2 area, you must continue to follow tier 2 rules when you travel to a tier 1 area. Avoid travel to or overnight stays in tier 3 areas other than where necessary, such as for work, education, youth services, to receive medical treatment, or because of caring responsibilities.You can travel through a tier 3 area as a part of a longer journey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;for international travel see the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice"&gt;travel advice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for your destination and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-travel-corridors"&gt;travel corridors list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From the 2nd of December Hampshire will be in Tier 2; find out what this means here.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2819</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T21:50:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T21:50:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 27 November</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Yesterday, the Government announced that South Yorkshire will be in Tier 3 restrictions from 2 December. I’ve been clear that we must not stay there a moment longer than we have to, which is why I’m pushing for a clear roadmap out of restrictions and for fairer economic support package for our residents and businesses. This week’s Spending Review was a golden opportunity to provide that immediate support; deliver on the Government’s manifesto commitment to level up the North of England; and reward those workers who have kept our country going. It was an opportunity that the Chancellor failed to take.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Amber Valley &amp; Derbyshire Tier update from the 2nd December 2020]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3042</id>
		<updated>2020-11-26T17:01:51Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-26T16:53:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2nd December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2<sup>nd</sup> December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. Cases for the week to 20 November were 367, down from 580 the week before. This equates to 274 cases per 100,000 well above the national average. The local area of Openwoodgate and Holbrook with a rate of cases of nearly 600 per 100,000 was the 4<sup>th</sup> highest area in England. The overall average for Derbyshire was 248 cases per 100,000, and England 217. The decision by the Government was based on this data plus the relatively high level of cases in the over 60s and the occupation levels of local hospitals.</p>
<p>The move into tier 3 means that from Wednesday 2 December non-essential shops can re-open along with personal care providers like hairdressers and barbers. Indoor and outdoor leisure activities can resume but groups and classes cannot take place indoors. You can meet in groups of up to 6 in outdoor public spaces like parks, but not meet in private gardens or indoors. Sadly pubs and restaurants cannot reopen. The full details are available on the Gov.UK site as are the details of support for businesses affected by these restrictions.</p>
<p>The Tier 3 decision will be reviewed again in 2 weeks’ time. If the recent fall in the number of cases continues then there is a good chance the county can be moved into Tier 2 before Christmas allowing us all some more freedoms, and enabling hospitality venues to open.</p>
<p>I would like to thank everyone who has obeyed the rules during lockdown helping bring about the substantial reduction in cases last week. I would urge everyone  to stick to the rules  for the rest of the lockdown and then the tier 3 rules afterwards so that we can get the virus under control locally and left more restrictions in a couple of weeks’ time.</p>
<p>You can find the rules in full for tier 3 <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know#what-tiers-mean">here</a> and you can still register for my zoom residents&#8217; meeting at 7.30pm on Friday (27th November 2020) by emailing nigel.mills.mp@parliament.uk.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Epidemiological predictions – Analysis of prior model failure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2020/11/epidemiological-predictions-analysis-of-prior-model-failure/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Epidemiological predictions – Analysis of prior model failure, a presentation provided to ministers on 26 November 2020 further to this report: Summary of methodological issues in epidemiology, all by Mike Hearn, plan99.net.</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18318</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T14:23:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T14:23:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Technology"/>
    <category term="Ideas"/>
    <category term="Liberty"/>
    <category term="Modelling"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett backs Chancellor’s package to deal with economic emergency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-chancellors-package-deal-economic-emergency" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Vice Chairman of the Conservative Party, has strongly endorsed the Chancellor of the Exchequer’s Spending Review 2020, which aims to deliver on the peoples' priorities. “The emphasis on jobs, infrastructure and economic growth, as well…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-chancellors-package-deal-economic-emergency</id>
    <published>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-26T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CHRISTMAS GUIDANCE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Scottish Government has agreed a cautious and limited relaxation of the rules on household meetings to support people over the Christmas period. First Minister Nicola Sturgeon stressed it is clear that there is a risk inherent in any relaxation … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/christmas-guidance/">CHRISTMAS GUIDANCE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Martin Docherty-Hughes</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1470708</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T15:42:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T15:42:40Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter on Israeli-Palestinian Peace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/letter-on-israeli-palestinian-peace/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following Catherine’s debate in Parliament last week making the case for an international fund for Israeli-Palestinian Peace, she has written to Minister James Cleverly. The UK has a chance to seize this crucial opportunity to support multilateral efforts to advance peace in the Middle East. Text of letter: Rt Hon James Cleverly MP Minister of … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/letter-on-israeli-palestinian-peace/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Letter on Israeli-Palestinian Peace</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=6999</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T15:15:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T15:15:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="peace fund"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated
announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce
the spread of Covid-19 in England.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed
once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to
ensure we keep people safe and well. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is vital that careful consideration is given
to ensuring the right areas are placed in the right tiers. While we welcome the
way the three tiers recognise that different areas require different approaches
to managing the virus, we believe that Nottingham City Council is uniquely
placed to understand the best interests of its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last month, Nottingham was placed in tier 2 before being
stepped up to tier 3, alongside our partners in the neighbouring
Nottinghamshire County Council. At that time, we had one of the highest rates
of Covid-19 in the country. Since then, we have seen a significant and
sustained reduction in the rate of Covid-19 in Nottingham City, with 40
consecutive days of falling Covid cases and counting. We now sit below the
national average for rates per 100,000 population and are ranked 121&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;
Lower Tier Local Authority nationally. I’m sure you would agree this is a
dramatic and impressive turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our rate is now 50 per cent lower than when we were last
placed into tier 3. We believe our sustained lower rate of Covid-19 should be
reflected in the way Nottingham is allocated a tier this time around.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our fall in cases of Covid-19 is a reflection of the hard
work which has taken place, along with neighbouring councils, the police,
businesses and our city’s two universities – as well as with the local NHS. All
organisations have united in a shared response to reducing the spread of the
virus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also, of course, attributable to the efforts of our
local communities, and their support in adhering to the guidelines and
restrictions in place. We feel that people in Nottingham have worked hard to
bring down the rate of Covid-19 in our communities and among our older
population – and that our position in the tier system should reflect this
decrease.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We know that ongoing restrictions will continue to have a
significant impact on our businesses, our hospitality sector and our
communities. It is vital the right decisions are made for our city.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We would like the opportunity to build on Nottingham’s
successful partnership work in a way that allows us more freedom to reopen key
parts of our economy: to keep restaurants and indoor entertainment venues open
and to ensure our city can begin to reopen in a way that is safe, supported and
protected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would welcome the opportunity to discuss this further.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;br&gt;Cllr David Mellen&lt;br&gt;Leader, Nottingham City Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/"&gt;Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Prime Minister, I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce the spread of Covid-19 in England. It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2569</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Big Spending Boost for Defence!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/big-spending-boost-for-defence/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last week’s announcement of an additional £16.5 billion boost for defence represents the biggest spending boost for our Armed Forces for more than 30-years.</p>
<p>This will result in 10,000 new jobs a year, it will help revitalise UK shipbuilding, help the UK to become a world leader in cyber and space as well as allowing us to invest more resources in research and development.</p>
<p>Our Armed Forces do a tremendous job from keeping us safe to assisting with humanitarian operations. Their sense of duty and their professionalism is an example to us all and this additional support for defence spending is very welcomed news.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week’s announcement of an additional £16.5 billion boost for defence represents the biggest spending boost for our Armed Forces for more than 30-years. This will result in 10,000 new jobs a year, it will help revitalise UK shipbuilding, help the UK to become a world leader in cyber and space as well as allowing […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3474</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T11:28:28Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T11:28:28Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We’re halfway there, so well done</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>As we approach the halfway point of the Government’s nationwide lockdown, I want to thank constituents and businesses for abiding by the new restrictions.</p>
<p>The Government has lost control of the virus, and my first duty is to keep my constituents safe. That is why I voted for the lockdown. Nobody voted for the regulations with anything but a heavy heart. I did not come into Parliament to restrict people’s freedoms.</p>
<p>This period must be used to undertake the transfer of test and trace to local public health departments, including a full resource transfer. In addition, the Government must ensure that the NHS and social care are fully prepared with adequate PPE, as high as possible uptake of flu vaccinations and regular testing regimes.</p>
<p>I have proposed measures to protect the clinically vulnerable and providing ‘supportive shielding’ so that people don’t experience the devastating isolation that happened last time. We must also make sure we have simple, coherent messaging with local community engagement as well as monitoring and enforcement capacity to support people complying during the lockdown.</p>
<p>Local restrictions have had a devastating effect on people living in care homes and their families.  As co-Chair of the APPG on Dementia I have received heart-breaking stories from Oldhamers, unable to visit their loved ones for months on end, and who have seen a marked deterioration in their condition, particularly for those living with dementia.</p>
<p>I secured a Westminster Hall debate on the impact of coronavirus on people living with dementia, their families and carers last week, where I challenged the Minister on these issues. I pressed the Minister to report back to Parliament on her trial of visitor testing which starts on 16<sup>th</sup> November in 30 care homes, with the intention of rolling out testing for visitors across the country in December.  It is essential that family members are able to safely visit their loved ones in care homes, especially as we approach Christmas.</p>
<p>I have also been challenging the Government on how they’ve been awarding Covid-related contracts. Billions of pounds of public money has been awarded to private companies often with no experience in delivering medical supplies. The Government’s repeated refusal to come clean about where this public money has left no option but to compel the Government to come clean through the courts. This is why I partnered with Caroline Lucas MP, Layla Moran MP and the Good Law Project in legal action to force the Government to publish details of private covid and PPE related contracts.</p>
<p>Whilst we recognise that at the beginning of the pandemic we needed to move quickly, this does not justify the Government’s wholesale disregard for transparency including the publication of contracts awarded. The Government has now disclosed that at least £17 billion worth of Covid-19 contracts have been awarded by the Department of Health and Social Care since April, with over £4 billion of these contracts being hidden. The transparency gap is therefore growing.</p>
<p>I am pleased that last week the High Court granted our judicial review to challenge the Government’s persistent failure to publish these contracts. The hearing is scheduled for mid-January 2021 and I’ll keep you informed of our progress.</p>
<p>Do look after yourselves and stay safe.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/">We’re halfway there, so well done</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/were-halfway-there-so-well-done/">We’re halfway there, so well done</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6722</id>
    <published>2020-11-20T12:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-20T12:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Activities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/update-activities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I take no pleasure in the downfall of anyone but I am pleased that Mr Cummings has left Downing Street. His behaviour over a trip north to Durham and visit to Barnard Castle apparently caused a major rift in relations between himself and the Prime Minister. At the time I thought it unacceptable and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/update-activities</id>
    <published>2020-11-20T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Joins Advisory Board of the John Mills Institute for Prosperity</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-joins-advisory-board-of-the-john-mills-institute-for-prosperity/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2930" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1.jpg 1024w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1-980x490.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/ELB-John-Mills-institute-1-1-480x240.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;span class="has-inline-color has-very-dark-gray-color"&gt;Earlier this month I was delighted to be personally invited by renowned businessman, entrepreneur and philanthropist, John Mills to join the advisory board of his new Institute for Prosperity recently. The nine person advisory board is made up of a group of cross-party MPs, former MPs and Peers. All of whom have Ministerial or Shadow Ministerial experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Institute was set up earlier this year by Mr Mills who is also the founder and Chairman of South Shields based consumer goods company JML, which sells high-volume consumer products in the UK and 85 countries worldwide.&amp;nbsp;The Institute’s aim is to increase prosperity, growth and equality by putting a more successful economic future at the heart of British political discourse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;South Shields, like many towns across the country have been decimated by lack of investment and deindustrialisation and many have been forgotten by successive governments. Growing up I watched this powerful and prosperous industrious town slowly wither and as a result 100’s of skilled jobs, like that of my fathers disappeared too along with much needed investment. So, I am delighted to work alongside John and parliamentary colleagues to do all we can to find a consensus, to provide a platform to bring people with fresh ideas together and to find new solutions to Britain’s economic problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Earlier this month I was delighted to be personally invited by renowned businessman, entrepreneur and philanthropist, John Mills to join the advisory board of his new Institute for Prosperity recently. The nine person advisory board is made up of a group of cross-party MPs, former MPs and Peers. All of whom have Ministerial or Shadow […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2020-11-19T14:30:14Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-19T14:30:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ashfield MP says track and trace was 'first class' for him - and the Prime Minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week, I was delighted to have had breakfast with the Prime Minister in Downing Street where we spoke about my hopes for Ashfield and Eastwood.
It was a productive meeting and I am confident that this Government will deliver the investment our area has been crying out for now for decades.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister</id>
    <published>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Libraries</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Really pleased to see this news, especially for Bradford on Avon and Melksham. Libraries are more important than ever as many of us will be spending more time at home this month. Thank you to all the staff involved who are making this possible!</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/">https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/">Libraries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Really pleased to see this news, especially for Bradford on Avon and Melksham. Libraries are more important than ever as many of us will be spending more time at home this month. Thank you to all the staff involved who are making this possible! https://www.gazetteandherald.co.uk/news/18850551.wiltshire-libraries-support-residents-lockdown/</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/libraries/">Libraries</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33829</id>
    <published>2020-11-15T15:55:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-15T15:55:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Wiltshire Council"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - Businesses, small and large </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-businesses-small-and-large" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we all get used to the second lockdown there are difficulties for huge numbers of people, ranging from churchgoers to gym enthusiasts. But my biggest worry is the effect on businesses, as keeping people at work is so important for reasons that go well beyond the economic.
It was timely, then,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-businesses-small-and-large</id>
    <published>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith tells Government ‘the people of the north will hold you to account’ on rebalancing the economy.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning I took part in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanJarvisMP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DanJarvisMP&lt;/a&gt; debate on support for the economy in the North. We need a fundamental rebalancing of our economy after Covid. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this Government to account for their promises and their actions. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iCcp6jNBhp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iCcp6jNBhp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the
economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was
fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s handling of the Covid crisis, and in
particular their approach to local restrictions and regional packages of
financial support, has shown that too often the needs of the North are still an
after-thought or, worse, ignored altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Instead of
establishing a clear and transparent framework of support, proportionate to
need, the Government has employed a strategy of divide and rule.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are now in a national lockdown of course, and the
furlough scheme has been extended until March, but the Government must set out
exactly what will happen at the end of this period. They have indicated we will
go back into the tiered system, but many businesses in Bradford will simply not
survive if we go straight back into tier 2 or 3 with the current level of
support.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the short term, the Government must ensure that whatever
the restrictions are after December 2nd, there is a fair set of financial
support that takes into account how long an area has been under local
restrictions. For each measure, the Government should produce an impact
assessment by region, which includes the impact on regional inequality and the
regional economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the longer term, we need a fundamental rebalancing of our
economy. Levelling up rhetoric and the odd project here and there will not be
enough. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this
Government to account for their promises and their actions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith also called for reform of the Treasury’s ‘Green Book’
which is used to make decisions on Government investment, as it currently
“skews investment and therefore growth into where it already happens, rather
than where it needs to happen”. In response, the Government announced they
would be publishing the revised Green Book at this year’s spending review on
the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, support, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;90&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" alt="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has welcomed the latest proposals for tougher sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving and urges the government to act on them without delay Responding in Parliament, Leader of the House Jacob-Rees Mogg said: " “I thank the hon. Lady for the campaigning she's done on this very&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, judith, will, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/imgID149097243-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" alt="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A version of this article was first published in The Times Ever since I heard Matt Hancock, in a recent interview, extol the virtues of getting seven hours sleep a night through this pandemic, I’ve been thinking about what keeps me awake at night. At the top of my list&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: local, government, support, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;67&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: restrictions, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2359</id>
    <published>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[REMEMBRANCE DAY 2020]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=338</id>
		<updated>2020-11-11T10:44:30Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-11T10:43:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/11/11/remembrance-day-2020/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>‘Remembrance As Vital As Ever’ Says Grant Shapps MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/remembrance-as-vital-as-ever-says-grant-shapps-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=remembrance-as-vital-as-ever-says-grant-shapps-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Ex-RAF Serviceman Steve McNamara Remark on Remembrance Sunday 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional remembrance memorial services have halted by the coronavirus pandemic, preventing gatherings around memorials and cenotaphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps believes that this should not lessen our commitment to remembering those who have died in war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting the Hatfield Memorial Garden, Mr Shapps said: “Today cuts very deep inside really because it makes you recall…the ultimate sacrifice that so many have given to make sure that we have the freedoms that we have today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s so easy to forget what they went through- the horror of it all- so that we could live in peace.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve McNamara, an RAF veteran from Welwyn Garden City with grandfathers who fought in both First and Second World Wars, said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think every generation has historic, cataclysmic events that define them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For this generation, it is probably COVID. It has produced heroes and victims, and I think these will be remembered in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps also spoke of the vital role of the Armed Forces in the battle against the virus:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a Remembrance Sunday like no other, as we battle this coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But the thing to remember is that a lot of the people that we’re here commemorating and thanking, are actually out there serving right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thousands internationally, but also at home in the battle against the virus- for example in Liverpool, helping with mass-testing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps laid a wreath at the Hatfield memorial. He said: “I think in the Armed Forces we have as much to thank today as we ever have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s why Remembrance Sunday- even remembering it slightly differently than usual is so important.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video of the visit was produced, which you can view below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=555&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F1044960589283599%2F&amp;show_text=true&amp;width=560" width="1280" height="1280" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Welwyn Hatfield MP and Ex-RAF Serviceman Steve McNamara Remark on Remembrance Sunday 2020.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30047</id>
    <published>2020-11-08T08:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-08T08:30:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Hatfield Memorial Garden"/>
    <category term="Remembrance Sunday"/>
    <category term="Steve McNamara"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>APPG on Democracy in Burma Statement on Upcoming Elections in Burma</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/appg_on_democracy_in_burma_statement_on_upcoming_burma_elections" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Ahead of Burma's Election later this month, the All-Party Parliamentary Group for Democracy in Burma released the following statement, raising their concerns about the credibility of the elections. </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/appg_on_democracy_in_burma_statement_on_upcoming_burma_elections</id>
    <published>2020-11-04T17:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-04T17:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<figure id="attachment_2049" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2049" style="width: 428px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-2049" src="http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-300x76.png" alt="" width="438" height="111" srcset="http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-300x76.png 300w, http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1-768x195.png 768w, http://karinsmyth.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/Screen-25-10-2019_120259-1.png 905w" sizes="(max-width: 438px) 100vw, 438px"/><figcaption id="caption-attachment-2049" class="wp-caption-text">(Newspaper column as seen in The Pigeon in October 2020)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This month sees the end of the Coronavirus Jobs Retention Scheme, which was put in place at the start of lockdown to avoid mass job losses. It leaves many people in Bristol South facing a very uncertain future.</p>
<p>I, and my Labour colleagues, have been pushing to see the scheme extended for those hardest hit sectors which are still unable to operate properly due to ongoing restrictions. Disappointingly, the Government chose to ignore the calls from us, from business owners, trade unions, think tanks, the cross-party Treasury Select Committee and some of its own MPs; in doing so, it has let down hundreds of thousands of people working in vulnerable industries such as hospitality, leisure, travel and the arts.</p>
<p>Bristol South does not have lots of large employers which can accommodate mass remote working set up. Families across Bristol South rely on paid work with Bristol Airport and in cafes, bars and restaurants as well as the creative sector. It’s home to lots of small businesses, many of which were struggling before the pandemic hit and this has made things a hundred times harder. I’ve heard from local business owners and self-employed people with heartbreaking stories of their family business, in the community for decades employing local people, suddenly facing financial ruin and closure as a result of this pandemic.</p>
<p>The percentage of people claiming unemployment-related benefits in Bristol South has already risen from 3.6% in March to 6.2% this summer, and this is likely to increase further. I’m hearing from lots of people who’ve always worked and have never had to apply for government support before. And it’s hitting women and young people particularly hard. We must act now to avert the biggest jobs crisis of a generation.</p>
<p>The Government announced the launch of a Kickstart scheme to support younger jobseekers in August, but we’re yet to see this in action and there appears to be no job guarantee at the end of it. I welcome the offer of extra paid incentives for businesses taking on new apprentices and would encourage employers in Bristol South to explore this further, but they too will need jobs at the end of their training and, at the moment, there is no guarantee there either.</p>
<p>This piecemeal approach is not enough. We need a national plan for job retention and creation as well as retraining. I will continue lobbying the Government on this and am working on plans for my 2021 jobs and apprenticeships fair to help link local people up with jobs and training opportunities. In the meantime, there is help available locally to support people with job hunting and employability skills, see <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/16/support-for-employers-and-jobseekers/"><strong>here</strong></a> for more details.</p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/" target="_blank">OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The percentage of people claiming unemployment-related benefits in Bristol South has already risen from 3.6% in March to 6.2% this summer, and this is likely to increase further.</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/10/28/opinion-karin-smyth-mp-on-a-rise-in-unemployment-in-bristol-south/" target="_blank">OPINION: Karin Smyth MP on a rise in unemployment in Bristol South</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2810</id>
    <published>2020-10-28T17:10:23Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-28T17:10:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Newspaper Columns"/>
    <category term="newspaper column"/>
    <category term="pigeon"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tories deny free school meals to 2 million children</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/10/22/9045/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Conservative MPs – including all Scots Tories – refuse to back free meals for children in school holidays Yesterday afternoon in the House of Commons, Brendan O’Hara MP led for the SNP in the Opposition Day debate on access to free school meals and called on the UK Government to commit to tackling widespread poverty, […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9045</id>
    <published>2020-10-22T13:31:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-22T13:31:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rubbish dumping survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="caldera-grid" id="caldera_form_1" data-cf-ver="1.9.2" data-cf-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;&lt;div id="caldera_notices_1" data-spinner="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-admin/images/spinner.gif"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;form data-instance="1" class="CF5f8c811d77adc caldera_forms_form cfajax-trigger" method="POST" enctype="multipart/form-data" id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1" data-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc" aria-label="Flytipping on Cotterills Lane" data-target="#caldera_notices_1" data-template="#cfajax_CF5f8c811d77adc-tmpl" data-cfajax="CF5f8c811d77adc" data-load-element="_parent" data-load-class="cf_processing" data-post-disable="0" data-action="cf_process_ajax_submit" data-request="https://liambyrne.co.uk/cf-api/CF5f8c811d77adc" data-hiderows="true"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" id="_cf_verify_CF5f8c811d77adc" name="_cf_verify" value="a6fb810f40"  data-nonce-time="1607017519" /&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_wp_http_referer" value="/feed/" /&gt;&lt;div id="cf2-CF5f8c811d77adc_1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_id" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_ct" value="1"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="cfajax" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_cr_pst" value="7970"&gt;
&lt;div class="hide" style="display:none; overflow:hidden;height:0;width:0;"&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Company&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="text" name="company" value="" autocomplete="off"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-1"  class="row  first_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_949637" class="form-group" id="fld_949637_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_949637Label" for="fld_949637_1" class="control-label"&gt;First name &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_949637" class=" form-control" id="fld_949637_1" name="fld_949637" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_949637Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3720579" class="form-group" id="fld_3720579_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3720579Label" for="fld_3720579_1" class="control-label"&gt;Surname &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_3720579" class=" form-control" id="fld_3720579_1" name="fld_3720579" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_3720579Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_377714" class="form-group" id="fld_377714_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_377714Label" for="fld_377714_1" class="control-label"&gt;Postcode &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_377714" class=" form-control" id="fld_377714_1" name="fld_377714" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_377714Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8339186" class="form-group" id="fld_8339186_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8339186Label" for="fld_8339186_1" class="control-label"&gt;Email &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="email" data-field="fld_8339186" class=" form-control" id="fld_8339186_1" name="fld_8339186" value="" data-type="email" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_8339186Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id="fld_3670460_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8286015" class="form-group" id="fld_8286015_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8286015Label" for="fld_8286015_1" class="control-label"&gt;Has the dumping and littering problem in the area reduced recently?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_8286015" value="" data-field="fld_8286015" class="form-control" id="fld_8286015_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_8286015Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Not Sure"  data-calc-value="Not Sure" &gt;
						Not Sure					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_5317914" class="form-group" id="fld_5317914_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_5317914Label" for="fld_5317914_1" class="control-label"&gt;What further steps would you like to see taken?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;textarea name="fld_5317914" value="" data-field="fld_5317914" class="form-control" id="fld_5317914_1" rows="4"    aria-labelledby="fld_5317914Label" &gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_7237774" class="form-group" id="fld_7237774_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_7237774Label" for="fld_7237774_1" class="control-label"&gt;Would you be willing to join a residents’ group?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_7237774" value="" data-field="fld_7237774" class="form-control" id="fld_7237774_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_7237774Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Maybe"  data-calc-value="Maybe" &gt;
						Maybe					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3572997" class="form-group" id="fld_3572997_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3572997Label" for="fld_3572997_1" class="control-label"&gt;Can Liam email you about news and campaign updates? &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_3572997" value="" data-field="fld_3572997" class="form-control" id="fld_3572997_1"  required="required"  aria-labelledby="fld_3572997Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Liam can email me					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						Liam cannot email me					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_4555323" class=" form-control" id="fld_4555323_1" name="fld_4555323" value="1" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_3061013" class=" form-control" id="fld_3061013_1" name="fld_3061013" value="2020 Oct Flytipping Survey" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;hr id="fld_6111107_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_432351" class="form-group" id="fld_432351_1-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class=""&gt;
	&lt;input  class="btn btn-default" type="submit" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1" value="Submit" data-field="fld_432351"  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;input class="button_trigger_1" type="hidden" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1_btn" value="" data-field="fld_432351"  /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-2"  class="row  last_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/"&gt;Rubbish dumping survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/">Rubbish dumping survey</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=7970</id>
    <published>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Flytipping"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Leisure Centres are a lifeline for so many of us, we can’t let them fail</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/09/30/our-leisure-centres-are-a-lifeline-for-so-many-of-us-we-cant-let-them-fail/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1253</id>
    <published>2020-09-30T10:32:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-09-30T10:32:27Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency News"/>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost 50% of furloughed jobs in the Tees Valley are ‘at risk’]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/09/almost-50-of-furloughed-jobs-in-the-tees-valley-are-at-risk/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13752</id>
		<updated>2020-09-17T09:26:28Z</updated>
		<published>2020-09-17T09:11:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Alex Cunningham condemns government for putting thousands of North East jobs at risk. Latest figures suggest 350,700 jobs in the North East are still fully furloughed – including 81,300 here in the Tees Valley. Of those furloughed roles in the Tees Valley, 36,300, or 45%, are deemed to be at risk when the scheme is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/09/almost-50-of-furloughed-jobs-in-the-tees-valley-are-at-risk/">Almost 50% of furloughed jobs in the Tees Valley are ‘at risk’</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Network Rail is preparing the final stages of delivering step-free access at Garforth Railway Station, it has been announced. </p>
<p>Alec had been campaigning for new step-free access at Garforth for over a decade before finally securing funds direct from the Department for Transport. Alec will continue to work closely, cross-party, with Garforth’s Independent Councillors to represent the views of residents through the planning process. </p>
<p>Announcing the scheme in 2014, the then Transport Secretary Patrick McLoughlin said: “After years of false starts and broken promises under Labour, it is a testament to the local Conservative MP Alec Shelbrooke’s persistent campaigning that I can announce that this scheme is finally happening for the people of Garforth”.</p>
<p>Since 2014 Alec has been in regular contact with Transport officials pushing for firmer plans and no further delays. He also raised the matter several times in the House of Commons Chamber. </p>
<p>But today it has been announced that the final stage before construction is now underway.</p>
<p>Alec said: “Today I’m delighted that Network Rail has formalised a plan with four options for stakeholders to choose from before the submission of a full planning application to Leeds City Council. It is my hope that Leeds City Council can deal with the application swiftly to avoid no further delays”.</p>
<p>“I have been campaigning for step-free access at Garforth Station for many years. We had an original plan submitted but this then incurred unnecessary delays along the way but I have been committed to providing disabled people and pushchair users with the same access to travel as everyone else – and delivering step-free access at Garforth station will help thousands more people travel easily and without additional cost, time or stress”.</p>
<p>Previously, Garforth resident Mrs Morris said: “We’ve waited far too long for disabled access at Garforth. The elderly, disabled and those with pushchairs have not been able to use the station so we’re extremely grateful to Alec for fighting alongside us to deliver this disabled access”. </p>
<p>The Government’s Access for All programme was first launched in 2006 and has delivered more than 200 accessible routes into selected stations so far.</p>
<p>A further 1,500 stations have received smaller scale improvements such as accessible toilets, platform humps to reduce stepping distances and improvements to help those with a visual or hearing impairment.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/">Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Network Rail is preparing the final stages of delivering step-free access at Garforth Railway Station, it has been announced. Alec had been campaigning for new step-free access at Garforth for over a decade before finally securing funds direct from the Department for Transport. Alec will continue to work closely, cross-party, with Garforth’s Independent Councillors to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/" title="ReadGarforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/garforth-railway-station-step-free-access-ready-planning-permission/">Garforth Station – step free access ready for planning permission.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1727</id>
    <published>2020-08-19T16:04:10Z</published>
    <updated>2020-08-19T16:04:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
