<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-02-19T06:33:46Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit wins – change at the Treasury?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/02/19/brexit-wins-change-at-the-treasury/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>We were always told during our time in the EU by its UK advocates that Tax was a reserved matter which stayed under UK control. This was one of many untruths as proponents of the EU sought to play down the extent of the power transferred instead of arguing for a vision of a united Europe where enough power did rest with the centre to allow EU government. The EU required us to legislate for VAT, and set requirements on which items must be taxed and on minimum rates. It started to impose a number of new environmental taxes . It controlled customs duties. It used court decisions to circumscribe company taxation.</p>
<p>The first task must be to re-establish full control over our tax policy, and to make some tax changes that are desirable in themselves and important to show that we have regained control. This government that wishes to be green should take VAT off insulation materials, draught excluder, boiler controls, solar panels and other green goods. Stopped from doing so by the EU, what is now stopping them?  It would be good to remove VAT from domestic fuel all the time the price is so high, to assist with the cost of living crisis.</p>
<p>The government should review rules relating to Corporation tax that have been changed by European Court judgements, and reinstate the tax base Parliament thought it had legislated.</p>
<p>The new Freeports should be given a better offer over Business rates. A Freeport should be created for Northern Ireland. There the Corporation Tax rate should be aligned with the Republic of Ireland at 15% to attract more investment  to the Province.</p>
<p>The Chancellor should review again the economic policy framework. The modifications to the Maastricht debt and deficit controls still leave in place versions of the old debt and deficit rules. These are leading to bad policy to hike the tax rates of NI and Corporation Tax. Instead we need to build the inflation target given to the Bank into the policy requirement of the Treasury, to engage them when the Bank creates too much money and credit as it did again in the later months of 2021.  It should  supplement it with a Growth Target. This would help avoid policy error going for too much austerity. As the last nine months have shown the way to get the deficit down more quickly is to grow faster, not to put up tax rates.We need to cancel the NI rise which is driven by the Maastricht debt criteria.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We were always told during our time in the EU by its UK advocates that Tax was a reserved matter which stayed under UK control. This was one of many untruths as proponents of the EU sought to play down the extent of the power transferred instead of arguing for a vision of a united…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=32267</id>
    <published>2022-02-19T05:07:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-19T05:07:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Times: Cleaning up the City can help stop tanks in Ukraine]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/02/18/the-times-how-the-square-mile-could-help-stop-russian-tanks/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5215</id>
		<updated>2022-02-18T18:04:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-18T08:45:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Anti-Corruption"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Newspaper Articles"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article was written by John Penrose and originally published in The Times The West’s answer to Russian aggression in Ukraine is pretty clear: if you invade Kyiv then it won’t just turn into the kind of guerrilla-war quagmire that exhausted and humiliated you into leaving Afghanistan years ago. We will also make you permanently [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/02/18/the-times-how-the-square-mile-could-help-stop-russian-tanks/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong><em>This article was written by John Penrose and originally published in The Times</em></strong></p>



<p>The West’s answer to Russian aggression in Ukraine is pretty clear: if you invade Kyiv then it won’t just turn into the kind of guerrilla-war quagmire that exhausted and humiliated you into leaving Afghanistan years ago. We will also make you permanently and dramatically poorer, and then hamstring your ability to spend any cash that we’ve missed in our countries afterwards too. For a regime that’s built on a network of favours to oligarchs and cronies who’ve got rich at taxpayers’ expense, being unable to line the pockets of its supporters could be a death knell.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the West’s threats won’t work if Putin doesn’t believe we’re serious, which is why the global financial markets based in the City of London are central to what happens in Ukraine. The square mile is an amazing, brilliant economic asset for Global Britain, but it’s also a magnet for dirty cash. Even if only a tiny fraction of the billions that slosh through the City’s trading floors every day is illicit, it’s still big money. And since the City’s success depends on Britain’s reputation as an honest, rules-based, free-trading country, anything that corrodes our brand is lethal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the we’ve got to close any loopholes that let Putin’s oligarchs – to say nothing of an unsavoury ragbag of kleptocrats robbing other countries blind, and old-fashioned organised crime lords, drug smugglers and gun-runners too – launder their dirty cash through global financial markets and then, once it’s squeaky-clean, buy themselves posh London apartments and go shopping at Harrods.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The most important change is extra transparency, so anyone who owns UK property or controls a British company will have to come clean about who they really are. That will mean anyone in the UK, or in a country like Russia, will be able to ‘follow the money’ back to its source. And if you can follow the money, you can grab it from an oligarch, hitting them where it hurts most – in the wallet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How should we do it? Well the upcoming Economic Crime Bill is essential to plug the legal loopholes which the oligarchs and their lawyers know how to exploit. Plus more sanctions on Russian crooks and companies. And we need to spend a lot more time and money policing online fraud and money transfers because, while our public political debate is still stuck in a 1980s time-warp where everyone ritually demands more ‘bobbies on the beat’, the criminals have moved on. Old fashioned crimes like physically breaking into bank vaults have become quaintly old-fashioned bits of criminal history, so our law-enforcement has to keep up to date too. We need more ‘bobbies behind a screen’, sleuthing on digital highways rather than pounding a physical street.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other words, the West’s threats about Ukraine won’t work unless Putin and his oligarchs know that it won’t be business as usual for them in London. We are eyeball-to-eyeball at the moment and, if we blink, they will conclude that perhaps we Brits weren’t terribly serious about all this in the first place. And then their tanks will be free to roll.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Josh Keeling</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Half term activities]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11654</id>
		<updated>2022-02-18T15:39:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-18T15:39:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="leicester"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Young people"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Abbey"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Braunstone Park and Rowley Fields"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, after dropping into a regular coffee morning at St Patrick&#8217;s Church, Beaumont Leys Lane, Sarah Russell, Liz&#8217;s MP representative whilst she is on maternity leave, visited some of the fantastic activities available to young people during the school half term holidays.&#160;<br />
Sarah visited the Grove, in Braunstone Park, to see a sport and dance camp which has been organised by b-inspired, as well as the Braunstone Adventure Playground.<br />
Last week Sarah also visited a pop-up pantry which provided food for families during the half term holiday. You can read more ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/">Half term activities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/"><![CDATA[<p>This week, after dropping into a regular coffee morning at St Patrick&#8217;s Church, Beaumont Leys Lane, Sarah Russell, Liz&#8217;s MP representative whilst she is on maternity leave, visited some of the fantastic activities available to young people during the school half term holidays.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Sarah visited the Grove, in Braunstone Park, to see a sport and dance camp which has been organised by b-inspired, as well as the Braunstone Adventure Playground.</p>
<p>Last week Sarah also visited a pop-up pantry which provided food for families during the half term holiday. You can read more about that <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-leicestershire-60374321">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-11578" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-drops-into-craft-club/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/sewnso-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz drops into craft club" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-drops-into-craft-club/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz drops into craft club</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-9553" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-woodtsock-primary-school/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Liz-visits-Woodstock-Primary-School--150x150.jpg" alt="Liz visits Woodstock Primary School" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-woodtsock-primary-school/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz visits Woodstock Primary School</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-9515" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-lunch-at-the-oak-centre/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunch-at-the-Oak-Centre-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz joins lunch at the Oak Centre" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-lunch-at-the-oak-centre/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz joins lunch at the Oak Centre</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-9485" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-welcomes-new-safety-outside-belgrave-st-peters-primary-school/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/Liz-visits-Belgrave-St-Peters-for-Aspiration-week-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz welcomes new safety outside Belgrave St Peter&#8217;s Primary School" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-welcomes-new-safety-outside-belgrave-st-peters-primary-school/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz welcomes new safety outside Belgrave St Peter&#8217;s Primary School</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-9423" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tackling-traffic-concerns-at-belgrave-st-peters-school/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/22.jpg" alt="Tackling traffic concerns at Belgrave St Peter&#8217;s School" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tackling-traffic-concerns-at-belgrave-st-peters-school/" class="wp_rp_title">Tackling traffic concerns at Belgrave St Peter&#8217;s School</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/">Half term activities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Stay safe and be careful</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1966-stay-safe-and-be-careful"/>
		<published>2022-02-18T15:35:37+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-18T15:35:37+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1966-stay-safe-and-be-careful</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Stay safe and be careful &lt;a href="https://t.co/C58xLYaIMX"&gt;https://t.co/C58xLYaIMX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1494678315726168069?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Stay safe and be careful &lt;a href="https://t.co/C58xLYaIMX"&gt;https://t.co/C58xLYaIMX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1494678315726168069?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;February 18, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fortnightly e-newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/fortnightly-e-newsletter-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to read my February e-newsletter
I weld yr e-gylchlythyr hwn yn Gymraeg cliciwch yma</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/fortnightly-e-newsletter-0</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Maria visits new building at Ashwood Academy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-visits-new-building-ashwood-academy" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Basingstoke MP, Maria Miller, recently visited the Ashwood Academy, to catch up with Headteacher Dave Moran, and to view the new extension to the school.
 
Maria commented: “I am really glad to visit Ashwood and see the finishing touches being made to a brand new building to expand the teaching…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/maria-visits-new-building-ashwood-academy</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Standing with Ukraine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/standing-ukraine" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">#WeStandWithUkraine 🇬🇧🇺🇦 in the face of hostility from Russia 🇷🇺 and the Prime Minister has stated we will do all we can to de-escalate the situation through dialogue.
Seen here proudly sporting my Ukraine shirt whilst taking the family for a spot of lunch at the excellent The Chequers at Ranby on…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/standing-ukraine</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Ukraine Crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/ukraine-crisis" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I spent many of my early years as an infantry officer being part of the 1st (British) Corps in Berlin and West Germany (see photograph on exercise there). Our mission was to deter a Warsaw Pact invasion of Western Europe and, with the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991, it appears we succeeded.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/ukraine-crisis</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cooper &amp; Jordan School Visit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/cooper-jordan-school-visit/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It was great to make my first return face to face school visit last week, since the start of the Covid-19 pandemic, at the invitation of Cooper and Jordan School in Aldridge.</p>
<p>It was really good to hear first-hand about the topics which the Year 3 groups were undertaking to look at how video games can be used as a way to help us learn in school.  I also saw their creative artwork.</p>
<p>It is a fascinating project, particularly the help that the children are giving one of their classmates who is currently unable to be in school, through the use of an AV1 robot.</p>
<p>I would like to thank all of the pupils, staff and Head Teacher Mr Farquhar for a lovely visit.  Keep up the great project work!</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was great to make my first return face to face school visit last week, since the start of the Covid-19 pandemic, at the invitation of Cooper and Jordan School in Aldridge. It was really good to hear first-hand about the topics which the Year 3 groups were undertaking to look at how video games […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3969</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T11:34:09Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T11:34:09Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE RAISES NESTLE FAWDON CLOSURE IN PARLIAMENT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-raises-nestle-fawdon-closure-in-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Newcastle North MP Catherine McKinnell has raised the devastating closure of Nestle’s Fawdon factory in Parliament. Catherine highlighted the history of the factory, which has provided good quality manufacturing jobs for over half a century, at the site in Fawdon. Speaking during a debate Catherine highlighted the impact of the news, stating that it was … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-raises-nestle-fawdon-closure-in-parliament/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE RAISES NESTLE FAWDON CLOSURE IN PARLIAMENT</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7581</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T10:54:24Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T10:54:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill responds to Herefordshire Council Cabinet Member for Transport and Infrastructure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/02/18/sir-bill-responds-to-herefordshire-council-cabinet-member-for-transport-and-infrastructure/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Cllr Harrington blames Herefordshire’s current pothole issues on austerity.   Roads are devolved to Herefordshire Council who have a statutory responsibility for managing and maintaining their roads as set out in the Highways Act 1980. Between 2020-2022, the Government provided... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/02/18/sir-bill-responds-to-herefordshire-council-cabinet-member-for-transport-and-infrastructure/#more-4233">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4233</id>
    <published>2022-02-18T09:25:24Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-18T09:25:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Proposal for Edinburgh to ask for new city-wide powers to control short term lets</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13417/proposal-for-edinburgh-to-ask-for-new-city-wide-powers-to-control-short-term-lets" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Councillors will be asked to approve a proposal to designate the City of Edinburgh Council area as a short term let (STL) control area at the Planning Committee next week (February 23).</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13417/proposal-for-edinburgh-to-ask-for-new-city-wide-powers-to-control-short-term-lets</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T15:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T15:55:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surgeries February 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/17/surgeries-autumn-2021-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Face-to-face surgeries can now restart and my next two constituency surgeries will take place on Friday 25th February.</p>



<p>Please note, however, in order to comply with Covid protocol, these will not be drop-in surgeries – <strong>appointments must be made in advance</strong>.</p>



<p>To book, please call 01294 311 160 or email philippa.whitford.mp@parliament.uk </p>



<p>For scheduled dates and times, please see below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Surgeries-FEB22.png" alt="" class="wp-image-2383" srcset="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Surgeries-FEB22.png 1013w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Surgeries-FEB22-300x197.png 300w, https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Surgeries-FEB22-768x505.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1013px) 100vw, 1013px"/></figure>



<p><em><strong>Please note that all surgery dates are subject to change dependent upon Covid guidelines and Parliamentary business. </strong></em></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202022" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202022" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202022" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202022" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20February%202022" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F02%2F17%2Fsurgeries-autumn-2021-2%2F&amp;title=Surgeries%20February%202022" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/17/surgeries-autumn-2021-2/" data-a2a-title="Surgeries February 2022"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/17/surgeries-autumn-2021-2/">Surgeries February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Face-to-face surgeries can now restart and my next two constituency surgeries will take place on ... <a title="Surgeries February 2022" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/17/surgeries-autumn-2021-2/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/02/17/surgeries-autumn-2021-2/">Surgeries February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2382</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T15:39:59Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T15:39:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If the gig economy won’t look after its workers, this government must</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/if-the-gig-economy-wont-look-after-its-workers-this-government-must/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Article written for the Guardian - published 17 February 2022 When the then Conservative cabinet minister, Norman Tebbit, fondly remembered how his dad went out on his bike to look for work he could hardly have imagined how many hundreds of thousands of people would be doing just that. The number of delivery riders working in the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6038</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T14:19:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T14:19:45Z</updated>
    <category term="My Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>CC</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[It was wrong to overlook fraud]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/02/17/it-was-wrong-to-overlook-fraud/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=5685</id>
		<updated>2022-02-17T13:33:10Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-17T13:33:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Policing, Justice and the Fight Against Crime"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="crime"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="police"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="tackling crime"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a fine line between oversight, in a democracy, and interference in operational police decisions, especially if it benefits the interests of those in power. I was surprised to hear cabinet minister Kwasi Kwarteng dismiss fraud as not being real crime. He was speaking after the UK Statistics Authority criticised the Prime Minister for claiming<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/02/17/it-was-wrong-to-overlook-fraud/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">It was wrong to overlook fraud</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/02/17/it-was-wrong-to-overlook-fraud/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img data-attachment-id="5140" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2021/09/09/we-need-a-real-social-care-plan-not-just-broken-boris-promises/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-3/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?fit=1126%2C232&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1126,232" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-5140" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?resize=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image.jpeg?w=1126&amp;ssl=1 1126w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>There&#8217;s a fine line between oversight, in a democracy, and interference in operational police decisions, especially if it benefits the interests of those in power.</p>



<p>I was surprised to hear cabinet minister Kwasi Kwarteng dismiss fraud as not being real crime. He was speaking after the UK Statistics Authority criticised the Prime Minister for claiming crime has fallen when it&#8217;s gone up 14% if the fraud figures, which he deliberately excluded, are counted.</p>



<p>Fraud is serious, it hurts people. Perhaps the Business Secretary has never met anyone who&#8217;s had their bank account emptied or an elderly person scammed by some slick conman.</p>



<p>Is the government suggesting the police shouldn&#8217;t &#8216;waste&#8217; time on fraud and that ministers rather than police officers can decide what is or isn&#8217;t a crime? That&#8217;s the start of a slippery slope.</p>



<p>We can&#8217;t have such interference or senior officers afraid to act because they&#8217;re expected to second guess their political masters.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m curious to know who suggested that &#8216;party-gate&#8217; should be investigated by sending those involved questionnaires rather than interviewing them in line with standard police procedures.</p>



<p>While reflecting on this, I&#8217;ve also been catching up on the news that the Chief Constable of the West Midlands intends to retire after the Commonwealth Games and the Commissioner of the Met Police has resigned. Both have served relatively short periods.</p>



<p>They are very different forces. West Midlands has around 7,000 officers serving a population of about three million while the Met has 34,000 officers but serves a population of more than 14 million and is also responsible for Counter Terrorism, Diplomatic Protection and safeguarding the Houses of Parliament. I&#8217;m bound to ask if that&#8217;s too big a job for any one person.</p>



<p>Here in the West Midlands, the relationship between politicians and operational policing seems settled.</p>



<p>We can be grateful that Sir Dave Thompson, whom I wish to thank, will be leaving a force which has benefitted from his commonsense leadership and refusal to become engaged in political arguments. The Met faces very different challenges but is the lesson that oversight is good and political interference bad?</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/02/17/it-was-wrong-to-overlook-fraud/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/02/17/it-was-wrong-to-overlook-fraud/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>EXTRA SUPPORT FOR 1,770 UNPAID CARERS IN WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE WELCOMED BY LOCAL MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/extra-support-for-1770-unpaid-carers-in-west-dunbartonshire-welcomed-by-local-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>1,770 unpaid carers across Dumbarton, Clydebank and the Vale of Leven have benefited from the SNP Scottish Government Carer’s Allowance Supplement since it was introduced in September 2018. The Carer’s Allowance Supplement – unique in the UK – is an extra payment introduced by the Scottish Government for people in West Dunbartonshire and across Scotland who get Carer’s … </p>
<p class="link-more"><a href="http://martindocherty.scot/extra-support-for-1770-unpaid-carers-in-west-dunbartonshire-welcomed-by-local-mp/" class="more-link">Continue reading<span class="screen-reader-text"> "EXTRA SUPPORT FOR 1,770 UNPAID CARERS IN WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE WELCOMED BY LOCAL MP"</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/extra-support-for-1770-unpaid-carers-in-west-dunbartonshire-welcomed-by-local-mp/">EXTRA SUPPORT FOR 1,770 UNPAID CARERS IN WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE WELCOMED BY LOCAL MP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1767557</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T12:19:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T12:19:32Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Urgent Storm Eunice Update for Norfolk and Broadland</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/urgent-storm-eunice-update-norfolk-and-broadland" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> The Met Office has issued an AMBER WARNING for Norfolk due to the high winds forecast across the county. 
The strongest gusts are likely to reach 60-70mph and in some places they will hit 80mph. This will begin early on Friday morning and last throughout the day.
 So what impact will that have?
•…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/urgent-storm-eunice-update-norfolk-and-broadland</id>
    <published>2022-02-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne welcomes £580k funding boost for Shropshire to support domestic abuse victims</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-welcomes-ps580k-funding-boost-shropshire-support-domestic-abuse-victims" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7112" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">16 February 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne welcomes £580k funding boost for Shropshire to support domestic abuse victims</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span>Philip Dunne MP has welcomed £580k of government funding for Shropshire Council to provide vital support services for domestic abuse victims, helping victims recover and rebuild their lives.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The Government is providing £125 million to councils across England to make sure that safe accommodation spaces, such as refuges and shelters, can provide victims with vital support services including healthcare, social workers and benefits.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Interpreters, immigration advice, drug or alcohol support and other specialist services will also be funded and made available so that anyone who flees their home gets the help they need.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The funding Shropshire Council will receive from the Government will help increase the support they can offer domestic abuse victims, whilst allowing them to choose how the funding is spent to match local priorities and benefit those in need.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The Government also announced that it will consult on current housing rules, with the aim of giving victims more choice on where they rebuild their lives. By removing Local Connection Tests for abuse victims, this could help victims apply to social housing outside their local area, escaping the community their abuser lives in.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Mr Dunne said:</span></span></span></span></p>

<blockquote>
<p><span><span><span><span>“Domestic abuse is a horrific crime, and we must do everything we can to help victims recover and rebuild their lives.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>“I am pleased the Government is giving additional funding to Shropshire Council to help local victims of abuse and their children start again – with better services such as healthcare, social workers and benefits.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>“Combined with the Government’s landmark Domestic Abuse Act, we are helping victims escape their abusers and making sure that perpetrators feel the full force of the law.”</span></span></span></span></p>
</blockquote></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7112 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T16:45:19Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T16:45:19Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>No Government help for Family members in serious danger in Afghanistan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/02/no-government-help-for-family-members-in-serious-danger-in-afghanistan/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="12098" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/02/no-government-help-for-family-members-in-serious-danger-in-afghanistan/website-co-letter-to-lord-ahmad-response-re-family-in-afghanistan-15-feb-2022/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?fit=1847%2C2560&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1847,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="WEBSITE CO letter to Lord Ahmad response re Family in Afghanistan 15 Feb 2022" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?fit=216%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?fit=700%2C970&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12098" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=700%2C970&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="970" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?w=1847&amp;amp;ssl=1 1847w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=216%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 216w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=739%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 739w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=768%2C1064&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=1108%2C1536&amp;amp;ssl=1 1108w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?resize=1478%2C2048&amp;amp;ssl=1 1478w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/WEBSITE-CO-letter-to-Lord-Ahmad-response-re-Family-in-Afghanistan-15-Feb-2022-scaled.jpg?w=1400&amp;amp;ssl=1 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="12096" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/02/no-government-help-for-family-members-in-serious-danger-in-afghanistan/lord-ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-website/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?fit=1554%2C2560&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1554,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Lord Ahmad 28 jan letter for Website" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?fit=182%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?fit=622%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12096" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=700%2C1153&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="1153" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?w=1554&amp;amp;ssl=1 1554w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=182%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 182w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=622%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 622w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=768%2C1265&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=933%2C1536&amp;amp;ssl=1 933w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?resize=1243%2C2048&amp;amp;ssl=1 1243w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-for-Website-scaled.jpeg?w=1400&amp;amp;ssl=1 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="12097" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/02/no-government-help-for-family-members-in-serious-danger-in-afghanistan/lord-ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-website-jpeg/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?fit=1847%2C2560&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1847,2560" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Lord Ahmad 28 jan letter p2 for Website.jpeg" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?fit=216%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?fit=700%2C970&amp;amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12097" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=700%2C970&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="970" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?w=1847&amp;amp;ssl=1 1847w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=216%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 216w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=739%2C1024&amp;amp;ssl=1 739w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=768%2C1064&amp;amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=1108%2C1536&amp;amp;ssl=1 1108w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?resize=1478%2C2048&amp;amp;ssl=1 1478w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Lord-Ahmad-28-jan-letter-p2-for-Website.jpeg-scaled.jpeg?w=1400&amp;amp;ssl=1 1400w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">       </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12093</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T13:35:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T13:35:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Correspondence"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Commemorating Holocaust Memorial Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/02/16/commemorating-holocaust-memorial-day-2/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=640</id>
		<updated>2022-02-16T13:34:25Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-16T11:42:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/02/16/commemorating-holocaust-memorial-day-2/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-end-crisis-in-dentistry/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The current dental contract and under-investment makes work for dentists highly stressful and doesn’t allow them to provide the quality of care to their patients they feel they deserve. There are long-standing problems with burnout, recruiting and retention, with almost a thousand dentists leaving the NHS in England in the last financial year.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to the British Dental Association, over 40 million NHS dental appointments have been lost since the start of the pandemic, which amounts to a whole year’s worth of NHS dentistry in pre-COVID times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith continued: “While the government has provided limited amounts of money for dentists to catch up on missed appointments, dental practices in my constituency tell me the funding is virtually unusable. It must be used by March and there is simply physically not enough time to fit these appointments in.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this was an issue brewing long before the pandemic, as even before COVID, there was only enough dentistry for around half of the adult population in England to see an NHS dentist every two years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the debate, Judith said: “There is not a week that goes by where I don’t have someone contacting me about the lack of dentists. We’ve lost a whole year of appointments while the government is giving with one hand and taking away with the other because the government just knows the money just cannot be spent.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yorkshire and the Humber has the worst child oral health in the country, with twice the level of tooth decay than in the East of England. In Bradford, almost a thousand children under the age of 10 had to be admitted to hospital to have decayed teeth removed under a general anaesthetic last year. That is thousands of children who are in pain while they await surgery.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We need a new deal that treats dentistry as an equal member of the NHS family and not as a Cinderella service. We must work to achieve a fully funded service where NHS dentistry is available to all. The government needs to act and it needs to act now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;84&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, service, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, government, service, year, speaking, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy"&gt;People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-affected-by-dementia-urgently-need-a-national-rehabilitation-strategy/" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy" alt="People affected by dementia urgently need a national rehabilitation strategy" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A year on from the start of the pandemic, Judith is joining Alzheimer’s Society, TIDE, Dementia UK and John’s Campaign to remember the tens of thousands of people with dementia whose lives have been lost to Covid and to call for lasting change this Coronavirus Action Day. Judith has written&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, lost, pandemic, year, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/282909116.gallery-1-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" alt="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith, alongside Susan Hinchcliffe, leader of the council and Tracy Brabin, candidate for West Yorkshire Mayor, has called for the Government to ensure there is a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop in the city centre. Representing all three of Bradford's Labour MPs, Judith said: "There is a world out there that&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;80&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse. Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes: “The current dental contract and under-investment makes […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2587</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T13:22:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T13:22:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby hits out at record NHS waiting lists</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/02/16/toby-hits-out-at-record-nhs-waiting-lists/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/02/16/toby-hits-out-at-record-nhs-waiting-lists/">Toby hits out at record NHS waiting lists</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/02/16/toby-hits-out-at-record-nhs-waiting-lists/">Toby hits out at record NHS waiting lists</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4951</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T12:55:08Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:55:08Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK Power Networks Advice for Upcoming Storms</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/uk-power-networks-advice-upcoming-storms" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">UK Power Networks Advice for Upcoming Storms</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-02-16T12:21:00+00:00">Wed, 02/16/2022 - 12:21</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1109 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T12:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:21:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Belt: How to save the lungs of London</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/green-belt-how-save-lungs-london" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My top priority for 2022 is protecting our green spaces and particularly preserving our Green Belt land in the south of the county. The last two years have taught us how precious these spaces are, their importance to the character of our communities, and the vital role they play in all of our…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/green-belt-how-save-lungs-london</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Storms Dudley and Eunice - key support info</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/storms-dudley-and-eunice-key-support-info" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">STORMS DUDLEY AND EUNICE - key emergency contact details
With severe weather forecast over the next few days, with Storm Dudley arriving today and tomorrow, and Storm Eunice on Friday, I thought it would be sueful to collate the best contact details should you need assistance and to report any…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/storms-dudley-and-eunice-key-support-info</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robert Kett School Road Safety</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/robert-kett-school-road-safety" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2322" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">15 February 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Robert Kett School Road Safety</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span>Safety outside our schools is of the utmost importance to us all. Whether walking, cycling or in a vehicle, children and families should feel safe at school pick up and drop off times. </span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>That’s why I have worked closely with local councillors across Mid Norfolk over the years on this issue - most recently around the Robert Kett Primary School in Wymondham, who I am delighted to hear are taking part in a trial of temporary road closures at drop off and pick up times during term aimed at boosting safety. Norfolk County Council will be working very closely with schools, residents, and local businesses on this project, with<span><span> careful planning taking place as part of the School Streets scheme to ensure that any displaced traffic can adequately be accommodated elsewhere on the surrounding network. </span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The trial will be delivered on the ground by volunteer marshals who will operate the road closures in accordance with training from Norfolk County Council.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span><span>The programme should benefit children’s health and reduce air pollution and reduce reliance on cars too.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span><span>To stay up to date with my work on this issue, please do check my website for further web stories in the weeks ahead.</span></span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p> </p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>To see more on this story from the EDP click: </span></span><span><a href="https://www.edp24.co.uk/news/education/traffic-to-be-banned-around-norfolk-schools-8686486"><span>here</span></a></span></span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2022-02/george_freeman_robert_kett_school.jpg" width="972" height="583" alt="George Freeman MP visiting Robert Kett Primary School" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2322 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T18:40:22Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-15T18:40:22Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet meets with Indian classical music superstars </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-meets-indian-classical-music-superstars" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Ties between British and Indian musicians were boosted this week with a visit by four classical music superstars to Royal Birmingham Conservatoire - who told the audience that ‘music has the power to change your life in a way you couldn’t even imagine’. </p>
<p>Tabla supremo Zakir Hussain, acclaimed singer-composer Shankar Mahadevan, leading flautist Rakesh Chaurasia, and legendary keyboardist and producer Louiz Banks met staff, students, diplomats, MPs and business leaders including the Indian Consul General of India Dr Shashank Vikram and Preet Kaur Gill MP at the world-renowned centre of music, based at Birmingham City University. </p>
<p>The visit, organised by BCU India and West Midlands India Partnership, saw the artists – who are known to hundreds of millions of fans in their home country and across the globe – share advice and stories with a captivated audience in the Conservatoire’s Bradshaw Hall, before enjoying performances from RBC percussion and brass students.</p>
<p>Preet Kaur Gill, MP for Birmingham Edgbaston said, “What an absolute honour to meet the four great Indian Maestros - Zakir Hussain, Shankar Mahadevan, Rakesh Chaurasia and Louiz Banks, who gave an incredible performance. My sincere thanks go to Birmingham City University for helping us to continue to build such links between British and Indian musicians.” </p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Standard (Image)</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Screenshot%202022-02-15%20145817.jpg" width="1270" height="844" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>1066 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T14:59:24Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-15T14:59:24Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The cost of living crisis cannot be ignored – My monthly article for the Stockport Express</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-cost-of-living-crisis-cannot-be-ignored-my-monthly-article-for-the-stockport-express/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-cost-of-living-crisis-cannot-be-ignored-my-monthly-article-for-the-stockport-express" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-234935" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Cost-of-Living-Crisis.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>Many people across <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>, and indeed across the country, will have been understandably anxious at the news that from April, millions of households will typically pay an extra £693 a year on their energy bills. The announcement had been anticipated for some time, but the sheer scale of the expected price rise took many by surprise.</p>
<p>I know that for households across <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>, soaring energy prices will add pressure to household budgets which are already incredibly stretched.</p>
<p>The Government have shown themselves to be fundamentally ill-equipped to deal with the cost-of-living crisis. Earlier this month, the Chancellor set out a scheme with the apparent goal of ‘easing’ the pressures on working people.</p>
<p>What we got was essentially a loan, which will leave taxpayers in debt, all whilst oil and gas companies continue to make unprecedented profits.</p>
<p>Needless to say, this botched scheme will do very little for the people of <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>. We need a scheme that taxes the massive oil and gas companies and gets that money to households in need. More generally, we need a Government that stands up for working people and gives them the proper support they need to get through this crisis.</p>
<p>Rising fuel bills have an obvious knock-on effect on other household finances. That’s why I’m grateful that here in <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>, the Council will once again be distributing holiday support vouchers to families with children in receipt of income-based school meals. I know that these vouchers were a real lifeline for many over the Christmas period, and their continued distribution will be a relief to so many families.</p>
<p>There is also some innovative community-based work taking place, which I wanted to take a moment to recognise. For example, the Local Pantry scheme – organised by <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>Homes – operates in five locations across the borough. Members pay a small subscription fee, and in return can choose groceries worth many times more. The aim of the Local Pantry scheme is to drive down food poverty, whilst strengthening health and wellbeing.</p>
<p>There is no escaping the fact that this is a difficult time for many people, and it’s important to remember to look out for one another and do all you can to support friends and neighbours.</p>
<p>I hope that sooner, rather than later, the Government outlines a proper plan of action to address the crisis. Until then, I will continue to do all I can to work alongside <span class="markqfk2dzb9p" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Stockport</span>Council to give people the support they need.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-cost-of-living-crisis-cannot-be-ignored-my-monthly-article-for-the-stockport-express/">The cost of living crisis cannot be ignored – My monthly article for the Stockport Express</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Many people across Stockport, and indeed across the country, will have been understandably anxious at the news that from April, millions of households will typically pay an extra £693 a year on their energy bills. The announcement had been anticipated for some time, but the sheer scale of the expected price rise took many by […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-cost-of-living-crisis-cannot-be-ignored-my-monthly-article-for-the-stockport-express/">The cost of living crisis cannot be ignored – My monthly article for the Stockport Express</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=234934</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T14:34:15Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-15T14:34:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton welcomes £412,738 funding boost for Blackpool Council to support domestic abuse victims</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-ps412738-funding-boost-blackpool-council-support-domestic-abuse-victims" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
Scott Benton has welcomed the Conservative Government’s decision to give councils £125 million to provide vital support services for domestic abuse victims in 2022-23, taking the total support to date to £330 million.
This funding will play an important role in funding healthcare, social workers…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-welcomes-ps412738-funding-boost-blackpool-council-support-domestic-abuse-victims</id>
    <published>2022-02-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[FIGHTING THE CLOSURE OF HYDE TEST CENTRE]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/02/14/fighting-the-closure-of-hyde-test-centre/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=419</id>
		<updated>2022-02-14T12:44:12Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-14T12:44:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/02/14/fighting-the-closure-of-hyde-test-centre/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/02/14/fighting-the-closure-of-hyde-test-centre/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/02/14/fighting-the-closure-of-hyde-test-centre/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southern Rail Update – February 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Chris,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow up on previous emails about changes to the timetable in February, I wanted to confirm the plan.  We will be amending our timetables from Monday 28 February, following a period of significant staff absence due to Covid and a major blockade of engineering works on the Brighton mainline between 19-27 February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the picture is improving overall, and the direct impact of Covid on colleagues is reducing, its legacy continues to have an impact on our business and services.  One example is a backlog of driver training due to previous social distancing requirements where, for example, two people were not permitted to be in a train cab together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in the short term, we have taken a prudent approach to adding services, with the aim of ensuring we can offer reliability, rather than having to cancel trains last minute and create large gaps in the service.  We want to thank customers for their patience and understanding throughout this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now starting to see more people return to rail, albeit in much lower numbers than before the pandemic, particularly as people continue to work from home some of the week. We will therefore be introducing a new timetable from Monday 28 February to ensure our services and resources are the best possible fit.  We are focusing on providing more capacity for commuters returning to the office. Our February timetable change includes more direct services to London Victoria and London Bridge, increases to peak services, especially in the early morning and in areas where there are no other public transport options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what this means specifically for your constituency, Southern services will return to the timetable used in the Autumn of 2021 from the 21 February.  This means that the direct routes to London Victoria from Epsom via Hackbridge and Epsom Downs via West Croydon will resume, as will Tattenham Corner’s fast trains to London Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As in the Autumn, something to be aware of is while the service from Epsom to London Bridge will resume, there will be a reduced frequency in the morning. Trains from Epsom to London Bridge will depart at 05:45, 07:16, 08:15 then every 30 minutes until 22:45. The reason being, as in September, the morning peak is the busiest point on the network and we will be seeking to spread our available crew resource as best we possibly can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual journeys for the timetable of 28 February are due in journey planners this week and we will be increasing customer communications about the changes.  We advise customers to plan their journeys in advance and re-check before they travel, especially the weeks commencing 21 February and 28 February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior Stakeholder Manager&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/"&gt;Southern Rail Update &amp;#8211; February 2022&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Chris, To follow up on previous emails about changes to the timetable in February, I wanted to confirm the plan.  We will be amending our timetables from Monday 28 February, following a period of significant staff absence due to Covid and a major blockade of engineering works on the Brighton mainline between 19-27 February. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/southern-rail-updates-february-2022/">Southern Rail Update – February 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6225</id>
    <published>2022-02-14T10:25:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-14T10:25:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>Universal Credit rate must keep up with inflation to avoid more people relying on foodbanks - MP</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1423910/universal-credit-rate-must-keep-up-with-inflation-to-avoid-more-people-relying-on-foodbanks-mp"/>
  <updated>2022-02-11T16:22:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1423910/universal-credit-rate-must-keep-up-with-inflation-to-avoid-more-people-relying-on-foodbanks-mp</id>
  <summary type="text">On the floor of the House of Commons this week, South Lakes MP urged ministers to bring Universal Credit in line with the cost of living to avoid thousands of local residents being plunged into destitution.
On Monday, MPs voted through the annual pensions and benefits uprating order, designed to bring a whole range of social security benefits in line with inflation and the cost of living. However, this year it could actually mean a real-terms cut in the living standards for millions.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the floor of the House of Commons this week, South Lakes MP urged ministers to bring Universal Credit in line with the cost of living to avoid thousands of local residents being plunged into destitution.</p>
<p>On Monday, MPs voted through the annual pensions and benefits uprating order, designed to bring a whole range of social security benefits in line with inflation and the cost of living. However, this year it could actually mean a real-terms cut in the living standards for millions.</p>
<p>The increase voted through was 3.1 per cent, but it is based on last September's inflation figures. Inflation is currently at 5.4 per cent and the Bank of England are forecasting that inflation will reach 7.25% by April, leading to more expensive energy bills and pricier food in the shops.</p>
<p>Speaking during a debate in Parliament on the cost of living crisis, Tim said: "<em>Too little is being done to help those whose need is greatest. With inflation predicted for 7.25%, the 3.1% benefits uprating will lead to utter destitution.</em></p>
<p><em>"It is not just about physical hardship, but about the misery, shame and lack of dignity that go with it and the stress and mental health problems that go with abject poverty, when people cannot afford to feed their children, pay the rent or put fuel in their car to get to work - if they are lucky enough to have a car.</em></p>
<p><em>"Kendal in my constituency is not a huge town by most people's standards, yet Linda Sutherland's wonderful team at King's Food Bank in Kendal provided 48,225 meals last year, which was 50% more than in 2020.</em></p>
<p><em>"The massive demand for services from people in desperate need tells us that we are doing something seriously wrong as a country."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/02/11/weekly-round-up-17/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-17" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This week the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee began a new inquiry into the scrutiny of international treaties and other international agreements in the 21</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">st</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> century. The first session was really an introduction, International Treaties 101 if you like, to set the context of the inquiry and to ensure a grounding in understanding of the issues involved in international treaty building. We heard from former legal advisers to the House of Lords and other parliamentary organisations as well as academic staff from UK universities. As the UK seeks to build its relations with other states outside of the EU, this will be a really important aspect of the Committee’s work, ensuring that the treaties that are signed work for the UK uphold our traditions of promoting democratic and transparent values in our public and political life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was pleased to lead Labour’s response to the Government’s White Paper on integration in the NHS. This is essentially the Government undoing the poor reforms of the Lansley Act – the Health and Social Care Act 2012. We know that reversing the Lansley Act and implementing a health and social care system fit for 21</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">st</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> century Britain will be difficult, but it is unclear how the ideas in this White Paper fit in with the Health and Care Bill currently in the House of Lords. Like a house made of crepe paper, this gossamer-thin White Paper collapses with the faintest breeze of scrutiny. Let us be clear: it is not a plan, nor is it even a starting strategy. It is just a series of woolly claims about how things could be better, unsupported by any evidence or analysis of the resources, organisational and funding flow changes that will obviously be necessary. It could have been written at any time over the past 30 years. It contains little that is new and nothing to illustrate new thinking or new attitudes. It relies on the bogus assumption that because something may work for a while on a small scale, it will obviously work everywhere. It is not any kind of plan for integrated care that people will recognise; these are just aspirations about integrated systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Health and social care in the 21</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">st</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> century goes beyond GP surgeries, care homes, and hospitals and must be considered across other sectors. I was pleased to speak at an event for the East of England Regional Roadshow this week on the topic of transport, benefits and social care with Vicky Foxcroft, the Shadow Minister for Disabled People and Tan Dhesi, the Shadow Minister for Transport. We have to consider how we ensure our society is inclusive for everyone and how we enable people to live independent lives while living with a physical or mental disability. We do not want a society where people with any kind of disability are having to live isolated in their homes and whose only interaction with people is through their carers. A disability simply means that there are certain obstacles to living a normal life that other people do not have; but crucially, it does not mean that those obstacles cannot be overcome and that someone living with a disability is not able to participate fully in society. We want to build the sort of society where that is a given and is considered across sectors in all policy-making.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I responded to a debate in Westminster Hall this week on behalf of the Labour Party on access to NHS dentistry in the UK. While the Covid pandemic has clearly had a huge impact on waiting times and access to care, the Care Quality Commission highlights that problems with access predate the pandemic quite significantly. The Government’s plans, that include paying dentists to work overtime in the early morning or at weekends, clearly underestimate the scale of the problem. If Covid is not the main cause for lack of access, there is a problem with the underlying assumptions about the requirements of NHS dentistry. Those are the assumptions the Government needs to tackle, and pushing dentists to work longer hours is not a safe way of solving the problems we’re seeing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I am very much looking forward to joining the Bedminster Winter Lantern Parade this Saturday, seeing the creativity of the schools, residents, and businesses in their lanterns and celebrating the community in Bedminster. It really is a lovely event, bringing together young and old in a celebration of the community and giving us something bright and cheerful to look forward to in the dark winter months. If you want more information about the event, sponsorship, and taking part, visit </span><a href="https://www.lanternparade.org/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">their website here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </span></p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/02/11/weekly-round-up-17/">Weekly Round-Up</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee began a new inquiry into the scrutiny of international treaties and […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/02/11/weekly-round-up-17/">Weekly Round-Up</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3143</id>
    <published>2022-02-11T13:53:39Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-11T13:53:39Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nai's House</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/nais-house" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Children’s Mental Health Week is a time to reflect on the importance of young people’s mental wellbeing.
This afternoon, I visited the fantastic Nai's House in Bicester. Founded by Gem Barrett, Nai’s House offer holistic support for young people struggling with their mental and emotional wellbeing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/nais-house</id>
    <published>2022-02-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We must remain united with our NATO partners in pushing back against Russian aggression</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/we-must-remain-united-our-nato-partners-pushing-back-against-russian-aggression" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The massive build up of Russian troops on it's border with Ukraine remains hugely concerning. The Prime Minister, Foreign Secretary and Defence Secretary are demonstrating that diplomacy remains our preferred method of de-escalation, but we need strong and clear sanctions against those in Russia…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/we-must-remain-united-our-nato-partners-pushing-back-against-russian-aggression</id>
    <published>2022-02-11T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-11T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Angus MacNeil MP backs widespread call for action on ferries</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/02/10/angus-macneil-mp-backs-widespread-call-for-action-on-ferries/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is writing to Transport Scotland stressing the urgent need for a &amp;#8220;fast assessment&amp;#8221; of the current issues facing the ferry network to the Hebrides where four ferries are currently out of service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3529" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/loch-seaforth/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg" data-orig-size="2903,2705" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;2.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G780F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1626901157&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;7.12&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.016666666666667&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="loch-seaforth" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-3529" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/loch-seaforth.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After months of constant contact with the Scottish Government and CalMac regarding the network, Mr MacNeil is writing to the new Transport Minister, Jenny Gilruth MSP, to stress once again the need for prompt action starting with Transport Scotland doing an urgent short-sharp assessment on the current situation which would need to be done within a month maximum. Mr MacNeil is backing calls by Comhairle nan Eilean Siar and others for action.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The current disruption to the lifeline network is due to 3 vessels being in dry dock and the critical MV Hebrides being out of action with engine trouble, meaning the islands network is, an important, 4 vessels short.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I am writing to Transport Scotland to do a short-sharp assessment of the ferry problems and needs as identified by many people today including Comhairle nan Eilean Siar. We need action to bring about change in the Hebridean ferries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“At the moment there has been a construction delay, as we know, at the Fergusons yard in Greenock. We need more ferries, as has been identified by the Comhairle and others. A logical consequence of what Comhairle nan Eilean Siar is calling for, is that enquiries must be made with shipyards in Poland and Germany that have built CalMac ferries in the past.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Pentalina meantime would look like a stop gap if it is fully seaworthy and there are no problems with it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Another obvious issue to be addressed is that the CalMac Board has to have islanders on it and I would suggest that the Council Leader and Transport Chairman be entrusted with these responsibilities. We wouldn’t have other bodies in Scotland without people resident in Scotland on them. To have CalMac ferries serving the island and not have anyone living on the islands on the CalMac Board is a clear and glaring problem!&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The previous Transport Minister was obviously wrong in his decision and hopefully the current Transport Minister will bring about change, then we might not have 4 ferries out of action at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“But this is also a time to remind Comhairle nan Eilean Siar that while they demand action on transport from other bodies they must live up to their own responsibilities and reinstate the inter-island flights they chose to cut. That was the greatest piece of vandalism to island transportation in decades and ironically placed extra burdens on ferries, and it was done by the Comhairle.&amp;nbsp; The Comhairle pocketed that transportation money, without a thought or care for islanders, especially those needing hospital appointments.&amp;nbsp; If they lived up to their responsibilities it would add greater weight to their worthy call today.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is writing to Transport Scotland stressing the urgent need for a “fast …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/02/10/angus-macneil-mp-backs-widespread-call-for-action-on-ferries/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3706</id>
    <published>2022-02-10T16:37:22Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-10T16:37:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Ashford Police Station</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-police-station" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Years ago I remember having to battle to keep a police station open in Ashford. I accepted the logic of closing smaller stations which few people ever visited, but not one as busy as Ashford.
In the light of those memories it was a real pleasure to be shown round the new much-improved station which…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-ashford-police-station</id>
    <published>2022-02-10T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-a-tale-of-two-reports" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p>Last week saw two publications from the UK Government, both of them were unedifying and deeply unsatisfactory in their own ways.</p>
<p>The Sue Gray update, which was supposed to be a complete, unredacted report of the rule-breaking parties at number 10 Downing Street, rightly got a lot of attention in the press.</p>
<p>I’ve received hundreds of emails from many of you, sharing your anger at the lack of respect and humility shown by the Prime Minister and his Government. I am sure it won’t surprise you that I share your frustration at the situation, and I wish I could do more than respond with words of agreement. Rest assured, in Parliament, I will continue to make your views on the subject heard.</p>
<p>The Sue Gray update was a heavily censored summary but made it clear that there had been ‘Serious failures of leadership” at Number ten. The Prime Minister cannot escape this verdict; he is the leader at No. 10. No amount of cover-up and no matter how high the mountain of lies, the fact is that he is unfit to hold office. He said he was “furious” with staff when the story first broke and, remember, gratefully accepted the resignation of his Press Secretary, Allegra Stratton, before Christmas. Yet, he thinks he can carry on regardless.</p>
<p>The second report published last week was the ‘Benefits of Brexit’ report. It was published alongside the Sue Gray report – obviously, a failed attempt to divert the news cycle. Frustratingly, it only got minimal coverage, and there was little to no opportunity to challenge the Government on their supposed ‘advantages of Brexit included in the report. (You can watch my full response <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XbYQGRBVD3Y&amp;ab_channel=DrewHendry">here</a>.)</p>
<p>The report is over 100 pages yet fails to acknowledge the catastrophic impacts of Brexit on businesses and households. It offers no solutions or answers. The report lists’ cheaper holidays in the EU’ as a flagship Brexit achievement. Hundreds of thousands of families are struggling to find the money to pay for fuel to drive to work because of the tory costs of living crisis – never mind holiday abroad.</p>
<p>The report goes on to celebrate the fact that Brexit is ‘Saving UK consumers money by allowing them to do more of their shopping duty-free.’ Again, talking up high-end shopping in airports when more and more folk can’t even afford to do their weekly food shop shows just how out of touch this UK Government are. Where’s the part of the report that acknowledges Brexit’s impact on prices; where’s the solution from this Government?</p>
<p>Of course, there was enough space in the report for an entire section dedicated to  ‘Global Britain’. Yet, it is hard to remember a time when the UK’s reputation was so much in tatters.</p>
<p>These two documents sum up Westminster – and why we now need to make our own decisions, here, in Scotland.</p>
<p>I will keep highlighting the severe impact of the cost of living crisis and the energy price hike on your families. I also want to remind you all that if there is anything you think I may be able to help your family with, please get in touch with my office. While I cannot promise to fix the problem, my team and I will do all we can to help or point you in the right direction. Please don’t suffer alone – support is out there.</p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com/">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last week saw two publications from the UK Government, both of them were unedifying and deeply unsatisfactory in their own ways. The Sue Gray update, which was supposed to be a complete, unredacted report of the rule-breaking parties at number 10 Downing Street, rightly got a lot of attention in the press. I’ve received hundreds …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-tale-of-two-reports/">ARTICLE: A Tale of Two Reports</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6245</id>
    <published>2022-02-10T10:10:54Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-10T10:10:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="EU / Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hawick MP probes TSB post-closure plans</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/hawick-mp-probes-tsb-post-closure-plans" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hawick MP, John Lamont, has grilled a Director of TSB in Westminster after the bank closed their branch in the town during 2021.
The closure means that their customers now must travel 18 miles to their nearest branch in Galashiels.
Mr Lamont, speaking during a Scottish Affairs Committee session on…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/hawick-mp-probes-tsb-post-closure-plans</id>
    <published>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Saltend MP backs new hydrogen era in meeting with Minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/saltend-mp-backs-new-hydrogen-era-meeting-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Beverley and Holderness MP, Graham Stuart, whose constituency is set to include vital energy-generating infrastructure at Saltend Chemicals Park and the Yorkshire Energy Park, has met Energy Minister, Greg Hands, to back plans for a 600-megawatt, low-carbon hydrogen production plant.
The H2H…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/saltend-mp-backs-new-hydrogen-era-meeting-minister</id>
    <published>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-147" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It is now very clear that the cost of living is going up! It’s now at 6% and rising. Energy bills are set to double as the cap set limiting the amount energy companies can charge has been lifted effective from April increasing the average household energy bill by almost £700.  The government has…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-147</id>
    <published>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Smear on Demand]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/02/08/smear-on-demand/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1611</id>
		<updated>2022-02-08T11:08:10Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-08T11:08:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="cancer"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="healthcare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="HPV"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="smear"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="women"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/02/08/smear-on-demand/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Child Maintenance Service</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/02/07/child-maintenance-service/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7236</id>
    <published>2022-02-07T14:09:22Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-07T14:09:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="Conor in Westminster"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-15" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday I visited a Stanton Hill man in his home which he shares with his wife and two small children as he had contacted me due to the poor state of his rented housing. What I saw will haunt me for a long time. The brick work throughout was riddled with black damp patches, walls were wet,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-15</id>
    <published>2022-02-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid Vaccine Newsletter from Swansea Bay University Health Board</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/covid-vaccine-newsletter-from-swansea-bay-university-health-board/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal" align="center"><b>Covid Vaccine Newsletter from Swansea Bay University Health Board</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><u>Date: February 4, 2022</u></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><u>Edition number: 34 </u></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><u>Introduction:</u></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">We have given more than 800,000 doses and continue to vaccinate seven days a week.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Full details of where you can get the dose you need are below, along with information on other developments.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><u>Latest news</u></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Statement from our Executive Director of Public Health, Keith Reid, following an issue at the Bay Mass Vaccination Centre last weekend.</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“I wish to apologise to those young people who were turned away from the vaccination centre at the weekend after responding to an invitation for a second dose.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“This shouldn’t have happened and I am sorry for the upset and upheaval this will have caused you and your families. I also recognise that you now have to attend again to get the vaccination and I hope that your experience on your recent visit has not put you off getting a second dose of vaccine.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“I have asked for an investigation to establish why this occurred so we can prevent it happening again.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“We understand that at least 30 young people were turned away in error over the Saturday and Sunday and we are really sorry about this. The investigation will look in detail at why this happened and the exact numbers who were affected. But at this stage it does not appear that the invitations were issued too early.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Vaccination for those with allergies</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">If you have an allergy or allergies, we understand you will need good quality information on how your body might react to vaccination before deciding to go ahead.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">If you do have questions or concerns you can speak to one of our clinicians by contacting our booking line on <span dir="ltr">01792 200492</span> or <span dir="ltr">01639 862323</span> before attending for vaccination.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">After speaking to you, the clinical lead may refer you to the allergy clinic where there is the potential option of having the vaccine in a specialised clinic if deemed appropriate.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">We have also pulled together some vaccination facts that may help:</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst">·         The Covid vaccines are safe for those with allergies (including anaphylaxis) to wasp, bee or other insect stings and allergies to any food or drink.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         The current vaccines do not contain any traces of nuts, gluten, egg, or soy.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         The current vaccines do not contain latex and are therefore suitable for those with an allergy to latex.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         All UK approved Covid vaccines do not contain penicillin or any other antibiotics. If you are allergic to penicillin or another antibiotic, you can still receive the vaccines.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         All immunisers are trained and will assess suitability for vaccination when they go through the eligibility questions prior to vaccination. If there is any concern they will refer to our allergy service for advice.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpLast">·         If vaccination goes ahead the immuniser might request you wait for longer post vaccination – up to 30 minutes.<b> </b></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Getting the vaccine</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">You can get whatever dose you need at drop-in sessions or by booking online.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">In addition, we continue to invite those who become eligible.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Drop-in sessions are available at the Bay MVC, our containers (local vaccination centres) at the Guildhall in Swansea, Pontardawe Leisure Centre and in a number of community pharmacies.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><span dir="ltr">From Wednesday, February 16</span><sup><span dir="ltr">th</span></sup>, we will also have a container outside Croeserw Community Hub.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/PqoOCL73oFzAxl3CBXxla?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/">Please go to our website for more details on vaccination sessions and the online booking link.</a></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Important information:</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraph">·         Anyone 18 or over or under 18 and in an at-risk category who has had a positive Covid test result must wait until 28 days have passed following the positive result before having a vaccination.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst">·         Anyone aged 12 to 17 who is not at risk and has had a positive Covid test result must wait until 12 weeks have passed following the positive result before having a vaccination.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         Please note, the vaccination appointment system generates appointments based on the date of the previous dose and is not able to take a positive Covid test result into account. So you may get an invitation to attend before the 28 day or 12-week waiting period is up. Please only attend once the appropriate period has passed post the positive test result.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">·         There does not need to be any gap between a HPV vaccine and Covid vaccine, no matter which comes first.</p>
<p class="x_MsoListParagraphCxSpLast">·         There must be a gap of 13 weeks or more between a 2nd or 3rd primary dose and a booster.</p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Trial for Covid treatment</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Have you just tested positive for Covid-19? Would you like to join a new UK-wide trial for effective early treatments?</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This trial is available for people who are at wider risk of serious illness from Covid-19 either because:</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">•        They are over the age of 50, or</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">•        They are aged 18 to 49 with underlying health conditions. (Many will already qualify for free annual flu jabs.)</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To take part people need to fall into one of the at-risk groups, have tested positive for Covid-19 by either a PCR or LFT test, and have symptoms.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The PANORAMIC trial involves a course of oral tablets. These tablets are already used to treat some people who are ill enough with Covid-19 to be in hospital.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The trial is now looking at how effective the treatment is for people who are still at home who test positive for Covid-19, and who have symptoms.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It is a UK-wide study and anyone who is in the at-risk categories can apply to take part, whether they have been vaccinated or not.  More details, including a link to apply online, are available on the PANORAMIC website <a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/Yyf4CNL3qigAKw6fj9Wln?domain=panoramictrial.org">www.panoramictrial.org</a>  Or, ring <span dir="ltr">08081 560017</span> (calls are free.)</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Once accepted onto the trial, the tablets are posted to you straight away as they should be taken within five days. You will be asked to answer follow up questions online or by telephone, but no face-to-face visits are needed.</p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Afghan interpreter’s move to Swansea translates into new NHS career</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Having flown out of Afghanistan, fearing for his life as the Taliban stormed Kabul, Mohamed Ferooz Noori is now helping save lives by working with Swansea Bay’s vaccination programme.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The father of two was relocated to the UK following the withdrawal of troops from Afghanistan last August.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">He had been working as a translator alongside the British military, and when he arrived in the UK was originally sent to Cardiff before moving to Swansea. He now works as a call handler in Bay Mass Vaccination Centre.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/yASeCOM3rcBJVEOhrcX5i?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/">Go to this page on our website to read the full story.</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Vaccination team reflects on happy relationship with wedding venue</b><b> </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Swansea Bay’s vaccination team has undergone an amicable parting of the ways with The Orangery at Margam.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">After delivering more than 150,000 Covid vaccinations, over the course of the past year, at the picturesque wedding venue in the grounds of Margam Park, the team is set to move to a new venue in Aberafan Shopping Centre.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The change of venue will allow The Orangery to revert to its former use as a sought-after location for happy couples to celebrate tying the knot.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/qETVCP73vFLOYJ6f6U3F3?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/">Go to this page to read more about the closure of our vaccination centre in Margam.</a></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b> </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Walking group uses great outdoors to help tackle long Covid</b><b> </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">People suffering with long Covid symptoms are benefiting from getting out in the great outdoors as part of their ongoing recovery.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">A new walking group sees those taking part exercising at their own pace as they are accompanied along the route by a GP and a physiotherapy assistant practitioner.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Patients who have been referred to the Long Covid Rehabilitation Service, which runs from the Bay Field Hospital, are invited to take part in the weekly walks as an extension of the support available to them.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/5ZQyCQn9wCw8GJRiAExUC?domain=sbuhb.nhs.wales/">Go to this page to read more about the long Covid walking group.</a></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b> </b><b> </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><u>Latest Covid vaccination figures </u></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Please note: Figures correct as of 1pm on Friday, February 4th. These figures are for the Swansea Bay University Health Board area, not the whole of Wales.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">1<sup>st</sup> dose: <b>303,954</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">2<sup>nd</sup> dose:<b> 282,985</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">3<sup>rd</sup> dose (for the immunosuppressed): <b>7,106</b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Booster dose: <b>214,418 </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Running total (1, 2, 3 and booster doses): <b>808,463</b></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covid Vaccine Newsletter from Swansea Bay University Health Board Date: February 4, 2022 Edition number: 34 Introduction: We have given more than 800,000 doses and continue to vaccinate seven days a week. Full details of where you can get the dose you need are below, along with information on other developments. Latest news   Statement […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2625</id>
    <published>2022-02-04T15:56:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-04T15:56:45Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on the cost of living crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_costofliving" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Ofgem has announced that the energy price cap will increase by £693 from April.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_costofliving</id>
    <published>2022-02-04T13:39:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-04T13:39:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex demands clarity on Teesside production of Novavax vaccine]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/02/alex-demands-clarity-on-teesside-production-of-novavax-vaccine/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14417</id>
		<updated>2022-02-04T12:12:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-02-04T12:12:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP, Alex Cunningham, has demanded clarity on whether the Novavax vaccine will be produced on Teesside after Novavax bosses refused to confirm when or if any of the vaccine would be made at Fujifilm, Billingham. Correspondence from Novavax to Alex on 2 February 2022 suggested that the company was readying Fujifilm, Billingham, for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/02/alex-demands-clarity-on-teesside-production-of-novavax-vaccine/">Alex demands clarity on Teesside production of Novavax vaccine</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman welcomes boost for Boston and Skegness under Conservative Government’s Levelling Up Plans</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/02/03/matt-warman-welcomes-boost-for-boston-and-skegness-under-conservative-governments-levelling-up-plans/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li><strong>Matt Warman has welcomed the Conservative Government’s Levelling Up White Paper and the boost it will bring to Boston &amp; Skegness by increasing wages, improving living standards, and regenerating local communities across the country.</strong></li>
<li><strong>This is the next step on the Conservative Government’s mission to unite and level up Britain, with radical new policies announced across the board – including a devolution revolution, London-style transport systems and 5G across the country, as well as elimination of innumeracy and illiteracy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>The Conservative Government is creating a better quality of life for people in every part of the UK – so everyone can access the opportunities they need to succeed.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>Matt Warman has welcomed the Levelling Up White Paper unveiled by the Levelling Up Secretary, Michael Gove, on 2 February 2022, and the benefits it will bring to Boston &amp; Skegness. The document sets out the Government’s plan to transform the UK by spreading opportunity and prosperity to every community in every region of the country.</p>
<p>At the heart of this new way of making and implementing policy will be 12 bold national missions – all quantifiable and to be achieved by 2030. These missions will be cross-government, cross-society efforts.</p>
<p>By 2030, the missions set out by the Conservative Government will see:</p>
<ul>
<li>The rest of the country’s local public transport systems becoming much closer to London standards,</li>
<li>The large majority of the country gain access to 5G broadband,</li>
<li>90 per cent of primary children achieving the expected standard in reading, writing and maths – with the government’s education efforts focussed on the most disadvantaged parts of the country,</li>
<li>55 Education Investment Areas established in parts of the country with weakest school outcomes,</li>
<li>The mobilisation of £16 billion of local government pension schemes to turbocharge local investment,</li>
<li>Hundreds of thousands more people completing high quality skills training every year,</li>
<li>Disparities in healthy life expectancy narrowed,</li>
<li>The number of poor-quality rented homes halved,</li>
<li>Kings Cross style regeneration deals across 20 places in England,</li>
<li>The most run-down town centres and communities across the country rejuvenated,</li>
<li>£39 million to widen access to parks – particularly in areas with the lowest access to green space,</li>
<li>A significant decrease in serious crime in the most blighted areas,</li>
<li>Every part of England getting a devolution deal if they wish to.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Commenting, Matt Warman said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“This Conservative Government is committed to levelling up the whole of the UK – which means increasing wages, living standards, and quality of life for people in Boston &amp; Skegness too.</p>
<p>“That is why I am delighted to welcome the Levelling Up White Paper, which lays out the Government’s plan to create jobs, spread opportunity and empower communities across the UK, including in Boston &amp; Skegness.</p>
<p>“Through this plan, which builds on work over the last two years, this Conservative Government is delivering on its commitments to the British people by levelling up across the whole of the country.”</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Commenting, Prime Minister Boris Johnson said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“From day one, the defining mission of this government has been to level up this country, to break the link between geography and destiny so that no matter where you live you have access to the same opportunities.</p>
<p>“The challenges we face have been embedded over generations and cannot be dug out overnight, but this White Paper is the next crucial step.</p>
<p>“It is a vision for the future that will see public spending on R&amp;D increased in every part of the country; transport connectivity improving; faster broadband in every community; life expectancies rising; violent crime falling; schools improving; and private sector investment being unleashed.</p>
<p>“It is the most comprehensive, ambitious plan of its kind that this country has ever seen and it will ensure that the government continues to rise to the challenge and deliver for the people of the UK.”</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Commenting, Levelling Up Secretary Michael Gove said:</strong></p>
<blockquote><p>“The United Kingdom is an unparalleled success story. We have one of the world’s biggest and most dynamic economies. Ours is the world’s most spoken language. We have produced more Nobel Prize winners than any country other than America.</p>
<p>“But not everyone shares equally in the UK’s success. For decades, too many communities have been overlooked and undervalued. As some areas have flourished, others have been left in a cycle of decline. The UK has been like a jet firing on only one engine.</p>
<p>“Levelling Up and this White Paper is about ending this historic injustice and calling time on the postcode lottery.</p>
<p>“This will not be an easy task, and it won’t happen overnight, but our 12 new national levelling up missions will drive real change in towns and cities across the UK, so that where you live will no longer determine how far you can go.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Notes to editors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>On 2 February 2022, we published our Levelling Up White Paper, which sets out our plan to spread opportunity and reduce geographical inequality across the UK.</strong> The paper sets out 12 missions by which to measure our success at levelling up and a range of policies to achieve this ambition (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1052064/Levelling_Up_White_Paper_HR.pdf">DLUHC, Levelling Up White Paper, 2 February 2022</a>).</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Our Conservative record on levelling up the UK:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>Increasing overall skills spending by £3.8 billion over this Parliament, turbocharging productivity, wages and prospects for all. This real terms increase of 26 per cent will fund more hours learning for 16-19 year olds, expanding T Levels, more traineeships, funding the Lifetime Skills Guarantee, upgrading our further education college estate, quadrupling the number of places on our skills bootcamps, and spending record sums on apprenticeships (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Investing an additional £4.7 billion per year on schools funding, investing in our children. We are committing another £4.7 billion per year by 2024 to lift real terms per pupil spending to historic 2010 levels – a cash uplift of over £1,500 per pupil (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Increasing spending on healthcare by £44 billion over the course of this Parliament, improving health outcomes across our country. Resource spending on health services will increase to over £177 billion and we will deliver at least 100 Community Diagnostic Centres and 40 new hospitals (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Investing £11.5 billion through our Affordable Homes Programme, improving access to high quality affordable housing. Our Affordable Homes Programme will deliver up to 180,000 homes by 2028-9, with 65 per cent of the funding for delivery of homes outside London (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Establishing a £500 million Beeching Reversal Fund, reconnecting towns and villages across England. The Fund will restore rail lines in the north of England and Midlands, which were cut off from the rest of the network during the 1960s (<a href="https://assets-global.website-files.com/5da42e2cae7ebd3f8bde353c/5dda924905da587992a064ba_Conservative%202019%20Manifesto.pdf">Conservative Party, Manifesto 2019, 24 November 2019</a>).</li>
<li>Channelling investment in green industry across the UK, creating skilled and well-paid jobs. The £140 million Industrial Decarbonisation and Hydrogen Revenue Support scheme and £240 million Net Zero Hydrogen Fund will support innovative hydrogen projects across the UK. Our £160 million investment in offshore wind power hubs will create and safeguard at least 2,500 jobs in Teesside, Humberside and the North-East, ultimately enabling the sector to support up to 60,000 jobs by 2030 (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Improving local and civic infrastructure with our £4.8 billion Levelling Up Fund. We have announced the first £1.7 billion of allocations, which will fund over 100 projects to improve local infrastructure, including a new medical training facility in Bolton, the regeneration of Doncaster Town Centre, and upgrades to coastal attractions in Southend-on-Sea, among others (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Making £3.6 billion available for towns to kickstart local projects, driving growth and improving the environment in 101 towns. The Towns Fund will invest in transport, technology, skills, and culture in towns across the country (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Investing £830 million into 72 high streets and town centres, restoring high streets to their former glory. Our Future High Streets Fund is helping communities redevelop high streets, improve transport and access to town centres, and turn empty retail units into homes and workspace (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1028814/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
<li>Providing the largest funding settlement to the devolved administrations since devolution in 1998 – making sure everyone across the UK can access high-quality public services. This Budget increases Scottish Government funding by an average of £4.6 billion per year, Welsh Government funding by £2.5 billion per year, and £1.6 billion per year for the Northern Ireland Executive (<a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/1043689/Budget_AB2021_Web_Accessible.pdf">HM Treasury, Autumn Budget and Spending Review, 27 October 2021</a>).</li>
</ul>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Matt Warman has welcomed the Conservative Government’s Levelling Up White Paper and the boost it will bring to Boston &amp; Skegness by increasing wages, improving living standards, and regenerating local communities across the country. This is the next step on the Conservative Government’s mission to unite and level up Britain, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>oiomin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4036</id>
    <published>2022-02-03T10:50:05Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-03T10:50:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job advert: Caseworker for Tulip Siddiq MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/job-ad-caseworker-for-tulip-siddiq-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing date: Sunday 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Job title: Caseworker&lt;br&gt;Working for: Tulip Siddiq MP&lt;br&gt;Location: Constituency Office (Hampstead and Kilburn)&lt;br&gt;Salary: In line with IPSA payscales and dependent on experience&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team and support constituents as a caseworker. Previous experience of this or a similar role is desirable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The position will be based primarily in Tulip&amp;#8217;s constituency office in Hampstead and Kilburn and there will also be opportunities to work from the Parliamentary office in Westminster. We are happy to discuss options for flexible working at any stage including part-time remote working, flexi-time, job shares and other forms of flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assist with surgeries and other meetings and follow up as appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Respond to daily correspondence and enquiries from constituents.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage professionally, confidentially and sensitively with members of the public, through telephone enquiries, emails, social media and face to face.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Liaise with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve issues facing constituents.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Manage a large caseload of complex cases, exercising good judgement in taking decisions about how to procced and ensuring all identified actions are taken.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ensure all cases are logged in line with data protection legislation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Help other members of the team when needed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills Required&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Excellent written and oral communication skills as well as the usual IT skills.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clear and concise letter writing style.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to prioritise a demanding workload to meet deadlines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to deal with issues sensitively and in a confidential manner.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ability to work effectively in a small team.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sympathetic to the aims and objectives of the Labour Party.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview/Start dates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interviews will be held in London the week starting 14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; February and will involve written tasks. The start date will be as soon as possible after that, to be agreed with the successful candidate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applicants should send their CV and a one page covering letter to &lt;a href="m&amp;#x61;&amp;#x69;l&amp;#116;&amp;#x6f;:&amp;#116;&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6c;i&amp;#x70;&amp;#x2e;s&amp;#105;&amp;#x64;d&amp;#105;&amp;#x71;&amp;#x2e;m&amp;#x70;&amp;#x40;p&amp;#97;&amp;#x72;l&amp;#105;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6d;e&amp;#x6e;&amp;#x74;.&amp;#117;&amp;#x6b;"&gt;&amp;#x74;&amp;#x75;li&amp;#x70;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#115;id&amp;#x64;&amp;#x69;&amp;#113;.m&amp;#x70;&amp;#x40;&amp;#112;ar&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x69;am&amp;#x65;&amp;#x6e;&amp;#116;.u&amp;#x6b;&lt;/a&gt; with the subject heading ‘Caseworker – Full name’. Due to the expected high volume of applications, only successful those applicants selected for interview will receive a response.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Closing date: Sunday 13th February 2022 Job title: CaseworkerWorking for: Tulip Siddiq MPLocation: Constituency Office (Hampstead and Kilburn)Salary: In line with IPSA payscales and dependent on experience Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team and support constituents as a caseworker. Previous […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Taggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5524</id>
    <published>2022-02-02T19:07:02Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-02T19:07:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Job ad"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>City Council Leader Responds to “Levelling Up” Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today Nottingham City Council Leader, Cllr David Mellen responded to the Government&amp;#8217;s long overdue &amp;#8220;Levelling Up&amp;#8221; White Paper, cautiously welcoming the next steps on devolution but highlighting that these words do little to reverse the damage that twelve years of unprecedented Conservative cuts has caused to Nottingham. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cllr Mellen said: “Nottingham people will hear the
Government talking about ‘levelling up’ today, but they will wonder what it
really means for them in their daily lives and what it means for the place they
call home. That is the big test for the Government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Words from Government Ministers won’t deal with the
soaring cost of energy and food or assist with the enormous pressures on
household budgets. In April many of the people I represent will see big
increases in National Insurance, steeply rising prices for home-energy and the
government’s adult social care levy added to Council Tax bills yet again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I’ve worked proactively with colleagues in other Councils
across Nottinghamshire to make the case to government about the investment our
area desperately needs after 12 long years of cuts and underfunding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We’ve always been pro- devolution in Nottingham, but
detail in terms of additional powers and new investment must be forthcoming. If
Government is serious about genuine devolution for our area it has to be about
more investment, better transport infrastructure, higher skills for local
people and creating more good jobs in our area.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The East Midlands region has suffered greatly over the
past decade with chronic under investment. Our residents and our businesses
expect and deserve much better than the sustained funding cuts we’ve seen and
the huge regional funding variations with the East Midlands often losing out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“If the government is finally recognising that to create
stronger regional growth that the investment is required I absolutely welcome
that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It is imperative that the Minister matches his word with
deeds and begins to deliver in a meaningful way.&amp;nbsp; As a Core City,
Nottingham has much to be proud of and much to build on. We have ambitious plans
to truly unlock the potential of our area and be at the heart of growth in our
region, plans that are ready to be put into action if we get the green light on
funding.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I urge the government to work with us, to adequately fund
local public services, which continue to be under severe strain, to invest in
the huge potential of Nottingham, Nottinghamshire and the East Midlands and to
start to deliver for people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/"&gt;City Council Leader Responds to &amp;#8220;Levelling Up&amp;#8221; Announcement&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Today Nottingham City Council Leader, Cllr David Mellen responded to the Government’s long overdue “Levelling Up” White Paper, cautiously welcoming the next steps on devolution but highlighting that these words do little to reverse the damage that twelve years of unprecedented Conservative cuts has caused to Nottingham.  Cllr Mellen said: “Nottingham people will hear the...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/02/02/city-council-leader-responds-to-levelling-up-announcement/">City Council Leader Responds to “Levelling Up” Announcement</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2703</id>
    <published>2022-02-02T15:06:59Z</published>
    <updated>2022-02-02T15:06:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bert Warne awarded Freedom of City in Southampton</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/01/31/bert-warne-awarded-freedom-of-city-in-southampton/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Couldn’t be happier to be with the Remarkable Bert Warne, former Far East Prisoner of War, when he received his Freedom of the City of Southampton. Congratulations Bert.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/01/31/bert-warne-awarded-freedom-of-city-in-southampton/">Bert Warne awarded Freedom of City in Southampton</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=4951</id>
    <published>2022-01-31T10:22:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-31T10:22:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cllr Linda Bailey, Rest in Peace</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/cllr-linda-bailey-rest-peace" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of our most dedicated, hugely respected and long-standing campaigners, Linda Bailey, sadly passed away on the 25th January 2022. Our thoughts are with her family and friends, who also very recently lost Linda’s husband, Bill.
During her decades of support for our Association and the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/cllr-linda-bailey-rest-peace</id>
    <published>2022-01-27T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Holocaust Memorial Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/01/holocaust-memorial-day-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8359" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/01/holocaust-memorial-day-2/220127-holocaust-landscape-002/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=1965%2C1394&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1965,1394" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone XR&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1643037106&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.25&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.04&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="220127 holocaust landscape (002)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=300%2C213&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=790%2C560&amp;ssl=1"/>
<p>It was an honour to sign the Holocaust Education Trust UK Book of Commitment earlier this week ahead of Holocaust Memorial Day today. </p>



<p>It is important that we all take time to remember the millions of Jews and others who died in the Holocaust and pay tribute to the survivors. </p>



<p>We must also redouble our efforts to stand up to all forms of racism and prejudice. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8359" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/01/holocaust-memorial-day-2/220127-holocaust-landscape-002/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=1965%2C1394&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1965,1394" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone XR&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1643037106&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;4.25&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;500&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.04&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="220127 holocaust landscape (002)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=300%2C213&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/220127-holocaust-landscape-002.jpg?fit=790%2C560&amp;ssl=1"/>It was an honour to sign the Holocaust Education Trust UK Book of Commitment earlier this week ahead of Holocaust Memorial Day today. It is important that we all take time to remember the millions of Jews and others who died in the Holocaust and pay tribute to the survivors. We must also redouble our […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8358</id>
    <published>2022-01-27T08:46:55Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-27T08:46:55Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Susah bermain akan membuat penghasilan macet dan berimbas pada kehidupan. Tapi hal tersebut bisa diatas dengan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Permainan taruhan sepakbola sudah menjadi kegiatan sehari hari bagi banyak orang. Tua muda atau pun dewasa memainkan permainan yang satu ini. Tak heran sebenarnya karena bola adalah permainan berbagai kalangan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sudah ada kecintaan terhadap permainan bola membuat permainan versi judi akan disukai. Hanya dengan menebak permainan sepele saja sudah akan bisa menghasilkan untung siapa yang tahan? Oleh karena itu tak heran minat memainkan taruhan sepakbola semakin membludak akhir akhir ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapi, ada dilema yang membuat permainantaruhan sepakbola banyak penggemar terjadi. Dilema tersebut adalah susah bermain. Banyak pemain akan membuat server sering mengalami trouble yang berakibat pada susah bermain. Sudah sering terjadi seperti pada pendaftaran cpns yang selalu membuat server breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oleh sebab itu, untuk mengatasi permasalahan yang akan terjadi. Pastikan diri Anda menggunakan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Dengan link tersebut semuanya akan bisa teratasi, tetapi juga akan ada cara lainnya yang mungkin akan berfungsi untuk Anda. Tergantung dari permasalahan yang anda alami.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif Resmi&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untuk permasalahan link yang mengalami breakdown, Anda bisa menggunakan link alternatif. Setiap agen penyedia permainan pasti menyediakan link situs taruhan sepakbola terpercaya alternatif. Dengan link tersebut, Anda akan mendapatkan bantuan untuk tetap bermain meskipun server sudah tidak bisa dibuka karena kepenuhan user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link alternatif ini adalah lalu lintas alternatif bila lalu lintas pokok mengalami masalah. Jadi, lalu lintas browsing Anda dialihkan kepada cara lain. Meskipun menggunakan cara lain Anda akan tetap bisa digunakan dengan mudah tanpa harus melakukan hal khusus. Untuk menggunakannya, Anda hanya perlu mengakses seperti biasanya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lantas dimana tempat mendapatkan link alternatif? Tepatnya anda bisa mendapatkan link alternatif pada bagian laman pengenal. Atau mungkin lebih amannya Anda bertanya kepada costumer service. Mereka pasti akan memberikan link alternatif agar anggota anggotanya tetap bisa bermain meskipun situs utama breakdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bila Anda belum sempat mendapatkan link alternatif. Bergabunglah kepada forum diskusi karena biasanya mereka akan mendiskusikan link alternatif juga. Dengan begini Anda akan mendapatkan informasi yang bagus mengenai link terpercaya. Link terpercaya seperti ini pastinya akan berguna untuk Anda dapatkan permainan yang akurat serta aman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Vpn, Proxy, Kpn Tunnel untuk Situs Terblokir&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sedangkan untuk permasalahan link live casino taruhan sepakbola terpercaya yang mengalami blokir. Anda bisa menggunakan vpn, proxy, kpn tunnel dan penyamar alamat ip. Dengan alamat ip yang disamarkan pasti akan tetap membuka situs yang mengalami blokir. Alat alat seperti ini banyak jenisnya namun yang direkomendasikan adalah vpn, proxy dan kpn tunnel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dengan ketiga alat tersebut, Anda akan bisa membuka situs yang terblokir tanpa susah. Untuk vpn cara kerjanya dengan aplikasi kebanyakan, sedangkan untuk proxy dan kpn tunnel kebanyakan cara kerjanya dengan browser. Tetapi tetap ada cara lainnya yang bisa Anda pergunakan sesuai dengan selera pribadi diri.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cara kerja yang digunakan oleh alat alat ini sebenarnya tidak jaug berbeda dengan link w2ebsite taruhan sepakbola terpercaya. Tetapi disini alamat yang anda gunakan tetap sama dengan alamat utamanya. Tidak ada alamat yang berbeda karena yang akan disamarkan adalah ip Anda. Sebenarnya cara seperti ini akan lebih aman dibandingkan sebelumnya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semua masalah susah bermain pasti akan bisa teratasi bila Anda tahu permasalahannya. Sekarang zaman sudah canggih dan semuanya bisa Anda atasi tanpa perlu bantuan teknisi. Banyak aplikasi dan solusi untuk mengatasi permasalahan susah bermain. Oleh sebab itu selalu catat link website taruhan sepakbola terpercaya dari tempat Anda bermain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca Juga Tentang: &lt;a href="https://www.chrisleslie.org/provider-situs-slot-online-gacor-jackpot-terlengkap-2022/"&gt;Provider Situs Slot Online Gacor Jackpot Terlengkap 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain – Susah bermain akan membuat penghasilan macet dan berimbas pada kehidupan. Tapi hal tersebut bisa diatas dengan link situs judi bola terpercaya. Permainan taruhan sepakbola sudah menjadi kegiatan sehari hari bagi banyak orang. Tua muda atau pun dewasa memainkan permainan yang satu ini. Tak heran […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/">Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=27</id>
    <published>2022-01-25T06:31:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-25T06:31:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Judi Bola"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Letter to Buckinghamshire Council on the Local Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/01/my-letter-to-buckinghamshire-council-on-the-local-plan/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Buckinghamshire Council’s Local Plan will shape future development in Wycombe for years to come. The Plan is currently at an early stage of the consultation. I have written to Ian Thompson, Corporate Director of Planning, Growth and Sustainability at Buckinghamshire Council, setting out my position on a range of issues. I strongly encourage all of my constituents to take part in the consultation so that your voices are heard and can shape the future of our area. The consultation can […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18524</id>
    <published>2022-01-20T12:51:04Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-20T12:51:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Buckinghamshire County Council"/>
    <category term="Bucks County Council"/>
    <category term="Planning"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jakson</name>
							<uri>https://jakson.co</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Residents&#8217; Zoom meeting]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/</id>
		<updated>2022-01-11T18:16:55Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-23T12:19:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="In Parliament"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subscribe to my future newsletters&#160;here Dear Constituent, I hope you&#8217;re keeping safe and well. Please find my latest newsletter, with news of what&#8217;s been happening in Parliament and what&#8217;s coming up with Brexit. I&#8217;m also holding another zoom residents&#8217; meeting, on Friday 27th November &#8211; please get in touch for the details if you would [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-residents-zoom-meeting/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters&nbsp;<a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/1507626306.png"></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>I hope you&#8217;re keeping safe and well. Please find my latest newsletter, with news of what&#8217;s been happening in Parliament and what&#8217;s coming up with Brexit. I&#8217;m also holding another zoom residents&#8217; meeting, on Friday 27th November &#8211; please get in touch for the details if you would like to join.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Invitation to Zoom residents&#8217; meeting&nbsp;&#8211; 7.30pm, Friday 27th November&nbsp;2020:</span></strong></p>
<p>Thank you to everyone who has joined my virtual residents&#8217; meetings so far. My next residents&#8217; meeting will be held at 7.30pm on Friday 27th November&nbsp;2020, again via&nbsp;Zoom, to discuss the latest on Brexit and Covid-19 measures, and answer any questions you may have.</p>
<p>If you’re a constituent and would like to attend, please reply to this email or email nigel.mills.mp@parliament.uk and I’ll send you the link to join the meeting.</p>
<p>As always, if you have a personal or specific issue you would like to raise with me, or for a virtual surgery appointment, do also continue to contact me by replying to this&nbsp;email or by ringing 01773 744341.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit update:</span></strong></p>
<p>Time is now getting very tight for a future partnership with the EU to be negotiated, agreed, ratified and in place in time for the end of the Transition period on 31 December 2020. The expectation seems to be that a deal will be done in the next few days or not at all (or at least not until next year).</p>
<p>The issues seem to be much the same as in my last update, namely fishing, equivalence of regulatory standards between the UK and the EU (the so called level playing field) and state aid rules. I&nbsp; have set out a summary of the these issues and potential areas of compromise below.</p>
<p>I remain of the view that the best way forward for the UK would be to agree a good deal with the EU covering not just trade but also security, law and order, travel rights for citizens etc. That said, if we can’t agree a deal which respects our right to govern ourselves than we should walk away. I have seen no sign that the Government will give up this key red line but equally there will need to be some compromises to achieve a deal. Avoiding tariffs on imports and exports is a huge prize that will make the move out of the EU much smoother. As vice-chair of the Select Committee scrutinising the negotiations with the EU, I have been examining many of the key issues for the negotiations and our preparedness– you can see the details <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-exiting-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-exiting-the-european-union">here</a> – and I am looking forward to in depth scrutiny of any deal in the coming weeks.</p>
<p><strong>Main outstanding issues:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fishing is a totemic Brexit issue, and out fishing industry has suffered especially badly over the last 40 years. Leaving the EU gives us the opportunity to rebuild our industry and catch a much higher proportion of the fish in our waters. Of course this means that EU fishing communities will lose out. The arguments are around how the quotas for each type of fish are calculated and how they are allocated between UK and EU fleets, with the UK wanting the default position under international maritime agreements of annual negotiations and the EU wanting to a long term agreement that retains most of their current access. The further challenge is that much of the fish caught in UK waters is exported to the EU. In reality it will take us many years to increase our fishing fleet and processing capacity so it would seem to me that a deal could be found based around gradual reductions in EU access to our waters via some form of transition.</li>
<li>The EU’s original negotiation position on the level playing field demanded dynamic alignment ie the UK would have to follow not just current EU rules but whatever they changed them to in key areas like environment, workers rights, taxation etc. In their view this would prevent us competing unfairly with them. This demand was very different to the wording agreed in the Political Declaration agreed a year ago which envisaged a non-regression clause ie we would not reduce key regulatory standards below the levels as at 31 December 2020. We could clearly never agree to blindly follow future EU rules over which we had no say. The discussion appears to have reverted back to non-regression clauses but with issues over how either side could enforce action against any breaches. Given that we are strengthening environmental standards and already go further than the EU rules in many areas on workers rights, I would not be too concerned about agreeing not to reduce standards in these areas. It would then seem possible to agree that if either side did make fundamental changes, the other side could give notice to terminate the trade deal either entirely on in part if they considered the issue serious enough.</li>
<li>State Aid rules restrict how much subsidy Governments can give to businesses. Currently if the UK government wishes to provide State Aid, we, like all EU members, need permission from the EU Commission. They also review whether policies like low tax rates or exemptions effectively represent State Aid. The UK has generally not been keen on State Aid in comparison to many other EU countries. Originally the EU seemed to want the UK to remain subject to the EU rules – clearly we could not as an independent country be in a position of following EU rules and especially not seeking permission from the EU. The talk seem to have progressed now to the UK being willing to set out rules which hare equivalent to EU ones on where State Aid can be used (indeed the WTO requires such rules anyway) but the dispute remains how these rules will be enforced so a UK government couldn’t just ignore them. The proposal seems to be for some sort of independent regulator but it strikes me that again, in extremis, giving notice to cancel the trade&nbsp; agreement would be an effective remedy.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Latest Covid-19 guidance:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can find the current Covid-19 guidance <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>, along with the support available for residents (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/worker-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/worker-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>) and businesses (<a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>). The latest business grants for businesses affected by the recent restrictions are now available through the local Council, which you can find <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/covid-19-business-grants/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/covid-19-business-grants/">here</a>. For constituents self-isolating who are struggling financially, there is also the £500 self-isolation NHS Test &amp; Trace Support payment, which you can find further details on the eligibility criteria for <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/benefits/test-and-trace-support-payment/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/benefits/test-and-trace-support-payment/">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">If you have any queries about the guidance or potential support available, as always, please don&#8217;t hesitate to get in touch.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Defence Spending update:&nbsp;</strong></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Last week, the Prime Minister announced an additional £24.1 billion in funding for our country&#8217;s defence, to help safeguard our security and revitalise our shipbuilding industry. Over the next four years, this investment will create 10,000 extra jobs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">This is the largest investment in our defence industry in the last 30 years and&nbsp;</span>will allow the Government to invest in cutting-edge technology &#8211;&nbsp;positioning the UK as a global leader in domains such as cyber and space and cementing the UK’s position as the largest defence spender in Europe and the second largest in NATO.</p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">I welcomed this update, and the increased investment, during the subsequent debate on it in the House. I also highlighted the need to spend this additional money wisely and efficiently, and buy from British suppliers wherever possible. You can find the debate in full <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-19a.487.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g501.6" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-19a.487.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g501.6">here</a>&nbsp;and read more about the investment <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/defence-secures-largest-investment-since-the-cold-war" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/defence-secures-largest-investment-since-the-cold-war">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">In Parliament:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">In Parliament I&#8217;ve continued my work on anti-corruption and pensions, with questions in the House on preventing economic crime to further reduce corruption. You can find my question to the Chancellor in full <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-09b.619.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g627.3" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-09b.619.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g627.3">here</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">With a local focus, I&#8217;ve also highlighted the importance of supporting the recovery of our high streets from the challenges caused by Covid-19, with one example being the recent announcement of the closure of many Argos stores, including the one in Alfreton. I know many independent retailers are also struggling (even though they&#8217;ve come up with many innovative ways to continue trading during this time), and so I will continue to raise this issue. You can find my most recent question in Parliament <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-05c.483.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g488.2" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-05c.483.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g488.2">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Lastly, on a positive note, I welcomed the announcement of an additional bank holiday for the Queen&#8217;s platinum jubilee, and raised the issue of support or grants for community groups to hopefully be able to organise events to commemorate and celebrate this big event &#8211; you can find more on this debate <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-12b.1086.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g1093.3" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-12b.1086.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g1093.3">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Pension Schemes Bill:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">Earlier this month, I also contributed to a debate in Parliament on the new Pensions Schemes Bill, which continues to progress through the Houses (you can find out more about the bill <a href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-8693/" data-cke-saved-href="https://commonslibrary.parliament.uk/research-briefings/cbp-8693/">here</a>). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">As a member of the Work &amp; Pensions Select Committee, I&#8217;ve been working on this Bill, and I took the opportunity of the debate in the Commons on the latest stage to highlight various amendments I was supporting, including the importance of encouraging a greater take-up of&nbsp;independent free guidance to help people decide which pension option&nbsp;is best for them, scam prevention measures, improving pension dashboards and encouraging pension funds to support investment in climate goals and positive social activities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">I&#8217;m really keen for to make pensions guidance as close to mandatory as possible, for instance through auto-enrolment onto the pensions dashboard, as the current take-up of the free, good quality advice provided by Pensions Wise guidance service is very low. I will continue to push the Government to introduce measures to improve and promote usage of pensions advice services.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can find my speeches in full, and the rest of the debate,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-16b.55.2&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g68.1" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-11-16b.55.2&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g68.1">here</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Select Committees:</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">In other Work &amp; Pensions Committee inquiries, we&#8217;re looking into Universal Credit and the wait for a first payment, the disability employment gap and DWP&#8217;s response to the Covid-19 pandemic, including the use of foodbanks and support available for people experiencing food and fuel poverty (which you can find more on <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/news/130962/committee-holds-session-on-support-for-people-claiming-benefits/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/news/130962/committee-holds-session-on-support-for-people-claiming-benefits/">here</a>). You can find more about all of these current inquiries and evidence sessions&nbsp;<a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/164/work-and-pensions-committee/">here</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: verdana;">You can also find full details of the evidence sessions recently held by the Committee on the Future Relationship with the European Union, as mentioned above, <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/">here</a>.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" rel="noopener">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">GDPR and privacy notice:</span></strong></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com?wpmllink=56631c0a7eeed56aa432bf53c6b13695&amp;history_id=83&amp;subscriber_id=5667" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com?wpmllink=56631c0a7eeed56aa432bf53c6b13695&amp;history_id=83&amp;subscriber_id=5667">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/Nigel-signature.jpg"></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grant Shapps welcomes hospital improvements as he meets new NHS Trust CEO</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/grant-shapps-meets-new-nhs-trust-ceo/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=grant-shapps-meets-new-nhs-trust-ceo" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular">
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><p><strong>MP for Welwyn Hatfield Grant Shapps recently met with Adam Sewell-Jones, the new CEO of the East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust to discuss health services in the area.</strong></p>
<p>During the meeting, Mr Shapps was updated on the current status of the Trust with regard to dealing with the current omicron variant of covid, as well as new investments being made in the local Trust to improve the quality of its services.</p>
<p>Key amongst the announced investments Grant and Adam discussed was a new Community Diagnostic Centre will be built in Welwyn Hatfield, one of 40 across the country – providing a one-stop-shop for key testing to boost early diagnoses and speed up and increase referrals.</p>
<p>The Centres will provide a full range of scans and tests to patients to catch illnesses at the earliest signs – increasing NHS capacity and saving lives as the NHS aims to work through the historic elective backlog caused by the pandemic.</p>
<p>Local MP Grant Shapps has welcomed the announcement that the QEII centre in Welwyn Garden City has been selected as one of 40 sites across England for a new Community Diagnostic Centre to be built, with an initial investment of £2.85 million awarded by the Department for Health &amp; Social Care.</p>
<p>The centre will provide services closer to home for people in Welwyn Hatfield to meet rising demand, as part of the Conservative Government’s plan to tackle the NHS backlog and catch health issues quickly.</p>
<p>The QEII’s new Community Diagnostic Centre will achieve earlier diagnoses for patients through easier, faster, and more direct access to the full range of scans and tests needed to understand patients’ symptoms – including breathlessness and cancer symptoms.</p>
<p>The centre will also help reduce the risk of Covid transmission and contribute to the NHS’ net zero efforts by reducing the number of patients journeys required in Welwyn Hatfield through providing multiple scans and tests in a single visit.</p>
<p>Also on the cards for the local health service is a £2.4 million investment to create three new procedure rooms, split between the QEII and Lister hospitals.</p>
<p>The rooms will provide extra capacity for minor procedures, freeing up valuable space in operation theatres- improving theatre productivity and supporting efforts to reduce waiting list.</p>
<p>Adam Sewell-Jones said: “It was great to meet Mr Shapps and to share our plans for services in the area, including investing in the New QEII Hospital and working hard to reduce waiting times.</p>
<p>“Work begins shortly on a new procedure room at the New QEII, which will allow for minor procedures to take place locally. This means we can more effectively use our main theatre space at Lister Hospital to treat people who are waiting for more serious operations.</p>
<p>“We are also ensuring better access to diagnostics at the New QEII, such as MRI, CT, X-rays and ultrasound – seven days a week, and with extended opening hours. This will help us to diagnose conditions more quickly.</p>
<p>“The urgent treatment centre at the New QEII is now closed overnight because there were very low numbers of people needing care in those hours. It remains open and well-used during the day and I urge people to continue to seek treatment there for minor injuries and illnesses.</p>
<p>“I’d like to thank the public for their support for our hardworking staff and the Trust while we continue to work through the effects of the pandemic.”</p>
<p>Mr Shapps said: “We know that many people have not been coming forward for key tests throughout the pandemic, which has contributed to the backlog, and can result in worsening health outcomes.</p>
<p>“The new Community Diagnostic Centre will help deliver better services for people across Welwyn Hatfield. By allowing problems to be detected earlier, better treatment can be given to patients.</p>
<p>“Through investing in early diagnosis and increasing NHS capacity we will be able to treat serious illnesses sooner and save lives – levelling up health outcomes across the country. Alongside these new procedure rooms, things are looking positive for our local health services.”</p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/grant-shapps-meets-new-nhs-trust-ceo/">Grant Shapps welcomes hospital improvements as he meets new NHS Trust CEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>MP for Welwyn Hatfield Grant Shapps recently met with Adam Sewell-Jones, the new CEO of the East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust to discuss health services in the area.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/grant-shapps-meets-new-nhs-trust-ceo/">Grant Shapps welcomes hospital improvements as he meets new NHS Trust CEO</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=40083</id>
    <published>2022-01-07T16:41:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-07T16:41:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccination Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/vaccination-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=vaccination-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The Lights in Andover is one of 10 additional GP-led vaccination sites opening up in Hampshire over the next couple of days to deliver the lifesaving vaccine to the most vulnerable.  </p>



<p>This is great news for Andover and the surrounding villages where the most vulnerable residents will have easier access to a vaccination site when their time comes to receive it. For now, vaccinations remain limited to the most vulnerable and the NHS will be contacting recipients. You can find further information about the vaccination programme on the NHS website. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.england.nhs.uk/coronavirus/covid-19-vaccination-programme/?fbclid=IwAR1fpUmKNp4yRr6QmFb7LJiCh5LvoLTJx6-Qah39dx87VAq6ASeUi1ZiApM" target="_blank">https://www.england.nhs.uk/…/covid-19-vaccination…/</a>This is more progress on the path to recovery and a bit of good news as we keep up the fight against C-19. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Lights in Andover is one of 10 additional GP-led vaccination sites opening up in Hampshire over the next couple of days to deliver the lifesaving vaccine to the most vulnerable. This is great news for Andover and the surrounding villages where the most vulnerable residents will have easier access to a vaccination site when […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2829</id>
    <published>2021-12-21T14:26:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-21T14:26:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas and New Year Office Opening Hours</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-and-new-year-office-opening-hours/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;"&gt;Information about office opening hours &lt;span style="color:#06396a;"&gt;and who to contact for support over the festive period&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_empty_space"   style="height: 20px" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_empty_space_inner"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " &gt;
		&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Due to the festive break, my office will close from 22 December &amp;#8211;  3 January. From 4th January, my team and I will be here to help you with any issue you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be periodically checking my email and voicemail over Christmas and the New Year, so if you have a very urgent query you can contact me as below. All other correspondence will be dealt with on our return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a very urgent query, please email details to &lt;a href="mailto:abrahamsd@parliament.uk"&gt;abrahamsd@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;. If you do not have access to emails, you can call &amp;amp; leave a voicemail regarding your urgent matter with details on 07494553005 or 07495995509.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other enquiries will be dealt with when the office re-opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team and I would like to wish you all a very Merry Christmas and a happy &amp;amp; healthy 2022!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debbie Abrahams MP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham East &amp;amp; Saddleworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful contacts/information for the festive period:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus"&gt;Government guidance&lt;/a&gt; for Christmas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Metropolitan Borough Council – Full information about Oldham Council closures and contact numbers can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.oldham.gov.uk/christmasclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Homelessness Advice Team: Outreach Service 0161 770 4605&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Emergency 24 hour homelessness team: 0800 988 7061&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Coronavirus helpline: 0161 770 7007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social services (out of hours emergency only) –  0161 770 6936&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council First Response team – 0161 770 2222&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police General Switchboard (24 hours) – 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police emergencies (24 hours) – 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical emergencies:  visit your local &lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/service-search" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hospital&lt;/a&gt; or call 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-urgent medical advice – 111&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas (24 hour emergency helpline) – 0800 111 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity North West (24 hour emergency helpline) – 105&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Utilities website and details &lt;a href="https://www.unitedutilities.com/emergencies/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizens Advice Bureau national phone service: &lt;a href="tel:08001448848"&gt;0800 144 8848&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater Manchester Law Centre: 0161 769 2244&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Foodbank: &lt;a href="tel:0161 622 1061"&gt;0161 622 1061&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Welfare Rights: 0161 770 6655&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcho.co.uk/contact-us/ways-to-contact-us/"&gt;First Choice Homes Oldham:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact centre: 0161 393 7117&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For heating issues, ring SURE group: 03333 212797&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emergency repairs: 0161 770 2222.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"&gt;&lt;h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;"&gt;Feel strongly about this article? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"&gt;&lt;a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact"&gt;Contact Debbie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-and-new-year-office-opening-hours/"&gt;Christmas and New Year Office Opening Hours&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk"&gt;Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-and-new-year-office-opening-hours/">Christmas and New Year Office Opening Hours</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6912</id>
    <published>2021-12-20T11:14:10Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-20T11:14:10Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Statement on Plan B Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/planb" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Lots of people have been getting in touch to ask about my position on the Government's decision to move to Plan B and the votes in Parliament this week. Due to medical reasons I was unable to be in Parliament to vote, however, I wanted to set out my position on this important matter.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/planb</id>
    <published>2021-12-15T09:40:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-12-15T09:40:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Tory plan will undermine our human rights]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2021/12/14/uk-government-trashing-human-rights-act-and-devolution-settlement/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10234</id>
		<updated>2021-12-15T09:29:14Z</updated>
		<published>2021-12-14T16:18:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Controversial reforms &#8216;hot on heels of multiple, dreadful pieces of legislation designed to trash rights&#8217; Today in Parliament, the UK Justice Secretary launched a review of human rights laws that Amnesty, Liberty &#38; human rights lawyers say will in fact actually deprive so many people of many rights. The highly controversial reforms will create a ... <a title="Tory plan will undermine our human rights" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2021/12/14/uk-government-trashing-human-rights-act-and-devolution-settlement/" aria-label="More on Tory plan will undermine our human rights">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/final_61b89b9a5c4abd0044e8c6ff_87889.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="18375076" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Benefits of Distance Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">Right now, the pros of distance learning in school are not at all obvious to thousands of teachers. It seems that distance education is nothing but inconvenience, a threat to discipline and academic performance. But it isn't: distance education has many advantages. 

<strong>Here are some of them.</strong>

<strong> The opportunity to work with each student individually. </strong>

<strong>1) Distance teaching technology helps to find a personal approach to each student. </strong>There are times when a shy child is shy to work actively in a classroom where twenty classmates are staring at him. 
But such a shy kid feels freer at a distance, asks the teacher questions in a chat room, and successfully completes tasks. And the teacher can choose additional tasks for such students, which correspond to their aptitudes, to maintain an interest in learning. 
Distance learning is a great chance to get to know your students better.

<strong> 2) Automate routine processes.</strong>

Simply put, technology can take over the most boring part of a teacher's job. For example, checking homework and compiling classroom statistics. On average, using technologies with automatic checking will save at least 1-2 hours per day, if not more. This system works very simply: the teacher goes to the site, selects a subject, class and topic, finds the appropriate assignment and sends a link to the students, and then just look at the same site to see how they did. 

<strong> 3) A chance to learn new technology. </strong>

The high demand for teachers with distance learning experience is a reality. Knowing how to use interactive learning platforms, Google Docs, electronic workbooks, and video conferencing services increases your value in the job market and gives you a chance to find a part-time job at an online school (and there are many such schools, they are growing and in need of new personnel). But even more valuable are the skills to organize your time, work with students remotely, and be able to monitor and motivate them from a distance. If you can manage it now, by the next school year you can try your hand at online tutoring.

<strong>4) Game assignments. </strong>

Distance learning involves a very active use of digital technology. Including gamified tasks: online games, quizzes, interactive tasks for ingenuity. Let us not forget that for any child the game is the most natural way to learn the world. And older students like these more dry tasks from the textbook. Games not only make learning fun - they help to evaluate progress and bring to school an element of healthy competition. Learning games are not part of the official curriculum, but we recommend that you dilute regular assignments with them. A child who enjoys learning will make more progress than one who is bored in class.

<strong>Minuses of Distance Education</strong>

<strong>1. Limited choice</strong>

Unfortunately, not everything can be learned remotely. In some cases, you cannot do without practical studies under the guidance of an experienced tutor. You can study history or literature remotely, you can become an excellent designer or programmer. But you cannot learn to be a pilot or a surgeon.

Perhaps that will change in the near future. One day, virtual reality technology will allow people from different parts of the world to participate in collaborative lab work. When that happens, the list of professions and skills that can be learned remotely will greatly expand.

<strong>2. Lack of face-to-face interaction</strong>
Face-to-face learning is not only valuable as a set of knowledge. An important element of offline learning is personal communication. While getting traditional higher education, a student spends several years simmering in the swirling cauldron of university life. He interacts with professors and classmates in an informal setting. These interactions can generate amazing ideas and dramatically change people's lives.

<strong>3. the absence of positive "side effects</strong>
The fact that distance learning gives a person a specific set of knowledge can be considered not only a plus, but also a minus. By studying remotely, a person deprives himself of many of the positive "side effects" of academic education.

For example, the process of taking notes on long lectures trains the speed of writing, develops mechanical memory, and teaches on the fly to isolate the most important fragments from the flow of information. All these skills are very useful in everyday life, but distance learning does not provide them.</pre>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/">Benefits of Distance Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Right now, the pros of distance learning in school are not at all obvious to thousands of teachers. It seems that distance education is nothing but inconvenience, a threat to discipline and academic performance. But […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/benefits-of-distance-education/">Benefits of Distance Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=191</id>
    <published>2021-11-10T09:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-10T09:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Leads a Debate on Sewage Pollution in Whitburn</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-leads-a-debate-on-sewage-pollution-in-whitburn/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Last week, I lead an important debate in Parliament on sewage pollution in Whitburn, an issue that many people in our town are rightly concerned about.</p>



<p>South Shields, like many other coastal towns across the country, takes pride in ensuring our beaches demonstrate the highest environmental standards to make it a place for everyone to enjoy. Yet raw sewage dumping at the Whitburn end of Seaburn beach and into the North Sea has caused problems for decades.</p>



<p>I thought it was important to remind the Government that the European Court of Justice ruled in 2012 that the UK had failed to fulfil its obligations and breached standards for treating wastewater in relation to the sewage dumping at this location. And that in 2020, the European Court of Justice found again that the levels of sewage dumping at Whitburn continued to breach standards.</p>



<p>As the sewage flows, our gorgeous beach is continually damaged. The wildlife and sea life that once inhabited our rock pools is disappearing. Dolphins and seals, regulars on our coastline, now swim through sewage soup and the seagrass meadows in the nearby River Tyne estuary are being ruined. This is wholly unacceptable.</p>



<p>In the nine years that I have been the MP for South Shields and part of this campaign alongside constituent Mr Latimer and the Whitburn Residents Forum, I have seen us stonewalled by various Departments, bodies, companies, Secretaries of State and Ministers who claim this sewage dumping is a figment of our imagination. It is not. We know that, because we live there.</p>



<p>Sewage has rightly been the topic of conversation in recent weeks after the Governments shameful behaviour voting down an amendment from the Lords on the Environment Bill that would have legally required water companies to take all reasonable steps to ensure untreated sewage is not discharged from storm overflows.</p>



<p>The Government has subsequently U-turned over the sewage amendment after fierce backlash from Labour MP’s, campaigners and the public, however, it is a disingenuous attempt to appease the public. If the Government really did care about sewage dumping, why have they sat back while knowing that Whitburn is continually being blighted.</p>



<p>I concluded my opening speech by pleading with the Minister Rebecca Pow to do once and for all what her predecessors have refused to, and outline what steps she is going to take to clean up our beach. The Minister came to the debate unprepared and failed to answer my questions but did subsequently agreed to meet with me.</p>



<p>You can read my full speech <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2021-10-27/debates/2FE67ECE-5C5C-4910-876B-9610627E645A/SewagePollutionWhitburn">here.</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week, I lead an important debate in Parliament on sewage pollution in Whitburn, an issue that many people in our town are rightly concerned about. South Shields, like many other coastal towns across the country, takes pride in ensuring our beaches demonstrate the highest environmental standards to make it a place for everyone to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=3143</id>
    <published>2021-11-04T12:52:50Z</published>
    <updated>2021-11-04T12:52:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="Sewage"/>
    <category term="Whitburn beach"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Community Spirit Within The Aberavon Constituency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/community-spirit-within-the-aberavon-constituency/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2731</id>
    <published>2021-10-04T12:24:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-04T12:24:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1615380759618">

<div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- ">

	
	<p>Steve Reed has asked Croydon Council to listen to local people over the future of South Norwood Library.  The library’s future is uncertain because the Conservative Government has cut funding to Croydon by 70% and pushed it into a financial crisis.</p>
<p>Local MP Steve Reed has spoken to residents and campaign groups who are fighting to save the library.  He’s now written to the Council asking them to consider how closing the library will affect the areas poorest residents who may not have access to WiFi or quiet spaces for learning or reading at home.  He’s also asked the Council to fully involve the local community before taking any decisions.</p>
<p>Steve Reed said: “Croydon Council is faced with some really difficult decisions after ten years of Conservative funding cuts.  But they do not have to go it alone. Now more than ever people want a say over what happens in their area. The Council should harness this enthusiasm and work with residents to come up with plan that could protect library services for South Norwood.”</p>
<p><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/ue8jCq7zvFrArvJhZnZ9o?domain=stevereedmp.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">You can see the full letter here.</a></p>
<p>If you would like to get involved in the campaign to save South Norwood library, email Steve at steve.reed@croydonlabour.org.uk</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	<div class="templatera_shortcode">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"/>

<div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center"><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span><div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"><div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey"><span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"/></div></div><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span>
</div></div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-">
	<ul>

	
		<li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7">
			<div class="item-holder">
				<div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true">
							<img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-pd7vw3u9f02hah596hrf1872w2mpjdjw6lnhj87yk8.png" data-mk-image-src-set="{&quot;default&quot;:&quot;https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg&quot;,&quot;2x&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;mobile&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;responsive&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}"/>


					
				</div>

				<div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">
						<span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333">Steve Reed</span>
					<span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1">Member of Parliment for Croydon North</span>
					
					<div class="clearboth"/>

					
<ul class="mk-employeee-networks">
			<li><a target="_blank" href="mailto:steve.reed.mp@parliament.uk" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-62108e4c84ccc" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-62108e4c84e9a" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-62108e4c85042" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-62108e4c85134" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/></svg></a></li>
	</ul>
				</div>
			</div>
		</li>

					<div class="clearboth"/>
			</ul>
<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>
</div>

<div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155">

<div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text">

	
	<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steven Reed</a> is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/">reducing violent mental health restraint</a> became law. In June 2019 he launched <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/">Labour’s civil society strategy</a> outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>
</div></div>
	</div>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Reed MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10621</id>
    <published>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</updated>
    <category term="Croydon Community Notice Board"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time>
</div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=A2jCtxsd" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/>



  </div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>


</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Alec urges all constituents to book their COVID-19 vaccination or access the NHS Test &amp; Trace system if you have symptoms. </p>
<p><strong>Vaccine</strong></p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved a number of vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has organised the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, with all adults now eligible to book a vaccine. You can book your vaccine online <a href="https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/coronavirus-vaccination/book-coronavirus-vaccination/">here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Testing</strong></p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p><strong>Help from Alec</strong></p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Alec urges all constituents to book their COVID-19 vaccination or access the NHS Test &amp; Trace system if you have symptoms. Vaccine The UK medical regulatory agency has approved a number of vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has organised the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, with all adults now eligible to book a vaccine....  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-62108f20281d5" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-62108f20281d5').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"62108f20281d5","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-62108f20281d5" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-62108f20281d5" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="62108f20281d5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_62108f20281d5" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_62108f20281d5" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_62108f20281d5" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_62108f20281d5" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_62108f20281d5" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_62108f20281d5" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_62108f20281d5_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-62108f20281d5 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxb5Ea_qWB0BGpvm3n69Xbgc-VFJqH_rT2v_xjMw9BRDvfaYEFffB1frwdy6JJYvPGLekxaLG7-otImiY_5fw' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thank you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" rel="attachment wp-att-281"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="281" data-permalink="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" data-orig-size="640,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 09-06-2017, 10 43 04 (2)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=300%2C186" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" src="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=640%2C396" alt="" width="640" height="396" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?w=640 640w, https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=300%2C186 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will be closing down shortly, but you can keep up to date with my work on my &lt;a href="http://www.carolynharris.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;main webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Google+" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;#038;title=Thank%20you" data-a2a-url="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" data-a2a-title="Thank you"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  We did it! Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me. I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East. This website will be closing down shortly, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>linzi_isaac</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/?p=279</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
