<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-11-02T06:32:12Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>The elite does not like debate or challenge</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/11/02/ministerial-battles-ahead/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Recent history shows it is very difficult for Prime Ministers and Ministers  to challenge the internationalist orthodoxy even in a relatively strong and well based democracy like the UK.</p>
<p>I do not buy into silly conspiracy theories that the world is run by a couple of billionaires who enforce their views on world governments. I do observe that there is a very powerful consensus pumped out by most western governments, by leading international bodies, and by many academics and professionals.This consensus can make dreadful mistakes, as it has in economics with the recession machine of the Exchange Rate mechanism ,then the boom/bust of the banking crash and now the rough ride from excessive money printing and inflation to  recession again.</p>
<p>Many experts, professionals and officials genuinely believe the consensus they help form. Others have to go along with it if they want to get a job or if they wish to be in the rooms where the conversations take place that shape these things. It is very difficult getting a university science post if you challenge aspects of the global warming story. It is difficult influencing economic policy if you point out Central banks often get it wrong. It is very difficult in the UK to become a government Minister if you consistently advocated leaving the EU. It is very difficult being Home Secretary if you want to stop illegal migration.</p>
<p>The elites interplay with conventional media to constantly reinforce their spin lines. Forecasts and opinions by international bodies and conforming governments are treated as facts. Alternative views and forecasts are ignored or traduced. It leads the populist majorities that form  to become more disillusioned with the media as well as with governments. It leads more  to then prefer bizarre conspiracy theories.</p>
<p>How many times were we told inflation would stay at 2% however much money they printed? How often were we told when inflation was setting in it would be temporary? Why were those of us who wanted to stop the money printing in 2021 not allowed airtime to put the alternative view?</p>
<p>Most governments pursued lockdown in response to covid, trying to prevent an alternative policy. Most governments claim to want to rush to net zero, though many miss targets or refuse to work to targets applying to them. They usually want to increase the power and revenues of the states they lead.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Recent history shows it is very difficult for Prime Ministers and Ministers  to challenge the internationalist orthodoxy even in a relatively strong and well based democracy like the UK. I do not buy into silly conspiracy theories that the world is run by a couple of billionaires who enforce their views on world governments. I…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33736</id>
    <published>2022-11-02T05:06:50Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-02T05:06:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Westminster – November 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/letter-westminster-november-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7271" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">1 November 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Letter from Westminster – November 2022</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>As the days grow shorter and colder, we approach winter and can expect morning frosts and later sunrises. We are all concerned by the higher cost of our energy bills, as the global crisis caused by President Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine impacts us here in Shropshire.</p>

<p>While Putin may be on the backfoot, it may also be a long time before the global energy market stabilises again. Our resolve in supporting Ukraine must hold. But we also have to manage higher costs for now.</p>

<p>The new Prime Minister Liz Truss has acted swiftly and decisively to help households and businesses through this challenging period.</p>

<p>This builds on the introduction announced in March of a £400 reduction in electricity bills for all, a non-repayable £150 cash rebate for homes in Council Tax bands A-D, equivalent to 80% of households, and £144 million of discretionary funding for local authorities.</p>

<p>I have been urging Ministers to make support available for those off the gas grid reliant on alternative energy sources, including domestic heating oil, many of whom live in remote rural areas, as well as those whose fuel bills are paid by others, such as those in park homes in rural Shropshire.</p>

<p>The Chancellor made explicit in his September fiscal statement that households reliant on alternative energy sources would benefit from the £400 of universal support available and announced a further £100 for those using alternative energy sources, to be paid through discounts on electricity bills from 1st October. At the time of writing, Ministers are developing appropriate provisions for landlords to pass on discounts to tenants paying all-inclusive bills.</p>

<p>But the Government knows we need to go further. The Prime Minister introduced an Energy Price Guarantee (EPG) from 1st October to give households certainty with their bills. The EPG will cap the unit cost for gas and electricity charged by suppliers.</p>

<p>This guarantee will mean typical three-bedroom households will pay no more than £2,500 per year. This will save the average household £1,000 a year compared with forecast increases in energy costs this coming winter.</p>

<p>Energy cost rates for businesses have been capped for six months.</p>

<p>In the medium term, it is vital that we create a sustainable domestic energy supply through the expansion of renewables (which successive Conservative Governments have increased from 6.5% of electricity generation in 2010 to nearly 43% in 2020) and new nuclear. The Government remains committed to the 2050 net zero target, but this assumes we will continue to rely on fossil fuels for 15% of our electricity generation in 2050, so we need to maintain some domestic production to ensure sustainable supply.</p>

<p>Finally, we must work to improve the energy efficiency of our buildings which generate 30% of UK emissions. Over 40% of homes now meet EPC Standards A-C, an increase from around 10% in 2010.</p>

<p>Several energy efficiency schemes have had funding boosts: the three-year Boiler Upgrade Scheme offering grants of up to £5,000 for low-carbon heating systems; the Home Upgrade Grant Scheme which funds energy efficiency measures for low-income households operated under the ECO programme which received a £800 million boost last month; and the Social Housing Decarbonisation Fund which is helping to upgrade social housing stock to EPC rating C which received £950 million more last month as well.</p>

<p>Over £6 billion has been committed to retrofit schemes over this Parliament and VAT has been cut on materials such as solar panels, heating pumps and roof insulation for five years. Much has been done, though there is also much to do.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7271 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T22:00:17Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T22:00:17Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Josh Keeling</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz brings together community to tackle cost of living crisis]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-brings-together-community-to-tackle-cost-of-living/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11813</id>
		<updated>2022-11-01T19:06:00Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-01T19:04:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Braunstone Park and Rowley Fields"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="COST OF LIVING CRISIS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This Friday Liz had a busy day in the constituency, meeting with constituents, local groups and organisations working hard to tackle the impact of the cost of living crisis.<br />
She began the day out and about in Braunstone Park along with ward councillor Su Barton, speaking to constituents about their concerns over energy bills, as well as crime and housing concerns.<br />
We know that food banks are seeing sharply increasing demand as more people struggle with the cost of living, and on Friday Liz brought together Leicester West&#8217;s food bank organisers ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-brings-together-community-to-tackle-cost-of-living/">Liz brings together community to tackle cost of living crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-brings-together-community-to-tackle-cost-of-living/"><![CDATA[<p>This Friday Liz had a busy day in the constituency, meeting with constituents, local groups and organisations working hard to tackle the impact of the cost of living crisis.</p>
<p>She began the day out and about in Braunstone Park along with ward councillor Su Barton, speaking to constituents about their concerns over energy bills, as well as crime and housing concerns. <img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11816" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-540x304.jpeg" alt="" width="540" height="304" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-540x304.jpeg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-260x146.jpeg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-184x104.jpeg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-768x432.jpeg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-1.jpeg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></p>
<p>We know that food banks are seeing sharply increasing demand as more people struggle with the cost of living, and on Friday Liz brought together Leicester West&#8217;s food bank organisers for a productive roundtable meeting at Manor House, to discuss the support they&#8217;ll need this winter to continue helping their communities through a very difficult period.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11817" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-540x304.jpeg" alt="" width="540" height="304" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-540x304.jpeg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-260x146.jpeg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-184x104.jpeg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-768x432.jpeg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2-1536x864.jpeg 1536w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/WhatsApp-Image-2022-10-28-at-1.57.02-PM-2.jpeg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></p>
<p>Liz also paid a visit to the <a href="https://www.leicester.gov.uk/your-community/libraries-and-community-centres/find-a-community-centre/the-brite-centre/">Brite Centre</a>, meeting manager Elaine and her hard-working team to find out more about the fantastic range of activities and community services they offer. As with all of Leicester City Council&#8217;s libraries, the Brite Centre is a &#8216;warm space&#8217; this winter , where anyone struggling to heat their home can come to sit and spend time in a warm and welcoming environment. The Brite Centre also has a wealth of resources &#8211; including access to computers and learning sessions, as well as lots of information on further support, so its well worth a visit.</p>
<p>Find out more here about <a href="http://Libraries (leicester.gov.uk)">Leicester&#8217;s libraries</a> and <a href="https://news.leicester.gov.uk/news-articles/2022/october/get-a-warm-welcome-at-our-libraries/">warm spaces</a>&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-11814" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022-540x405.jpeg" alt="" width="540" height="405" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022-540x405.jpeg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022-260x195.jpeg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022-184x138.jpeg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Liz-at-the-Brite-Centre-Elaine-Felton-and-Lee-Warner-LCC-Oct-28-2022.jpeg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-11654" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/13.jpg" alt="Half term activities" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/half-term-activities/" class="wp_rp_title">Half term activities</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-11578" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-drops-into-craft-club/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/sewnso-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz drops into craft club" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-drops-into-craft-club/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz drops into craft club</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-9515" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-lunch-at-the-oak-centre/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Lunch-at-the-Oak-Centre-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz joins lunch at the Oak Centre" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-lunch-at-the-oak-centre/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz joins lunch at the Oak Centre</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-9413" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-holds-coffee-morning-in-braunstone-park/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/Coffee-morning-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz holds Coffee Morning in Braunstone Park" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-holds-coffee-morning-in-braunstone-park/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz holds Coffee Morning in Braunstone Park</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-9164" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/9164-2/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/IMG_1864-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz talks to Fullhurst students about social media" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/9164-2/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz talks to Fullhurst students about social media</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-brings-together-community-to-tackle-cost-of-living/">Liz brings together community to tackle cost of living crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins’ question in Parliament on BBC Radio</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/01/toby-perkins-question-in-parliament-on-bbc-radio/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/01/toby-perkins-question-in-parliament-on-bbc-radio/">Toby Perkins’ question in Parliament on BBC Radio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/11/01/toby-perkins-question-in-parliament-on-bbc-radio/">Toby Perkins’ question in Parliament on BBC Radio</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5123</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T16:56:56Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T16:56:56Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP challenges Health Secretary to save Ambleside and Hawkshead GP surgeries</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437019/mp-challenges-health-secretary-to-save-ambleside-and-hawkshead-gp-surgeries"/>
  <updated>2022-11-01T16:47:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1437019/mp-challenges-health-secretary-to-save-ambleside-and-hawkshead-gp-surgeries</id>
  <summary type="text">On the floor of the House of Commons this morning, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron urged the new Secretary of State, Steve Barclay, to intervene to save the under threat GP surgeries in Ambleside and Hawkshead
Tim also asked for the Minister to set up a sustainable small surgeries fund to protect the long term future of rural GP practices.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the floor of the House of Commons this morning, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron urged the new Secretary of State, Steve Barclay, to intervene to save the under threat GP surgeries in Ambleside and Hawkshead</p>
<p>Tim also asked for the Minister to set up a sustainable small surgeries fund to protect the long term future of rural GP practices.</p>
<p>It comes after news figures from the NHS revealed that the number of GPs in South Cumbria and North Lancashire has fallen from 210 and 176 since 2016.</p>
<p>Meanwhile in North Cumbria, there has been a 17% drop from 180 to 150.</p>
<p>Speaking during Health and Social Care Questions in Parliament, Tim said: <em>"In Cumbria we have lost one in six of our GPs in the past six years, most recently at the Central Lakes Medical Practice in Ambleside and Hawkshead.</em></p>
<p><em>"Will the Secretary of State pay special attention to the letting of that new contract to ensure that there is a GP service running out of the surgeries in Ambleside and Hawkshead?</em></p>
<p><em>"Will he also give thought to the fact that the Government's removal of the minimum practice income guarantee has cost many rural surgeries their ability to be sustainable, and consider bringing back a sustainable small surgeries fund so that small rural surgeries can stay open?"</em></p>
<p>In response, the Health Secretary Steve Barclay said: <em>"As a rural MP and having worked in Kendal earlier in my career, I know the geography to which the honourable gentleman refers.</em></p>
<p><em>"That is why we are investing in more GP training, increasing the number from 2,671 in 2014 to 4,000, but it is also why we introduced the payment of £20,000, to encourage GPs into those areas that are hard to recruit in."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tenants urged to give their views on plans for use of rental income</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13582/tenants-urged-to-give-their-views-on-plans-for-use-of-rental-income" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The City of Edinburgh Council is encouraging its housing tenants to take part in a housing rent consultation. </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13582/tenants-urged-to-give-their-views-on-plans-for-use-of-rental-income</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T15:22:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T15:22:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debbie Abrahams on Compassionate Conservatism – Independent Comment Piece</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/compassionate-conservatism-oped/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Debbie Abrahams on <span style="color:#06396a;">'Compassionate Conservatism'</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>Everyone, it seems, is talking about it. In recent weeks the Prime Minister, <a href="https://twitter.com/CompInPolitics/status/1585334592269320192?s=20&amp;t=hDroWgBvw5J9S8PkARk--Q">Rishi Sunak</a>, his Chancellor, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2022/oct/17/new-chancellor-shreds-pms-economic-plans-in-unprecedented-u-turn">Jeremy Hunt</a>, and Ministers including <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2022/oct/29/michael-gove-says-tories-should-apologise-for-liz-trusss-holiday-from-reality">Michael Gove</a>, have all mentioned the need for “compassion” in politics and an era of “compassionate Conservatism”.</p>
<p>As Co-Chair of the All-Party Group for Compassionate Politics, this is, of course, something I welcome. But I do so cautiously. Compassionate conservatism is not new. As a political ideology it emanated from 1970s America and later developed some traction under President George W Bush. Critics have, however, suggested that whilst sounding good, without a programme to deliver a compassionate agenda, it’s nothing but empty rhetoric. These warm words need to be accompanied by a genuine commitment to transformative change in both the practice of politics and the policies that it produces.</p>
<p>Because compassion demands nothing less. <a href="https://www.compassionatemind.co.uk/">The accepted definition</a> amongst compassion researchers, trainers, and therapists is that compassion involves an awareness of suffering with a commitment to alleviate and prevent it. To govern effectively through compassion will therefore require a willingness to engage with and understand suffering and courageous action to address its symptoms and uproot its causes.</p>
<p>In very immediate terms, a compassionate government would take steps to help ordinary people weather our current economic storm. Failure, for example, to uprate benefits in line with inflation could <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/oct/10/liz-truss-must-raise-benefits-in-line-with-inflation-sajid-javid-says">lead to half a million more people being pushed into poverty</a>. That wouldn’t satisfy anyone’s definition of compassion. A compassionate government would also take action to support those who are most badly affected by the current cost of living crisis – disabled people, older people and children – and who have been suffering from previous crises in recent years.</p>
<p>As a Labour politician I would argue that the state has a key role to play in delivering a compassionate society; I don’t believe the market has all the answers and that our country’s wealth will reach those who need it. In fact, there’s a massive evidence-base saying that ‘trickle- down’ economics doesn’t work. A compassionate approach to funding the support needed for those in vulnerable circumstances would therefore be to address the fundamental imbalances in our economy – one where the <a href="https://researchbriefings.files.parliament.uk/documents/CBP-8513/CBP-8513.pdf">richest 1% of individuals pay 12.5% of their income in tax compared with the 50% lowest earners who pay 25.5% of their income in tax</a>. Similarly, the tax from corporations has flatlined over the last 12 years at about 2% despite, for example, energy companies like <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-60295177">BP reporting its highest quarterly profit for 14 years. Their figures are eclipsed by Shell</a> who delivered second quarter profits of over £9bn. An extended windfall tax on energy companies coupled with the backdating of the profits it applies to would help to deliver the finances we need to ensure that everyone receives the support they need during this cost of living and energy crisis. And there are other inequalities in wealth and power that also need considering.</p>
<p>Looking to the long-term and the structural changes that are needed, I believe we have to set course for a very different economic model – one that prioritises not just growth, but the wellbeing of all. We need to (finally) introduce into law a duty to ensure that the public have access to the essential ingredients for a secure and healthy life: food, housing, and a decent income. The UK has recognised that these rights matter by signing up to the <a href="https://www.ohchr.org/en/instruments-mechanisms/instruments/international-covenant-economic-social-and-cultural-rights">UN Covenant on Economic, Cultural, and Social Rights</a> but never introduced them into domestic law. This – <a href="https://www.compassioninpolitics.com/charities_academics_and_campaigners_urge_leadership_contenders">as a host of charities recently argued</a> – is an oversight that must be addressed if we are to pivot our economy (and the businesses, public services, and communities that comprise it) toward the common good.</p>
<p>Compassion also recognises our common humanity. For example, a compassionate immigration system, would be one which upholds the rule of law, would abide by our obligations under the UN Refugee Convention and works with the international community to address the main causes of forced displacement: war and persecution. It wouldn’t use the appalling human suffering of migrants as a political opportunity to sow hate and division. It would instead ensure safe routes to apply for refuge, timely responses to asylum applications, and decent accommodation for people fleeing for their lives.</p>
<p>All of this must go hand-in-hand with an effort to reform the culture of our politics. Good policies can only come from good politics and if our government is truly committed to a compassionate future it will create the right environment for such a future to grow and prosper. That has to start with the conduct of those in high office. We need to put the Ministerial Code on a statutory footing so that it can be properly enforced, empower the ethics advisor to launch independent investigations into ministerial conduct, and <a href="https://www.theoldhamtimes.co.uk/news/20133887.make-lies-parliament-sackable-offence-oldham-mp-argues/">strengthen the rules to prevent politicians from willfully lying to the public</a>. We also need to look at how we can reconnect politicians to the people they serve by divesting power away from Westminster and establishing citizen and constituency assemblies. Compassionate governance means working alongside those we seek to serve, not dictating policies from the centre.</p>
<p>If the government is serious about a compassionate future – and I truly hope they are – these are just some of the policies, and changes to our political system, I’d like to see them champion and endorse. My colleagues and I in the APPG are here ready and waiting to work with them so that we can truly transform our politics and improve lives.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/compassionate-conservatism-oped/">Debbie Abrahams on Compassionate Conservatism – Independent Comment Piece</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/compassionate-conservatism-oped/">Debbie Abrahams on Compassionate Conservatism – Independent Comment Piece</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7053</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T15:19:53Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T15:19:53Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/weekly-update-0" type="text/html"/>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/weekly-update-0</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Havering Mind Ready For Adulthood Programme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/havering-mind-ready-adulthood-programme" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Havering Mind Ready For Adulthood Programme</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-11-01T11:16:00+00:00">Tue, 11/01/2022 - 11:16</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1164 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:16:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-81/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">Members of Parliament return to Westminster on Mondays after spending the weekend in their constituencies. Parliamentary business in the Chamber starts at 2.30pm with Oral Questions, and following the end of Orals, there are often UK Government Statements, and/or Urgent Questions (UQs) about events that have occurred throughout the world and the UK over the weekend. The UK Government decides which Statements it presents, but it is the Speaker who chooses which UQs are granted.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Last Monday there were 2 UQs at 3.45pm on <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-24/debates/ECCEF9B2-FD8D-424D-B1E7-1526A5884780/GreatBritishRailways">The Future of GB Railways</a>, and The Imminent Closure of <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-24/debates/4D724395-D3B2-498E-A7DF-962B3A940E54/DoncasterSheffieldAirport">Doncaster Sheffield Airport</a>, which was followed by a Statement on The Publication of the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-24/debates/4DFF9311-EDE4-4B14-9026-84130D08B9A3/IndependentInquiryIntoChildSexualAbuseFinalReport">Independent Inquiry into Child Sexual Abuse: Final Report. </a></p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The MPs were eager to see which UK Government Ministers appeared at the Dispatch Box after the new PM had appointed his members of Cabinet and Front Bench. Kevin Foster MP has been Transport Minister from 7th September 2022, and he appeared for the UK Government in the first UQ, (but was sacked on Wednesday). Katherine Fletcher MP (South Ribble) was promoted to Under Secretary of State for Transport and appeared in the second UQ. The Statement was delivered by Grant Shapps, as Secretary of State for the Home Department, but the new PM replaced Shapps with Suella Braverman, who had been sacked by Liz Truss following a breach of the Ministerial Code. Mr Shapps was only in post for six days, and Ms Braverman was only out of post for six days. Mr Shapps was appointed as Secretary of State for BEIS, after the Boris-backer Rees-Mogg was sacked.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The rest of the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-24">Chamber business for Monday</a> was financial supplementary estimates, the Stamp Duty Bill (England), EU Delegated Legislation (without debate), and an Adjournment Debate on Doncaster Airport granted to Doncaster Central MP Nick Fletcher.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">There are many events that take place outside the Chamber. One of which are All Party Parliamentary Groups (APPGs) that are very important for raising issues and campaigning for worthwhile causes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">This week, I attended 4 APPGs.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.parallelparliament.co.uk/APPG/liver-disease-and-liver-cancer">APPG for Liver Disease and Liver Cancer</a> has been at the forefront of raising awareness of the hidden prevalence of Liver Disease in the UK. The UK is facing a liver disease public health emergency with the main causes being alcohol, obesity, and viral hepatitis, which are prevalent in disadvantaged communities. Public Health Data from the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/office-for-health-improvement-and-disparities">Office for Health Improvement and Disparities</a> (OHID) highlights that liver disease mortality rates are nearly 4 times higher in most deprived areas, with regional variations.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">We heard from Professor Julia Verne, Deputy Director in the OHID, about her research on levelling up liver disease outcomes to narrow the gap in healthy life expectancy. Professor Verne previously worked at a Liver Unit and saw first hand the challenges facing patients with cirrhosis and advanced liver disease. Mortality rates are very high for patients diagnosed at a late stage. But 90% of liver disease is preventable and in many cases can be reversed or halted, because if diagnosed early, the liver has the ability to regenerate.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Vanessa Hebditch, Director of Policy and Comms at the <a href="https://britishlivertrust.org.uk/">British Liver Trust</a>, gave an update of the launch of Liver Cancer UK. Its research found that only 26% of areas in the UK have an effective pathway for the early detection and management of liver disease. Urgent action is needed to level up inequalities in liver disease care and outcomes. Liver disease is the leading cause of premature deaths and lost working years. The Levelling Up and Regeneration Bill will place a statutory duty on the UK Government to report back on delivery of narrowing the gap in healthy life expectancy between areas of lowest and highest areas by 2030, and increase healthy life expectancy by five years by 2035. But the British Liver Trust and our APPG are calling for a full review of adult liver services by NHS England to address unwarranted variation in treatment care and outcomes. Health and Social Care are devolved, and there is an established early detection and management pathway operating in Wales.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://twitter.com/steelappg">APPG for Steel and Related Metal Industries</a> continues to promote the importance of UK Steel Production which strengthens national resilience, its jobs are crucial to levelling up, growing market opportunity, vital to environmental challenges, and boosts infrastructure potential. The UK Steel Sector produces 7.2 million tonnes a year, 70% of UK requirements, directly employs 34,500 people with a further 43,000 in the supply chain, pays an average £37,629, 45% higher than UK national median, contributes £2.4 billion to UK GDP, and £3.1 billion in supply chains. The priority for the sector is competitive electricity prices, net-zero steel strategy, level trading field, using UK steel in UK infrastructure projects, and innovation.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.parallelparliament.co.uk/APPG/hospitality-events-and-major-food-and-drink-businesses-in-wales">APPG for Hospitality, Events, Major Food and Drink Businesses in Wales</a> was addressed by Dave Chapman, Executive Director, UK Hospitality Cymru, and Kate Nicholls, Chief Executive, UK Hospitality. We were joined online by a number of businesses located in Wales who told us about the challenges of operating in the hospitality and events sectors following the major challenges resulting from years of austerity, Brexit and Covid-19.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Businesses are struggling to survive because of rising costs, and diminishing footfall. Energy bills have doubled, and suppliers are not offering favourable deals after the 6 month UK Government support scheme ends in April 2023. There is an acute shortage of labour which has caused many hospitality venues and events to reduce operations from full time opening to around 80%. There is a UK vacancy rate of 10% and it’s 15% in Wales. UK Hospitality are calling for a Welsh Government Minister for Hospitality who would work with UK Government, an All-Party Senedd Group for Hospitality, deregulation of the immigration regime which takes at least 12 weeks for a work visa application to be processed, and it does not support a tourism levy.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.parallelparliament.co.uk/APPG/uk-shared-prosperity-fund">APPG on the UK Shared Prosperity Fund</a> has written many times to UK Ministers in BEIS, Levelling Up, Housing and Communities Department DLUHC, who change every time there is a new PM, asking for clarification on how the UKSPF would operate. The latest letter on 20 September 2022 was to Simon Clarke, Secretary of State for Levelling Up, who held the position for the duration of Liz Truss’s reign. We told Mr Clarke about the very successful UKSPF Stakeholder Online Event, attended by over 180 representatives from public, private, voluntary, community and business organisations across England, Scotland and Wales, setting out their views. We highlighted five problematic areas: the short timescale for drawing up investment plans; the local authority-led structure for drawing up investment plans is a problem for organisations that operate across boundaries; all investment plans should be published online by DLUHC, so that organisations can work out how they fit in; the hiatus in funding in 2023-4 will cause redundancies and re-recruiting in 2024; the EU 7-year programme with a roll-on spending option for a further 3 years has been replaced with a 3-year (now two and a half years) UKSPF with no guarantee of funding beyond 2024-5. Mr Clarke did not respond to our letter before he was replaced. The APPG has always had difficulty in finding out which UK Government Minister is responsible for the UKSPF, which crosses Whitehall Departments. And when we do have constructive dialogue with a Minister, for example Neil O’Brien, they are replaced, and we have to start again. Another problem is that the UK Government Spending Reviews work on a 3-year timeline, and 2024-5 hasn’t been signed off yet, and this will produce a “cliff edge” for any prospective UKSPF projects. The UK Government has created the Future High Streets Fund, Towns Fund, Levelling Up Fund, Community Renewal Fund, and the UKSPF. There is a rumour that these would be amalgamated and the UKSPF will be subsumed. The APPG decided that we would meet again after the LUHCC Cross Party Committee concludes its enquiry into Levelling Up, which it launched on 20th October 2022, and includes looking into whether the UKSPF is a sufficient replacement of EU Structural Funds – evidence sessions begin next month.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">There is a stand-off between UK and Welsh Government. The APPG wrote to Vaughan Gethin, Minister for Economy in the Welsh Government, and his reply stated that the UK Government’s engagement with Welsh Government Ministers and its officials has been unacceptable. Despite years of work in Wales developing the strongest possible model for post-EU regional investment, the Welsh Government were only consulted in April 2022, because the UK Government wanted to publish its SPF prospectus before the local elections in May 2022. The Welsh Government does not endorse and will not support delivery of UK policies and programmes in Wales which are flawed and undermine the devolution settlement. The Welsh Government suggested a simple formula based on the <a href="https://statswales.gov.wales/Catalogue/Community-Safety-and-Social-Inclusion/Welsh-Index-of-Multiple-Deprivation">Welsh Index of Multiple Deprivation</a> (WIMD) taking into account a wide range of socio-economic factors, including income, employment, education and distance from services. The UK Government gave the WIMD a 30% weighting and combined it with its Community Renewal Fund Index. But this disadvantages Welsh local authorities with larger populations, and as a result, two of the more populous local authorities Rhondda Cynon Taff (RCT) and Caerphilly, which would have high allocations under the WIMD, will have allocations barely above the Wales average. The Welsh Government was not consulted on the final allocations before publication by the UK Government, and consider the SPF formula to be complicated, methodologically flawed, and not reflective of economic need. The UK Government’s repeated promises to replace EU Structural and Investment Funds in full falls £1.1 billion short between January 2021 and March 2025. For these reasons and those set out in Mr Gethin’s written statements of 13th April and 1st June, the Welsh Government will not be using its resources to support the implementation of the SPF in Wales but will support local government partners to implement the fund, despite its inadequacies. Mr Gethin has also written to Michael Gove to stress that the Welsh Government would welcome further discussion and a genuine co-decision-making arrangement.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://www.parallelparliament.co.uk/APPG/pension-clawback">APPG on Pension Clawback</a>, which was formed to campaign against banks such as HSBC and Midland Bank, clawing back state pensions from the amount of occupational pension that they pay to former employees, met online to listen to an update from our chair, Clive Betts MP, and to have a preview of research being conducted by <a href="https://law.exeter.ac.uk/public/probono/">University of Exeter Law Department</a> into Defined Contributions and the use of State Clawback. This independent research is using personal experiences of the post-1974 Midland Pension Scheme Section, with respect to the legality and actions of organisations who have applied clawback to pension schemes, and the impact on employees in these organisations. I look forward to its publication.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I went into the chamber for <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2022-10-26/debates/DA634E71-6A00-4C9C-8D40-CCE730776B42/Engagements">Prime Minister’s Questions</a> (PMQs) Wednesday lunchtime to watch the new PM’s first performance at the Dispatch Box. Keir Starmer asked whether the PMs officials had raised concerns about the decision to re-appoint the Home Secretary just days after she had been sacked for a security breach, but Rishi Sunak failed to answer. Keir said the Tories put Party first and Country second, with working people paying for their mess. Keir said that Rishi was a PM who got trounced by his successor who herself was beaten by a lettuce. There were repeated calls for a General Election from opposition MPs.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">When I returned to Neath constituency on Thursday 27<sup>th</sup> October, I attended <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1587008443189190657?cxt=HHwWgoCz_anxl4YsAAAA">Dove Workshop in Banwen</a>.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">DOVE Workshop has been awarded a tree from Buckingham Palace, as part of the late <a href="https://queensgreencanopy.org/get-involved/communities-and-groups/">Queen Elizabeth II Jubilee initiatives</a>. The tree has been awarded to Dove Workshop in recognition for all that it has achieved; for the work it has done in inspiring the communities it serves, and on the understanding that there is an expectation they will continue to deliver services of the same quality for a good many years to come.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The ceremony was led by the <a href="http://www.lordlieutenantwestglamorgan.org.uk/">Lord Lieutenant, Mrs Louise Fleet JP</a>, and Dove Workshop’s Manager, Lianne Byrne. The Tree of Trees was planted in Dove’s Sarn Helen Garden, where it will take pride of place and by nurtured to grow as a reminder of this moving tribute to both Dove Workshop and our late Queen.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Members of Parliament return to Westminster on Mondays after spending the weekend in their constituencies. Parliamentary business in the Chamber starts at 2.30pm with Oral Questions, and following the end of Orals, there are often UK Government Statements, and/or Urgent Questions (UQs) about events that have occurred throughout the world and the UK over the weekend. The […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2692</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:14:26Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:14:26Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The importance of celebrating our local businesses – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-importance-of-celebrating-our-local-businesses-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-importance-of-celebrating-our-local-businesses-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235804" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/biz.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></div>
<div/>
<div>
<p>Last month, I launched my 2022 Local Business Awards. Each year, I take nominations from across Denton and Reddish for the best local businesses. Every nominated business receives a certificate to proudly display, and on Small Business Saturday (December 3rd) I announce winners for each ward as well as an overall winner and runner-up. Businesses must be located in Denton, Dukinfield, Audenshaw, Reddish, Heaton Norris or Heaton Chapel to be eligible.</p>
<p>I started the Local Business Awards some years ago as a bit of fun to celebrate the burgeoning independent shops, restaurants and pubs popping up across the local area. Since then, the Business Awards have become bigger and better than I could have ever imagined.</p>
<p>Last year, we received 4,500 nominations, and more than 250 businesses were celebrated. As soon as I open these awards, my office is inundated with nominations. From craft shops to craft ales and top-notch cafes to accountancy firms, there’s seemingly no end to local entrepreneurial spirit.</p>
<p>There’s something really special about making time to recognise local businesses that are the lifeblood of our communities. During the darkest days of lockdown, when non-essential businesses were forced to close, I still remember how surreal it all felt, and how much I missed nipping into a cafe for a cup of tea or bumping into a friend out and about.</p>
<p>Thankfully, businesses are no longer having to contend with lockdowns, but there are still plenty of challenges for small business owners to contend with: economic instability, an ever-changing trade picture and a cost-of-living crisis to name just a few daunting hurdles. That’s why it’s more important than ever that we don’t take for granted our local businesses, and carve out time to say thanks to the ones that go above and beyond. Without them, not only would we be economically poorer as a nation, but socially poorer too.</p>
<p>I can’t wait for Small Business Saturday, when I get to travel the length breadth of the constituency and chat to local business owners.</p>
<p>They are always beyond delighted to see their hard work being recognised by the people who matter most – customers! So if you know a local business that deserves to be celebrated, visit <a href="http://www.andrewgwynne.co.uk/LBA">www.andrewgwynne.co.uk/LBA</a> to submit your nomination.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-importance-of-celebrating-our-local-businesses-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">The importance of celebrating our local businesses – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last month, I launched my 2022 Local Business Awards. Each year, I take nominations from across Denton and Reddish for the best local businesses. Every nominated business receives a certificate to proudly display, and on Small Business Saturday (December 3rd) I announce winners for each ward as well as an overall winner and runner-up. Businesses […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-importance-of-celebrating-our-local-businesses-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">The importance of celebrating our local businesses – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235803</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T10:23:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T10:23:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Aldridge Branch Royal British Legion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/aldridge-branch-royal-british-legion/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>After a 3-year absence due to Covid-19 it was lovely last weekend to attend the Partridge-Smail Royal British Legion Dinner organised by the Aldridge RBL Branch.</p>
<p>Held in honour of the late Mr David Partridge MBE and Mr Alex Smail it was good to meet with branch members who do so much work to raise funds and awareness of the work of the RBL throughout the year.</p>
<p>The evening was extremely well attended and raised over £1,200.</p>
<p>Thank you all the members of the Royal British Legion who continue to work so hard across Aldridge and the wider community.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">After a 3-year absence due to Covid-19 it was lovely last weekend to attend the Partridge-Smail Royal British Legion Dinner organised by the Aldridge RBL Branch. Held in honour of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4358</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T09:38:39Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T09:38:39Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Failing Private Rail companies are rewarded</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/11/failing-private-rail-companies-are-rewarded/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4124">Chi Onwurah </a></strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4124">(Newcastle upon Tyne Central) (Lab)</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>Thank you, Madam Deputy Speaker. Why does the Minister insist on rewarding private sector failure—Avanti or TransPennine Express—with more public money, while refusing to invest in transformative public transport services such as Northern Powerhouse Rail? Does he think that my constituents, deprived of an affordable or reliable means of getting to work, are pleased to know that their hard-worked-for taxes are being used by this Government literally to pay the private sector to profit from their misery?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-10-25/debates/216AA556-AF4F-425C-BE06-669B92562502/AvantiWestCoastContractRenewal#contribution-CF35706D-E0CA-488D-B2EB-156E6ED91775">https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2022-10-25/debates/216AA556-AF4F-425C-BE06-669B92562502/AvantiWestCoastContractRenewal#contribution-CF35706D-E0CA-488D-B2EB-156E6ED91775</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chi Onwurah  (Newcastle upon Tyne Central) (Lab) Thank you, Madam Deputy Speaker. Why does the Minister insist on rewarding private sector failure—Avanti or TransPennine Express—with more public money, while refusing to invest in transformative public transport services such as Northern… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=12825</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T08:19:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T08:19:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OPINION: RISHI IS RUNNING FEART OF THE VOTERS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/10/31/opinion-rishi-is-running-feart-of-the-voters/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As the Westminster circus rolls on, my inbox has been full of messages from Bankies in despair at the democratic deficit facing our country.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Scotland hasn’t voted Conservative since the 1950s, yet Rishi Sunak is now the fifth different Tory Prime Minister imposed on us in just six years. Despite all that, and the damage done since the Brexit vote of 2016, the Westminster parties still have the brass neck to deny the clear democratic mandate held by Scotland’s Parliament to deliver a fresh independence referendum.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise that the new Tory PM is running feart from the voters; following in the footsteps of the disastrous premierships of Liz Truss and Boris Johnson. The Tories are languishing in the polls after trashing the economy and bringing hardship to families across the country. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;PM Sunak wants to be seen as the saviour of the UK, but in reality he is complicit in the mess they have created. As Chancellor, multi-millionaire Sunak backed a damaging hard Brexit and slashed Universal Credit for those on the lowest incomes. He’s voted against free school meals, and even boasted of diverting cash from deprived areas like ours to wealthy parts of England.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As Prime Minister, Sunak has signalled plans for another wave of austerity that will be devastating to living standards and public services. Nobody voted for that, but in Scotland we face paying a heavy price for living under Westminster rule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As winter approaches, and the UK’s cost of living crisis worsens, how can super-rich Rishi Sunak possibly understand the pressures facing ordinary families in West Dunbartonshire?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Figures from the ONS show the price of food soaring – with everyday essentials like bread, tea and pasta up by close to 50 per cent in the past year alone. As energy bills double, and housing costs spiral, people are being pushed to breaking point.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here in West Dunbartonshire, local groups like Food for Thought, WD Community Foodshare and Old Kilpatrick Food Parcels are stepping up to help those in need. But the fact that foodbanks are needed at all in a wealthy country likes ours is a damning indictment of Westminster’s failures.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We cannot go on like this. The answer isn’t another out of touch Tory Prime Minister. Nor is it Labour’s Keir Starmer, who backs the Tories on Brexit and says no to Scots deciding their own future.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only the SNP can be trusted to stand up for the people of Scotland.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And it’s only with independence that we can escape the chaos of Westminster governments we don’t vote for, once and for all. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was written for publication in the &lt;a href="https://www.clydebankpost.co.uk/"&gt;Clydebank Post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As the Westminster circus rolls on, my inbox has been full of messages from Bankies in despair at the democratic deficit facing our country.  Scotland hasn’t voted Conservative since the 1950s, yet Rishi Sunak is now the fifth different Tory Prime Minister imposed on us in just six years. Despite all that, and the damage ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="OPINION: RISHI IS RUNNING FEART OF THE VOTERS" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/10/31/opinion-rishi-is-running-feart-of-the-voters/#more-1821410" aria-label="More on OPINION: RISHI IS RUNNING FEART OF THE VOTERS">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821410</id>
    <published>2022-10-31T12:49:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-31T12:49:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Clydebank Post"/>
    <category term="Cost of living Crisis"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Rishi Sunak"/>
    <category term="Scottish Independence"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-37" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The vile puppy smuggling trade sees helpless puppies and heavily pregnant dogs being transported thousands of miles to meet the UK’s demand for dogs. They're forced to travel in cramped, dirty conditions, often with no food and little water.
I was extremely proud to have supported the Government’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-37</id>
    <published>2022-10-31T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-31T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Want to save the economy? Scrap HS2 once and for all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/want-save-economy-scrap-hs2-once-and-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP writes for The Telegraph... 
Rishi Sunak and Jeremy Hunt have been crystal clear about the difficult financial decisions to come. That inevitably means reductions in public spending, which in turn conjures images of the axe falling on politically impossible budgets like health,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/want-save-economy-scrap-hs2-once-and-all</id>
    <published>2022-10-31T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-31T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bill of Rights Bill]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1704</id>
		<updated>2022-10-31T11:16:52Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-31T07:00:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bill of Rights Bill"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="European Convention on Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Human Rights"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="legislation"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Parliament"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/10/31/bill-of-rights-bill/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dog's Trust Pawlitical in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/dogs-trust-pawlitical-parliament" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There is currently no requirement for visual checks of dogs entering the country. Without them there is no hope of ending Puppy Smuggling.
The Animal Welfare (Kept Animals) Bill will reduce the number of puppies allowed to enter the UK to 5 per vehicle, disrupting the abhorrent Puppy Smuggling…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/dogs-trust-pawlitical-parliament</id>
    <published>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP attends Bridge Northumberland celebration</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-attends-bridge-northumberland-celebration" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Anne-Marie was delighted to accept Bridge's invitation to join them on Friday at a celebration for those who have successfully bridged the gap to work and skills in Northumberland.
Speaking of the event, she said: 
"It was wonderful to catch up with the team and meet those who have benefitted from…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/mp-attends-bridge-northumberland-celebration</id>
    <published>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scottish Borders MP appointed Scotland Office minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-appointed-scotland-office-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scottish Borders MP John Lamont has been appointed to the Scotland Office as a minister.
On Thursday evening, John Lamont MP joined the UK Government as Parliamentary Under Secretary of State in the Scotland Office.
He will serve as a junior minister to Scotland Office Secretary of State, Alister…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-appointed-scotland-office-minister</id>
    <published>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-28T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP shows support for Royal Mail postal workers threatened with job losses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/10/27/isles-mp-shows-support-for-royal-mail-postal-workers-threatened-with-job-losses/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has called on the Royal Mail to &amp;#8216;stop the threats of job cuts to valued postal workers’ and &amp;#8216;engage meaningfully&amp;#8217; with the Communications Worker Union to find an acceptable solution to prevent further postal strikes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Local postal workers took strike action earlier this week and several more strike days are planned next month.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil &amp;#8211; whose late father was a Post Man &amp;#8211; signed a Joint Letter from SNP MPs to the Royal Mail Chief.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The letter stated that it is &amp;#8220;unacceptable to see the language employed by Royal Mail in threatening its workforce with job losses because they dare to ask for a fair work package.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Last week, the Royal Mail&amp;#8217;s announced its intention to slash 10,000 jobs, citing the strike action and low parcel delivery sales as the reason. Mr MacNeil has called this move a &amp;#8216;tactic in the ongoing pay dispute with postal workers&amp;#8217; and has accused Royal Mail of &amp;#8216;acting in bad faith&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting, Mr MacNeil said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Postal workers are struggling to make ends meet in the face of the cost-of-living crisis while Royal Mail shareholders benefited from bumper profits in the millions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;It is understandable that postal workers find the argument that there isn&amp;#8217;t money for them to have a fair wage unpalatable when there are millions of pounds of profit for shareholders, who should share the burden – when hard working postal staff are struggling to put food on their table this winter.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Royal Mail staff and their families need financial security. The decision to strike will not have been easy for any of them, but this is about more than pay; it is also about protecting the universal mail service we all expect and value.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Royal Mail need to get back to the negotiating table – in a meaningful way – and put our communities at the heart of discussions.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3946" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/10/27/isles-mp-shows-support-for-royal-mail-postal-workers-threatened-with-job-losses/angus-post-box/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg" data-orig-size="1200,1600" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Angus post box" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=225" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-3946" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=113 113w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg?w=225 225w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/10/angus-post-box.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil has called on the Royal Mail to ‘stop the threats of job …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/10/27/isles-mp-shows-support-for-royal-mail-postal-workers-threatened-with-job-losses/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3943</id>
    <published>2022-10-27T13:14:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-27T13:14:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Visits Linkage Community Trust in Beverley</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-visits-linkage-community-trust-beverley" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, met Valerie Waby, the CEO of the Linkage Community Trust, to learn more about the Trust’s plans for the coming years.
The Linkage Community Trust is a charitable organisation which works with people with a range of learning…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-visits-linkage-community-trust-beverley</id>
    <published>2022-10-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MPs join Dogs Trust in calling for an end in puppy smuggling</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/mps-join-dogs-trust-calling-end-puppy-smuggling" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MPs discussed with the charity how to combat the Puppy Smuggling trade and the importance of the Kept Animals Bill
This week Scott Benton, MP for Blackpool South, attended an event organised by Dogs Trust at the House of Commons where the charity called on the Government to take urgent action to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/mps-join-dogs-trust-calling-end-puppy-smuggling</id>
    <published>2022-10-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>LP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[End this Game of Thrones and let the people decide]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/27/end-this-game-of-thrones-and-let-the-people-decide/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6499</id>
		<updated>2022-10-27T10:08:24Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-27T11:00:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Uncategorised"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="general election"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="steve mccabe"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I didn’t think I’d be returning to this so soon, but Tory leaders change quicker than football managers these days. &#160; Just six weeks after telling us Liz Truss was the answer, we’re inundated with Tory MPs claiming Rishi Sunak, whom they rejected in favour of Liz Truss, is now the answer.&#160;&#160; I wish the<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/27/end-this-game-of-thrones-and-let-the-people-decide/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">End this Game of Thrones and let the people decide</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/27/end-this-game-of-thrones-and-let-the-people-decide/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6478" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/20/its-time-for-change/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-1/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6478" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I didn’t think I’d be returning to this so soon, but Tory leaders change quicker than football managers these days. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Just six weeks after telling us Liz Truss was the answer, we’re inundated with Tory MPs claiming Rishi Sunak, whom they rejected in favour of Liz Truss, is now the answer.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wish the new PM well but can’t ignore the fact this is a coronation and not an election and he did serve as Boris Johnson’s Chancellor while presiding over 10% inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The government of our country isn’t some board game where you make and change alliances on the throw of the dice. It’s about honest, difficult decisions which have far reaching consequences. Our system relies on a democratic election where people vote for the party which makes the best offer, and its leader forms a government.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re now on three PMs and four chancellors in the last four months. There’s yet another cabinet reshuffle pending. It’s almost impossible to know who’s responsible for anything. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Promises to level up communities and put right problems in social care, the NHS and justice have all been abandoned. &nbsp;</p>



<p>After 12 years, the Tories have nothing to offer but another bout of crippling austerity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s obvious they’ve run out of ideas. &nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re so busy fighting among themselves and acting out of self-interest that they no longer care about the country. That’s why we need a general election. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Rishi Sunak can only be regarded as a caretaker. He should be given the necessary support to enact a minimum programme designed to protect the economy from the difficulties which the Tories have caused but only until preparations can be made for an election where the public decides.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe it’s time for a change and time for a Labour government which will be honest and realistic about the challenges ahead. We need to protect energy supplies, create new jobs for the future with our green prosperity plan and manage the economy in the interests of everyone, not a privileged few. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m ready to pit that offer against the tired, played out Tories no matter who leads them.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/27/end-this-game-of-thrones-and-let-the-people-decide/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/10/27/end-this-game-of-thrones-and-let-the-people-decide/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex backs Kinship charity campaign to support struggling kinship carers]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/10/alex-backs-kinship-charity-campaign-to-support-struggling-kinship-carers/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14534</id>
		<updated>2022-10-27T10:04:29Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-27T10:04:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP, Alex Cunningham, is backing Kinship charity’s new #ValueOurLove campaign which aims to secure urgent government support for kinship families across England and Wales. Kinship care is where a family relative or close friend steps up to care for a child when their parents aren’t able to. Grandparents, aunties, uncles, cousins and other [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/10/alex-backs-kinship-charity-campaign-to-support-struggling-kinship-carers/">Alex backs Kinship charity campaign to support struggling kinship carers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Karin Smyth MP says “serious questions must be answered regarding the Home Secretary’s appointment”</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/27/karin-smyth-mp-says-serious-questions-must-be-answered-regarding-the-home-secretarys-appointment/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=karin-smyth-mp-says-serious-questions-must-be-answered-regarding-the-home-secretarys-appointment" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Karin Smyth – MP for Bristol – has called on the new Prime Minister to outline why Suella Braverman MP was reappointed as Home Secretary just six days after being fired for breaching security protocols.</p>
<p>The resignation of Liz Truss MP after 44 days as Prime Minister created the need for the Conservative Party to once again turn inwards and select a new leader, and by extension Prime Minister. 357 Conservative MPs were the electorate for this process. It was planned to then go the Tory membership, but ultimately all candidates dropped out of the contest except Rishi Sunak MP.</p>
<p>Rishi Sunak, Member of Parliament for Richmond, Yorkshire, was Chancellor of the Exchequer under Boris Johnson MP until he resigned in July of this year. He is the first British-Asian to become Prime Minister and has only been an MP since 2015.</p>
<p>The new Prime Minister went about appointing a Cabinet following the request by His Majesty the King to form a government. This saw Dominic Raab MP return as Justice Secretary and Deputy Prime Minister; Simon Hart MP return to Cabinet as Chief Whip; Suella Braverman MP returning as Home Secretary just six days after resigning for breaching security protocols and Michael Gove MP returning as Levelling Up Secretary just 44 days after leaving the post.</p>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, said:</p>
<p>“The new Prime Minister has reverted to Tory type. The appointment of Suella Braverman to Home Secretary just six days after her resignation due to serious security breaches means serious questions must be answered regarding her appointment.</p>
<p>“The Prime Minister promised integrity on the steps of Downing Street, but instead has seemingly undertaken grubby deals to secure his premiership. We cannot forget that Rishi Sunak was also fined for attending parties in Number 10 alongside Boris Johnson. Standards are an afterthought to the current Tory Government.</p>
<p>“Other appointments to Cabinet show a party that has run out of ideas. Dominic Raab returns as Justice Secretary. This beggars belief as under his watch some courts had average waiting times of 426 days for a trial. That’s on top of the shocking statistic that only 1.3% of rape cases are now being prosecuted. We don’t need another Tory Prime Minister selected behind closed doors; we need a General Election. We need a Labour Government.” </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/27/karin-smyth-mp-says-serious-questions-must-be-answered-regarding-the-home-secretarys-appointment/">Karin Smyth MP says “serious questions must be answered regarding the Home Secretary’s appointment”</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth – MP for Bristol – has called on the new Prime Minister to outline why Suella Braverman MP […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/10/27/karin-smyth-mp-says-serious-questions-must-be-answered-regarding-the-home-secretarys-appointment/">Karin Smyth MP says “serious questions must be answered regarding the Home Secretary’s appointment”</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3359</id>
    <published>2022-10-27T09:36:44Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-27T09:36:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our national, regional and local rail network is in chaos.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/10/26/our-national-regional-and-local-rail-network-is-in-chaos/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7556</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T13:00:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T13:00:06Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Stewart Requests Station Bridge Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-requests-station-bridge-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has written to Network Rail Requesting an update on the works to replace the footbridge which connects platforms 1&amp;2 with 3&amp;4. The bridge was closed, and the floor removed in February.
 
A number of constituents raised the issue with Bob via…</content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-requests-station-bridge-update</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Question to the Department for Trade on the UK India Trade Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-department-trade-uk-india-trade-deal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Does my right hon. Friend agree that this is an exciting opportunity to help unlock the economic potential of the living bridge that Prime Minister Modi has recently described? As for the notional timeline of Diwali, does he also agree that getting the right deal is much more important than getting…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-department-trade-uk-india-trade-deal</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith wants Bradford at the centre of the next Rugby League World Cup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-wants-bradford-at-the-centre-of-the-next-rugby-league-world-cup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities in her Bradford South constituency:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Week in, week out, local communities come together to support their clubs, their local kids’ teams and young players.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, levels of investment and opportunities haven’t always matched the pride we feel in our towns and cities, but it’s moments like the world cup that will give communities the opportunities to stand tall and showcase where they live to the world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A compelling levelling-up bid has been submitted to government for a world-class stadium and training complex for elite sports with a Rugby League Skills, Training and Education centre in Odsal to serve the people of Yorkshire and the North. I can’t wait to host the world cup again in a decade’s time and be standing in our very own Odsal stadium in Bradford cheering England on!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding to Judith’s invitation to visit Odsal, Sports Minister Stuart Andrew MP said: “If I’m still in post by the end of the week I’ll still come but, if not, I’ll leave a note to my successor that their first trip needs to be to Bradford!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2022 Cup’s world-leading social impact programme has invested more than £26 million in equipment and facilities, volunteering, mental health, culture and education, to transform clubs into hubs for their communities. And, for the first time, the men’s, women’s and wheelchair tournaments will be held concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study from the Sheffield Hallam University shows that investment in sport and physical activity gives back four times the investment in social value, equivalent to around £72 billion each year across the UK, improving people’s health and wellbeing, creating jobs and stimulating local economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith is fighting for Bradford to have its share:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When the competition is over and the winning teams raise their trophies, it is only the start of the story for communities, not the end. With the Rugby League world cup in full swing, Bradford’s year as capital of culture in 2025, and Bradford’s bid for a world-class stadium and sports complex that will bring over a billion pounds of benefits to Bradford, now is the time to ensure that people of Bradford benefit from this legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3c9.png" alt="🏉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;The Rugby League World Cup &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLWC2021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@RLWC2021&lt;/a&gt; is more than just a competition – it’s a force for good that can transform the fortunes and unlock the potential of towns and cities like Bradford.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; Today I led a debate in Parliament celebrating this fantastic sport. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheRFL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheRFL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ysM6QHjEO9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ysM6QHjEO9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1584880580881063937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, culture, sports, stadium, odsal, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/santander-picture.jpg.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" alt="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has said that banking provision in the constituency has been totally wiped out. "People will have to travel over three miles to get to a bank,” she said, adding that the bank has “failed to take into account the social costs to the local area of removing this vital&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, will, local, bradford, people, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, people, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford. Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2685</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Shows Support for Local Postal Workers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/mp-shows-support-for-local-postal-workers/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=mp-shows-support-for-local-postal-workers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Royal-Mail-Strikes-251022.pdf">Royal-Mail-Strikes-251022</a></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/mp-shows-support-for-local-postal-workers/">MP Shows Support for Local Postal Workers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Royal-Mail-Strikes-251022</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/mp-shows-support-for-local-postal-workers/">MP Shows Support for Local Postal Workers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6514</id>
    <published>2022-10-25T13:31:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-25T13:31:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John asks Ministers to review upcoming rail reforms following changes in the industry]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/10/25/john-asks-ministers-to-review-upcoming-rail-reforms-following-changes-in-the-industry%ef%bf%bc/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5526</id>
		<updated>2022-10-25T12:20:41Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-25T12:01:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/10/25/john-asks-ministers-to-review-upcoming-rail-reforms-following-changes-in-the-industry%ef%bf%bc/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin calls in Parliament for a new name for the West Coast Main Line franchise</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-parliament-new-name-west-coast-main-line-franchise" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Tuesday Aberconwy MP Robin Millar asked the Minister of State for Rail, Kevin Foster MP, if the UK Government agreed that the name of the West Coast Mainline franchise should be changed to reflect the strategic importance of the North Wales Main Line.
Speaking during a debate in Parliament,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-parliament-new-name-west-coast-main-line-franchise</id>
    <published>2022-10-25T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-25T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-176" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Much has happened since I last wrote this column. But I am hopeful a new leader of the Conservative Party and therefore a new Prime Minister following Liz Truss’s resignation, will bring back the stability and certainty we all want to see. In the end there was only one candidate for that role,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-176</id>
    <published>2022-10-25T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-25T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Prime Minister Rishi Sunak</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/prime-minister-rishi-sunak/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I congratulate Rishi Sunak on his election as leader of the Conservative Party. It is important that as our Prime Minister he receives the united support of Conservatives in parliament, as we work together to restore stability to the economy and continue delivering the manifesto on which we were elected in 2019. I had supported […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Kieran Leigh</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6169</id>
    <published>2022-10-25T09:11:29Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-25T09:11:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2021 Christmas Card Competition Winner Welcomed to Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/2021-christmas-card-competition-winner-welcomed-parliament" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was delighted to have welcomed Isabelle, last year’s winner of my Christmas card competition, to Westminster today! Isabelle was joined by her Mum, Lynsey, her Dad, Mark, and her younger sister, Emily. I had a lovely chat with them in Westminster Hall: we discussed just about everything from…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/2021-christmas-card-competition-winner-welcomed-parliament</id>
    <published>2022-10-24T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-24T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Information on using non-barcoded stamps before 1 February 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/10/24/information-on-using-non-barcoded-stamps-before-1-february-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Information I received from Royal Mail regarding the 100-day countdown for customers to use their non-barcoded definitive stamps: “On Monday 24 October there will be just 100 days until non-barcoded Definitive stamps cease to be a valid form of postage.... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/10/24/information-on-using-non-barcoded-stamps-before-1-february-2023/#more-4474">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4474</id>
    <published>2022-10-24T11:31:36Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-24T11:31:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>I respect Boris Johnson's decision, he has stood aside in national interest</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2139-i-respect-boris-johnson-s-decision-he-has-stood-aside-in-national-interest"/>
		<published>2022-10-24T06:35:48+01:00</published>
		<updated>2022-10-24T06:35:48+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2139-i-respect-boris-johnson-s-decision-he-has-stood-aside-in-national-interest</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I respect &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BorisJohnson?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BorisJohnson&lt;/a&gt;’s decision. It is clear he would win amongst the members &amp;amp; I have seen he had the numbers to be nominated. He has stood aside in national interest as he believes you need 2/3 of MPs to govern effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1584415733517537281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I respect &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BorisJohnson?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BorisJohnson&lt;/a&gt;’s decision. It is clear he would win amongst the members &amp;amp; I have seen he had the numbers to be nominated. He has stood aside in national interest as he believes you need 2/3 of MPs to govern effectively.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1584415733517537281?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 24, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Goods Shed Official Opening</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8596" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=3954%2C2417&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3954,2417" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone SE (3rd generation)&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1666363400&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;64&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.01&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="221021 Goods Shed Opening 2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=300%2C183&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=790%2C483&amp;ssl=1"/>
<p>Many, many thanks to ?First Minister, Mark Drakeford, for opening phase one of Llanelli Railway Good Shed in Marsh Street, Llanelli today, a project transforming a grade II listed building into a vibrant community hub. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img data-attachment-id="8597" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-3/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?fit=3939%2C2476&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3939,2476" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone SE (3rd generation)&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1666363320&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;50&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.01&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?fit=300%2C189&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?fit=790%2C497&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?w=790&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-8597" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?w=3939&amp;ssl=1 3939w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?resize=300%2C189&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?resize=768%2C483&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?w=1580 1580w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-3.jpg?w=2370 2370w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img data-attachment-id="8598" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-6/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?fit=4032%2C3024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="4032,3024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone SE (3rd generation)&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1666359884&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;32&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.0010626992561105&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?fit=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?fit=790%2C593&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?w=790&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-8598" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?w=4032&amp;ssl=1 4032w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?w=1580 1580w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-6.jpg?w=2370 2370w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img data-attachment-id="8599" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-10/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?fit=2960%2C2307&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="2960,2307" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone SE (3rd generation)&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1666361601&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;50&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.01&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?fit=300%2C234&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?fit=790%2C616&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?w=790&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-8599" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?w=2960&amp;ssl=1 2960w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?resize=300%2C234&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?resize=768%2C599&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?w=1580 1580w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-10.jpg?w=2370 2370w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img data-attachment-id="8600" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-14/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?fit=3326%2C3024&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3326,3024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?fit=300%2C273&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?fit=790%2C718&amp;ssl=1" src="https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?w=790&amp;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-8600" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?w=3326&amp;ssl=1 3326w, https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?resize=300%2C273&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?resize=768%2C698&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?w=1580 1580w, https://i2.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-14.jpg?w=2370 2370w" sizes="(max-width: 790px) 100vw, 790px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8596" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/10/goods-shed-official-opening/221021-goods-shed-opening-2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=3954%2C2417&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="3954,2417" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;1.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;iPhone SE (3rd generation)&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1666363400&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;3.99&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;64&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.01&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="221021 Goods Shed Opening 2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=300%2C183&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/221021-Goods-Shed-Opening-2.jpg?fit=790%2C483&amp;ssl=1"/>Many, many thanks to ?First Minister, Mark Drakeford, for opening phase one of Llanelli Railway Good Shed in Marsh Street, Llanelli today, a project transforming a grade II listed building into a vibrant community hub.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8595</id>
    <published>2022-10-21T17:26:03Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-21T17:26:03Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3349</id>
		<updated>2022-10-21T16:54:04Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-21T16:46:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="All News"/><category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="In Parliament"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This has been another tumultuous period in British politics culminating with the resignation of the Prime Minister. This had looked inevitable once her mini-budget had to be reversed following the loss of market confidence. The Prime Minister’s diagnosis of the need to do more to increase the growth rate was correct, but sadly the policies [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/">Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/"><![CDATA[
<p>This has been another tumultuous period in British politics culminating with the resignation of the Prime Minister. This had looked inevitable once her mini-budget had to be reversed following the loss of market confidence. The Prime Minister’s diagnosis of the need to do more to increase the growth rate was correct, but sadly the policies she prescribed made the situation worse and it’s right that she has resigned.</p>



<p>We knew that Liz Truss was inheriting a difficult position a few weeks ago with the ongoing cost of living crisis, the significant NHS backlogs, the war in Ukraine and the resulting serious issues with energy prices and supply. To those crises we can now add the market turmoil and the increases in interest rates which are so painful for those with mortgages and will worsen the public finances given the amount of debt we owe – and our ongoing need to borrow.</p>



<p>We should have a new Prime Minister in place by the end of next week, in time for the critical statement by the Chancellor on 31 October setting out the details of the public finances and proposed measures to bring borrowing under control. Regrettably it looks very likely that this will include some difficult measures including tax rises and spending cuts. We will need the new Prime Minister and their team to present a coherent plan that we can unite behind to avoid any further market turmoil.</p>



<p>There has been speculation that these measures should include restricting the increases in the state pension and benefits next April to less than the inflation rate of 10.1%. While increases of this level will represent a significant cost, we cannot seek to balance the books on the backs of the least well off and those unable to work to earn extra money. The state pension has never increased by less than inflation and I’m glad the outgoing Prime Minister confirmed the increase would indeed be 10.1%. We should do the same for benefits too. We can’t expect people livings on the least to get through next winter with less money in real terms than this one.</p>



<p>There have been encouraging signs that global gas prices have started to fall. I hope that this continues and signals that efforts to boost supply and reduce demand around the world have stabilised the position. There are however significant risks this winter and next that in the event of a lengthy period of cold weather we might run out of gas. In the short term we all need to be careful with our use – to reduce our bills and protect supply.</p>



<p>In the longer term we need to do more to obtain secure domestic sources of energy including nuclear, wind solar – and fracking for our own gas. None of these are easy – and very often applications are unpopular. The key thing is to ensure we develop these in areas where they have the least impact and that all applications are properly considered through the planning process with local people consulted. We’ve gone further on fracking and proposed requiring actual local consent which is not required for other planning issues. Again, none of this is easy or popular but relying on cheap imports from abroad is no longer a viable strategy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img alt=""/></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/liz-truss-resignation-my-thoughts/">Liz Truss’ resignation &#8211; My column for the Derby Telegraph</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP at Adjournment Debate on the International response to persecution and discrimination of the Rohingya in Myanmar</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_at_adjournment_debate" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_at_adjournment_debate</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T16:51:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T16:51:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Constituent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing to do so if they contact me directly. But these emails are designed to be informative about local matters, and go to everyone who wants them, regardless of political persuasion, and I do not want to change their local focus even at times when there are significant events at a national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Charity Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a reminder that the Charity Volunteer Fair, which was postponed because of the sad death of Her Majesty the Queen, is being held between 4pm and 6pm this Friday, 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; October at the Dell Centre, St Giles Church, Park Lane, Ashtead, KT21 1EJ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 20 charities will be there, and there will be a wide range of volunteering opportunities. So please do come along. If you can’t make it but are interested in volunteering, please let me know and I will steer you towards the right opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom Methodist Church &amp;#8211; Warm Wednesdays&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epsom Methodist Church is launching a programme of Warm Wednesdays for the winter if people are struggling with their bills and need a place to go and warm up and get some company. The events will be held every Wednesday from November 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; until the end of February. From 9am &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be complimentary hot drinks served in their café, from  12.30 &amp;#8211; 2pm there will be Hot and tasty soup and a roll, from 2pm onwards complimentary hot drinks and homemade cakes, and from 3pm &amp;#8211; 6pm a family after-school club with space for homework, story time, games, films and a free hot meal for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church is in Ashley Road, Epsom, KT18 5AQ. People are welcome just to drop in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Epsom &amp;amp; Ewell Energy Relief Programme&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally thank you to everyone who has supported the Epsom and Ewell Energy Efficiency Programme. The appeal has already raised more than £12,000. If you do not need the £400 Government contribution towards bills this winter, please do donate it to the programme and help those locally who are already struggling with higher bills make their homes more energy efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details of how to give are at &lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/98eeCRO3xsv5ggnEf9CRxP?domain=justgiving.com"&gt;https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best wishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/"&gt;Local Update&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Constituent I am writing with a reminder about a couple of local things. A few people have asked me why I do not address national issues in these emails except where there is useful information to provide. I know that many people want to discuss those issues with me, and I am always willing [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-8/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6321</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T13:39:56Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DOUBLE-DIGIT INFLATION SQUEEZES FAMILY FINANCES FURTHER</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/double-digit-inflation-squeezes-family-finances-further/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Inflation figures for September released today show that inflation once again rose to double-digits last month, with prices rising at the fastest rate for over 40 years. Commenting on the figures, Newcastle North MP Catherine McKinnell said: “Britain faces a cost of living emergency with double-digit inflation hitting a forty year high. “Especially alarming is … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/double-digit-inflation-squeezes-family-finances-further/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">DOUBLE-DIGIT INFLATION SQUEEZES FAMILY FINANCES FURTHER</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7770</id>
    <published>2022-10-19T11:16:19Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-19T11:16:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="cost of living"/>
    <category term="economy"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP Visits Carter’s Sunflowers Nursery</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-visits-carters-sunflowers-nursery/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=local-mp-visits-carters-sunflowers-nursery" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p><strong>Local MP Grant Shapps visited Carter’s Sunflowers Specialist Nursery for children with autism, social communication needs and associated disabilities on Friday. </strong> </p>



<p>Over the course of the visit Mr Shapps heard about the establishment’s achievements and met with parents whose children attend the nursery.</p>



<p>Through its amazing work, Carter’s Sunflowers has helped many parents return to work rather than being a full-time carer – in turn improving their own mental health and wellbeing. </p>



<p>Carter’s Sunflowers supports 26 families in the Welwyn Hatfield and wider Hertfordshire area.</p>



<p>Based in Ludwick Family Club, Welwyn Garden City, the nursery is hoping to expand to provide services for more children in need.</p>



<p>“The feedback from parents today is clear – Carter’s Sunflowers is a unique place for children with specialist needs<a>,”</a> said Mr Shapps.</p>



<p>“The attention to detail from those caring for the children was incredible – I could see that they felt comfortable here”.</p>



<p>“I’m proud to be the local MP for the nursery and will be doing all I can to help find them a larger premisis so they can expand and continue their vital work.”</p>



<p>Lucy Oliveira of Carter’s Sunflowers said “we really appreciate Grant coming along today to find out more about our nursery.</p>



<p>“Having Grant on side to find a larger building is excellent news and we’re grateful for his support<a>.”</a></p>



<p>The organisation also offers special educational needs training and gives confidence to parents that their child is making progress.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-visits-carters-sunflowers-nursery/">Local MP Visits Carter’s Sunflowers Nursery</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Local MP Grant Shapps visited Carter’s Sunflowers Specialist Nursery for children with autism, social communication needs and associated disabilities on Friday.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-visits-carters-sunflowers-nursery/">Local MP Visits Carter’s Sunflowers Nursery</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=45068</id>
    <published>2022-10-18T16:00:41Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-18T16:00:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Carter&amp;#039;s Sunflowers"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Hatfield"/>
    <category term="Nursery"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Surgeries October 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/14/surgeries-may-2022-3-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>My next constituency surgery will take place on <strong>Friday 21st October.</strong></p>



<p>Please note, however, in order to comply with both Covid and security protocol, these will not be drop-in surgeries – <strong>appointments must be made in advance</strong>.</p>



<p>To book, please call 01294 311 160 or email philippa.whitford.mp@parliament.uk </p>



<p>For scheduled dates and times, please see below:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://scontent.fgla3-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t39.30808-6/310316604_414866097493569_8822356364332867418_n.jpg?_nc_cat=101&amp;ccb=1-7&amp;_nc_sid=730e14&amp;_nc_ohc=lEoAdwhU07MAX913cLz&amp;_nc_ht=scontent.fgla3-1.fna&amp;oh=00_AT9yXWheSbZli6mBcIIxLtFJqeWjARPwMYCOAuVNPC0isA&amp;oe=634D4212" alt="May be an image of 1 person, standing and text that says &quot;MP Surgery Friday 21st October 2022 2pm 2.45pm Tarbolton Community Campus Dr Philippa Whitford Central Ayrshire Appointments must be booked in advance. To register, call 01294 311 160 or email phiippa.hiford.mp@parliament.uk&quot;"/></figure>



<p><em><strong>Please note that all surgery dates are subject to change dependent upon Covid guidelines and Parliamentary business. </strong></em></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20October%202022" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20October%202022" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20October%202022" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20October%202022" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;linkname=Surgeries%20October%202022" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F10%2F14%2Fsurgeries-may-2022-3-2%2F&amp;title=Surgeries%20October%202022" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/14/surgeries-may-2022-3-2/" data-a2a-title="Surgeries October 2022"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/14/surgeries-may-2022-3-2/">Surgeries October 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My next constituency surgery will take place on Friday 21st October. Please note, however, in ... <a title="Surgeries October 2022" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/14/surgeries-may-2022-3-2/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/10/14/surgeries-may-2022-3-2/">Surgeries October 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2582</id>
    <published>2022-10-14T13:44:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-14T13:44:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Surgeries"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Zahawi guests at Conservative Annual Dinner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nadhim Zahawi, Chancellor of the Duchy of Lancaster, Minister for Intergovernmental Relations and Minister for Equalities, was the guest speaker at the Bexleyheath and Crayford Conservative Association on Thursday evening (13 October) held at Stuzzichini restaurant in Bexleyheath. In the Chair was…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/zahawi-guests-conservative-annual-dinner</id>
    <published>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking with Business South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Great to speak with Business South about the work they are doing to support businesses in our region, encouraging new start-ups and increasesing apprenticeship opportunities across Southampton. The pressures of increasing energy costs and staff shortages are a big worry for Southampton businesses and I will continue to push for more action to help these [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/10/11/speaking-with-business-south/">Speaking with Business South</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5068</id>
    <published>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-11T12:15:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Veterans in Action BBQ</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/veterans-in-action-bbq/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=veterans-in-action-bbq" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Over the last few years I’ve got to know this brilliant little charity quite well. We’ve done sponsored walks and visits, and as they’ve developed their facilities at Redenham, I’ve dropped by the catch up. And so it was last week when I dropped in to their annual barbecue when they thank supporters and let people have a look around. The brain child of Billy MacLeod MBE, the organisation works with veterans struggling with PTSD and other mental health challenges, giving them confidence and a sense of mission in their lives. It’s a really good example of a little platoon making a huge difference, rebuilding lives one by one. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over the last few years I’ve got to know this brilliant little charity quite well. We’ve done sponsored walks and visits, and as they’ve developed their facilities at Redenham, I’ve dropped by the catch up. And so it was last week when I dropped in to their annual barbecue when they thank supporters and let […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2958</id>
    <published>2022-10-08T14:48:01Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-08T14:48:01Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Autumn Newsletter 2022]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/10/05/autumn-newsletter-2022/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10590</id>
		<updated>2022-10-07T08:26:31Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:38:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="Newsletter"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been a lot happening over the past few weeks and I am glad to finally be getting back to Parliament after a short break during recess and due to the sad passing of the Queen. In that time, the new Government has announced a &#8216;mini&#8217; budget of a seismic scale &#8211; and which ... <a title="Autumn Newsletter 2022" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/10/05/autumn-newsletter-2022/" aria-label="More on Autumn Newsletter 2022">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Supporting Local Pubs </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-supporting-local-pubs" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I have been spending some time recently in pubs—purely in the interests of work you will understand. There have been a number of issues surrounding specific village pubs around Ashford, and their ability to continue to operate, and on top of that there are obviously general issues about the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-supporting-local-pubs</id>
    <published>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-06T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP welcomes Prime Minister Liz Truss speech to Conservative Party Conference 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning the Prime Minister set out our Conservative vision for the future. A country focussed on growth, aspiration and enterprise. Turning away from those who say much and do little, the anti-growth coalition we are so used to seeing on our screens and in the hall today.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[CHECKMATE!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=467</id>
		<updated>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</updated>
		<published>2022-10-05T11:25:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/10/05/checkmate/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/september-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5588" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" data-type="URL" data-id="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for September 2022.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for September 2022.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5587</id>
    <published>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="September"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bust Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/09/27/bust-budget/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</p>



<p>The tax cuts in this mini budget, are mainly for the super wealthy, for corporations and for the bankers. The top tax rate of 45p (%) has been completely removed, which is great news for those lucky few that earn over £150,000 a year. Corporation tax increases have been discarded, and the cap on bankers’ bonuses brought in after the financial crisis of 2008 have been scrapped.</p>



<p>But the Tories aren’t content with just giving handouts to the rich, they have also increased the number of Universal Credit recipients who have to actively search for work and attend weekly or fortnightly job centre appointments, if they are working up to 15 hours a week. If they don’t then their benefits will be reduced. Unsurprisingly the mini-budget also attacks trade union rights further, making it harder for working people to strike for the pay and conditions they deserve.</p>



<p>While they have suspended National Insurance increases and cut stamp duty, this support is minute compare to the support for those best off in society. Even in terms of energy bill support, prices being frozen where they are now, simply means they are only twice what they were last year, at the same time that the price for everything else from food to transport is increasing, while wages and benefits remain completely stagnant.</p>



<p>This budget does not serve the needs of the people of Nottingham, it does not help those who need help the most. People earning £20,000 will only save £167 a year. What it will do is drive Britain into an inflationary spiral. It will cause the prices of the goods that residents need to survive to increase further, at a time where benefits and wages are not rising. This will wipe out any gains that residents in the city see from this mini-budget.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg"><img src="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2931" width="398" height="271" srcset="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg 1024w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-768x524.jpg 768w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1536x1047.jpg 1536w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px"/></a><figcaption>the Tory mini-budget will only give most people small change</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Tories say their budget will stimulate growth; it remains to be seen if it will. What is certain though is that growth in the economy is pointless if it does not lead to increased wages for the average person, if people are not supported to re-skill and obtain jobs in growing sectors, and if people do not have access to suitable affordable housing, whether that’s via home ownership or renting.</p>



<p>The mini budget does nothing to help achieve these aims, Nottingham Labour strongly believe that the budget will not help the people of Nottingham, it will only help a tiny minority of people. A Labour government is needed nationally to give the people of this country and of Nottingham the support and help that they need, and that they deserve.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</updated>
    <category term="east midlands"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Cuts"/>
    <category term="debt"/>
    <category term="inflation"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="taxes"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes the Conservative Government’s Growth Plan, helping two million people across the East Midlands keep more of their hard-earned money</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/09/23/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-the-conservative-governments-growth-plan-helping-two-million-people-across-the-east-midlands-keep-more-of-their-hard-earned-money/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan, starting a new era focused on economic growth, whilst tackling the immediate energy crisis and removing barriers for businesses to build the infrastructure we need to grow the British economy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan puts more money in people’s pockets by cutting National Insurance and Income Tax – including an extra £330 a year from the cut to National Insurance contributions and saving families £1,400 on their energy bills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To deliver on this mission, the Chancellor has also announced 38 Investment Zones and over 100 infrastructure projects across the country to drive the investment and growth in the areas that need it the most.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan – setting out support for families with their energy bills and unleashing a new era of growth through tax cuts and investment incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Warman MP has welcomed the Chancellor’s measures set out for families across Boston and Skegness who will have their energy bills cut by up to £1,400 through the Energy Price Guarantee, whilst businesses eligible for The Energy Bill Relief Scheme will have their energy bills slashed by cutting the price of wholesale gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor also confirmed people across the East Midlands will benefit from personal tax cuts – cutting National Insurance contributions by 1.25 per cent, putting an extra £330 a year in people’s pockets and helping them with cost-of-living pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means two million people across the East Midlands region will save £255 a year thanks to the cut to National Insurance contributions, and 2.4 million people across the East Midlands will save £160 a year thanks to the slash to Income tax in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside these measures the Conservative Government announced further personal cuts – including cutting stamp duty permanently by doubling the nil-rate band to £250,000 (from £125,000), increasing the nil-rate band for first time buyers to £425,000 (from £300,000) and increasing the value of the property which first-time buyers can claim relief to £625,000 from (£500,000).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These measures combined mean a typical family moving into a semi-detached property will save £2,500 on stamp duty and £1,150 on energy bills – and if they have a combined income of £50,000 around an additional £560 on tax. This is around £4,200 in total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan also unleashes 38 Investment Zones across England, unlocking housing and driving growth through tax incentives and over 100 infrastructure projects that will be accelerated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These measures will unleash growth through tax cuts and reform, tackle the immediate energy crisis, removing barriers for business, and building the infrastructure needed to grow the British economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Matt Warman MP said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;“In the face of rising energy prices and cost of living pressures it is right that this Conservative Government has come forward with a serious support package and a plan for growth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I welcome support set out for people across Boston and Skegness today, including cuts to National Insurance contributions, Income Tax and Stamp Duty – all helping families to keep more of their hard-earned money.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Only the Conservatives can be trusted to make the reforms we need to grow our economy – delivering higher wages, lower taxes and more money for our public services.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, The Chancellor of the Exchequer said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Growth is not as high as it should be. This has made it harder to pay for public services, requiring taxes to rise and cost of living pressures to increase.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We need to change this and be unashamed in our Growth Plan – expanding the supply side of the economy, through tax incentives and reform, whilst we help families now by cutting their energy bills by £1,400 a year and slashing personal taxes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“That is how we will deliver higher wages, greater opportunities, and crucially, fund public services, now and into the future.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the Conservative Government delivered The Growth Plan, starting a new era focused on economic growth, whilst tackling the immediate energy crisis and removing barriers for businesses to build the infrastructure we need to grow the British economy. The Conservative Government’s Growth Plan puts more money in people’s pockets by […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4127</id>
    <published>2022-09-23T14:20:21Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-23T14:20:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom</h2>



<p>The availability of free education is a gift, but only if it can come with high quality. Google Classroom has given students in classrooms around the country an online option to supplement their learning. A potential downside to these options is the inability to meet with professors and apply classroom learning. As a part of the University of Washington system, we have found the use of Google Classroom during the quarter distance courses produced good results for both parties. Distance learning is here to stay and has only grown over time. If you want to make sure you aren’t left behind in a digital world, you may want to consider your options and how they will help or hurt your future professional prospects.</p>



<p>Google Classroom is a reliable one-stop-shop for managing all of your coursework and communication. It is definitely worth checking out if you are in a distance learning program, or even just want to streamline some of your everyday communication tasks.</p>



<h3>Benefits and Drawbacks</h3>



<p>There are several other features that set Google Classroom apart from the competition. It is a free tool and it works on computers and mobile devices through the GAFE platform. The discussion features of Google Classroom do an excellent job at encouraging interaction between students and teachers, making it a very effective tool for working with groups of all sizes. The major drawback to Google Classroom is that it is a relatively new tool, so it does not work with iPads, Android tablets or Kindle Fires. The lessons created within Google Docs can be exported directly into Google Classroom on the computer, but in order to view or edit those documents or upload them onto the iPad tablet, students will have to use other third-party tools such as Documents 5 and iBooks Author.</p>



<h2>Integration</h2>



<p>If you are using Google Classroom for your teaching and learning, it is important to note that it does require integration with Google Apps for Education. This means that you are using Gmail along with Calendar and Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides) etc., so the other school faculty members need to have access to all of these tools. The obvious way to do this is through the use of a domain. It is required that you have a domain in order to use Google Classroom or any other GAFE tool/application.</p>



<p>By going through a step by step process, one can easily move one’s entire digital repository into Google Classroom for easy organization and management; therefore, allowing access to all student work without having to worry about losing any data or files that are not needed for a current class engagement.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom Future Prospects</h2>



<p>According to the Scholastic Parent &amp; Child list of the most popular educational apps , in 2015 Classroom wasn’t one of them, indicating that this tool is still relatively new and also relatively unknown. While the design is nothing particularly innovative, the new Google Classroom 2022 is a promising step towards more effective and efficient learning, especially in a classroom setting. Though it appears to be geared towards teachers, students will benefit from having access to Google Classroom, whether they’re in an online or a traditional classroom. With that said, it should be noted that it may take some time before this update fully penetrates into secondary schools and universities. But nonetheless, Google Classroom is off on the right foot, leaning further into an online world which we’ll all have to face sooner or later.</p>



<h2>Bottom Line</h2>



<p>Google Classroom has made a huge impact in the world of educational technology, especially for teachers who don’t have face-to-face access to students. It’s a powerful tool that will likely continue to be developed and improved upon, as educators keep gravitating towards it.</p>



<p>In the end, there is no one best way to teach and learn, but instead many valid options. Whether you are interested in the low-cost education of a MOOC or the high-end technology of Sketchfab virtual reality tours, it’s exciting to see that educational technology is progressing at a rapid rate. Let’s hope that as more schools begin to adopt innovative techniques like Google Classroom, we will continue to see positive changes in how students learn around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission. Google […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=211</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time>
</div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=5_dyguZK" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/>



  </div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-63620eb6cc164" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-63620eb6cc164').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"63620eb6cc164","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-63620eb6cc164" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-63620eb6cc164" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="63620eb6cc164" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_63620eb6cc164" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_63620eb6cc164" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_63620eb6cc164" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_63620eb6cc164" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_63620eb6cc164" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_63620eb6cc164" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_63620eb6cc164_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-63620eb6cc164 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dx2kyeNuki_tCvzxzWNgGih9Hs-rCkutP2GRmfkuNtmd4ldNhqwTNfmHTGcolBA-XsTYajtTo4ThMwJF68YSQ' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
