<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-01-22T18:00:44Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/01/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Supported Samaritans’ #BrewMonday to encourage people to have a virtual cup of tea (or coffee!) together to keep in touch with friends and family. You can find this here: https://twitter.com/SteveBakerHW/status/1351135030442135557 Helped raise awareness for Cervical Cancer Prevention Week. You can find this here: https://twitter.com/SteveBakerHW/status/1351543698996269056/photo/1 Highlighted serious human rights abuses in Kashmir &amp; asked the FCDO for a coordinated international effort to have UN human rights officials on both sides of the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy-Anne Hickey</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18360</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T17:25:50Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T17:25:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="#Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A vaccination update from West Berkshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/01/22/a-vaccination-update-from-west-berkshire/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The vaccination programme is being delivered by the NHS but we retain a keen interest in how the roll out is progressing locally. We were pleased to be joined at Monday’s Local Outbreak Engagement Board Dr Abid Irfan from the Berkshire West Clinical Commissioning Group and to hear his update on the progress made so far.</p>
<p>We know what residents are most interested in is what is happening in their community – and when they and those they care about will get their doses.</p>
<p>Whilst there is monumental effort by the NHS nationally to distribute the vaccine, much of the hard work to get doses to residents is being done by local GP surgeries. They have been working collaboratively to set up local vaccination centres which they are running together, and with the support of our local Clinical Commissioning Group.</p>
<p>There are two local vaccination centres; one in Pangbourne, involving three GP local surgeries, and one in Newbury which is a larger site covering nine individual GPs surgeries. Until the end of January they will be vaccinating anyone over 80 as well as frontline health workers and social care workers. From there they will move on to the over-75s, and then the over 70s and those who are clinically extremely vulnerable.</p>
<p>GP surgeries have worked really hard to get these vaccination centres up and running as quickly as possible. It has been great to read the praise for the centre staff from patients grateful to have received their vaccine. Although vaccinations are being delivered as quickly as possible it will take time to get to everyone – please be patient and wait for your GP to contact you about making an appointment.</p>
<p>The speed at which our NHS partners are working and the complexity in arranging a national vaccination programme means that along the way they will experience some logistical difficulties. This week Newbury Racecourse has come in for a little criticism for not allowing vaccinations to continue at their site on race days. The reality is that it would be challenging for the site to operate seven day a week due to the vaccine distribution process. GPs were aware of these operational issues before setting up the centre and they did so confident that they would still be able to reach their targets within timelines – even without doing on the odd few days.</p>
<p>Speaking of the vaccination centre, we have received several enquiries asking whether more trains can stop at the Newbury Racecourse station. We’ve asked the question of GWR, and are pleased to say that they have agreed to put on more trains. It will take a couple of weeks to implement, but we’re grateful to them for their flexibility and delighted that local residents will have more sustainable travel options when journeying to get their vaccination.</p>
<p>Elsewhere we are ploughing on with our plans for new community testing facilities in the district. We are close to agreeing our first testing site for Newbury which should open next month and will allow testing for critical and key workers, as well as people involved in the management of local outbreaks. There will be a phased approach to those identified for testing and the relevant cohorts will be invited to join the testing programme over a series of weeks. Once that is up and running we will then be looking at additional sites in the east and west of the district, and potentially a mobile unit too. Testing to identify asymptomatic Covid carriers is important in managing the outbreak, and a potential release of the restrictions so we are working to get these open as quickly as we can. We’ll keep you updated on this as our plans progress.</p>
<p>Away from the pandemic response, business as usual continues and this week we were thrilled to announce this year’s Community Champion Awards. We haven’t been able to do an awards ceremony this year but it shouldn’t take anything away from this year’s winners with the standard as high as ever. This year we introduced special categories in relation to coronavirus, in addition to our usual categories and it allowed us to recognise a broad spectrum of community-minded activities this year. There are far too many to mention here but do please take a look at the website and read about the incredible winners we’ve had this year.</p>
<p>We’re continuing to look beyond the immediate demands of the pandemic to plan for the future and we have a number of important consultations closing in the next few weeks. These include the Newbury Town Centre Masterplan Study (which closes on 31 January), Local Plan Review 2037 (closes on 5 February) and the Minerals and Waste Plan (closes on 15 February). We have also started a consultation this week on our proposal for a new sports ground at Newbury Rugby Club. Each one is really important in helping us take into account local views as we look at how the district develops in the coming years. Whilst we all find ourselves confined to our homes please take a time to look at these documents and tell us what you think.</p>
<p>•For more information about vaccinations, including the number of people vaccinated as we receive the data, visit: <a href="https://info.westberks.gov.uk/covid-vaccination">https://info.westberks.gov.uk/covid-vaccination</a></p>
<p>•To find out more about the Community Champion Awards visit <a href="https://info.westberks.gov.uk/awardwinners">https://info.westberks.gov.uk/awardwinners</a></p>
<p>Yours sincerely,<br/>
Lynne Doherty<br/>
Leader of the Council</p>
<p>Nick Carter<br/>
Chief Executive</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The vaccination programme is being delivered by the NHS but we retain a keen interest in how the roll out is progressing locally. We were pleased to be joined at Monday’s Local Outbreak Engagement Board Dr Abid Irfan from the Berkshire West Clinical Commissioning Group and to hear his update on the progress made so…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29504</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T16:21:17Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T16:21:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Wokingham and West Berkshire Issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>LAPTOP SUPPORT TO HELP CHILDREN REACH THEIR TRUE POTENTIAL WELCOMED BY LOCAL MP.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/laptop-support-to-help-children-reach-their-true-potential-welcomed-by-local-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, Member of Parliament for Newcastle North has expressed her gratitude to True Potential LLP who have donated much needed laptops to Farne Primary School. The donation was made possible when the local business approached Catherine to say they had excess equipment that they would like to donate to a local school in need. … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/laptop-support-to-help-children-reach-their-true-potential-welcomed-by-local-mp/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">LAPTOP SUPPORT TO HELP CHILDREN REACH THEIR TRUE POTENTIAL WELCOMED BY LOCAL MP.</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7077</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T15:41:49Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T15:41:49Z</updated>
    <category term="Children and Young People"/>
    <category term="Education"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A great start – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-great-start-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=a-great-start-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233249" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Great-start.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching or reading the news over the past ten months or so has – unsurprisingly – not always been fun. The pandemic has been a grim time and some days it feels like the only news around is bad news. This week, I’d like to focus on some very positive and promising news right here in Tameside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure you were just as delighted as I was when, towards the end of last year, we found out that there was not just one but three working vaccines for COVID-19. We all worked out fairly early in the pandemic that a vaccine was the only way for us to return to normality so this was probably the best news of 2020 (admittedly there wasn’t a lot of competition!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even with the vaccines approved, we knew there would be a wait as they were rolled out. Luckily for us here in Tameside, the start of this rollout has been a huge success locally. Thanks to the incredible hard work and dedication of those in our local NHS, the council, the armed forces and others, all working in careful coordination with each other, the vaccination programme is going incredibly well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 90% of those over 80 have received at least one jab, which compares to 35% nationally. There has been no wastage or stockpiling and all vaccines that have been received have been distributed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, of course, early days, but I’d like to thank everyone involved in this amazing effort for working so quickly and efficiently to vaccinate some of our residents who are most vulnerable to the virus. The quicker we get vaccinated, the quicker restrictions can be lifted and we can start to return to normality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of the roll-out also shows the difference it makes putting local bodies in charge, rather than outsourcing to private companies at a national level, as we saw with the Test and Trace system, which has been incredibly expensive despite never really working. Our local health and council workers understand the situation here and this has helped them deliver this programme so successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still a long way to go before all the vaccines have been given (both first and second jabs) but this is a great start and evidence from elsewhere has shown that infections will also come down as more people are vaccinated. So let’s follow restrictions to keep each other safe while we wait for our turn to be vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-great-start-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/"&gt;A great start &amp;#8211; my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Watching or reading the news over the past ten months or so has – unsurprisingly – not always been fun. The pandemic has been a grim time and some days it feels like the only news around is bad news. This week, I’d like to focus on some very positive and promising news right here […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/a-great-start-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">A great start – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233248</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T15:18:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T15:18:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus"/>
    <category term="Local"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Spaces for People update looks beyond pandemic</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13085/spaces-for-people-update-looks-beyond-pandemic" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The latest review of Edinburgh’s Spaces for People programme proposes a citywide consultation and assessment criteria for retaining some of the schemes implemented once COVID restrictions are eased.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13085/spaces-for-people-update-looks-beyond-pandemic</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T15:06:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T15:06:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-40/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>My thoughts are with everyone affected by the terrible flooding in Skewen this week.  I’ve spoken with the leader of Council Rob Jones, local councillor Mike Harvey and colleagues Stephen Kinnock and David Rees, in whose constituency the events occurred, and offered them my full support. My thanks and admiration go to those frontline staff and emergency services who continue to work tirelessly on site. The vast majority of properties affected are in the Aberavon constituency, but if any of my constituents in surrounding streets are affected and need any help please get in touch with my office. This of course also goes for anyone else affected by flooding in parts of the Neath constituency.</p>
<p>I have attended several All Party Parliamentary Groups (APPGs) this week.  Gareth Thomas MP was re-elected Chair and I was elected Treasurer of the APPG on Mutuals. We heard presentations from Robin Fieth, Chief Executive of the Building Societies Association, Kate Creagh, Public Affairs Manager, BSA, Rose Marley, Chief Executive, Co-operatives UK and Martin Shaw, Chief Executive of the Association of Financial Mutuals, which represents 45 Mutuals/Friendlies/Not for Profits in UK. All contributions outlined the benefits of mutuals. The BSA represents 49 building societies and credit unions in the UK, but as a Labour and Co-operative MP, I was particularly interested in Co-operatives UK, which represents 7063 independent co-ops in the UK, and 241,714 employees and aims to create new livelihoods, keep jobs in local communities, and use local assets to transfer Coronavirus community spirit into local social actions.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the MPs and Peers of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Steel and Metal related industries met for the first time in 2021 in a meeting that was extremely well attended. Members of the APPG were able to welcome Lord Grimstone, the Minister for Investment at DIT and BEIS who holds Steel within his responsibilities, to the meeting and to question him on his priorities for the sector and vision for the UK steel sector and government working together. Lord Grimstone emphasised that, while new to the role, he understood that he could be a champion within Government for the sector on issues such as procurement and committed to meeting with members of the APPG on individual issues where appropriate.</p>
<p>Additionally, APPG members had the opportunity to hear from Frank Aaskov of UK Steel, who gave a preview of ‘Closing the Gap’, UK Steel’s fifth annual report into the industrial energy price disparity faced by our steel producers compared to those in France and Germany. As with years previously, the figures continue to be eye-watering, and MPs were interested to hear about what individual steps recommended in the report would each mean. When the report is formally launched on the 4th February, MPs will have access to a full suite of suggested talking points and suggested Parliamentary Questions as we urge the government to take action on this continuing disadvantage our steelmakers face.</p>
<p>I attended the Co-operative Party Parliamentary Group made up of 26 Labour and Co-operative MPs plus many Peers. We made plans to build on the successful Parliamentary campaigns we held in 2020 in association with trade unions, such as protecting shop workers and promoting the co-operative values in Parliament in 2021. We discussed campaigning in the forthcoming May elections, in which we have a record number of candidates standing under the Labour and Co-operative banner for national and Police and Crime Commissioner elections. We also looked towards campaigning in the local government elections to be held in 2022.</p>
<p>Also on Tuesday I attended the APPG for Gaps in Support, which was set up at the start of the first lockdown for the specific purpose of highlighting the several million people who have been left without support, such as freelancers and some small business owners. This month’s meeting focused on the potentially 2 million active non-employing limited companies that have received little help from the UK Government since last March, and ForgottenUK’s proposal for a ‘Directors Income Support Scheme’. The well-crafted DISS proposal addresses the Government’s concerns with providing support to directors of limited companies by basing any grants on a company’s taxable profits and not dividends. The meeting was well attended by a range of cross-party MPs, as well as representatives from employment status bodies and sector federations.</p>
<p>A new Covid recovery app was launched this week in Wales for people recovering from Covid or living with the effects of Long Covid. The app has been designed to offer people a bespoke tool to monitor symptoms and track the progress of your recovery. It includes advice from consultants, therapists, psychologists, dieticians and other experts in how best to support yourself with your symptoms. GPs are still incredibly important in signposting help and providing the necessary medical tests and advice, but this app is a great resource in monitoring any changes in symptoms that indicate you need to seek medical advice. To download the app, search ‘Covid Recovery’ in the App Store or Google Play.</p>
<p>Remember, you can keep up to date with Welsh Government announcements on their dedicated <a href="https://gov.wales/coronavirus">coronavirus page</a>, and you can also find useful information on my Facebook and Twitter accounts.  As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch about any matters that fall under my role as an MP, please do not hesitate to drop us an email on christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call us on 01639 630152. My staff are working from home to comply with the social distancing measures, but, as always, we remain there should you need to get in contact with us.</p>
<p>I hope you stay well, and remember – observe social distancing, wash your hands regularly and keep Wales safe.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My thoughts are with everyone affected by the terrible flooding in Skewen this week.  I’ve spoken with the leader of Council Rob Jones, local councillor Mike Harvey and colleagues Stephen Kinnock and David Rees, in whose constituency the events occurred, and offered them my full support. My thanks and admiration go to those frontline staff […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2365</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T13:41:46Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T13:41:46Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccination Questions </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/vaccination-questions" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week saw the vaccine roll out gathering pace, which is exciting news for those receiving the vaccine and provides some much-needed positive news for the rest of us. Local Age UKs have reported that they are receiving calls from older people who are worried about how they will receive their…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/vaccination-questions</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The views of women and girls across Hampshire are being sought to help shape government strategy to tackle violence and abuse.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/views-women-and-girls-across-hampshire-are-being-sought-help-shape-government-strategy-tackle" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Government is updating the Violence Against Women and Girls strategy and has launched a nationwide Call for Evidence in order to ensure that those who have lived experiences of abuse and violence, and the views of members of the public are at the heart of plans to stop these harmful crimes. The…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/views-women-and-girls-across-hampshire-are-being-sought-help-shape-government-strategy-tackle</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccination priority</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/vaccination-priority" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A lot of people have asked questions about local vaccine supply and who we are prioritising. Anne-Marie's statement on that is below:
 
First, I want to praise the incredible efforts of our local teams of GPs, nurses, healthcare assistants, support staff and volunteers who have been working so hard…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/vaccination-priority</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP praises local NHS after South Cumbria administers 4th highest percentage of vaccinations in the country</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1390897/mp-praises-local-nhs-after-south-cumbria-administers-4th-highest-percentage-of-vaccinations-in-the-country"/>
  <updated>2021-01-22T11:31:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1390897/mp-praises-local-nhs-after-south-cumbria-administers-4th-highest-percentage-of-vaccinations-in-the-country</id>
  <summary type="text">Local MP Tim Farron has praised the work of after it was revealed that the South Cumbria and Lancashire region has administered the fourth highest percentage of COVID-19 vaccines to people aged 80 and over in the country.
New figures from NHS England show that as of January 17th, 75.7% of people in South Cumbria and Lancashire aged 80 and over had received their first dose of the vaccine, totalling to 70,027 people.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Local MP Tim Farron has praised the work of after it was revealed that the South Cumbria and Lancashire region has administered the fourth highest percentage of COVID-19 vaccines to people aged 80 and over in the country.</p>
<p>New figures from NHS England show that as of January 17<sup>th</sup>, 75.7% of people in South Cumbria and Lancashire aged 80 and over had received their first dose of the vaccine, totalling to 70,027 people.</p>
<p>Out of the 42 sub-regions in England, South Cumbria and Lancashire had administered the fourth highest percentage of vaccines, closely followed by the North Cumbria and North East region in fifth where 114,117 people have been given their first dose which is 70.8% of those aged 80 and over.</p>
<p>Tim said: <em>"I'm absolutely delighted to see our area making such brilliant progress in rolling out the vaccine.</em></p>
<p><em>"From GPs to nurses, from pharmacists to volunteers, I want to say a massive thank you to everyone who is working their absolute socks off in this Herculean effort to get people vaccinated.</em></p>
<p><em>"The speedy delivery of the vaccine will save lives and ultimately end this pandemic so we can protect livelihoods and restore liberties."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz responds to rise in care home outbreaks in Leicester]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-rise-in-care-home-outbreaks-in-leicester/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=10852</id>
		<updated>2021-01-22T10:34:07Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-22T10:34:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="leicester"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Liz in the news"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="liz kendall"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="NHS"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Social Care"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Supporting families"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spoke to a number of care homes this week about the vaccine roll-out in Leicester. It&#8217;s very worrying to hear that some homes haven&#8217;t been able to vaccinate all of their residents and staff. The Government promised that all care homes would be vaccinated by Sunday, and they must deliver on this.<br />
While it is good news that over 56,000 people have been vaccinated in Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland, we are still in a race against time against this virus. The rise in care home outbreaks is concerning, and I ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-rise-in-care-home-outbreaks-in-leicester/">Liz responds to rise in care home outbreaks in Leicester</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-rise-in-care-home-outbreaks-in-leicester/"><![CDATA[<p>I spoke to a number of care homes this week about the vaccine roll-out in Leicester. It&#8217;s very worrying to hear that some homes haven&#8217;t been able to vaccinate all of their residents and staff. The Government promised that all care homes would be vaccinated by Sunday, and they must deliver on this.</p>
<p>While it is good news that over 56,000 people have been vaccinated in Leicester, Leicestershire and Rutland, we are still in a race against time against this virus. The rise in care home outbreaks is concerning, and I will keep raising this with the Government and the NHS to make sure everything is being done to protect our care staff and residents.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.leicestermercury.co.uk/news/leicester-news/major-coronavirus-outbreaks-flare-up-4914589">Read more in the Leicester Mercury.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-8352" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tackling-crime-and-anti-social-behaviour-in-new-parks/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/asb1-150x150.jpg" alt="Tackling Crime and Anti-Social Behaviour in New Parks" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/tackling-crime-and-anti-social-behaviour-in-new-parks/" class="wp_rp_title">Tackling Crime and Anti-Social Behaviour in New Parks</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-7409" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-pledges-new-support-for-families-caring-for-elderly-and-disabled-relatives/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/IMG_4221-150x150.jpg" alt="Labour will support families caring for elderly and disabled relatives" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/labour-pledges-new-support-for-families-caring-for-elderly-and-disabled-relatives/" class="wp_rp_title">Labour will support families caring for elderly and disabled relatives</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-9420" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-closure-of-foxs-glacier-mints-factory/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/25.jpg" alt="Liz responds to closure of Fox’s Glacier Mints factory" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-closure-of-foxs-glacier-mints-factory/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz responds to closure of Fox’s Glacier Mints factory</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-8941" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/98-mps-support-calls-for-parliamentary-commission-on-health-and-social-care/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/First-page-TM-letter-2703-150x150.jpg" alt="98 MPs support calls for Parliamentary Commission on Health and Social Care" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/98-mps-support-calls-for-parliamentary-commission-on-health-and-social-care/" class="wp_rp_title">98 MPs support calls for Parliamentary Commission on Health and Social Care</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-6253" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/hospital-patients-face-higher-risk-of-death-at-night-because-nhs-cuts-have-left-wards-short-staffed-daily-mirror-14-apr/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/24.jpg" alt="Hospital patients face higher risk of death at night because NHS cuts have left wards short staffed (Daily Mirror, 14 Apr" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/hospital-patients-face-higher-risk-of-death-at-night-because-nhs-cuts-have-left-wards-short-staffed-daily-mirror-14-apr/" class="wp_rp_title">Hospital patients face higher risk of death at night because NHS cuts have left wards short staffed (Daily Mirror, 14 Apr</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-responds-to-rise-in-care-home-outbreaks-in-leicester/">Liz responds to rise in care home outbreaks in Leicester</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli MP &amp; MS call on Carms Council for more time on Ysgol Mynyddygarreg closure plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2021/01/llanelli-mp-ms-call-on-carms-council-for-more-time-on-ysgol-mynyddygarreg-closure-plan/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Llanelli’s MP, Nia Griffith, and MS, Lee Waters, have
called on Plaid Cymru run Carmarthenshire County Council to extend the
consultation period on its controversial proposal to close Welsh-medium Ysgol
Mynyddygarreg in Kidwelly so that the local community has more time to have its
voice heard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Under the plans, Ysgol Mynyddygarreg is set to close at
the end of August this year with pupils transferring to Ysgol Gwenllian
instead.&amp;nbsp; The public consultation was launched earlier this month and is
due to end on February 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; but has come in for criticism from
parents and local residents due to it being held in the middle of the
coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;NIA GRIFFITH, Member of Parliament for Llanelli, said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This is a massively important decision that will affect
the future of education in the area for generations to come.&amp;nbsp; Local people
and those who rely on the school must have every opportunity to have their
voice heard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Staff and governors at the school are extremely busy at
the moment just trying to keep things going as normally as possible.&amp;nbsp; As a
result of the pandemic and the current lockdown, parents are also under the
cosh now that they have to do their best to support their children’s home
learning as well.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To have this consultation come at such a difficult time
is not helping and the onus is now on the Plaid Council to be more sympathetic
and extend the period for people to respond to the closure plan and give them
more of a chance to get their views across before any decisions are made.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2018, Welsh Government guidelines were changed so that
there was a presumption against the closure of small rural schools. Council’s
must now explain why closure is the ‘most appropriate’ course of action, with
Education Secretary Kirsty Williams saying that all viable alternatives should
be considered first.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;LEE WATERS, Llanelli’s Member of the Senedd, added:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A little bit of flexibility from the Council on this
would go a long way in enabling everyone who will be affected by the plans to
get all the information they need to respond properly.&amp;nbsp; Just a few weeks
extra will make a huge difference and allow for local people to make a more
informed contribution.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I don’t think that the community is asking for much,
especially given the magnitude of the proposals and the exceptional
circumstances that we all find ourselves in at the present time.&amp;nbsp; It will
also be key that when the time comes for the consultation responses to be
considered that concerns raised are answered in as much detail as possible,
taking into account the need to provide the best quality education for all
existing and future pupils.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Llanelli’s MP, Nia Griffith, and MS, Lee Waters, have called on Plaid Cymru run Carmarthenshire County Council to extend the consultation period on its controversial proposal to close Welsh-medium Ysgol Mynyddygarreg in Kidwelly so that the local community has more time to have its voice heard. Under the plans, Ysgol Mynyddygarreg is set to close […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7943</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T10:29:26Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T10:29:26Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 22 January</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron22jan" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>This week started with ‘Blue Monday’ – said to be the most depressing day of the year. In 2021, it’s especially important that we take the opportunity to talk about mental health. People are rightly worried about the numbers of people losing their lives to Covid and the impact on loved ones. Local business owners lie awake at night wondering how they will survive with their livelihoods intact. Families, friends and neighbours have been apart from one another – with major milestones celebrated virtually. This pandemic has been especially tough for older people, particularly those who live on their own and are already at greater risk of loneliness and social isolation; and it comes on top of an epidemic in a mental health that has roots long predating Covid.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron22jan</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T09:56:29Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T09:56:29Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP hails county jab progress</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/mp-hails-county-jab-progress" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;West Worcestershire MP Harriett Baldwin has praised health chiefs and local health teams and GPs who are rolling out vaccines to vulnerable groups and essential health and care workers at a speed that offers hope of a release of lockdown in the near future. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/mp-hails-county-jab-progress" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5029 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-22T07:24:45Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-22T07:24:45Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccine Rollout Continues!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/vaccine-rollout-continues/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">The vaccination centre at Oak Park has now been up and running for over a week and I would like to commend the work of all those who are directly involved, or supporting this remarkable roll out of the Covid-19 vaccination programme.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">At the same time Millennium Point in Birmingham is now also up and running creating extra vaccination capacity.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">Over 756,433 vaccines have now been administered across the Midlands as we lead the way in the vaccination programme.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">We are making terrific progress, and whilst there is still a long way to go, we should be pleased with the current progress. Thank you again to everyone involved!</div>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">I appreciate that people want to receive their vaccinations but please do remember, it is really important that as residents you wait until you are contacted by your GP practice or by the NHS.</div>
</div>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The vaccination centre at Oak Park has now been up and running for over a week and I would like to commend the work of all those who are directly involved, or supporting this remarkable roll out of the Covid-19 vaccination programme. At the same time Millennium Point in Birmingham is now also up and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3513</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T17:03:53Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T17:03:53Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne calls for vaccine deliveries to prioritise areas that have not yet started over 80s</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/parliament/dunne-calls-vaccine-deliveries-prioritise-areas-have-not-yet-started-over-80s" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="6872" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;21 January 2021&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dunne calls for vaccine deliveries to prioritise areas that have not yet started over 80s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Philip Dunne calls for vaccine deliveries to be prioritised to those areas such as South West Shropshire primary care network which have yet to deploy vaccine for over 80s in the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-72524" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/blFhAxX3vy4?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1542"&gt;Philip Dunne (Ludlow) (Con) [V]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I applaud my right hon. Friend and his colleagues across the NHS, especially here in Shropshire, for the massive effort by so many people to get this vaccination into those in the highest priority groups so quickly. However, there are still some parts of the country where only care homes and NHS frontline staff have been vaccinated, and in the South West Shropshire primary care network, no one in the community over 80 has yet received the vaccine, and none are expected to until late next week. May I ask my right hon. Friend, in common with the pleas made by a number of colleagues, to look at prioritising deliveries for those areas where the highest priority groups have yet to receive the vaccinations that they are being led to believe are now widely available?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4070"&gt;Matt Hancock (Secretary of State for Health &amp; Social Care) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across Shropshire, and Telford and the Wrekin, 14,000 doses have been delivered to the over-80s. I will look into the specific question of the primary care network that my right hon. Friend raises, because I was not aware of that fact. Clearly, Shropshire is vaccinating the over-80s but I will look into that specific. It is true that, right across the country, the catch-up is absolutely vital in areas if they are behind, because it is right that this is done fairly across the country. I will get back to my right hon. Friend with the details of the individual case that he raises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2021-01-21/debates/c91b69b6-4c91-4af7-bd74-ba8239397778/CommonsChamber#contribution-9388F307-BC28-4EDC-BB6E-6965AD90208C"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6872 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T15:29:32Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T15:29:32Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UPDATE on vaccination queue jumping, supplies and centres</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/OzWIjYjpI60/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4767</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T15:27:09Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T15:27:09Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 VACCINATION INFORMATION</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/covid-19-vaccination-information" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As I believe everyone knows Covid-19 vaccinations are currently being offered by the NHS; starting with people most at risk from coronavirus.
The NHS is currently focused on vaccinating first, those aged 80 plus with care home residents and staff and frontline health and care staff also as a first…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/covid-19-vaccination-information</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pfizer/ BioNtech Covid-19 FAQs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/01/21/10579/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
		&lt;div class=" vc_custom_1611229564105"&gt;

&lt;div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- "&gt;

	
	&lt;p&gt;Vaccines save lives. Yet there is a lot of disinformation online deterring people from getting the vaccine. Below I have shared a frequently asked questions briefing I received from the British Society for Immunology . It provides a host of questions and answers about the Pfizer/ BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the answers to the following questions apply only in relation to the Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine, and many will be different for other COVID-19 vaccines as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the answers to the following questions apply only in relation to the Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine, and many will be different for other COVID-19 vaccines as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rollout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is eligible to receive the vaccine?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunisation (JCVI) has prioritised people for vaccination based on their risk of serious COVID-19 disease after SARS-CoV-2 infection. The priority order, confirmed on 2nd December and subject to logistical challenges in rollout, is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.       Residents in a care home for older adults and their carers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.       All those 80 years of age and over; frontline health and social care workers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.       All those 75 years of age and over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.       All those 70 years of age and over; clinically extremely vulnerable individuals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.       All those 65 years of age and over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.       All individuals aged 16 years to 64 years with underlying health conditions which put them at higher risk of serious disease and mortality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.       All those 60 years of age and over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.       All those 55 years of age and over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9.       All those 50 years of age and over&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As more vaccine becomes available, it will be rolled out to those in each descending group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are older people being prioritised over younger people who are out of the house working?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The priorities are based on reducing risk of harm. The immune system of older people differs from that of younger people and whilst the younger, working population are just as likely to become infected they are much, much less likely to become severely ill. An older person becoming infected with SARS-CoV-2 is more likely to result in severe COVID-19 disease. The biggest risk of mortality from COVID-19 comes with age, even more so than underlying conditions such as cardiovascular disease or diabetes, for example, or being male or being in BAME groups. Each older generation has approximately 10 times the risk of dying from COVID-19 than the generation below it. When a vaccine has been shown to be effective in preventing disease in older people, then they should be the first to receive it as they are most at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do I need to get the vaccine if I have contracted COVID-19 and recovered?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Yes. There is a lot of uncertainty about how much immunity a person gains after natural infection. The levels of immunity that we can measure so far show a lot of individual variation &amp;#8211; some people have very few antibodies after infection but these antibodies can be boosted by vaccination. We can’t assume that everyone who has had COVID-19 would have enough immunity to protect them. It is likely that, in a significant proportion of the population, the vaccine will induce more effective and longer lasting immunity than that induced by infection. Hence it is recommended that everyone take the vaccine so that, if your immunity after disease is absent or low, it can be boosted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should a young person take the vaccine when the risk of COVID-19 mortality is so low?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;There is a huge variability in the symptoms and severity of COVID-19 disease between different people; from an infection with SARS-CoV-2 that doesn’t have any symptoms (asymptomatic infection) to severe COVID-19 disease resulting in hospitalisation and in some cases death. While younger people are usually at the less severe end of the spectrum this does not mean that the illness is not harmful to their health. In fact, there are many instances of long COVID that have blighted the lives of young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, although we don’t yet have a lot of evidence to support this, having the vaccine might stop you being able to be part of the chain of infection that spreads the virus. So, an added benefit might be to help reduce spread of the virus for everybody.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is COVID-19 at my child’s school. Why aren’t my children being given the vaccine?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Initial vaccine testing was not done on children. Children are at extremely low risk of becoming severely ill with COVID-19 – they are at higher risk of being involved in a serious traffic accident than they are of ending up in hospital with Covid-19. So the benefits of vaccinating children are not yet clear. If the vaccine stops people from passing the infection to others, then vaccinating children in order to stop the spread of the virus will make a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Safety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the vaccine being developed so quickly mean that it is less safe than other vaccines?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;No, it doesn’t. The reasons that this was developed so quickly do not include cutting corners on safety. There are a few reasons that enabled the speed in 2020:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.       Technology. These mRNA vaccines (in common with many of the approaches used for the other vaccine candidates) could be rapidly deployed for development and testing once the SARS-CoV-2 sequence became known, but this was actually done on the back of 10 years prior research using this platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.       Scientists. A LOT of scientists contributed to this, working extra long hours to make it work and to assess the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.       Money. Normally raising money to develop a vaccine takes a long time. At each stage you have to stop and apply for more funding to carry out the next stage. Funding applications take a year or more. In 2020 for SARS-CoV-2, rapid investment of a lot of taxpayers’ money in many countries meant there weren’t the normal financial obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.       Environment. Sometimes you can develop a vaccine but can’t test it until there is an epidemic in progress. There was no problem in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.       Luck. Sometimes the target that is picked for vaccine studies, which is usually something seen on the outside of the virus, is not a good candidate for raising an immune response. The S protein target on SARS-CoV-2 that most vaccine companies picked to work with turns out to be an excellent target for activating the immune response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.       Volunteer test subjects. Last but definitely not least. Tens of thousands of volunteers took part in the safety trials and the randomised control trials so recruiting volunteers was not an issue as it may be under normal circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there any side effects from the vaccine?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Yes, but these are generally mild. As with all vaccines, because you are stimulating the immune system you may experience some mild flu-like symptoms, but these are temporary. The most common reactions are fatigue, headache and pain at the injection site. Some people might also get chills, joint pain or fever. Younger people are more likely to get these reactions than older people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should people with allergies take the vaccine?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;There are varying degrees of allergy. Some allergies, such as hay fever, are mild and do not pose a risk. Others are more dangerous and can lead to immediate anaphylactic shock. The vaccine should not be given to people who have a history of immediate-onset anaphylaxis to a vaccine, medicine or food. If you carry an EpiPen in case of allergic reaction, you have a history of immediate-onset anaphylaxis and so should discuss this with your doctor before getting the vaccine. All people who are vaccinated are asked not to leave immediately so that the health care professionals can check there is no anaphylaxis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who should not get the vaccine? (I’m immunocompromised/pregnant etc.)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine has not yet been tested on pregnant women or children so these groups should not be vaccinated, unless a child is at high risk of severe disease for some other reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immunocompromised people are at high risk so should get the vaccine. However, because their immune systems may not be able to make a response to vaccine they should still take other precautions against the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who was the Pfizer/BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine tested on?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;There were 43,448 people in the phase 3 clinical trial, 21,720 of whom had the COVID-19 vaccine and the rest were given a placebo injection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the COVID-19 vaccine recipients, 58% were aged between 16 and 55, 42% were aged over 55 (the oldest being 89). 35% were classified as obese, 17% were BAME, 51% were male. Volunteers were from Argentina (15%), Brazil (6%), South Africa (2%) and USA (77%). People characterised as high risk due to underlying conditions (e.g. autoimmunity, hypertension; diabetes; asthma; pulmonary, liver, or kidney disease) or due to high risk occupations were included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are there risks that might have been missed in the trials, but will become apparent in the longer term?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;All known risks have been checked, but there may be unknown risks. Reactions to vaccines usually happen very soon after vaccination – if you have the vaccine, you are asked to wait for a few minutes as a precaution. All the initial phase 1 safety trial volunteers have been followed up for at least 4 months and no major concerns have been raised. Safety monitoring, known as pharmacovigilance, is to be continued for 2 years after the vaccine is released – in the UK, this is carried out by the MHRA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are long term side effects tested/monitored?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Safety monitoring is to be continued for 2 years after the vaccine is released. There is a system in place to monitor and report adverse events immediately in a process known as pharmacovigilance. In the UK, this is carried out by the MHRA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has the vaccine been tested on people of different ethnicities?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Yes, of the 21,720 volunteers who had the COVID-19 vaccine, 17% were BAME.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Effectiveness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does immunity from the vaccine last longer than immunity after getting COVID-19?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;We do not know the answer to this question yet because people have only been followed up for a maximum of 6 months after vaccination so far. We suspect that in some cases (e.g. mild or asymptomatic infection), the immunity elicited by the vaccine would be better than that elicited by the natural infection but we do not know for sure. But, from the concentrations of antibodies induced by the vaccine, and the rate at which these antibodies decline over time, it is looking very promising that immunity induced by the vaccine will last at least as long as the immunity induced by infection and in all likelihood it will last much longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do I still need to wear a mask or observe social distancing after receiving the vaccine?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Yes. We know the vaccine can protect people from getting sick from the disease COVID-19 that is caused by the viral infection. However, we do not yet know if it will stop you getting the viral infection so you could be an asymptomatic carrier who could pass the infection onto others who may be vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, you will not be fully protected against the disease until the second dose of vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do mRNA vaccines, such as the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine, work?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;The vaccine contains a segment of the SARS-CoV-2 virus genetic material that codes for a specific protein from the virus. In the case of the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine, the specific code is for the spike protein from the surface of the SARS-CoV-2 virus. The genetic material in the vaccine is mRNA, which is used as instructions for the cell to make proteins. When the vaccine is given, our cells at the site of injection take up the mRNA and make the SARS-CoV-2 spike protein. The mRNA is subsequently destroyed by the body. The spike protein is then recognised by the immune system and triggers a response. This response builds immune memory so your body can fight off SARS-CoV-2 immediately if you come across it in future. Please also see this infographic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will the Pfizer/BioNTech vaccine still provide protection against the new strain of Coronavirus in the UK?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;We think it will, but we don’t yet know this for a fact. Scientists are currently carrying out tests in the lab to check this out. We expect to find out more about this in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	&lt;div class="templatera_shortcode"&gt;
&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	
&lt;div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"&gt;&lt;span  style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"&gt;&lt;span  style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div  data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid"&gt;
				
&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
	
&lt;div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-"&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;

	
		&lt;li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7"&gt;
			&lt;div class="item-holder"&gt;
				&lt;div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true"&gt;
							&lt;img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-owwwgkdrjtxtzs5i2ll8hok1khkbl72gz2cnu2gj3s.png" data-mk-image-src-set='{"default":"https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg","2x":"","mobile":"","responsive":"true"}'/&gt;


					
				&lt;/div&gt;

				&lt;div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person" &gt;
						&lt;span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333"&gt;Steve Reed&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1"&gt;Member of Parliment for Croydon North&lt;/span&gt;
					
					&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

					
&lt;ul class="mk-employeee-networks"&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="mailto:&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;.&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#46;mp&amp;#64;p&amp;#97;&amp;#114;liame&amp;#110;t.u&amp;#107;" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-600b10afb17ed" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"&gt;&lt;path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-600b10afb1999" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"&gt;&lt;path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-600b10afb1b08" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"&gt;&lt;path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"&gt;&lt;svg  class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-600b10afb1beb" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; "  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"&gt;&lt;path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;

					&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full"&gt;
		&lt;div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155"&gt;

&lt;div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text"&gt;

	
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;Steven Reed&lt;/a&gt; is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on &lt;a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/"&gt;reducing violent mental health restraint&lt;/a&gt; became law. In June 2019 he launched &lt;a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/"&gt;Labour’s civil society strategy&lt;/a&gt; outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;div class="clearboth"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/01/21/10579/"&gt;Pfizer/ BioNtech Covid-19 FAQs&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk"&gt;Steve Reed MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/01/21/10579/">Pfizer/ BioNtech Covid-19 FAQs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Louis Carserides</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10579</id>
    <published>2021-01-21T11:43:41Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-21T11:43:41Z</updated>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex slams Chancellor’s plans to hit 4,300 Stockton North key workers earning over £18,000 with a pay cut]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/alex-slams-chancellors-plans-to-hit-4300-stockton-north-key-workers-earning-over-18000-with-a-pay-cut/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13908</id>
		<updated>2021-01-21T09:43:51Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-21T09:43:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP, Alex Cunningham has slammed the Chancellor’s plans to hit every 4,300 key worker earning over £18,000 in Stockton North with a real-term pay cut this year. With Stockton South included, the number of key workers – the teachers, police officers and Armed Forces personnel on the front line of the battle against [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/01/alex-slams-chancellors-plans-to-hit-4300-stockton-north-key-workers-earning-over-18000-with-a-pay-cut/">Alex slams Chancellor’s plans to hit 4,300 Stockton North key workers earning over £18,000 with a pay cut</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Pension Fund Must Divest from Fossil Fuels</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/20/nottingham-pension-fund-must-divest-from-fossil-fuels/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;One of the actions of Nottingham City Council’s &lt;a href="https://www.nottinghamcity.gov.uk/media/2619917/2028-carbon-neutral-action-plan-v2-160620.pdf"&gt;Carbon Neutral Action Plan&lt;/a&gt; is to campaign for divestment and move the Nottinghamshire Local Government Pension Scheme away from fossil fuels investments. This is why ahead of their Annual General Meeting tomorrow I submitted a question on behalf of City members of the scheme, and urged the Fund to commit to consult with its members on a divestment strategy and timeline before their next AGM. This is essential to ensure the long term sustainability of the Fund and to play it’s part in the prevention of catastrophic climate change.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;The Pension Fund covers over 300 members including Nottingham City Council, Nottinghamshire County Council, the District Councils and many other organisations who are generally non-profit making, or are undertaking a service which was, or could be carried out by the Local Authority. It is controlled by County Councillors and the City Council has no voting rights on the Pension Fund.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; I know that the primary responsibility of the Pension Fund is to protect the financial benefits of the scheme, and now that there is growing evidence that fossil fuel investments are performing less well than comparators it is the time to grasp the divestment nettle. Currently Nottinghamshire Pension Fund holds at least £170m in fossil fuel company shares and has no investments in sustainable, low carbon or renewable energy equity funds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Given over 1300 institutions worldwide have already committed to divestment, including at least 10 UK local government pension funds and a large number of UK universities and faith organisations, it is time for Nottinghamshire to catch up and  do its bit for a sustainable future. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You can watch the Nottinghamshire Pension Fund AGM live on &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/wdMyWgYd-gA"&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt; from tomorrow at 10:30am. Further information about the agenda of the meeting and those in attendance can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.nottinghamshire.gov.uk/dms/Meetings/tabid/70/ctl/ViewMeetingPublic/mid/397/Meeting/5514/Committee/526/SelectedTab/Documents/Default.aspx"&gt;Nottinghamshire County Council website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/20/nottingham-pension-fund-must-divest-from-fossil-fuels/"&gt;Nottingham Pension Fund Must Divest from Fossil Fuels&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>One of the actions of Nottingham City Council’s Carbon Neutral Action Plan is to campaign for divestment and move the Nottinghamshire Local Government Pension Scheme away from fossil fuels investments. This is why ahead of their Annual General Meeting tomorrow I submitted a question on behalf of City members of the scheme, and urged the...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/20/nottingham-pension-fund-must-divest-from-fossil-fuels/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/01/20/nottingham-pension-fund-must-divest-from-fossil-fuels/">Nottingham Pension Fund Must Divest from Fossil Fuels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2631</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T16:13:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T16:13:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Thank you for letting me highlight the terrible issues facing Leaseholders, listen here</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1745-thank-you-for-letting-me-highlight-the-terrible-issues-facing-leaseholders-listen-here"/>
		<published>2021-01-20T14:21:44+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-20T14:21:44+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1745-thank-you-for-letting-me-highlight-the-terrible-issues-facing-leaseholders-listen-here</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you Naga Munchetty and BBC 5 Live for letting me highlight the terrible issues facing Leaseholders. Listen here:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;audio src="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/images/stories/News2021/210119_Interview_FireBill.mp3" controls="controls"&gt;Your browser does not support the audio element.&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you Naga Munchetty and BBC 5 Live for letting me highlight the terrible issues facing Leaseholders. Listen here:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;audio src="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/images/stories/News2021/210119_Interview_FireBill.mp3" controls="controls"&gt;Your browser does not support the audio element.&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Takes Action Over Askwith Road Flytip</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/mp-takes-action-over-askwith-road-flytip" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/askwith%20road.png?itok=Ll7mz8ei" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p class="MsoNormal"> </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">Back in November, Jon Cruddas MP emailed Havering Council after receiving emails from constituents regarding an abandoned property at 89 New Road, Rainham. This property has sat abandoned for many years and is increasingly attracting fly tipping. Residents mentioned that as quick as the council clean up the fly tipping, it’s back again the same week.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">This month Jon finally received a response from the council stating that the site was visited by an Enforcement Officer, who noted that there is a Planning notice on the building dated December 2020 with the property due to be demolished for new flats.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">The council confirmed that although there is excessive waste within the confines of the property, the site is secured, and that they are unable to take any further action until the planning application is determined. A decision is due by 18th February 2021.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal"><strong>Jon Cruddas MP said:</strong> “I don’t think this is a suitable response. Regardless of planning, the property is close to residential streets and the continuation of fly-tipping, without action, could lead to a public health issue. Not to mention an eyesore for residents which has spilled onto the highway and if left could cause an obstruction.”</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">Jon went back to the council raising these points and today received a response. The council has informed Jon that officers have enquired with planning who holds responsibility to clear the waste while the site is waiting for planning permission.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">While the council have no issues with serving the relevant enforcement notices, they must be issued to the correct parties. But thanks to Jon raising this issue the council have tasked an officer to patrol the area and refer any issues to the correct council departments accordingly. The council also informed Jon that the rubbish obstructing the post box has been removed.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">Havering Council have provided assurances that Jon will be kept thoroughly updated on the matter and all future actions taken.</p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/fly-tipping" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Fly-tipping</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/waste" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Waste</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/council" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Council</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/action" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Action</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1453 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T12:17:54Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T12:17:54Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New £23m fishing fund ‘positive step’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/new-ps23m-fishing-fund-positive-step" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A new financial support package for Scottish fishing businesses that export to the EU has been announced by the UK Government.
Borders MP, John Lamont, recently called for a compensation scheme in the House of Commons due to issues faced by Berwickshire businesses.
Seafood exporters across the UK…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/new-ps23m-fishing-fund-positive-step</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP encouraging momentum on flooding issues</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-encouraging-momentum-on-flooding-issues/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_10925" style="width: 750px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/01/graham-stuart-mp-encouraging-momentum-on-flooding-issues/exif_jpeg_picture/" rel="attachment wp-att-10925"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-10925" loading="lazy" class="size-large wp-image-10925" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/burstwick-flooding-06-740x555.jpg" alt="" width="740" height="555" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/burstwick-flooding-06-740x555.jpg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/burstwick-flooding-06-300x225.jpg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/burstwick-flooding-06.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"/></a><p id="caption-attachment-10925" class="wp-caption-text"><span style="font-size: 16px;">Graham Stuart, MP for Beverley and Holderness, is encouraging local bodies to build on record investment from the Government to tackle the risks of flooding and coastal erosion.</span></p></div>
<p>
£5.2 billion Government money will create over 2,000 new flood defences across the country by 2027 – protecting an additional 336,000 properties, including 46,000 ‘key sites’ like schools and hospitals. Some of the funding will also provide extra support for homes and businesses to get back on their feet when affected by flooding.</p>
<p>The local MP has held talks with officials at East Riding Council and has pledged to work with them to bring more funding to the county to tackle flooding, including bringing forward more nature-based solutions and increasing public awareness of how to mitigate the worst effects of flooding.</p>
<p>The East Riding and Hull experienced traumatic flooding in the summer of 2007. By July of that year, almost 20,000 homes had been affected with repair costs numbering in the hundreds of millions. Six years later, in 2013, Beverley and Holderness was once again affected by flooding as a result of tidal surges along the Humber.</p>
<p>Graham said, “The memories of flooding in our area, particularly the floods in 2007, will never leave me as long as I live. Since then I’ve been doing work to combat flood risk, such as by chairing the River Hull Board – which helped remove sunken vessels and upgraded pumping stations.</p>
<p>“No area received more investment in the last funding cycle than the East Riding and Hull – hundreds of millions has been spent – but I really do think we should capitalise on the record funding contained in this new long-term plan to keep up the momentum.</p>
<p>“Flood risk is only going to increase as we experience the effects of climate change and more extreme weather, so we should act now to make sure we’re prepared for this.”</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the River Hull Board – which disbanded in autumn 2016 – was reconvened last year following the flooding experienced in winter 2019. It is now chaired by East Yorkshire MP Sir Greg Knight and is in abeyance, to be reconvened in case of emergency.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">£5.2 billion Government money will create over 2,000 new flood defences across the country by 2027 – protecting an additional 336,000 properties, including 46,000 ‘key...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10924</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T11:46:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T11:46:58Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Environment Agency"/>
    <category term="Flooding"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Holderness"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Universal credit: Covid responsible for over 50% of claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/universal-credit-covid-responsible-for-over-50-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"/><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>In a House of Commons speech, I revealed that over half of the 14,633 Universal Credit (UC) claimants in my constituency are on social security since the start of the pandemic. I then urged the Government to keep the £20 ‘uplift’ for people claiming Universal Credit.</p>
<p>You can read my speech in full below:</p>
<p><em>Universal Credit (UC) has never been fit for purpose.</em></p>
<p><em>When introduced in 2012, it had a number of design flaws including the original 6-week wait for the first payment, a single payment to a household, usually the man, setting women’s independence back a generation, and a monthly payment period creating all sorts of problems for many who were paid weekly, fortnightly and 4-weekly.</em></p>
<p><em>But these were made even worse in 2015 when the then Chancellor did a hatchet job on social security spending. With the cuts to the taper rate and work allowance, the freeze on ‘benefit uprating’, the abolition of disability premiums, and more, by the start of the Covid pandemic approximately £33bn of support had been cut for working age people.  </em></p>
<p><em>Although for some people, UC is more slightly generous than legacy benefits, all the analysis I have seen has shown that UC is far less generous to single parent families and to disabled people.</em></p>
<p><em>UC claimants have been driven into debt, rent arrears and the increase in foodbank demand is attributed to UC’s introduction.</em></p>
<p><em>The associated negative impacts on UC claimants’ health and wellbeing is also now increasingly being understood. For example, a peer-reviewed report published in the Lancet last March showed people who moved onto Universal Credit experienced clinically significant psychological distress as a direct result. Another report from the BMJ showed that the ‘hostile and demeaning’ Universal Credit system worsened physical and mental health.  And the Health in all Policies All Party Parliamentary Group which I chair undertook an inquiry into the impacts of the changes to UC in the 2016 Welfare Reform and Work Bill, predicting an increase in child poverty and a subsequent deterioration in child health; sadly, the follow analysis is showing how accurate these predictions were.</em></p>
<p><em>Indeed, the discriminatory and punitive nature of UC has even been successfully challenged in the courts.</em></p>
<p><em>Fast forward to the start of the Covid pandemic, when we saw the number of UC claimants increase from over 3 million in March to over 5.6 million in July. As the crisis hit, not everyone could work from home and it was the low paid in vulnerable sectors such as hospitality and leisure who’ve been most affected. We know that this health crisis is far from over, and neither are impacts on the economy and jobs. People need reassurance, that in their time of need, like the NHS, an adequate safety net is there for them. </em></p>
<p><em>In my Oldham East and Saddleworth constituency more than half of the 14,633 claimants are now claiming UC as a result of the pandemic.</em></p>
<p><em>The response I have had from constituents about the debate in Parliament calling for the uplift to be extended has been phenomenal! And it wasn’t just those relying on UC who have written to me reflecting the Health Foundation/IPSOS Mori poll that showed 74% of the public support the increase in UC and want to see it extended beyond March.  </em></p>
<p><em>The UC APPG which I chair held an inquiry into the impact of Covid on claimants last spring and we wrote to the Chancellor with our recommendations last November. We urged him to:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><em>Retain the £20 per week uplift to standard allowance beyond April</em></li>
<li><em>Extend the £20 per week uplift to legacy benefits</em></li>
<li><em>Offer new UC claimants an initial non-repayable starter payment instead of making them wait 5 weeks for their first payment, as recommended by the Work and Pensions Select Committee</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em>Unfortunately, I am still waiting for a reply to this letter.</em></p>
<p><em>Save The Children found that parents who were given the uplift predominantly used it to buy food, followed by paying the rent, bills, and essential items needed for school. They estimate that withdrawing this uplift will increase those living in poverty by half a million including 200,000 children. By 2024, the Resolution Foundation estimate that relative poverty will have increased to 23% with an additional 730,000 children living in poverty.</em></p>
<p><em>Even with this uplift people living on UC are struggling to manage. In November, Turn2Us examined the financial resilience of households on different social security support and found that 1 in 5 on UC ‘always’ run out of money compared with only 8% for people not reliant on UC.</em></p>
<p><em>Citizens’ Advice estimate that since the start of the pandemic half a million people have accrued rent arrears with an average of £730 debt. And of course, the ban on evictions also runs out at the end of March. The implications for homelessness are self-evident.</em></p>
<p><em>Mr Speaker, as Joseph Rowntree Foundation’s Poverty report has shown, before Covid, there were 14.5 m people living in poverty, that’s 1 in 5 people, and this was escalating in spite of the high employment rate and an increase in the living wage. Work, seen by many as the route out of poverty was failing to deliver, with over 8 million working people living in poverty. 7 out of 10 of the 4m children living in poverty come from working families. Covid saw those already struggling to stay afloat bear the brunt of the economic and the health burden.</em></p>
<p><em>We cannot, we must not let them down. We must extend the UC and Working Tax Credit uplift, and ensure those on legacy benefits also receive the uplift.  </em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/universal-credit-covid-responsible-for-over-50-of-claimants/">Universal credit: Covid responsible for over 50% of claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/universal-credit-covid-responsible-for-over-50-of-claimants/">Universal credit: Covid responsible for over 50% of claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6747</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T09:59:39Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T09:59:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Jobs"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Parliament"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Speeches"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccines in Hythe, Folkestone &amp; Lydd</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/vaccines-in-hythe-folkestone-lydd/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It's excellent news that this week sees the start of mass COVID vaccination in Folkestone at the Civic Centre, as well as at Lydd Airport on Romney Marsh. The Folkestone centre will be open seven days a week and operate eleven hours a day. It is expected that they will perform over 2000 vaccinations per […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5521</id>
    <published>2021-01-20T01:08:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-20T01:08:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jonathan Djanogly backs calls for trade deals to be approved by Parliament before being signed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-backs-calls-trade-deals-be-approved-parliament-being-signed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Djanogly supports an amendment that would mean trade deals must be approved by Parliament before being signed by the Government as is the case in the US, EU and Japan. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-backs-calls-trade-deals-be-approved-parliament-being-signed" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5022 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T22:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SNP MP for Na h-Eileanan an Iar comments on Barra entering Level 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/19/snp-mp-for-na-h-eileanan-an-iar-comments-on-barra-entering-level-4/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3326" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg" data-orig-size="1600,1200" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-3326" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2021/01/8b2490b4-3685-4d13-b5cb-2c8bc4ea5ab1.jpeg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Angus MacNeil MP said:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;Firstly, this is the official designations catching up with the reality of the situation in Barra as people have been voluntarily in Level 4 in their actions for about a week now since the first COVID-19 cases emerged.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;This is good that it is only in Barra and not impacting the other islands. It is good that the distinction has been made.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;#8220;Hopefully, we can get this Covid situation in Barra under control soon. It looks like the rate of positives is going in the right direction already but still there is much to be done. We must remember social distancing when in shops, staying at home and not travelling unnecessarily and washing our hands regularly.&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commenting Angus MacNeil MP said: “Firstly, this is the official designations catching up with the reality of the situation in …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/01/19/snp-mp-for-na-h-eileanan-an-iar-comments-on-barra-entering-level-4/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3322</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T15:14:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T15:14:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett welcomes Government’s support for schools but raises concerns about social mobility during lockdown</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-welcomes-governments-support-schools-raises-concerns-about-social-mobility-during" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday evening (18 January), Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Vice Chairman of the Conservative Party, participated virtually in the House of Commons debate on Remote Education and Free School Meals. During his speech, he praised the incredibly hard work of the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-welcomes-governments-support-schools-raises-concerns-about-social-mobility-during</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercury Article: New hope in third lockdown due to vaccine]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/19/mercury-article-new-hope-in-third-lockdown-due-to-vaccine/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4553</id>
		<updated>2021-01-19T10:32:27Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-19T10:32:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Local Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Newspaper Articles"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[O hell, here comes another one. No one wanted to start 2021 with a third lockdown but, as the new and more-infectious strain of Covid spread, it proved too strong for the local tier system. And with the NHS starting to fill up under the strain, even though covid treatments are getting better and the [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/01/19/mercury-article-new-hope-in-third-lockdown-due-to-vaccine/"><![CDATA[
<p>O hell, here comes another one.</p>



<p>No one wanted to start 2021 with a third lockdown but, as the new and more-infectious strain of Covid spread, it proved too strong for the local tier system.</p>



<p>And with the NHS starting to fill up under the strain, even though covid treatments are getting better and the vaccine rollout is picking up speed, here we are again.</p>



<p>A lot of us (me included) had been hoping we could just &#8216;ride it out&#8217; by keeping elderly and vulnerable people safe while everybody else carried on fairly normally.</p>



<p>But last autumn showed that, no matter how careful they’ve been, sooner or later grandparents catch it too, particularly with the new and more-infectious strain of the disease.</p>



<p>For a retirement town like Weston with plenty of elderly folk, but where lots of local jobs depend on hard-hit hospitality and tourism too, it’s a no-win dilemma.   </p>



<p>So it’s a rubbish start to 2021. But even though a full-scale lockdown is only a temporary ‘reset’ rather than a long-term answer to the problem, this time is different because there’s hope.</p>



<p>The vaccines mean there’s a decent chance of normality returning in a few months. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The challenge is getting through until then: keeping jobs and firms alive, and not letting up on ‘hands, face, space’ in the meantime.</p>



<p>The most difficult stretch of all will be the few weeks after we’ve each been vaccinated, before our immune systems are fully booted up.</p>



<p>The temptation to go back to normal before we’re really safe will be super-strong, but we’ll all have to resist it.</p>



<p>It would be awful to catch Covid right at the end of the pandemic, after we’d stayed safe for so long. Roll on the jabs, and then perhaps we can have a normal summer!</p>



<p><em>Weston MP John Penrose</em></p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hatfield Local Celebrates 100th Birthday with Video Surprise by MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/hatfield-local-celebrates-100th-birthday-with-video-surprise-by-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=hatfield-local-celebrates-100th-birthday-with-video-surprise-by-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular">
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner">
					<p><strong>Arthur ‘Laurie’ Pyle receives greeting from local MP as he celebrates his 100<span style="font-size: 13.3333px;">th</span> birthday</strong></p>
<p>Laurie Pyle, a long term resident of Hatfield and Hertfordshire, has today received videos and messages from family and friends as he celebrates the 100 year milestone.</p>
<p>Mr Pyle was born on this day in 1921 in Ware, Hertfordshire.</p>
<p>He worked for many years in engineering companies- training as a toolmaker in 1936, and building the first fully automated gearboxes for commercial vehicles.</p>
<p>Laurie did his part to support Britain’s war effort- making under-carriages for bombers and military aircraft, producing coal cutting machinery in Glasgow, and working on tailpieces for Spitfires and Hurricanes as well as sea mine release mechanisms in Stevenage.</p>
<p>He spent the years after the war developing and assembling parts for the famous Black and Silver Shadow bikes at Vincent Motorcycles in Stevenage, where he moved with his wife.</p>
<p>Laurie built a home for his wife and two children in Hertford in 1958, where he lived for many years until he came to live in Lowlands, Hatfield- where he resides to this day.</p>
<p>A man of many talents, Laurie learned to play the organ as a teenager and played in a dance band that toured dance halls throughout Hertfordshire and London all the way up until 1939.</p>
<p>Being told by one of his friends that he was keen on politics, Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps surprised Laurie with a video from himself, played amongst videos from friends and family.</p>
<p>Mr Shapps said: “It’s great to hear that you’re going strong. I am told that you are very much into politics- which is music to my ears of course.”</p>
<p>Citing the pandemic, Mr Shapps said: “ I know it’s difficult at the moment, not being able to visit one another or celebrate birthdays properly.</p>
<p>“It would’ve been great to meet you in person- and I’m sure we’ll get to do that once this time has passed.”</p>
<p>Laurie’s friends say that he is as sharp as a pin, loves politics, trading stocks on his iPad, and appreciates family time above all else.</p>
<p>See Grant Shapps video to Laurie below:</p>
				</div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section --><div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular">
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_code_inner">
					<iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F474657997267998%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560" width="1920" height="500" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowFullScreen="true"/>
				</div> <!-- .et_pb_code_inner -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_code -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section --></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Arthur ‘Laurie’ Pyle receives greeting from local MP as he celebrates his 100th birthday.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=31940</id>
    <published>2021-01-19T09:52:15Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-19T09:52:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PRESS RELEASE: Rushanara Ali MP Calls on the Government to End the Free School Meals and Home Learning Crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/press_release_rushanara_ali_mp_calls_on_the_government_to_end_the_free_school_meals_and_home_learning_crisis" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div>
<p><span>On 18 January the Labour Party secured a</span><span>n Opposition Day D</span><span>ebate on Free School Meals and Home learning.</span><span> </span><span>Whilst</span><span> </span><span>Rushanara was unsuccessful in the ballot to speak</span><span>, s</span><span>he has called on the Government to step up and end the ongoing crisis facing so many families. </span></p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/press_release_rushanara_ali_mp_calls_on_the_government_to_end_the_free_school_meals_and_home_learning_crisis</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T17:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T17:50:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Testing Site</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/new-testing-site/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-testing-site" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>A Coronavirus Testing Site has been opened at Shepherd’s
Spring Lane Car Park to bolster the local Test and Trace service. This is great
news and the location was determined after much consideration of the needs of
local communities.</p>



<p>Across the UK, testing capacity has been expanded to more
than 800,000 tests a day. Anyone experiencing a high temperature, a new,
continuous cough, or a loss or change to sense of smell or taste – should book
a test at nhs.uk/coronavirus, by calling 119, or using the NHS Covid-19 app.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A Coronavirus Testing Site has been opened at Shepherd’s Spring Lane Car Park to bolster the local Test and Trace service. This is great news and the location was determined after much consideration of the needs of local communities. Across the UK, testing capacity has been expanded to more than 800,000 tests a day. Anyone […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2838</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T16:33:52Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T16:33:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fishing Export Chaos post-Brexit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/18/fishing-export-chaos-post-brexit/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Following the chaos that has hit our fishing industry when trying to export since the start of the year, this week in Parliament I raised the problems experienced by the local fishing communities in my constituency suffering as a result of the new EU Trade and Co-operation Agreement.  &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;85% of the seafood caught by my local fishing fleet is sold into the EU. Bureaucratic chaos resulting from Brexit means they have been unable to sell to their usual markets and their boats are currently tied up. Logistics firms will not accept any more catch because of the current customs chaos. The situation is similar across much of Scotland and the UK.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;During this week&amp;#8217;s Committee for the Future Relationship with the EU public evidence session, I highlighted these issues to representatives from relevant stakeholders: Make UK, the British Retail Consortium and the Food and Drink Federation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the Committee for the Future Relationship with the EU Select Committee here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FnIDwBTE0no"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FnIDwBTE0no&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="13/01 CFREU Public Evidence Session" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FnIDwBTE0no?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I also asked the UK Secretary of State for Environmental, Farming and Rural Affairs what financial support the UK Government would provide to this struggling industry and how he planned to the resolve issues he previously described as &amp;#8216;teething problems&amp;#8217;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the urgent question session here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yu1mAcf-YqE"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yu1mAcf-YqE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="14/01 DEFRA Urgent Questions" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yu1mAcf-YqE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Far from promises of a &amp;#8216;sea of opportunity&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;taking back control&amp;#8217;, the stark realities of Brexit are being felt hard by fishing communities in Central Ayrshire and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford MP&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eight-five per cent. of the seafood caught by my local fishing fleet goes to customers in the EU. Along with boats right across the UK, they are currently tied up, as logistics firms will not accept any more produce due to the current customs chaos. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can the Secretary of State explain how he plans to resolve what he dismisses as “teething problems” and clarify what the Prime Minister meant when he talked about financial compensation for their losses?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;George Eustice&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are working closely with the industry and DFDS to identify what we can do to address some of the problems that have been encountered. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am aware that late last week, DFDS suspended the groupage service that it was offering to smaller consignments and has focused on single larger consignments, particularly of Scottish salmon. I understand that it believes it has sorted out some of those problems and intends next week to resume some of those groupage consignments. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a challenge here: in a group of several consignments, maybe three people would have got the paperwork right, but if one person has not, that can cause issues for everybody. We need people to pay attention to the detail and to get that paperwork right. We are working closely with the industry so that it can acclimatise itself to this administrative process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F01%2F18%2Ffishing-export-chaos-post-brexit%2F&amp;#038;title=Fishing%20Export%20Chaos%20post-Brexit" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/18/fishing-export-chaos-post-brexit/" data-a2a-title="Fishing Export Chaos post-Brexit"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/18/fishing-export-chaos-post-brexit/"&gt;Fishing Export Chaos post-Brexit&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Following the chaos that has hit our fishing industry when trying to export since the ... <a title="Fishing Export Chaos post-Brexit" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/18/fishing-export-chaos-post-brexit/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/01/18/fishing-export-chaos-post-brexit/">Fishing Export Chaos post-Brexit</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2039</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T14:52:17Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T14:52:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Central Ayrshire at Westminster"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="Central Ayrshire"/>
    <category term="Coastal Communities"/>
    <category term="Committee"/>
    <category term="EU"/>
    <category term="Europe"/>
    <category term="Fisheries"/>
    <category term="Fishing"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Response to Opposition Day Motions on Universal Credit &amp; Free Schools Meals</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/response-opposition-day-motions-universal-credit-free-schools-meals" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">This afternoon the Opposition has two motions before the House, one on Universal Credit &amp; Working Tax Credit and one on Access to remote education &amp; the quality of free school meals. Below I will set out my current view on both of these issues.
What are ‘Opposition Day’ debates?
Firstly,…</content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/response-opposition-day-motions-universal-credit-free-schools-meals</id>
    <published>2021-01-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">		&lt;div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="5677" class="elementor elementor-5677" data-elementor-settings="[]"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-inner"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-section-wrap"&gt;
							&lt;section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-330dca1e elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="330dca1e" data-element_type="section"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-row"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-4660dffb" data-id="4660dffb" data-element_type="column"&gt;
			&lt;div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-widget-wrap"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4fe4aa24 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="4fe4aa24" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"&gt;
				&lt;div class="elementor-widget-container"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wish you all a good and perhaps most importantly, a healthy New Year. This year begins with a shared goal; for us, all to get through it safely together. As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know our villages, towns and the city centre will be different and that now is the time to reflect on how we want to live and treat people locally in the future. The world has changed, and although the fabric that holds our communities together is stronger than ever, we have learned that what was paramount yesterday could now be a barrier to progress. While there are new and exciting endeavours that need our support, existing challenges outside the pandemic bubble remain pressing – globally, nationally and locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still a climate emergency, and we still need to provide a place fit for people of all ages, for the 21st Century. Finding a way to bring all of this together into a cohesive plan involving the most impacted people has to be a collective, local priority. I am already reaching out to businesses, community groups, charities and a wide range of organisations to work towards this common goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new, more contagious strain of the virus has pushed back many people&amp;#8217;s hopes and expectations for the early months of 2021. Of course, this is hard to take, especially for those whose jobs or livelihoods are affected directly by the lockdown. My team and I continue to support hundreds of families and businesses going through extreme hardship; for them right now, it&amp;#8217;s hard to see any light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this new strain is a setback, it is not the virus winning; we can get through this—rapid deployment of the vaccine underway. As hard as it is, we need to keep the faith, hunker down, stay home, go out for only essential purposes or exercise and keep out of other homes unless included in a specifically identified exemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is true that because of our efforts to follow the rules, rates of infection here have been lower, but we also now face rising numbers of infections fuelled by mixing over the festive period. A reminder of just how vulnerable we all are and how quickly our fortunes can change. Please keep staying at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep up to date with new articles at &lt;a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;www.drewhendrymp.scot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more about my work in parliament at &lt;a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com"&gt;www.theyworkforyou.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/"&gt;As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;Drew Hendry MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This year begins with a shared goal; for us, all to get through it safely together. As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/as-with-every-new-year-it-is-also-a-time-to-think-ahead-to-what-we-want-for-the-future/">As with every new year, it is also a time to think ahead to what we want for the future.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5677</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T16:12:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T16:12:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Community"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Tourism"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p><b><span data-contrast="none">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Gov</span></b><b><span data-contrast="auto">ernment over vaccinations rollout </span></b><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="none">Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has this week demande</span><span data-contrast="auto">d more clarity and transparency from the Government over the rollout </span><span data-contrast="none">of the Covid-19 vaccination programme.  The call comes as it </span><span data-contrast="auto">was revealed that although </span><span data-contrast="none">Ashton Gate Stadium is ready to go as a regional vaccine hub, working in partnership with the Clini</span><span data-contrast="none">cal Commissioning Group,  the Government have not yet explicitly set out their expectations for the </span><span data-contrast="auto">hub, or let those involved know when they will begin to receive supplies of vaccines to use.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Bristol GPs have also expressed concern that recent Government</span><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><span data-contrast="none">announcements regarding the number of weekly vaccinations and the fluctuating period between people accessing the first and second dose of the vaccine are </span><span data-contrast="auto">creating m</span><span data-contrast="none">ore confusion</span><span data-contrast="auto"> both for those </span><span data-contrast="none">delivering the </span><span data-contrast="auto">vaccine and those receiving it.  </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><b><span data-contrast="none">Karin Smyth</span></b><b><span data-contrast="none">, MP f</span></b><b><span data-contrast="auto">or Bristol South,</span></b><b><span data-contrast="none"> said:</span></b><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">“We will always be indebted to the researchers, volunteers and NHS professionals who have worked at incredible pace to bring us a vaccine so rapidly – but we now find ourselves with a new set of challenges.  The Covid-19 vaccination programme will be the m</span><span data-contrast="auto">ost complex task ever undertaken by our NHS, and it is vital that this Tory Government – which has been found wanting at so many points during this pandemic – do not let down the incredible NHS staff who continue to go above and beyond to tackle this pande</span><span data-contrast="auto">mic.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">“The</span><span data-contrast="auto"> Government must provide more details on who will be given what vaccine, where and when, so that those administering the vaccine and those receiving it can have confidence in the safety and efficacy of the rollout.  I’ll continue to press for more clarity so that together we can roll out the vaccine and rebuild our country”.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:276}"> </span></p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout   Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has this week demanded […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/01/15/bristol-south-mp-demands-clarity-from-government-over-vaccinations-rollout/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP demands clarity from Government over vaccinations rollout  </a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2839</id>
    <published>2021-01-15T11:49:39Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-15T11:49:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/20210112-Donelan-Whitehead.pdf" class="pdfemb-viewer" style="" data-width="max" data-height="max" data-mobile-width="500" data-scrollbar="none" data-download="on" data-tracking="on" data-newwindow="on" data-pagetextbox="off" data-scrolltotop="off" data-startzoom="100" data-startfpzoom="100" data-toolbar="bottom" data-toolbar-fixed="on">20210112-Donelan-Whitehead<br/></a>
<p class="wp-block-pdfemb-pdf-embedder-viewer"/>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/">My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/my-letter-to-the-leader-of-wiltshire-council/">My letter to the Leader of Wiltshire Council</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33911</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T17:34:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T17:34:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Wiltshire Council"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Update on Free School Food Parcels</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/update-on-free-school-food-parcels/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Images have been circulating online of some unacceptable food parcels which have been given to students entitled for free school meals but are not able to attend school. Some were claiming that the food parcels were supposed to feed children for two weeks and were costing the taxpayer £30. Both of these claims are not [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/update-on-free-school-food-parcels/">Update on Free School Food Parcels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3038</id>
    <published>2021-01-14T14:03:21Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-14T14:03:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>support for on line learning for all our childeren</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/01/11/support-for-on-line-learning-for-all-our-childeren/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6413</id>
    <published>2021-01-11T14:23:21Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-11T14:23:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[VACCINE CENTRE VISIT]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=343</id>
		<updated>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</updated>
		<published>2021-01-11T14:11:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/01/11/vaccine-centre-visit/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - A look at 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-look-2021" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Happy New Year, although that was no one’s idea of a quiet and peaceful Christmas, and the next few months are unlikely to be any easier.
Starting with the roads, the late addition of the French demand for Covid tests from everyone travelling across the Channel to the plans for the post-Brexit…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-look-2021</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job Vacancy: Chi Seeks to Appoint New Caseworker for Newcastle Central</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/job-chi-seeks-to-appoint-new-caseworker-for-newcastle-central/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below:</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Job Title</strong>: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31 March 2021</p>
<p><strong>Working For</strong>: Chi Onwurah MP</p>
<p><strong>Location</strong>: Internet</p>
<p><strong>Salary</strong>: £21,529- 24,000</p>
<p><strong>Job Details: </strong></p>
<p>Chi Onwurah MP (Newcastle Central) has a vacancy for a caseworker/admin officer. The most important factor is a willingness to learn and work together with the senior caseworker. Training will be provided.</p>
<p>(This post is currently until March 31st 2021, potential for extension dependant on IPSA funding)</p>
<p>The successful candidate will be well-organised with excellent IT and communication skills and attention to detail. Ideally s/he will have some knowledge of welfare benefits and public services including Universal Credit and experience of managing casework, confidential and sensitive information; and of drafting complex letters.</p>
<p>Experience of a similar role and CaseworkerMP would be beneficial. A good understanding of the political environment is advantageous, and a knowledge of local issues in the constituency is desirable. The successful candidate will demonstrate their enthusiasm to play a key role in a small team supporting Chi in her constituency work.</p>
<p><strong>Key Tasks</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Provide advice and support to constituents on a range of financial, health, housing and other issues variety of issues through liaison with Government agencies, the voluntary sector and others to resolve matters.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Key Responsibilities</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Deal with queries by phone/in person, taking appropriate action to resolve, by gathering information or evidence; then document or escalate their concerns or enquiries in order to progress or close the case.</li>
<li>Manage own caseload and progress of casework, prioritising, logging and updating any actions taken and following up any outstanding queries; with urgent cases reported to the Member.</li>
<li>Draft responses or respond to constituents on any issues raised on behalf of the Member.</li>
<li>Maintain an up-to-date knowledge of relevant guidelines/legislation as appropriate in dealing with casework.</li>
<li>Analyse patterns of enquiries and produce reports.</li>
<li>Ensure records are kept adhering to the Data Protection Act principles Undertake general administrative tasks.</li>
<li>Assist with the work of other colleagues as required and communicate appropriately with internal and external contacts.</li>
<li>Competent use of IT including casework management systems, Microsoft Of ce package, email and internet to support the above.</li>
<li>Attending surgeries and meetings as appropriate.</li>
</ul>
<p>Chi values inclusivity and diversity, and welcomes applications from candidates of all backgrounds.</p>
<p><strong>Closing Date</strong>: 15 January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Interview/Start Dates: </strong></p>
<p>Closing time for applications 5pm.</p>
<p>Interviews scheduled via zoom Monday 18th January 2021</p>
<p>Start date Monday 25th January 2021</p>
<p><strong>Application Details: </strong></p>
<p>Please send an email with the subject line “Caseworker application – YOURNAME” to <strong>Anthony.bone@parliament.uk</strong> Please attach a CV, a covering letter and a report (max 2 sides A4) which presents a complex situation you have dealt with.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong>: 0191 233 5838</p>
<p><strong>Website</strong>: <a href="http://chionwurahmp.com/">http://chionwurahmp.com</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chi Onwurah MP for Newcastle Central is looking to appoint a new full time remote caseworker on a fixed term contract until March 31st. Details below: Closing Date: 15 January 2021 Job Title: Caseworker (Full Time) Fixed Term to 31… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10769</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T17:16:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Casework"/>
    <category term="Constituency Casework"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK-EU Trade deal press release</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">‘I am currently reading through the 1246 pages of the new UK-EU Trade Deal, announced by the Prime Minister on Christmas Eve. I believe this deal makes good on the promises that were made, by the Prime Minister, myself and... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/30/uk-eu-trade-deal-press-release/#more-3749">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3749</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T15:50:22Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>From Brexit to coronavirus and everything in between - Ashfield MP reflects on eventful first year in office</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From sending Boris Johnson into isolation, to being trolled on social media, dealing with coronavirus and Brexit, it’s been a busy year for former miner Lee Anderson who has clocked up one year representing his home turf as Ashfield MP.
The married dad of two, raised in Huthwaite, is the area’s…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/brexit-coronavirus-and-everything-between-ashfield-mp-reflects-eventful-first-year-office</id>
    <published>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Johnson’s deal ‘social and economic disaster’ for Argyll &amp; Bute</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2020/12/29/johnsons-deal-social-and-economic-disaster-for-argyll-bute/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I can’t vote for a ‘deal’ that undermines our farmers, fishermen and future opportunities for young people Tomorrow (Wednesday) I will vote against Boris Johnson’s post-Brexit EU trade deal. I will do so because the deal we are being asked to support is woefully deficient, as it undermines our farmers, our fishing communities and the […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9118</id>
    <published>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-29T15:33:57Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Speaks Up for Traveling Showmen and Women</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-speaks-up-for-traveling-showmen-and-women/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2969" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-980x653.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled &lt;strong&gt;Future of fairs and Showgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and showmen community and steps in to provide vital support before it is too late. As a longstanding supporter and advocate for show people and a member of the All Party Parliamentary Group for Fairs and Showgrounds, I will continue to be a voice for this community and press the Government at every opportunity for better support and recognition. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the outset of the pandemic, many fairs were either cancelled or postponed – from summer fetes to Christmas Markets. As a result of the closures and postponing of fairs, many show people suffered huge financial loss, plunging them into financial insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The heart of the issue is that the financial support offered to the tourism industry during COVID-19 continually excluded the fairground community. Showmen and women also did not qualify for the assistance announced in the recent budget for retail, leisure and hospitality firms relating to business rates in the coming year, due to the way that the Show people operate, which falls outside the scope of static leisure providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Show people across the UK and particularly those here in South Shields, now face losing their businesses and livelihoods if the UK Government does not step in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read my speech by clicking &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2020-12-17/debates/3B335883-D800-426D-ACAD-2204734ED4F7/FairsAndShowgrounds#contribution-374A337C-9576-467B-95F1-505F40A37FE0"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled Future of fairs and Showgrounds. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2971</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rubbish dumping survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="caldera-grid" id="caldera_form_1" data-cf-ver="1.9.3" data-cf-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;&lt;div id="caldera_notices_1" data-spinner="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-admin/images/spinner.gif"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;form data-instance="1" class="CF5f8c811d77adc caldera_forms_form cfajax-trigger" method="POST" enctype="multipart/form-data" id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1" data-form-id="CF5f8c811d77adc" aria-label="Flytipping on Cotterills Lane" data-target="#caldera_notices_1" data-template="#cfajax_CF5f8c811d77adc-tmpl" data-cfajax="CF5f8c811d77adc" data-load-element="_parent" data-load-class="cf_processing" data-post-disable="0" data-action="cf_process_ajax_submit" data-request="https://liambyrne.co.uk/cf-api/CF5f8c811d77adc" data-hiderows="true"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" id="_cf_verify_CF5f8c811d77adc" name="_cf_verify" value="8ba8e32bc0"  data-nonce-time="1611337613" /&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_wp_http_referer" value="/feed/" /&gt;&lt;div id="cf2-CF5f8c811d77adc_1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_id" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_frm_ct" value="1"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="cfajax" value="CF5f8c811d77adc"&gt;
&lt;input type="hidden" name="_cf_cr_pst" value="7970"&gt;
&lt;div class="hide" style="display:none; overflow:hidden;height:0;width:0;"&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Web Site&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type="text" name="web_site" value="" autocomplete="off"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-1"  class="row  first_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_949637" class="form-group" id="fld_949637_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_949637Label" for="fld_949637_1" class="control-label"&gt;First name &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_949637" class=" form-control" id="fld_949637_1" name="fld_949637" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_949637Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3720579" class="form-group" id="fld_3720579_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3720579Label" for="fld_3720579_1" class="control-label"&gt;Surname &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_3720579" class=" form-control" id="fld_3720579_1" name="fld_3720579" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_3720579Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_377714" class="form-group" id="fld_377714_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_377714Label" for="fld_377714_1" class="control-label"&gt;Postcode &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="text" data-field="fld_377714" class=" form-control" id="fld_377714_1" name="fld_377714" value="" data-type="text" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_377714Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8339186" class="form-group" id="fld_8339186_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8339186Label" for="fld_8339186_1" class="control-label"&gt;Email &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;input   required type="email" data-field="fld_8339186" class=" form-control" id="fld_8339186_1" name="fld_8339186" value="" data-type="email" aria-required="true"   aria-labelledby="fld_8339186Label" &gt;			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr id="fld_3670460_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_8286015" class="form-group" id="fld_8286015_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_8286015Label" for="fld_8286015_1" class="control-label"&gt;Has the dumping and littering problem in the area reduced recently?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_8286015" value="" data-field="fld_8286015" class="form-control" id="fld_8286015_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_8286015Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Not Sure"  data-calc-value="Not Sure" &gt;
						Not Sure					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_5317914" class="form-group" id="fld_5317914_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_5317914Label" for="fld_5317914_1" class="control-label"&gt;What further steps would you like to see taken?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;textarea name="fld_5317914" value="" data-field="fld_5317914" class="form-control" id="fld_5317914_1" rows="4"    aria-labelledby="fld_5317914Label" &gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_7237774" class="form-group" id="fld_7237774_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_7237774Label" for="fld_7237774_1" class="control-label"&gt;Would you be willing to join a residents’ group?&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_7237774" value="" data-field="fld_7237774" class="form-control" id="fld_7237774_1"    aria-labelledby="fld_7237774Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Yes					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						No					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="Maybe"  data-calc-value="Maybe" &gt;
						Maybe					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_3572997" class="form-group" id="fld_3572997_1-wrap"&gt;
	&lt;label id="fld_3572997Label" for="fld_3572997_1" class="control-label"&gt;Can Liam email you about news and campaign updates? &lt;span aria-hidden="true" role="presentation" class="field_required" style="color:#ee0000;"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
	&lt;div class=""&gt;
		&lt;select name="fld_3572997" value="" data-field="fld_3572997" class="form-control" id="fld_3572997_1"  required="required"  aria-labelledby="fld_3572997Label" &gt;
		&lt;option value=""&gt;&lt;/option&gt;
					&lt;option value="Yes"  data-calc-value="Yes" &gt;
						Liam can email me					&lt;/option&gt;
										&lt;option value="No"  data-calc-value="No" &gt;
						Liam cannot email me					&lt;/option&gt;
							&lt;/select&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_4555323" class=" form-control" id="fld_4555323_1" name="fld_4555323" value="1" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;input    type="hidden" data-field="fld_3061013" class=" form-control" id="fld_3061013_1" name="fld_3061013" value="2020 Oct Flytipping Survey" data-type="hidden"   &gt;&lt;hr id="fld_6111107_1" class="" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;div data-field-wrapper="fld_432351" class="form-group" id="fld_432351_1-wrap"&gt;
&lt;div class=""&gt;
	&lt;input  class="btn btn-default" type="submit" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1" value="Submit" data-field="fld_432351"  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;input class="button_trigger_1" type="hidden" name="fld_432351" id="fld_432351_1_btn" value="" data-field="fld_432351"  /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div id="CF5f8c811d77adc_1-row-2"  class="row  last_row"&gt;&lt;div  class="col-sm-12  single"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/"&gt;Rubbish dumping survey&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/rubbish-dumping-survey/">Rubbish dumping survey</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=7970</id>
    <published>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-10-16T11:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Flytipping"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Written Answers — Department for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs: Gun Sports: Coronavirus (22 May 2020)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.cliftonbrown.co.uk/content/written-answers-%E2%80%94-department-environment-food-and-rural-affairs-gun-sports-coronavirus-22" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Geoffrey Clifton-Brown: To ask the Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, what steps his Department is taking to enable the early resumption of shooting after the covid-19 outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/wrans/?id=2020-05-13.46528.h&amp;amp;s=geoffrey%20clifton-brown%20section%3Awrans#g46528.q0" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.theyworkforyou.com/wrans/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>1332 at https://www.cliftonbrown.co.uk</id>
    <published>2020-05-22T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hull MP reacts to the Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/hull-mp-reacts-budget" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10.5755px;"&gt;Diana Johnson spoke in the Commons debate on the Chancellor's Budget Statement.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10.5755px;"&gt;The Hull North MP's remarks ranged across several key issues for Hull North, including support for workers over the Coronavirus, the NHS and public health, flood resilience and devolution for the Humber.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/14"&gt;Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item odd"&gt;&lt;a href="/tags/devolution"&gt;devolution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/7"&gt;Fair deal for Hull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin Morton</name>
    </author>
    <id>884 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-12T19:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-3822029382927366640</id>
    <published>2020-03-06T13:22:00.003+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-06T13:22:42.576+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Raise the rate"/>
    <title type="text">Raise the Rate debate</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="true" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" height="313" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FYvonneFovargue4Makerfield%2Fvideos%2F613975099449506%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/3822029382927366640/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html" title="Raise the Rate debate"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-600b118a6b599" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-600b118a6b599').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"600b118a6b599","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-600b118a6b599" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-600b118a6b599" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="600b118a6b599" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_600b118a6b599" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_600b118a6b599" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_600b118a6b599" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_600b118a6b599" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_600b118a6b599" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_600b118a6b599" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_600b118a6b599_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-600b118a6b599 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxz2SLEYsKm7TH7y1VMWf4cvfZyckQWg1oHOI-Ccb2Kdke7f2guiIbqlXNh788DGSJumejRMYfnxMDIhaxq9g' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~3/QVJ5Ukdon9g/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~4/QVJ5Ukdon9g" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>118389 - George Freeman - 08-Dec-2017 (Tabled)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/content/118389-george-freeman-08-dec-2017-tabled" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;George Freeman&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To ask the Secretary of State for International Development, what recent discussions she has had with her counterpart in the Lebanese Government on the potential forced return of refugees to Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-link field-type-link-field field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Link:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-statements/written-question/Commons/2017-12-08/118389" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.parliament.uk/business/publications/written-questions-answers-stateme…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2472 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</published>
    <updated>2017-12-08T16:58:12Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thank you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" rel="attachment wp-att-281"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="281" data-permalink="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" data-orig-size="640,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 09-06-2017, 10 43 04 (2)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=300%2C186" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" src="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=640%2C396" alt="" width="640" height="396" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?w=640 640w, https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=300%2C186 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will be closing down shortly, but you can keep up to date with my work on my &lt;a href="http://www.carolynharris.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;main webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Google+" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;#038;title=Thank%20you" data-a2a-url="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" data-a2a-title="Thank you"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  We did it! Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me. I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East. This website will be closing down shortly, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>linzi_isaac</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/?p=279</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcoming the Fantastic Ryanair Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/2016/01/11/welcoming-the-fantastic-ryanair-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport.<br/>
Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result.<br/>
The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here.<br/>
The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well.<br/>
It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have been ongoing for a considerable length of time now, have resulted in success for both Ryanair and the Northern Ireland economy.<br/>
We have a very proud aerospace industry here in Northern Ireland and it is very much engrained in our manufacturing heritage with the likes of Shorts Brothers, now Bombardier, having been established in Northern Ireland since the end of the Second World War.<br/>
We have gone through an extremely difficult 18 months in County Antrim with the announced closures of both the JTI Gallaher tobacco plant and the Michelin tyre factory bringing about almost 1800 redundancies and this investment is a huge step forward in finding new jobs and new opportunities for the people of this area.<br/>
Ryanair’s investment of £300 million will boost our local wage economy enormously and all of our local businesses and town centres will reap the benefits as a result.<br/>
Ryanair are also in discussions with Tourism Ireland to explore the possibility of introducing five new routes and I have every faith that Tourism Ireland and all other sectors who would benefit from such an arrangement will do everything they can to ensure its successful delivery.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">“I am delighted at the fantastic news for County Antrim that Ryanair have today announced a huge investment in their operations at Aldergrove airport. Ryanair have today confirmed they will be investing in three new aircraft to be based here and intend to run 4 flights daily to Gatwick as a result. The company anticipate carrying over 1 million passengers in their first year of expanded operations and will bring 750 new jobs to the aerospace industry here. The increased number of flights will not only benefit this industry but those of the business, tourism and hospitality sectors as well. It is wonderful to see that the negotiations, which have […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianpaisleymp.co.uk/?p=1623</id>
    <published>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</published>
    <updated>2016-01-11T10:56:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am not currently an MP, as Parliament has been dissolved until after the General Election.</div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.frankfield.co.uk/latest-news/press-releases/news.aspx?p=1021795</id>
    <published>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>1970-01-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
</feed>
