<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-05-31T03:29:41Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne Calls for Local Colleges to Secure Government Funding Boost for Skills Training</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-calls-local-colleges-secure-government-funding-boost-skills-training" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7419" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">30 May 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne Calls for Local Colleges to Secure Government Funding Boost for Skills Training</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span>South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne is urging colleges and further education providers in Shropshire to apply for additional government funding by June 20, 2023. This funding aims to enhance local skills training and support the employment prospects of individuals within their communities.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>A total of £165 million will be distributed across various regions, enabling them to improve their skills training initiatives. The funds will be used to upgrade facilities with modern equipment, enhance the skills of teachers, and introduce new courses in essential subjects.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>The additional funding will be directed towards courses focused on green construction, carbon capture, cyber security, and those aligned with the requirements of local employers. Successful applicants will be granted financial support to implement initiatives aligned with their region's Local Skills Improvement Plan, which is devised by employer bodies to ensure technical training after the age of 16 caters to local demands.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>This investment will have a positive impact on local economies by enabling businesses to access the necessary skills, aligning with the Prime Minister's priority of economic growth.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span><strong>Philip Dunne said:</strong></span></span></p>

<blockquote>
<p><span><span>“Investing in education and skills will unlock future growth, boost productivity, and help build the skilled workforce of the future in South Shropshire.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>“</span></span><span><span>That is why I welcome the extra £165 million investment in skills training from the Conservative Government and encourage colleges and further education providers across the county to apply for their share to help get more people into jobs closer to home.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>“</span></span><span><span>This new funding will deliver the skills our local employers need, while levelling up skills training across the country and helping to grow our economy.”</span></span></p>
</blockquote>

<p><span><span><strong>Commenting, Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education Robert Halfon said:</strong></span></span></p>

<blockquote>
<p><span><span>“Building a world-class skills and apprenticeships nation means listening to the specific needs of local people, businesses, and institutions.</span></span></p>

<p><span><span>“</span></span><span><span>This funding will revolutionise how we plug local skills gaps and provide a boost to the economy. Supporting colleges to better meet the needs of local employers not only boosts businesses, it extends the ladder of opportunity to even more people from all backgrounds who will be equipped with the skills they need to secure a rewarding job close to home.”</span></span></p>
</blockquote></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7419 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-05-30T15:27:50Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-30T15:27:50Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>North Elmham Garden Town Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/north-elmham-garden-town-update-2" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="2704" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;30 May 2023&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;North Elmham Garden Town Update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 30th May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Further to my previous posts in relation to the campaign against the ‘Garden Village/New Town’ proposals that may be resurfacing around North Elmham, Billingford and Bintree, I welcomed the brilliant article in the EDP today, highlighting that more than 30 parish councils have now united behind that campaign – up from the c.15 it was just a few weeks ago.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;See the article &lt;a href="https://www.edp24.co.uk/news/23537974.parish-councils-vow-stop-norfolk-railway-town/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;I remain firmly committed to working with and supporting local parishes, and local councillors Bill Borrett and Gordon Bambridge, as we collectively raise awareness on why this highly rural location is completely inappropriate and unsustainable for an industrial scale development of several thousand houses. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;To see my previous webstories and updates on this issue, please scroll down below the picture of the submission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;To stay up to date with my ongoing campaign efforts on this issue, please do regularly check back in on my  Planning and Protecting Our Rural Landscape and Heritage’ campaign page &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/planning-and-protecting-our-rural-landscape-and-heritage"&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-04/george_freeman_north_elmham_4.jpg" width="1000" height="523" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE 18th May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the deadline of the ‘Breckland Local Plan Update – Issues and Options Report for Consultation’, I have written to the Leader of Breckland Council to ensure that my opposition, in support for local councillors Bill Borrett and Gordon Bambridge and the c.15 concerned Parish Councils and communities in the area, is formally recorded and considered as part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see my submission below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(To see my previous webstories on this issue, please scroll down below the picture of the submission).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-05/letter_norfolk_railway_village.png" width="886" height="1076" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE – 3rd May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further to my previous posts on 5th and 24th April 2023, I am delighted to be able to share the below article published in the EDP this week – further highlighting why I, and many others, are opposing the idea of a new Garden Town to the north of Dereham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A link to the online article can be found &lt;a href="https://www.edp24.co.uk/news/23479929.battle-ramps-new-norfolk-railway-village-homes/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-05/article_1.jpg" width="827" height="854" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-05/article_2.jpg" width="827" height="1008" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE – 24th April 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further to my post on 5th April 2023, I am delighted to be able to share the below Op-Ed I recently wrote for the &lt;em&gt;Dereham Times&lt;/em&gt; – outlining in further detail why I am opposing the idea of a Garden Town to the north of Dereham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-04/dereham_times_article.jpg" width="1194" height="1422" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5th APRIL 2023 WEBSTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For decades now, our planning system hasn’t been delivering the housing we need, in the places we need it, for the people who need it. For too long, the system appears to have been driven by the national volume house builders who too often make their money from land banking and high density commuter housing estates on the edge of existing developments – rather than through a proper planning system run to deliver for the people who need planning to work for them, instead of being done TO them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long been concerned by the amount of development coming to areas like our own in rural Mid Norfolk – which is often inappropriate, “industrial” in scale and unsustainable. While most of our villages can take and are indeed up for (when properly asked) taking some additional new housing (without which our communities will gradually fade away), I fundamentally believe that more needs to be done to give local communities a greater say in how they develop in the years to come (with greater protections), which is why I have been so vocal in my opposition to the way so many large national developers abuse and take advantage of the planning system to dump such inappropriate and unsustainable developments on our towns and villages.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
That’s why, through &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Norfolk Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; project I set up before I became an MP, I have been so vocal in advocating for a better model of growth and development that places greater emphasis on delivering small pockets of housing of the type and aesthetic desired by local communities, and in the places they earmark. I truly believe the spirit of Localism enshrined in the 2011 Localism Act should be enhanced, with the Act itself strengthened to remove some of the loopholes we’ve seen exploited. (To read more about my views in full, please visit my ‘Planning and Protecting Our Rural Heritage and Landscape’ campaign page &lt;a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/planning-and-protecting-our-rural-landscape-and-heritage"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) I was delighted to see the NPPF reformed in the autumn by Michael Gove to give more power to local planners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continue to make the case I have long made that the right way to plan housing is to give local councils, democratically accountable to the local residents they serve, the freedoms and incentives to plan properly for the right sort of housing and growth where it is needed ie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;around hotspots of economic growth&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;on brownfield sites in areas needing regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;around growth towns with the infrastructure and services available to sustain further growth&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;in villages with a Neighbourhood Plan setting out the amount of housing they are happy/able to take and which ensures affordable &amp; appropriate local housing for local workers and residents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s what the &lt;strong&gt;Breckland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;South Norfolk Council&lt;/strong&gt; Local Plans rightly aim to do. What we don’t need in rural Norfolk is massive commuter estate “New Towns” dumped in the middle of rural mud Norfolk without proper infrastructure, facilities, sustainable transport links or fit with the existing pattern of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The North Elmham New Town&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The North Elmham New Town would also represent massive development of the precious River Wensum chalk stream habitats (not to mention a Site of Specific Scientific Interest).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I was delighted to chair a meeting on Friday in North Elmham with local parish councils and local councillors Bill Borrett and Cllr Gordon Bambridge to make clear that the idea of a new town in the area will NOT be supported by ourselves as elected local  representatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill and Gordon confirmed that Breckland Council are NOT zoning this area for major housebuilding, and will oppose a re-application of the New Town as we did successfully last time it was proposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5th APRIL 2023 WEBSTORY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For decades now, our planning system hasn’t been delivering the housing we need, in the places we need it, for the people who need it. For too long, the system appears to have been driven by the national volume house builders who too often make their money from land banking and high density commuter housing estates on the edge of existing developments – rather than through a proper planning system run to deliver for the people who need planning to work for them, instead of being done TO them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve long been concerned by the amount of development coming to areas like our own in rural Mid Norfolk – which is often inappropriate, “industrial” in scale and unsustainable. While most of our villages can take and are indeed up for (when properly asked) taking some additional new housing (without which our communities will gradually fade away), I fundamentally believe that more needs to be done to give local communities a greater say in how they develop in the years to come (with greater protections), which is why I have been so vocal in my opposition to the way so many large national developers abuse and take advantage of the planning system to dump such inappropriate and unsustainable developments on our towns and villages.&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
That’s why, through &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Norfolk Way&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; project I set up before I became an MP, I have been so vocal in advocating for a better model of growth and development that places greater emphasis on delivering small pockets of housing of the type and aesthetic desired by local communities, and in the places they earmark. I truly believe the spirit of Localism enshrined in the 2011 Localism Act should be enhanced, with the Act itself strengthened to remove some of the loopholes we’ve seen exploited. (To read more about my views in full, please visit my ‘Planning and Protecting Our Rural Heritage and Landscape’ campaign page &lt;a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/planning-and-protecting-our-rural-landscape-and-heritage"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) I was delighted to see the NPPF reformed in the autumn by Michael Gove to give more power to local planners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continue to make the case I have long made that the right way to plan housing is to give local councils, democratically accountable to the local residents they serve, the freedoms and incentives to plan properly for the right sort of housing and growth where it is needed ie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;around hotspots of economic growth&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;on brownfield sites in areas needing regeneration&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;around growth towns with the infrastructure and services available to sustain further growth&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;in villages with a Neighbourhood Plan setting out the amount of housing they are happy/able to take and which ensures affordable &amp; appropriate local housing for local workers and residents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s what the &lt;strong&gt;Breckland&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;South Norfolk Council&lt;/strong&gt; Local Plans rightly aim to do. What we don’t need in rural Norfolk is massive commuter estate “New Towns” dumped in the middle of rural mud Norfolk without proper infrastructure, facilities, sustainable transport links or fit with the existing pattern of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The North Elmham New Town&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The North Elmham New Town would also represent massive development of the precious River Wensum chalk stream habitats (not to mention a Site of Specific Scientific Interest).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I was delighted to chair a meeting on Friday in North Elmham with local parish councils and local councillors Bill Borrett and Cllr Gordon Bambridge to make clear that the idea of a new town in the area will NOT be supported by ourselves as elected local  representatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill and Gordon confirmed that Breckland Council are NOT zoning this area for major housebuilding, and will oppose a re-application of the New Town as we did successfully last time it was proposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
              
      &lt;div class="image-container"&gt;
        
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;  &lt;img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-04/george_freeman_north_elmham_1.jpg" width="1000" height="600" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
          &lt;div class="svg"&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s why I was delighted to join the c12 local parish councils representing the areas that would be affected by this idea to make clear my opposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the meeting we agreed some important Next Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;To reconvene a meeting of ALL the parish councils in the affected area after the forthcoming local elections on May 4th to make sure all write to Breckland Council formally to express their concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Bill and Gordon and I will liaise to ensure all the local residents who object have their objections properly acknowledged by BDC.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I will invite my neighbouring MP, Jerome Mayhew, to join that follow-up meeting given a number of his Broadland communities are in close proximity to the site around North Elmham and would also be affected.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I will write to Michael Gove (Secretary of State for Levelling Up, Housing and Communities) and the Minister for Housing to make clear why any New Towns and Garden Villages should only be  delivered in the right locations with the associated connectivity, infrastructure and services required) and not in inappropriate locations with the obvious environmental, sustainability and transport issues this scale of development would inevitably threaten.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt; Please be assured that I will keep on this in the weeks and months ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2704 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-05-30T15:17:08Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-30T15:17:08Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>CUMBRIAN MP CALLS FOR RADICAL REFORM OF DENTISTRY</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442234/cumbrian-mp-calls-for-radical-reform-of-dentistry"/>
  <updated>2023-05-30T13:19:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442234/cumbrian-mp-calls-for-radical-reform-of-dentistry</id>
  <summary type="text">This week, on the floor of the House of Commons, Westmorland MP Tim Farron has called for a radical reform of NHS dentistry.
Tim spoke of the desperation of patients within his constituency as they are faced with the decision to either go private or travel miles to access a dentist.
Tim said: "I have recently lost a surgery in my community [in Grange-over-Sands] that saw 5,800 patients lose their NHS status overnight. The private plan that those patients were offered to replace those places would have cost a family of four £1,000 a year just to stay registered and on the books."</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week, on the floor of the House of Commons, Westmorland MP Tim Farron has called for a radical reform of NHS dentistry.</p>
<p>Tim spoke of the desperation of patients within his constituency as they are faced with the decision to either go private or travel miles to access a dentist.</p>
<p>Tim said: <em>"I have recently lost a surgery in my community [in Grange-over-Sands] that saw 5,800 patients lose their NHS status overnight. The private plan that those patients were offered to replace those places would have cost a family of four £1,000 a year just to stay registered and on the books."</em></p>
<p>He offered another example of the dentistry crisis; that a family in Coniston's nearest available NHS dental practice is in Hexham, Northumberland. This would force a family to take a 160-mile round trip just to see their dentist.</p>
<p>He also warned of the potentially life-threatening consequences of patients not being able to receive regular dentistry appointments, as they are often the first to spot symptoms of oral related cancers and diseases.</p>
<p>Tim made the point that people are paying for services, via their taxes, they are not receiving. Additionally, that the money dentists receive from their patients for treatment is not enough to sustain most practices.</p>
<p>He said: <em>"A unit of dental activity payment, at the most basic level, could net perhaps £20 or £30 for a single examination. Diligent dentists seeking to do a good job might do three of those in an hour. Let us do the maths - that funding is not enough to pay to keep the lights and heating on, pay the rent and pay for salaries and materials."</em></p>
<p>He said that this has led to a situation where dentists must now effectively subsidise the NHS which does not incentivise good professional practice and is calling for reform: <em>"Unless there is radical reform of the system, good dentists will leave the NHS and thousands on thousands of our constituents will not be able to access the dental care that they have already paid for through their taxes for themselves and their children."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-50" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Since 2019, I have secured a significant amount of funding for Ashfield including two new school re-builds, over £70 million from the Future High Streets and Towns Fund so I am delighted to know that Florence Nightingale Academy in Eastwood will be receiving investment to upgrade their facilities.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-50</id>
    <published>2023-05-30T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-30T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My article on inflation and growth in the Independent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/05/30/my-article-on-inflation-and-growth-in-the-independent/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong>   So the Bank of England has done it again. Just like last autumn, they have let it be known they might want to sell more bonds at big losses, whilst they plough on with a large sales and repayment programme for government bonds they own. Last autumn it was their statement of intent to sell £80bn of bonds a year coupled with their wish to raise interest rates that started the big bond sell off. Last week it was musings about a bigger sales programme and market expectations of more rate rises to come on the back of poor inflation figures that triggered a similar sell off. As bonds fall so longer term interest rates rise. This matters, as it directly leads to dearer mortgages, threatening those who need to renew their loans with a further unwanted cost of living squeeze. Dearer and scarcer mortgages also means fewer new homes will be built, exacerbating our homes shortage. It’s the last thing we need now. Stop the bond sales at these low prices. Let the bond portfolio roll off as the bonds fall due for repayment. </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>     The Bank needs to own up to the big mistakes it made in 2021, keeping rates too low and paying crazy prices for far too many bonds. Now all it wants to do is to sell too many bonds at much lower prices and big losses. This erratically destructive policy if pursued too far will lurch us from too much inflation into recession. The Bank needs to revisit its models for forecasting inflation and output. In 2021 it was forecasting 2% inflation for today, yet it came in five times that as 2023 began. The Monetary Policy Committee declines to report and comment on the amounts of money in circulation, the state of credit and other issues which you would have thought a Committee with Monetary in its title might be interested in. They should ask themselves why price inflation stayed low in Switzerland, Japan and China, all big food and energy importers and look at their different targets and analysis to  steer their economies. </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>     UK inflation results from too much cash and credit chasing too few goods and services. The Bank needs to get amounts of money in better order, and  not lurch to too little. The government could help with the too few goods. The UK is chronically short of capacity of many kinds. We need to grow more of our own food, produce more of our own electricity and gas, make more of our own steel, cars, ceramics and the rest. Price controls, windfall taxes and higher business taxes make that less likely and will make inflation worse. Bring on the food growing grants to replace the wilding grants. Bring on the end of windfall taxes now the windfall surge in global oil and gas prices is over. Set corporation tax competitively. This will bring in more investment, encourage home based expansion, and start to correct the capacity shortages that  damage us today. The current  model is subsidy driven with government needing to offer large sums to get a single new car or battery factory over the line. </strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">   So the Bank of England has done it again. Just like last autumn, they have let it be known they might want to sell more bonds at big losses, whilst they plough on with a large sales and repayment programme for government bonds they own. Last autumn it was their statement of intent to…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=35231</id>
    <published>2023-05-30T04:09:04Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-30T04:09:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Call for apprentices as Council increases investment in homes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13737/call-for-apprentices-as-council-increases-investment-in-homes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Adverts are now live for over 30 jobs and apprenticeships across a variety of roles as part of the council’s plan to hire over 80 recruits in the housing service in the coming weeks.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13737/call-for-apprentices-as-council-increases-investment-in-homes</id>
    <published>2023-05-29T15:22:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-29T15:22:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Borders businesses recognised at No.10 reception</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borders-businesses-recognised-no10-reception" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was a pleasure to celebrate two fantastic Scottish Borders businesses at the Number 10 Downing Street Local Business Champions Reception.
Congratulations to Quins of Galashiels and Think Fitness in Hawick. They have received well-deserved praise for great customer service.
The small enterprises…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borders-businesses-recognised-no10-reception</id>
    <published>2023-05-29T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-29T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Chancellor of the Exchequer Regarding Mortgage Rates</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-the-chancellor-of-the-exchequer-regarding-mortgage-rates/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=letter-to-the-chancellor-of-the-exchequer-regarding-mortgage-rates" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="t1FU1CZ4Ow"><p><a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/correspondencechanceller2905/">CorrespondenceChanceller2905</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="“CorrespondenceChanceller2905” — " src="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/correspondencechanceller2905/embed/#?secret=jZJ5T3fHt3#?secret=t1FU1CZ4Ow" data-secret="t1FU1CZ4Ow" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"/></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-the-chancellor-of-the-exchequer-regarding-mortgage-rates/">Letter to the Chancellor of the Exchequer Regarding Mortgage Rates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>CorrespondenceChanceller2905</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/letter-to-the-chancellor-of-the-exchequer-regarding-mortgage-rates/">Letter to the Chancellor of the Exchequer Regarding Mortgage Rates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7491</id>
    <published>2023-05-29T07:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-29T07:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>London Road Level Crossing Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Barrier down time at the London Road level crossing has long been a cause of concern in Bicester. This is an issue which I have worked on since I was first elected, chairing meetings with previous administrations at the District and County Council, and meeting multiple Rail Ministers to discuss it…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update</id>
    <published>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Keir Starmer to open fifth annual India Global Forum UK-India Week]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/keir-starmer-to-open-fifth-annual-india-global-forum-uk-india-week/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=12933</id>
		<updated>2023-05-26T17:14:48Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-26T17:11:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Between June 26-30 is the fifth annual India Global Forum UK-India Week in London. I’m pleased that the leader of the Labour Party Keir Starmer will be opening the conference. In advance of his speech Keir said: “The time has now come to look to the future and work on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/keir-starmer-to-open-fifth-annual-india-global-forum-uk-india-week/">Keir Starmer to open fifth annual India Global Forum UK-India Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/keir-starmer-to-open-fifth-annual-india-global-forum-uk-india-week/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/India-UK-ties.png"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-12934" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/India-UK-ties.png" alt="" width="513" height="373" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/India-UK-ties.png 513w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/India-UK-ties-260x189.png 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/India-UK-ties-184x134.png 184w" sizes="(max-width: 513px) 100vw, 513px" /></a></p>
<p>Between June 26-30 is the fifth annual India Global Forum UK-India Week in London.</p>
<p>I’m pleased that the leader of the Labour Party Keir Starmer will be opening the conference.</p>
<p>In advance of his speech Keir said:</p>
<p>“The time has now come to look to the future and work on how we can deepen and widen our cooperation in critical areas such as trade and investment, technology and innovation, climate action, diversity and inclusion, and healthcare, the future of work, skills and education – all areas where I see huge scope for mutual benefit.”</p>
<p>“The Labour Party has a long and strong relationship with India which I am very proud of.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/keir-starmer-to-open-fifth-annual-india-global-forum-uk-india-week/">Keir Starmer to open fifth annual India Global Forum UK-India Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up :: 26 May 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/26/weekly-round-up-26-may-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-26-may-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>On Monday, I joined Keir Starmer in Braintree, as a member of the Shadow Health team, to share Labour’s vision for an NHS fit for the 21st century. This year the service will be 75 years old. If we are to secure the next 75 years, we must rethink how we provide services to people.</p>
<p>Labour’s ten-year ambition for the NHS and social care system are unashamedly ambitious. Like with the last Labour Government, we inherited an NHS that was struggling. But we turned it around that’s because we know that ambition is vital for securing healthcare for all. </p>
<p>We will bring about three fundamental reforms to make the NHS work for you.</p>
<p>1.	Change so that more people get care at home in their community.<br/>
2.	Securing the workforce we need in the healthcare system, with modern technology to deliver the patient outcomes we all want.<br/>
3.	Refocussing the NHS to prevention instead of cure.</p>
<p>A quick train journey to London from Braintree allowed me to join the MillionPlus parliamentary roundtable to discuss the future of nursing. Speaking at the event allowed me to share our vision and hear from those on the frontline on how we can harness best practice and look at innovative ways of training the workforce of the future.</p>
<p>As many of you know, I support the Dignity in Dying campaign to allow choice at the end of life. It was a pleasure to welcome, as Co-Chair, Prue Leith to Parliament who is a great supporter. It was an event that provided the opportunity for families to meet with MPs who are supportive and undecided about whether the law needs to change.</p>
<p>I was delighted to be re-elected Chair of the Women’s Parliamentary Labour Party. Labour has made great strides in this area – indeed 52% of the Parliamentary Labour Party are women. But more still must be done. I’m keen to ensure that we increase the 44% of candidates who have been selected being women to 50%.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, I popped in to a reception hosted by the Youth Sport Trust. They were encouraging more schools to sign up for their National School Sports Week. The aim of their campaign is to ensure all children are active for 60 minutes a day – in line with the Chief Medical Officers advice. And what better way to do that than with a national sports day. It takes place between 19 June to 25 June. Currently, no schools in Bristol South have signed up so if anyone wants their school to sign up click the <a href="https://www.youthsporttrust.org/join-us/nssw">link </a>to learn more!</p>
<p>On Thursday, I spoke in the Urgent Question secured by Labour’s Shadow Home Secretary, Yvette Cooper, on the new immigration figures. I put it to the minister that the Tories continues to badly managed immigration.</p>
<p>We have people stuck in hotels across the country. It’s appalling for those waiting for a decision &amp; is a huge cost to taxpayers. This is all because the Tories cannot clear the asylum backlog they created.</p>
<p>Then, during Business of the House statement, I raised my recent meeting with Action Greater Bedminster and how the housing crisis won’t be fixed if the Government doesn’t fix Primary Healthcare and improve public services. I’m clear: we need to build more homes. Decent homes which tackle climate change, give people a chance to put down roots and become a member of the community and drive our local economic growth. But none of that will be achieved if schools are full, you can’t get a GP appointment and our public transport is on its knees. I hope the Leader of the House listened carefully to my request for the Health and Levelling Up departments to work closely together and fix the shambles of our public services.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/26/weekly-round-up-26-may-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 26 May 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Monday, I joined Keir Starmer in Braintree, as a member of the Shadow Health team, to share Labour’s vision […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/26/weekly-round-up-26-may-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 26 May 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3516</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T15:05:33Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T15:05:33Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour Will End Unfair Foreign Worker Discounts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/labour-will-end-unfair-foreign-worker-discounts/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>joshuatuck</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3455</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T14:47:13Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T14:47:13Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rainham Foodbank: More Than Food</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/rainham-foodbank-more-food" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Rainham Foodbank: More Than Food</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-05-26T14:33:00+00:00">Fri, 05/26/2023 - 15:33</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1205 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T14:33:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T14:33:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/05/26/snp-call-for-uk-government-to-scrap-prohibitive-visa-requirements-to-support-fishing-industry/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10851</id>
		<updated>2023-05-26T13:57:55Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-26T13:42:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week, the UK Government announced that several fishing industry roles were to be added to the UK&#8217;s occupation shortage list. The Scottish fishing sector has been hugely struggling to employ enough deckhands and fishing related staff since the UK left the European Union. The combination of labour shortages, red-tape with the EU and ... <a title="SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/05/26/snp-call-for-uk-government-to-scrap-prohibitive-visa-requirements-to-support-fishing-industry/" aria-label="More on SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Westminster_Hall_25_05_23_14_41_07-1-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="43959823" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The impact of boundary changes – my weekly article of the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-impact-of-boundary-changes-my-weekly-article-of-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-impact-of-boundary-changes-my-weekly-article-of-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236614" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/impact-b-changes.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></div>
<div>
<p>On the morning of the 7th November last year, if you’d walked into Parliament and stood close to the main voting office, you’d have seen a long winding queue of MPs and their staff nervously checking their phones.</p>
<p>That morning, all MPs were given an embargoed copy of the revised boundary changes for the next General Election. A new rule means that there can only be a 5% variance from the average quotas of electors per seat (around 73,000), meaning constituencies must be chopped and changed, and some abolished outright.</p>
<p>It’s an important process, and quite a nerve-wracking one. Not only do you run the risk of potentially losing your seat as an MP, but you also have to do your utmost to protect the character and community of the area you represent.</p>
<p>The new boundaries mean big changes right across Greater Manchester, but particularly in Tameside. The Denton and Reddish constituency – which I serve and has existed for 40 years – is being abolished.</p>
<p>The Audenshaw and Dukinfield wards will go into the Ashton-under-Lyne constituency, Reddish North and South will move into the Stockport constituency and the three Denton wards will be joined with Gorton &amp; Abbey Hey, Longsight, Levenshulme and Burnage in the city of Manchester to form a brand new Gorton and Denton constituency.</p>
<p>I am delighted to announce that I will be standing as the Labour Party’s candidate to become the Member of Parliament for the new Gorton and Denton seat.</p>
<p>This will be a vibrant, diverse and unique seat, and I am excited to have the opportunity to represent residents living in Gorton &amp; Abbey Hey, Longsight, Levenshulme and Burnage alongside my home town of Denton.</p>
<p>It almost goes without saying that I will be sad to say goodbye to Audenshaw, Dukinfield and Reddish. I’ve served these areas for 18 years, and it remains the honour of my life. I am so grateful to all the exceptional residents and councillors I’ve worked with over the years. I am proud of what we have achieved locally, and I know that valuable work will continue for years to come.</p>
<p>Until the next General Election, however, I remain the MP for Denton and Reddish, and as fully committed to the job as I have always been. I feel enormously privileged to do what I do and will continue to be a strong voice in Westminster for the people I represent.</p>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-impact-of-boundary-changes-my-weekly-article-of-the-tameside-reporter/">The impact of boundary changes – my weekly article of the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On the morning of the 7th November last year, if you’d walked into Parliament and stood close to the main voting office, you’d have seen a long winding queue of MPs and their staff nervously checking their phones. That morning, all MPs were given an embargoed copy of the revised boundary changes for the next […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/the-impact-of-boundary-changes-my-weekly-article-of-the-tameside-reporter/">The impact of boundary changes – my weekly article of the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236613</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T12:40:36Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T12:40:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Video: Commonwealth Parliamentary Association - Move to change its status</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/video-commonwealth-parliamentary-association-move-change-its-status" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Video: Commonwealth Parliamentary Association - Move to change its status.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/video-commonwealth-parliamentary-association-move-change-its-status</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne-Marie's Tenant Farming Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/tenantfarmingupdate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Farmers here in North Northumberland are at the heart of our rural economy, including tenant farmers, which this Government fully supports, not least given the essential role they play as a route into farming.
Their voices must be heard, which is why, following the comprehensive review of tenanted…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/tenantfarmingupdate</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NEWS: Government Grants Awarded to Three New Grassroots Sporting Facilities In Beverley and Holderness </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/news-government-grants-awarded-three-new-grassroots-sporting-facilities-beverley-and" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, has welcomed the Government's announcement that grants have been awarded to three new grassroots sporting facilities across Beverley and Holderness. 
 
Projects across the area will receive £44,938 to improve facilities and increase…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/news-government-grants-awarded-three-new-grassroots-sporting-facilities-beverley-and</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg calls out HS2 Ltd over Elm Tree Farm - and demands action from Rail Minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-calls-out-hs2-ltd-over-elm-tree-farm-and-demands-action-rail-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP's working week continues to be dominated by matters relating to HS2. Constantly raising a seemingly never ending stream of unbelievable actions from HS2 Ltd and their contractors with the companies involved and the Department for Transport. Below is Greg's letter from last Friday to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-calls-out-hs2-ltd-over-elm-tree-farm-and-demands-action-rail-minister</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MARTIN PRAISES DEDICATION OF WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE’S VOLUNTEERS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/05/26/martin-praises-dedication-of-west-dunbartonshires-volunteers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>MP for West Dunbartonshire Martin Docherty-Hughes has praised the hard work and dedication of local volunteers as part of National Volunteers’ Week 2023.</p>



<p>In a motion tabled at the House of Commons, local MP Martin thanked volunteers in West Dunbartonshire and across Scotland for their contribution to supporting communities through the cost-of-living crisis.</p>



<p><a href="https://volunteersweek.org/">National Volunteers’ Week</a> runs from 1<sup>st</sup> June until 7<sup>th</sup> June and aims to celebrate the important work done by charities, volunteers and their supporters.</p>



<p>Prior to becoming the area’s MP in 2015, Martin Docherty-Hughes spent over a decade working for West Dunbartonshire Community and Volunteering Services (WDCVS) – supporting and developing local community and volunteering organisations.</p>



<p>According to the Volunteers Scotland group, more than 1 in 4 of Scotland’s adult population volunteered in the past year – equating to over 1.2 million people.</p>



<p>WDCVS are hosting two local Volunteer fairs in Clydebank and Dumbarton on Tuesday 6th June for residents interested in volunteering. Further information is available on the WDCVS website: <a href="https://wdcvs.com/success-story/volunteers-week-2023-celebrate-inspire/">www.wdcvs.com</a></p>



<p><strong>Commenting, Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:</strong></p>



<p>“I am proud to represent the communities of West Dunbartonshire which benefit so much from the dedication of local volunteers.</p>



<p>“As we mark Volunteers’ Week 2023, I want to put on record my thanks to everyone across Clydebank, Dumbarton and the Vale who gives their time to help others.</p>



<p>“In challenging times, through Covid and the cost-of-living crisis, so many of our local charities and voluntary groups have stepped up to help those in need.</p>



<p>“Volunteers play a central role in our communities – from supporting local food banks in tackling food poverty, to volunteering as a befriender and helping combat loneliness.</p>



<p>“For anyone interested in voluntary work, volunteer fairs organised by WDCVS in Clydebank and Dumbarton are a great opportunity to find out more.”</p>



<p><strong>Alan Stevenson, Chief Executive of Volunteers Scotland, said:</strong></p>



<p>“Volunteers are the lifeblood of Scottish communities and what better time to celebrate their very many vital contributions than during Volunteers’ Week.</p>



<p>“In celebrating volunteers and sharing their stories, we highlight the enormous breadth of volunteering opportunities on offer and demonstrate the many benefits – especially for volunteers.”</p>



<p><em><strong>The text of Martin’s Early Day Motion to Parliament on Volunteers’ Week 2023 is available <a href="https://edm.parliament.uk/early-day-motion/60937/volunteers-week-2023">here.</a></strong></em></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">MP for West Dunbartonshire Martin Docherty-Hughes has praised the hard work and dedication of local volunteers as part of National Volunteers’ Week 2023. In a motion tabled at the House of Commons, local MP Martin thanked volunteers in West Dunbartonshire and across Scotland for their contribution to supporting communities through the cost-of-living crisis. National Volunteers’ ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="MARTIN PRAISES DEDICATION OF WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE’S VOLUNTEERS" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/05/26/martin-praises-dedication-of-west-dunbartonshires-volunteers/#more-1821743" aria-label="More on MARTIN PRAISES DEDICATION OF WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE’S VOLUNTEERS">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821743</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T11:56:11Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T11:56:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Volunteers Scotland"/>
    <category term="Volunteers Week"/>
    <category term="WDCVS"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Patients and NHS workers are being failed: Alex blasts Conservative Government over Health Secretary’s rejection of new North Tees Hospital bid]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/05/patients-and-nhs-workers-are-being-failed-alex-blasts-conservative-government-over-health-secretarys-rejection-of-new-north-tees-hospital-bid/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14659</id>
		<updated>2023-05-26T09:03:51Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-26T09:03:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The announcement that North Tees NHS Foundation Trust’s new hospital bid was rejected by Health Secretary Steve Barclay has led Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham to blast the Conservative Government for presiding over a decade of failure to tackle health inequalities in Stockton on Tees. The issues surrounding the North Tees estate are well known [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/05/patients-and-nhs-workers-are-being-failed-alex-blasts-conservative-government-over-health-secretarys-rejection-of-new-north-tees-hospital-bid/">Patients and NHS workers are being failed: Alex blasts Conservative Government over Health Secretary’s rejection of new North Tees Hospital bid</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/05/13570/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great to visit the community owned Elswick Pool &amp;amp; Gym and  discuss with Rashima and Helen the fantastic facilities &amp;amp; classes on offer for all ages. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We discussed the impact of soaring energy costs &amp;amp; how best to support community led projects. A great and friendly space to swim! &lt;/strong&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="r-4qtqp9 r-dflpy8 r-sjv1od r-zw8f10 r-10akycc r-h9hxbl" draggable="false" src="https://abs-0.twimg.com/emoji/v2/svg/1f3ca.svg" alt="????" width="39" height="39" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Great to visit the community owned Elswick Pool &amp; Gym and  discuss with Rashima and Helen the fantastic facilities &amp; classes on offer for all ages. We discussed the impact of soaring energy costs &amp; how best to support community… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13570</id>
    <published>2023-05-26T07:04:21Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-26T07:04:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Island families paying the price for Westminster failure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/05/25/island-families-paying-the-price-for-westminster-failure/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says island families are paying the price for Westminster failure – amid warnings energy bills will not return to 2021 levels until around 2030 at the earliest.</p>



<p>While the Ofgem energy price cap has today been reduced slightly to £2,074 a year for the typical household from July, energy prices will still be around double what they were in 2021 (£1042) and they are expected to rise again in January. The figure will be even higher for island residents which has one of the highest levels of fuel poverty in the UK.</p>



<p>The UK government has also withdrawn the £400 energy bill rebate for households, and household incomes are falling behind the UK’s soaring inflation – leaving families worse off than they were pre-pandemic.</p>



<p>Commenting, Angus MacNeil MP said: “Families in Na h-Eileanan an Iar are paying the price for Westminster failure, with the typical household energy bill double what it was in 2021 and wages falling behind soaring inflation – showing exactly why Scotland needs to escape Westminster control as an independent country.</p>



<p>“Scotland is an energy-rich country and it’s absurd the UK government is forcing families to pay through the nose for a resource we have in abundance, while it refuses to reinvest the huge profits it is raking in from Scotland’s north sea oil and gas.</p>



<p>“Westminster should be using these profits to give families in Scotland an energy bill rebate – and it should match the ambition of progressive SNP government policies, like the £25 a week Scottish Child Payment, to help families struggling with the cost of living.</p>



<p>“The SNP is the only party in Scotland offering a real alternative to the damaging policies of the Tories and pro-Brexit Labour Party – and only a vote for the SNP at the next election can deliver the real change Scotland needs.”</p>



<p>Following the Ofgem announcement, Cornwall Insight warned “Despite the cap falling from the sky-high prices of the past two years, the figure remains over £1,000 per year more than the price cap levels seen prior to the pandemic… We do not currently expect bills to return to pre-2020 levels before the end of the decade at the earliest.”</p>



<p>Campaigners from the End Fuel Poverty Coalition also warned “People now face many more months with bills remaining stubbornly high. This will see them continue to use up their savings for everyday items, run up credit card bills, fall into debt with energy firms or turn to food banks as the cost of living crisis deepens.”</p>



<figure data-carousel-extra="{&quot;blog_id&quot;:29149039,&quot;permalink&quot;:&quot;https:\/\/angusmacneilsnp.com\/2023\/05\/25\/island-families-paying-the-price-for-westminster-failure\/&quot;}" class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg"><img data-attachment-id="4003" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/supreme-court2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg" data-orig-size="1200,1600" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Supreme Court2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=225" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=529" data-id="4003" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-4003" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=768 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=113 113w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg?w=225 225w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/supreme-court2.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px"/></a></figure>
</figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says island families are paying the price for Westminster failure – amid …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/05/25/island-families-paying-the-price-for-westminster-failure/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4199</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T20:34:29Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T20:34:29Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tory Immigration Minister quizzed on Stradey Park Hotel proposal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/05/tory-immigration-minister-quizzed-on-stradey-park-hotel-proposal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/230525NiaStradeyPark.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I told the Tory immigration minister, Robert Jenrick MP, how shocked and concerned we are to hear that he is planning to house 300 Asylum seekers in the Stradey Park Hotel. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I asked him to meet me to hear our concerns and asked him what he is doing to prevent the need to commandeer the Stradey Park Hotel, and to sort out the Home Office backlog of 160,000 claims so those from safe countries can be returned and those who are genuine refugees can move out of hotels and be integrated in small numbers into suitable communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He refused to answer and failed to agree to even meet with me to listen to the views of local people on the subject. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I told the Tory immigration minister, Robert Jenrick MP, how shocked and concerned we are to hear that he is planning to house 300 Asylum seekers in the Stradey Park Hotel. I asked him to meet me to hear our concerns and asked him what he is doing to prevent the need […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8848</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T14:33:51Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T14:33:51Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brendan Clarke-Smith MP welcomes new measures to improve patient choice</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-welcomes-new-measures-improve-patient-choice" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Brendan Clarke-Smith MP welcomes new measures to improve patient choice
Brendan Clarke-Smith MP has welcomed the Government’s announcement to introduce measures to empower people to choose where they receive their NHS care under new plans to help cut waiting lists, one of the Prime Minister’s top…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-welcomes-new-measures-improve-patient-choice</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>QUEEN ELIZABETH HOSPITAL TO BE REBUILT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/queen-elizabeth-hospital-be-rebuilt" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> FUNDING SECURED FOR QEH REBUILD
 The Health Secretary has announced the full rebuild of Queen Elizabeth Hospital in Kings Lynn by 2030. This will hugely improve patient care, quality and outcomes as well as support the wider healthcare sector in Norfolk and is additional to the total rebuild of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/queen-elizabeth-hospital-be-rebuilt</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith challenges government over cost of food</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-challenges-government-over-cost-of-food/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP (Bradford South) has challenged the Government to lower costs of a family shop following news that basic ingredients like sugar had risen by nearly 50%.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Questioning the Government in Parliament, Judith asked:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Sugar prices have risen a massive 47% in the past year, and industry experts predict it will rise again this autumn due to the high energy costs of extracting and refining sugar.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Will the Minister outline what steps the Government is undertaking to support the food and drinks sector throughout this period of extreme inflationary pressure, so that these costs are not yet again passed on to consumers?’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, the Minister acknowledged the pressures the industry was facing:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘We are very keen to help and support [the Food and Drinks sector] with new technology, with investment in genetic technologies to improve sugar beet yields, and we will continue to have those conversations.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘We are very much aware of the pressures on global sugar prices which is why we need a thriving and productive sugar market here in the UK.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking afterwards, Judith said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘We are in a period of high inflation, and the Government must act now to address this, so my constituents don’t have to struggle to feed their families.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;????Basic ingredients like sugar have gone up by nearly 50% this last year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I challenged the government to lower the costs of a family shop so my constituents don&amp;#39;t have to struggle to feed their families.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;???? Watch: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ZlGIcyGJFH"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ZlGIcyGJFH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1661694568385900544?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 25, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;80&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SDP3245-0810-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" alt="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked: “Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, government, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-support-energy-intensive-businesses-and-protect-families-from-winter-blackouts/" title="Government must act now to support energy intensive businesses and protect families from winter blackouts"&gt;Government must act now to support energy intensive businesses and protect families from winter blackouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-support-energy-intensive-businesses-and-protect-families-from-winter-blackouts/" title="Government must act now to support energy intensive businesses and protect families from winter blackouts"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/JudithPMQ-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Government must act now to support energy intensive businesses and protect families from winter blackouts" alt="Government must act now to support energy intensive businesses and protect families from winter blackouts" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;This week in Parliament, Judith called on the Government to take immediate action to protect families and businesses from skyrocketing energy costs. Recent reports have warned that millions of families face blackouts this winter, while some businesses have seen a five-fold increase in their energy bills. Unlike consumers, business energy&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: energy, government, families, judith, costs, support, minister, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-cummins-mp-launches-food-pantry-to-support-local-families/" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families"&gt;Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;78&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-cummins-mp-launches-food-pantry-to-support-local-families/" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/132720401_661727764520958_1473415729086859036_o-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families" alt="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins visited The Sutton Centre in BD4 to launch their new Food Pantry which provides essential food and hygiene products to local families. Open every Wednesday, the pantry asks for a donation of just £3 to fill a bag with a range of tinned goods, cereals&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: food, families, judith, mp, support, local, cummins, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;77&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;77&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP (Bradford South) has challenged the Government to lower costs of a family shop following news that basic ingredients like sugar had risen by nearly 50%. Questioning the Government in Parliament, Judith asked: ‘Sugar prices have risen a massive 47% in the past year, and industry experts predict it will rise again this […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2737</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T11:31:55Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T11:31:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chesterfield MP backs Labour’s plan to end unfair leasehold sales and fix Britain’s broken housing system</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/05/24/chesterfield-mp-backs-labours-plan-to-end-unfair-leasehold-sales-and-fix-britains-broken-housing-system/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/05/24/chesterfield-mp-backs-labours-plan-to-end-unfair-leasehold-sales-and-fix-britains-broken-housing-system/">Chesterfield MP backs Labour’s plan to end unfair leasehold sales and fix Britain’s broken housing system</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/05/24/chesterfield-mp-backs-labours-plan-to-end-unfair-leasehold-sales-and-fix-britains-broken-housing-system/">Chesterfield MP backs Labour’s plan to end unfair leasehold sales and fix Britain’s broken housing system</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5226</id>
    <published>2023-05-24T19:03:57Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-24T19:03:57Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Commonwealth War Graves Week 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/commonwealth-war-graves-week-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week is Commonwealth War Graves Week.</p>
<p>Across Aldridge-Brownhills we have 44 graves, across 5 different cemeteries, that are covered by the Commonwealth War Graves Commission.</p>
<p>The Commission carry out excellent work to honour and care for the men and women of the Commonwealth who died in the First and Second World Wars. The CWGC ensure these individuals will never be forgotten, with over 2,500 war cemeteries and over a million burials at military and civil sites around the world. For individuals who have no known grave, they have built memorials to the missing as <a href="https://www.cwgc.org/find-records/commemorations/">places of commemoration</a>.</p>
<p>The work of the Commonwealth War Graves Commission continues through their staff, supporters and volunteers who ensure that the stories of those who died are told. This year they invite us to <strong>Discover</strong>, <strong>Learn</strong> and <strong>Remember</strong> about the lives of the 1.7million men and women of the Commonwealth commemorated by the CWGC.</p>
<p>Thank you to the Commonwealth War Graves Commission, and all those who volunteer locally.</p>
<p>You can find more information on their work here: <a href="https://www.cwgc.org/war-graves-week/">https://www.cwgc.org/war-graves-week/</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week is Commonwealth War Graves Week. Across Aldridge-Brownhills we have 44 graves, across 5 different cemeteries, that are covered by the Commonwealth War Graves Commission. The Commission carry out […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4726</id>
    <published>2023-05-24T11:27:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-24T11:27:32Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-92/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the briefing about the forthcoming <a href="https://bills.parliament.uk/bills/3443">Victims and Prisoners Bill</a>, which was organised by Alex Mayes from <a href="https://www.victimsupport.org.uk/">Victim Support</a>, an independent charity dedicated to supporting people affected by crime and traumatic incidents in England and Wales. It provides all types of free confidential support 24-hours a day, 365 days a year, regardless of whether the crime has been reported. The Victims and Prisoners Bill received its Second Reading on Monday 15<sup>th</sup> May. Victim Support has called for a Bill to strengthen the rights and improve the experiences of crime victims, but this Bill falls short. Victim Support recommends that the Bill should return to its original form concentrating on victims; the enforcement of victims’ rights should be strengthened; the definition of victim should be broadened to include victims of persistent anti-social behaviour; and all victims must have access to specialist support services that are independent of the police and statutory services. The Bill contains welcome measures to improve data collection for the Victim’s Code, but this relies on the information being comprehensive and robust, so Victim Support urge the UK Government to ensure all rights within the Bill are monitored and reported on by responsible agencies under the Code. The Bill needs to do more to increase the oversight and enforcement of noncompliance by agencies. The parole measures in the new Bill have not been subject to the same degree of pre-legislative scrutiny as for the victims’ part, and will detract from the promised landmark Victims’ Law, and detracts from the UK Government’s commitment to put victims’ interests firmly at the heart of the justice system, given that victims won’t even be at the heart of this Bill.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">At the <a href="https://twitter.com/APPGStemCell">APPG on Stem Cell Transplantation and Advanced Cellular Therapies</a> chaired by my friend Mark Tami MP, who has for many years been a champion for people who are seeking or have undergone a stem cell transplant, we discussed how patients and families are being impacted by the cost-of-living crisis, the cost of undergoing a transplant, the support currently available, and considered possible policy solutions. We listened to the Shadow Health Minister Andrew Gwynne MP; Cheryl Bell, Haematology and Haemophilia Social Worker, Newcastle Council; and Tom Bishop, Head of Patient Information at Anthony Nolan. As chair of the APPG on Sepsis I offered that our APPG work jointly with Mark’s APPG, which Mark accepted.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was honoured to be elected as a vice chair at the AGM of the reconstituted Climate Change APPG, Caroline Lucas MP was elected as chair and Uplift are the secretariat. Uplift is a climate-based organisation founded by Tessa Khan and funded by charitable foundations. The APPG has five goals designed to re-power the UK in a way that safeguards the planet for future generations, whilst unlocking opportunities, strengthening energy security, and cutting the cost of living. The goals include transforming the North Sea’s economic future; boosting energy by scaling the alternatives; building a net zero workforce; aligning energy development with nature protection; and encouraging UK climate leadership on the world stage.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As chair of the APPG for Hairdressing, Barbering and Cosmetology, I joined my vice-chair John McNally MP in meeting with the new registrar, chair, and members of the Hair Council Board to listen to their aims and objectives for the next few years.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Dwr Cymru Welsh Water held the parliamentary launch of its <a href="https://corporate.dwrcymru.com/en/news-media/2023/welsh-water-publishes-manifesto-for-rivers-in-wales-and-plans-record-environmental-investment#:~:text=The%20Manifesto%20for%20Rivers%20in,Special%20Area%20of%20Conservation%20(SAC">Manifesto for Rivers in Wales</a>. The report includes the total phosphorus load and improvement schemes for the rivers Cleddau, Dee, Teifi, Usk and Wye. But it does mention Neath in that there will be investment during the period 2025-30 for the Trebanos Wastewater Treatment Works to increase the flow passed forward through the treatment works for Afon Tawe. Dwr Cymru are conducting a survey with customers and stakeholders to support people to enjoy open water swimming at coastal and inland waters which may not be recognised as official swimming sites or pools. The results are expected this month and will inform Dwr Cymru investment plans for 2025-30.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The APPG for Rare Diseases, chaired by Liz Twist MP met to receive an update from Louise Fish, CEO of Genetic Alliance UK, and discuss their report “<a href="https://geneticalliance.org.uk/coordinatingcarereport2023/">Coordinating Care: Learning from the experiences of people living with rare conditions</a>“. In this meeting we focused on Tuberous Sclerosis Complex (TSC), and received a presentation from Consultant Paediatric Neurologist University Hospitals Bristol, Sam Amim, which is featured on pages 30-31 of the report. We listened to a number of people whose children and families are living with the very rare disease TSC, and the challenges and difficulties they have experienced in getting a diagnosis, plus subsequent medical and education support.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Co-chairs for <a href="https://www.gov.wales/independent-commission-constitutional-future-wales">The Independent Commission on the Constitutional Future of Wales</a>, The Rt. Revd. and Rt. Hon. Rowan Williams and Professor Laura McAllister, held a briefing for parliamentarians from all parties on its interim report, consultation, and answered questions from the Peers and MPs who were in the room. They were accompanied by commissioners Albert Owen, former MP for Ynys Mon; Miguela Gonzales, Head of Diversity at Abcam; former civil servant for 30 years, Phillip Rycroft; and Conservative former UK Government Special Adviser to the Wales Office, Lauren McEvatt. The cross-party commission was set up by Welsh Government in November 2021, with two broad objectives: to consider and develop options for the fundamental reform of the constitutional structures of the UK, in which Wales is an integral part; to consider and develop all progressive principal options to strengthen Welsh democracy and deliver improvements for the people of Wales. The commission took oral evidence from politicians, academics, and civil society, plus a public consultation which attracted 2524 online contributions. A community engagement fund was set up to support community groups/organisations to hold engagement projects to facilitate the commissioners meeting with community groups, including youth sector, care sector, and ethnic minorities, because they wanted to learn what the people of Wales want and need. The interim report was published in December 2022, and it sets out the framework options from the results of the consultation: entrenched devolution; a federal UK; and independence. The commission sought views on the framework and new/supplementary evidence by May 2023, and its final report will use a prepared objective base analysis, and test the robustness of the initial findings, to make sure that Wales is on the front foot regarding governance and powers. The final report will be published by the end of 2023.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was proud to be elected the treasurer for the <a href="https://www.ukmusic.org/about/all-party-parliamentary-group-on-music/">APPG for Music</a> at its AGM, having served as a vice chair for many years. My dear friend Kevin Brennan MP was re-elected as chair, and I’m pleased to continue to support Kevin in all the good work that he does to highlight the wonderful benefits that music, its performers, and the music industry provides to the public all over the UK.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">At the AGM of the APPG on State Pension Inequality for Women, Andrew Gwynne MP and Peter Aldous MP were re-elected co-chairs and I was re-elected a vice chair.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="http://appg-humanrights.org.uk/">All-Party Parliamentary Human Rights Group</a> (PHRG) held a drop in event titled – <em>Levelling the playing field for UK companies: Mandatory supply chain due diligence to protect human rights and the environment</em>. The event was sponsored by the APPGs on Ethical and Sustainability in Fashion and Trade Justice, CAFOD, and Friends of the Earth. We listened to campaigners speak about the emerging new global standard for regulating global supply chains; mandatory human rights and environmental due diligence; and the proposed new law for the UK. Businesses, investors, and civil society demonstrated their support for a new law to bring the UK into alignment with the UN Guiding Principles on Business and Human Rights, and the increasing number of countries adopting new due diligence laws. Leading UK companies explained why they backed the call for new UK legislation which would, inter alia, level the playing field by mandating supply chain due diligence and increase legal certainty about standards expected from the business sector. Organisations at the event included: Anti-Slavery International; Aviva; Business and Human Rights Resource Centre; Ethical Trading Initiative; John Lewis Partnership; Marshalls PLC. In 2022, a G7 Leaders Communique, and UK businesses, investors, and business associations all supported the new law. Whilst I was at the event I signed <a href="https://edm.parliament.uk/early-day-motion/60909/potential-merits-of-new-legislation-on-mandatory-corporate-due-diligence">EDM 1169</a> created by my long-time friend Tony Lloyd MP.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I supported the <a href="https://www.fightbladdercancer.co.uk/">Fight Bladder Cancer</a> (FBC) awareness event which is campaigning for better outcomes for people living with bladder cancer, their families and carers. FBC is a national charity dedicated to changing patients’ lives for the better, providing information and support on what to expect at various stages of bladder cancer, connecting people to share their experiences and to help one another. Over 21,000 people are diagnosed with bladder cancer each year in the UK and FBC are calling for a standardised pathway for the diagnosis, assessment and treatment of bladder cancer and better investment in the BC workforce in 2023 and beyond.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was re-elected a vice chair at the AGM for the <a href="https://www.appgcoalfields.co.uk/">APPG on Coalfield Communities</a>. We agreed work plans for the forthcoming release of our enquiry: <em>Next Steps in Levelling Up the Former Coalfields</em>. The enquiry was launched last November, and received submissions from public and private sectors across the UK. The members of the APPG believe that the former coalfield regions are now at a critical juncture, but we have an opportunity to make representations to ministers to shape the levelling up agenda for years to come. I look forward to the publication and launch of the APPG’s enquiry report in early June.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As part of <a href="https://www.alzheimers.org.uk/about-dementia/symptoms-and-diagnosis/worried-memory-problems-or-dementia?sc=daw23&amp;utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=daw23&amp;gad=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwyLGjBhDKARIsAFRNgW8HeYCsfRL5M-hL7PU5EqLkMq4AzwhhhnkY5E78h4oUfYljsFhtBZUaAsOjEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">Dementia Action Week</a> (15-21 May) I attended a Parliamentary reception hosted by <a href="https://www.alzheimers.org.uk/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_campaign=Rebrand+23&amp;gad=1&amp;gclid=Cj0KCQjwyLGjBhDKARIsAFRNgW_ZIv734tpAtDlaxlrYGTBmhmjD-ptxPjwQ2juDEOTiw2c6sYC2GC0aAr_iEALw_wcB&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">Alzheimer’s Society</a>, which stressed the importance of getting a dementia diagnosis with the tagline “It’s not called getting old, it’s called getting ill” and it encourages people worried about their own or a loved one’s memory to seek support in getting a diagnosis using a symptoms check list available on the Alzheimer’s online hub. In England, the dementia diagnosis rate fell below the national ambition during the pandemic, and has remained around 62% since, so more than 30,000 have missed out on a diagnosis. Unfortunately, in Wales the scale of the problem is unknown because data is not collected. The Alzheimer’s Society believe that around 50,000 people in Wales are living with Dementia, but there is no way of knowing how many have been diagnosed, so they are calling for comprehensive diagnosis data to be collected in Wales so that this can be published centrally on a national level so that Wales can be compared to other parts of the UK. The Alzheimer’s Society believe that everyone living with dementia deserves an accurate, timely, and high-quality dementia diagnosis so that they can access vital care, support, and plan for their future.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I attended the briefing about the forthcoming Victims and Prisoners Bill, which was organised by Alex Mayes from Victim Support, an independent charity dedicated to supporting people affected by crime and traumatic incidents in England and Wales. It provides all types of free confidential support 24-hours a day, 365 days a year, regardless of whether the crime […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2740</id>
    <published>2023-05-24T08:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-24T08:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>North Wales Conservative MPs call for police investigation into Betsi Accounting Scandal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/north-wales-conservative-mps-call-police-investigation-betsi-accounting-scandal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The North Wales Group of Conservative MPs has called for an urgent police investigation into the Betsi Cadwaladr University Health Board (BCUHB) scandal, revealed in today’s Daily Mail.
The newspaper report reveals that senior executives of the Board apparently conspired to falsify accounts,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/north-wales-conservative-mps-call-police-investigation-betsi-accounting-scandal</id>
    <published>2023-05-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Let's fix social care now before it's too late </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/lets-fix-social-care-now-its-too-late" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Political crises come and go, but the crisis of social care has been growing for decades, and still needs a comprehensive solution. I have been trying to push it up the political agenda for years and will keep doing so, for a number of reasons.
The first is that it is simply not right for such an…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/lets-fix-social-care-now-its-too-late</id>
    <published>2023-05-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Working with Local Schools</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/local-schools/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday 19 May I joined year nine students at Brockhill Park Academy School who had taken part in the Be Internet Citizens programme that day. This programme has been designed by the family safety experts at Parent Zone and YouTube and is suitable for all young people aged thirteen and above. It aims to […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6301</id>
    <published>2023-05-23T08:57:34Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-23T08:57:34Z</updated>
    <category term="My Articles"/>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The new Executive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/22/the-new-executive/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor David Mellen will remain as Leader of the council, continuing the hard work of continuing the hard work of himself, Cllr Adele Williams, Cllr Sally Longford and all previous and current executive and backbench members. He is responsible for continuing devolution, strategic regeneration, development and work on the city’s ambitious plan to be carbon neutral by 2028, as well as promoting the vision of the council and supporting all of his Portfolio Holders in their work. There is much work to be done over the next term and the new executive will be key in achieving the goals Nottingham Labour want for the city.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Audra Wynter has been confirmed as the new Deputy Leader and she will have responsibility for the finance and HR portfolios. With a background in finance work, Councillor Wynter will ensure the council remains on track in delivering a balanced budget and sticking to the Medium-Term Financial Plan, while delivering high-quality services for residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-small-font-size"&gt;Councillor Corall Jenkins will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Energy, Environment and Waste Services and Parks. She will have responsibility for key services such as bin collection and disposal, keeping our city’s streets clean and maintaining all of our wonderful parks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Cheryl Barnard will remain as Portfolio Holder for Children, Young People and Education. She will continue to be responsible for leading our children’s services, working with Ofsted to improve it where necessary, ensuring children’s safeguarding and working with academy trusts across the city on schools, ensuring attendance and working to reduce exclusions, so that all children get the best start in life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Steve Battlemuch will be taking up the reins as Portfolio Holder for Skills, Growth, Economic Development and Property. He will lead on skills and employment, ensuring that the workforce in the city is prepared for any changes in the way we work, and that the people of this city have the right opportunities. He will also oversee the management of the city centre, attracting investment and helping to ensure that Nottingham is promoted nationally and internationally to business and tourism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Jay Hayes has been confirmed as the new Portfolio Holder for Housing. He will lead on managing the council housing service, student housing, private rented properties and areas such as selective licensing and homelessness. Housing is incredibly important, all those who live in the city deserve to have a property that is safe, secure and that can be called home, whether they rent in the private sector or have social housing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sajid Mohammed will lead as Portfolio Holder for Neighbourhoods, Safety and Inclusion. This covers areas such as community protection, domestic violence work, licensing, taxi strategy and more. It is so important that Nottingham is a safe place to work and live in. Councillor Mohammed with many years of experience of community work and as director of Himmah will bring the required expertise to lead in these vital areas, and he will also lead on refugee and asylum seeker work, to ensure that Nottingham is a welcoming city for all, and that those vulnerable refugees and asylum seekers can integrate and make new lives in Nottingham.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Pavlos Kotsonis will continue as Portfolio Holder for Leisure and Culture. He will ensure that we continue to offer an outstanding events programme. He will also oversee the reopening and flourishing of the Castle, the continued running of Wollaton Hall and Newstead Abbey as well as leisure centres, markets, libraries and community centres across the city. Access to cultural events and key things like libraries and leisure centres is so important for allowing the people of the city to thrive and create.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Linda Woodings will also remain as Portfolio Holder for Adult Social Care and Health. She will continue to work on Public Health and Wellbeing, tackling health inequalities and working to reduce smoking prevalence, working on mental health and generally improving the health of residents in the city. She will also lead on independent living. All of these will help to improve the quality and length of life for residents in the city for years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, Councillor Angela Kandola will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Highways, Transport and Planning. She will oversee public transport such as buses and the tram. She will also lead on greener transport such as cycling and cycling links in the city, ensure highways are correctly managed and repaired as well as the Workplace Parking Levy to help increase public transport usage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is just a short summary of the responsibilities that the Executive will have for the next year. They will bring both their expertise and new views to help ensure that there is strong and effective political leadership at the council. This will continue both our journey with the Improvement and Assurance Board but also enable us to bring in the pledges that we made to the residents of the city in our manifesto in the May local elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=3074</id>
    <published>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Arboretum"/>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="Berridge"/>
    <category term="Bestwood"/>
    <category term="Bilborough"/>
    <category term="Bulwell"/>
    <category term="Bulwell Forest"/>
    <category term="Castle"/>
    <category term="Dales"/>
    <category term="election"/>
    <category term="Housing"/>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton MP welcomes share of over £450 million from the Conservative Government to improve school buildings in Blackpool South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-share-over-ps450-million-conservative-government-improve-school" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Conservative Government is investing over £450 million in extra funding to improve school buildings, with over 1,000 projects receiving new investment to deliver safe, well-maintained facilities that support a high-quality education for pupils.   
859 academies, sixth form colleges and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-share-over-ps450-million-conservative-government-improve-school</id>
    <published>2023-05-22T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-22T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[UK competition tsar calls for crackdown on utilities ‘ripping off’ customers]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/05/18/uk-competition-tsar-calls-for-crackdown-on-utilities-ripping-off-customers/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5739</id>
		<updated>2023-05-22T07:55:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-18T07:50:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Best Brexit"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Article written by Gill Plimmer and originally published in The Financial Times Shareholders in water and energy monopolies should receive steady but unspectacular returns, says government adviser Britain’s water and energy watchdogs should be empowered to crack down on companies “ripping off” consumers and “causing harm to the economy”, a key government adviser has said. [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/05/18/uk-competition-tsar-calls-for-crackdown-on-utilities-ripping-off-customers/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong><em>Article written by Gill Plimmer and originally published in <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www-ft-com.ezp.lib.cam.ac.uk/content/2723bd15-7c41-4593-9021-8a07e328cb09" target="_blank">The Financial Times</a></em></strong></p>



<p>Shareholders in water and energy monopolies should receive steady but unspectacular returns, says government adviser</p>



<p>Britain’s water and energy watchdogs should be empowered to crack down on companies “ripping off” consumers and “causing harm to the economy”, a key government adviser has said. </p>



<p>John Penrose, the UK “competition tsar” who is advising the government on reforming the regulators, said that a new competition bill will tackle modern monopolies such as Google but is yet to address the regulation of water and energy utilities. </p>



<p>“Our economic regulation system isn’t working properly,” Penrose told the Financial Times, referring to Ofwat, which oversees water and sewage companies in England and Wales, and Ofgem, the energy regulator. </p>



<p>“It has been too soft, giving monopoly-owning firms an overly easy ride on prices and quality with suppliers and customers paying the price for this failure.” </p>



<p>Penrose’s comments follow research by the FT that showed the 10 largest privatised water monopolies paid out £1.4bn in dividends in the year to March 31 2022 despite concerns over the dumping of unknown quantities of untreated sewage and storm water into beaches, rivers and lakes. </p>



<p>“Water is the stuff of life and none of us can do without it, but the performance of our long-term regulatory model is looking poor,” Penrose said. “The regulated utilities should be delivering good quality standards while receiving a steady but unspectacular return in the process. </p>



<p>“Instead we are seeing that shareholders earn monopoly profits that are both very high and extremely stable too, which means customers are getting ripped off by paying too much.” He added: “This is causing harm to the economy.” </p>



<p>Penrose, chair of the Conservative Policy Forum, a grassroots-led think-tank, was appointed in 2020 by then chancellor and current prime minister Rishi Sunak to review UK laws intended to promote competition. </p>



<p>The digital markets, competition and consumers bill has its second reading in the House of Commons on Wednesday and is designed to give the watchdog, the Competition and Markets Authority, greater powers. </p>



<p>Penrose acknowledged there were calls from across the political spectrum to renationalise the water and energy sectors. A YouGov poll last year found 58 per cent of Conservative voters believed water should be brought under public control and 47 per cent for energy. </p>



<p>However, Penrose said: “More competition is the quickest way to reduce the costs which are ultimately passed on to customer bills.” </p>



<p>The business water market was opened to competition by the government and water regulator Ofwat in 2017 in an attempt to mimic the energy sector, which had liberalised services in the 1990s. </p>



<p>Independent retailers were licensed to handle customer complaints, bills, meter readings and enquiries anywhere in the country, although the water is still provided by the regional water company. But a huge surge in complaints over service cast doubt over the market’s success. </p>



<p>The opposition Labour party has called for a new regulator merging parts of Ofwat, the Environment Agency and the Drinking Water inspectorate but Penrose said: “Moving the deck chairs doesn’t fix the underlying problem.” </p>



<p>Cat Hobbs, director of We Own It, which campaigns for public ownership of water, rail and energy, said: “The attempts by regulators to mimic the market have clearly failed and water should be returned to state hands as is the norm worldwide.”</p>



<p>Ofwat said: “We agree that water company performance needs to improve and we are acting to drive that change. We have trebled our enforcement capacity, to help us hold companies to account.” </p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/05/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-39/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Met with the Parliamentary Under Secretary of State for Social Mobility, Youth and Progression on behalf of Wycombe Homeless Connection. Attended the Penn and Tylers Green Residents’ Society AGM. Visited the Christian Aid Week Reception in Parliament to discuss their work with women in Malawi and business as development. Supported Pine Trees residents to help get their community centre opened, including visiting Wrights Meadow Centre to see how a good community building […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18659</id>
    <published>2023-05-19T17:04:37Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-19T17:04:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="#Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-201" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A funny short week in Westminster following the Bank holiday, but that does not mean that it was not busy! The Energy Bill was properly debated for the first time on Tuesday, a piece of legislation that is seeking to support the delivery of the UK’s climate change commitments through reforming the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-201</id>
    <published>2023-05-18T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-18T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Bill Wiggin backs British farming as PM hosts Downing Street Summit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/05/17/mp-bill-wiggin-backs-british-farming-as-pm-hosts-downing-street-summit/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sir Bill Wiggin, Member of Parliament for North Herefordshire, has welcomed new investment and support for British farmers set out at the UK Farm to Fork Summit yesterday. Representatives from the whole food supply chain came together at 10 Downing... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/05/17/mp-bill-wiggin-backs-british-farming-as-pm-hosts-downing-street-summit/#more-4719">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4719</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T16:14:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T16:14:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southampton Jobs Fair</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/05/17/southampton-jobs-fair-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Please share with friends and family. There will be a Jobs Fair at St Mary's Stadium on the 16th of June 10am -1pm. There will be over 30 companies recruiting and hundreds of jobs available.  The Jobs Fair is free to attend for those looking to gain employment and suitable for any ages. No registration is required.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/05/17/southampton-jobs-fair-2/">Southampton Jobs Fair</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5145</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T14:27:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T14:27:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree was a beneficiary of the programme which is backed by £1.8 billion of government funding over this financial year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps was thrilled to see that Peartree had benefited from this funding and looks forward to seeing their transformation. In the past, Mr Shapps helped free up playground space at Peartree by getting a disused Victorian loo block removed which has helped generations of pupils enjoy a little more&amp;nbsp;open&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps also met with student members of the school council who asked him an array of questions about his career, local issues and his life as the constituency&amp;#8217;s parliament member. The members of the school council are aged between five and eleven and are elected by their classmates to give them a voice in Peartree School’s vision, projects and events.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps commented on his visit and on his time with members of the school council:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to catch up with staff and visit pupils at Peartree School last week. The children are clearly enjoying their time there very much, and it was really helpful to get an insight from Miss Hardy and her team as to how everyone’s getting on. Plus, I enjoyed a brilliant sit-down with the School Council &amp;#8211; they really put me through my paces with their questions.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Megan Hardy, the Head of School at Peartree, thanked Mr Shapps for visiting and meeting with the staff and students:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to show Mr Shapps around Peartree and to talk to him about our plans for the school’s transformation over the coming years.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She continued:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The children were really excited to meet their MP and they came up with plenty of interesting questions to ask him. They were very inspired by his visit, so we may even have a future prime minister among us!”&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps thanks Peartree for having him visit and wishes the staff and students all the best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/"&gt;Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students. During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/">Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Yarwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=48284</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, Member of Parliament for Newcastle North, has shown her support for people living with diabetes in Parliament alongside Diabetes UK.  Diabetes UK’s new “Diabetes Is Serious” campaign, highlights the challenges facing the five million people living with diabetes in the UK. The report includes shocking new figures showing that there were 7,000 excess deaths connected … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7946</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Health and Social Care"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/2023/05/17/april-newsletter-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>liamtaggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=333</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3374</id>
		<updated>2023-05-16T11:22:21Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-16T11:22:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; Dear Constituent, Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve been on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Illegal migration bill update:</u></strong></p>



<p>The main piece of legislation that has been going through the House of Commons in the last few weeks is the Illegal Migration Bill. I’ve heard from a number of constituents with a diverse range of views on this topic. On the 26<sup>th</sup> of April the bill completed its remaining stages in the Commons and is now moving through the House of Lords, before it will return to the Commons for a final review.</p>



<p>This Bill is set to enhance the powers of the Government to tackle illegal migration, including the ability to remove illegal migrants from the UK to safe countries, new ways to determine ages of migrants without formal identification, additional protections for child migrants, and tougher sentences for those found guilty of people smuggling. The Bill was also amended during its remaining stages to include the Government’s commitment to review the safe and legal routes that are available.</p>



<p>It is clear that we need an asylum system that does work for those families truly in need, but is also tough on those who are trying to exploit the process to gain entry to the UK and on human traffickers who are exploiting vulnerable people and worsening the crisis. The new bill tackles the latter problems, while leaving open safe and legal routes for those in need.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sewage &amp; storm overflows update:</u></strong></p>



<p>Another key development in Parliament was new plans to further increase water quality targets and reduce sewage being released into our waterways.</p>



<p>The Government has announced its plan to enshrine the Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published last August, into law through the Environment Act. This will make its target to reduce storm overflows legally binding. The Government’s Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published in August 2022, set out stringent targets to protect people and the environment and is backed up by up to £56 billion capital investment, which is the largest infrastructure programme in water company history.</p>



<p>Further, the Government is now consulting on proposals for unlimited fines to be imposed on water companies that break the rules. More than £142 million has already been levied in fines since 2015 and I am aware that money from fines and penalties will now be channelled back into the environment.</p>



<p><strong><u>East Midlands APPG:</u></strong></p>



<p>Outside the Chamber, the focus seemed to be local issues over the last few weeks, and we had another meeting of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on the East Midlands. This group brings together MPs from across the Chamber to discuss issues that are especially important to our region.</p>



<p>The most recent meeting was on the future of Infrastructure in the East Midlands. We heard from the East Midlands Chamber of Commerce and East Midlands Councils on infrastructure in our area and the need for infrastructure investment to fulfil our environmental commitments, to make it easier for people living here to travel and get to work, and to encourage businesses to move here.</p>



<p>Moving forward, we will continue to push for our region to receive funding in the future, by collecting evidence on the wider benefits of infrastructure projects to the local economy and local businesses and use this in future proposals for funding.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ferrero sustainable palm oil event:</u></strong></p>



<p>I was also able to welcome Ferrero, who own the Thornton’s factory in Somercotes, to Parliament. They hosted an event alongside Chester Zoo and the Orangutan Land Trust on Sustainable Palm Oil, where they discussed the damage palm oil farming has inflicted on jungles and local habitats of orangutans around the world. While many food producers have moved away from palm oil for these reasons, the same problems of deforestation and habitat destruction continue to persist regardless of the plant used.</p>



<p>Because of this, Ferrero highlighted the use of certified sustainable palm-oil to that avoids these poor practices by working with local wildlife experts, stopping further deforestation for farming land, and reducing the impact on the environment.</p>



<p>It was great to hear from a business that operates locally in our area that is tackling global issues and to talk to the charitable organisations that were supporting these efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="667" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3376" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg 1000w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Amber Valley Borough Council elections 4th May 2023 &amp; Parish/Town Council elections:</u></strong></p>



<p>On the 4th May 2023, elections were held for Amber Valley Borough Council. For the first time in a long time, elections were held for all 42 councillors over 18 wards (rather than the previous recent system of electing a third of councillors each year).</p>



<p>As a result of the election, the Labour Group took control of the Council and have 26 councillors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all who were elected and I look forward to working with the new Borough Council where needed and holding them to account where necessary too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find your borough councillor <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All the parish and town councils in Amber Valley were also up for election. You can find the results of these <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections/parish-and-town-councils/">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Access to Cash &#8211; Nationwide Heanor:</u></strong></p>



<p>I know for many constituents a key concern has been the closures of bank branches in our area.</p>



<p>Although banking is increasingly moving online, in-person branches are still relied upon by many in our communities and are staples in our high streets. People need access to bank branches so that they can speak to someone in person about their accounts and finances.</p>



<p>I was able to visit Nationwide in Heanor to discuss this issue and was reassured that they understood the important role they play on our high streets and intend to stay open for the foreseeable future.</p>



<p>I was also able to discuss the work they are doing to help vulnerable people more broadly, including their cost-of-living helpline, fraud prevention and work to teach useful financial skills to young people.</p>



<p>I’ll continue to support maintaining access to bank branches and cash in our communities and town centres.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="636" height="791" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3375" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg 636w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-241x300.jpeg 241w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Nieper Foundation visit:</u></strong></p>



<p>In Alfreton I joined Robert Halfon, the Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education, in a visit related to the Christopher Nieper Education Trust. The Trust was set up to allow David Nieper Ltd to invest in local education and help young people into long-term, rewarding employment.</p>



<p>We visited David Nieper Ltd and met with Dr Hobbs, the Headteacher of David Nieper Academy, others who are supporting the work of the Trust and met with a student to do an interview for the Spirit of Alfreton. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684233937.JPG" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong><u>Local primary school visits:</u></strong></p>



<p>I have also able to visit both Mundy Junior School and Heage Primary School to speak to teachers and school leaders about funding.</p>



<p>With schools also being hit with high energy bills, there was concern that planned increases to teacher’s salaries and additional provisions for students would not be fully funded if prices for heating stay high. I was able to talk to teachers about the worry this is causing.</p>



<p>It is only right that any increases to staff pay are properly covered by increased investment into schools and it is important that the Government has contingency plans and funding in place to reassure schools that they will be supported should energy bills stay high.</p>



<p><strong><u>Windows for Ukraine:</u></strong></p>



<p>I also took part in a visit to CPR Manufacturing in Alfreton, who are supporting a project called Windows for Ukraine. Cromwell Polythene is manufacturing polyethylene film used to make effective temporary windows as part of a project called Insulate Ukraine. The company have donated some of the film being used, which is an alternative to glass and insulates homes better than double-glazing. The local business usually manufactures bin liner products.</p>



<p><strong><u>Collis engineering visit &amp; 5G masts:</u></strong></p>



<p>To look at their new 5G masts I&#8217;ve also been to see Collis Engineering Ltd. They&#8217;re manufacturing a new mast and tower system to support the rollout of 5G and which has a high headload capacity, meaning several operators can share the same structure and system. Collis are an important local employer and it was good to learn more about this innovation that is being manufactured right here in the heart of Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that access to telephone and broadband signal remains an issue for many residents, so hopefully this innovation will help with that, and I&#8217;ll continue to pursue solutions for areas where there are concerns or problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684234142.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Street Watch:</h1>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[UP FOR THE CHALLENGE]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=494</id>
		<updated>2023-05-15T08:45:13Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-15T08:45:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<title>God Save the King</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/54-uncategorised/2181-god-save-the-king"/>
		<published>2023-05-06T14:28:12+01:00</published>
		<updated>2023-05-06T14:28:12+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/54-uncategorised/2181-god-save-the-king</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;God Save the King &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Coronation?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Coronation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4hWbeAa60E"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4hWbeAa60E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1654832795678654464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;God Save the King &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Coronation?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Coronation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4hWbeAa60E"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4hWbeAa60E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1654832795678654464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Uncategorised"/>
	</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>CH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Time To Put Children First]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6927</id>
		<updated>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Education"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="education"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership. It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Time To Put Children First</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" width="870" height="179" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership.</p>



<p>It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school success. Labour understands this. In the 60s and 70s the Wilson government created Educational Priority Areas and after 18 years of Tory rule, the last Labour government introduced Education Action Zones to once again boost the chances of children from poorer backgrounds.</p>



<p>It’s by working with parents and carers and putting schools at the centre of communities that we build the solid foundations from which children succeed. Over 13 years of Tory rule, we’ve seen teachers abused and experts ridiculed and an attempt to return schools to teaching models experienced by too many government ministers, in private schools, over the past 50 years. It’s not structures like free schools or academisation or gimmicks about a smattering of Latin that matter. We need support for parents and programmes to attract the best teachers to disadvantaged areas.</p>



<p>Almost every successful person has a story about the teacher who influenced their direction and put them on a path to success. We need to rediscover an ambition and love for education.</p>



<p>At Kings Heath Boys they’re not planning to rest on their laurels but open up choice and opportunity by changing to an intake of boys and girls. We’re blessed with several outstanding schools in south Birmingham, they do a remarkable job despite squeezed budgets, teacher retention problems and children’s mental health issues. These are all things the government should be addressing.</p>



<p>I hope the local community will get behind plans for Kings Heath Boys which will give more children a chance to attend a school that’s best for them. I’m hungry for a Labour government that treats teachers with the respect they deserve and puts our children first.</p>



<p>It’s time to focus on a system where the talents of every child can be nurtured and where their achievements are the priority.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HMRC and scam tax rebates</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="MortgageSmiths 27 04 23" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f9bgDDcDJnQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f4cd.png" alt="📍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; A constituent of mine discovered in November that HMRC had handed over £972 to the company MortgageSmiths, who took almost half of that in commission fees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As he hadn&amp;#8217;t commissioned this company in the first place, he demanded to see the application form, which was such a poor forgery that both his and his wife&amp;#8217;s signature were clearly in the same handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the government repeatedly warning the public not to fall for financial scams, it&amp;#8217;s incredible that the HMRC fell for this one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So can we have a Treasury statement, so we can understand the extent of this problem, what&amp;#8217;s being done to prevent it in the future, and when constituents like mine will actually get their money from the HMRC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government response&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt;Well, I thank the Honourable Lady for raising this case. I&amp;#8217;m very sorry to hear that. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She may of course wish to raise it at Treasury questions on the 9th of May.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But given this is a sizable chunk of money for them to be out of pocket with, I will certainly raise this today with HMRC and ask them to contact the Honourable Lady with regard to this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;#038;title=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/" data-a2a-title="HMRC and scam tax rebates"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/"&gt;HMRC and scam tax rebates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>  📍 A constituent of mine discovered in November that HMRC had handed over £972 ... <a title="HMRC and scam tax rebates" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/">HMRC and scam tax rebates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Parliamentary Assistant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2737</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T14:58:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T14:58:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="HMRC"/>
    <category term="Scam"/>
    <category term="Tax Rebate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Stewart welcomes 3,468 extra police officers for Met Police</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has welcomed the announcement that 3,468 extra police officers have been recruited for the Metropolitan Police since September 2019, bringing the total number of officers up to 35,411.
 
The recruitment drive is part of the Government’s Beating Crime…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Social Security Health Assessments System <span style="color:#06396a;">Has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>The cross party Work and Pensions Select Committee responsible for scrutinising the Department for Work and Pensions’ (DWP) policies, has published a damning report on the Government’s health assessments system which is used to screen whether sick and disabled people should have access to vital social security payments.</p>
<p>These payments provide financial support to a working age person who is unable to work because of their health condition or disability; the assessment for this is the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) and is for either Employment Support Allowance or Universal Credit Limited Capability to Work. In addition there is also the Personal Independence Payment (PIP) assessment process to access support to cover the extra costs disabled people face because of their disability which are estimated at over £580 a month on average; this is for the Personal Independence Payment.</p>
<p>The report exposed the detrimental impact of the assessment process itself on the health and well being of claimants.</p>
<p>Giving evidence to the Committee, Professor Ben Barr, from the University of Liverpool, was asked about research he carried out in 2015 which looked at the impacts of the WCA as claimants were reassessed to move onto Employment Support Allowance. His analysis estimated that across England, the WCA had caused an additional 600 suicides, 300,000 additional cases of mental health problems and a large rise in the prescribing of antidepressants over a nine-year period.</p>
<p>“We looked at whether it could be explained by other factors or other economic trends, but there was quite a unique pattern in the increase in mental health problems, and the most likely explanation was that it was due to the reassessment process”, he told the committee. He said it is difficult to assess improvements since this study as “there are no systems in place” to monitor the impact of the health assessments and the potential adverse outcomes.</p>
<p>A survey by the University of Kent last year found half of claimants who have been through the WCA process said it made their mental health worse. Dr Ben Baumberg Geiger, who led the research, told the committee: “It is not sufficient to say that this is a historical problem and that everything is fine now. If there was more transparency, it would be easier to know a bit more about it, but the evidence suggests that there are still major problems with the WCA that could lead to an increased risk of poor mental health.”</p>
<p>Debbie Abrahams the Member of Parliament for Oldham East and Saddleworth and a Member of the Work and Pensions Select Committee said:</p>
<p><em>“The evidence is clear – the current system is not fit for purpose. The DWP’s own figures show that <strong><u>274 people a month</u></strong> <strong><u>die 6 months after being found fit for work </u></strong>and <strong><u>60 people a month die 3 months after having PIP refused. </u></strong>These are poorly people not the shirkers and scroungers that some Conservatives refer to when discussing social security claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“We heard evidence during the inquiry that when people were being reassessed between 2010 and 2013, there were 600 additional suicides. In 2020, National Audit Office has said that the claimant deaths that the DWP had investigated were the tip of the iceberg. The current approach is contributing, directly and indirectly, to the physical and mental health harm of claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“Last year the Equality Watchdog, The Equality and Human Rights Commission, issued a Section 23 order against the Department of Work and Pensions over their discriminatory treatment of disabled claimants.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Government itself has effectively acknowledged a different approach is needed when they announced that they would abolition the Work Capability Assessments, something I have been calling for years, but the detail of the future process is too opaque and doesn’t provide reassurance. Given it will take place several years to replace, what happens until then?</em></p>
<p><em>“I remain deeply concerned about these health assessments but also about the punitive nature of the sanctions regime, introduced in 2012 and, once again, on the rise. </em></p>
<p><em>“I believe it is these social security policies, as well as the inadequacy of the social security support especially for working age people, and the dehumanising culture that claimants too often experience that collectively contribute to the adverse health effects is the It is so detrimental to vulnerable people especially, but to all people as well.</em></p>
<p><em>“Given the failure of the Government to make many of the changes recommended in our predecessor Committee in 2018, I hold little hope in them taking on board the improvements set out in the report.”</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7098</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
    <category term="Department for Work and Pensions"/>
    <category term="Health Assessment"/>
    <category term="Social Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bexleyheath Branch host Spring Lunch at The Boathouse </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/bexleyheath-branch-host-spring-lunch-boathouse" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">On Sunday 23rd April, Bexleyheath Branch of the Bexleyheath &amp; Crayford Conservative Association hosted a Spring Lunch at the Boathouse, Danson Park.  The event was organised by the Ward Chairman, Maureen King and Association Deputy Chairman (Membership &amp; Fundraising), Janet Power. 
The…</content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/bexleyheath-branch-host-spring-lunch-boathouse</id>
    <published>2023-04-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update on a few local matters.</p>
<p>First of all, for those of you intending to vote in the local elections in May, a reminder if you did not know, that you will need to take photo ID with you to the polling station. This is part of a new approach to avoid people impersonating someone else by voting in their name.</p>
<p>There are details on Council websites for Epsom and Ewell, Mole Valley and Reigate and Banstead and what to do if you do not have a suitable form of ID.</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.epsom-ewell.gov.uk/council/elections-and-voting/voter-id-elections</a></p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.molevalley.gov.uk</a></p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.reigate-banstead.gov.uk</a></p>
<h2>Stoneleigh Railway Crossing</h2>
<p>For those of you living in the Stoneleigh area, work is due to start soon on the new step free crossing over the railway at the station. I hope this will make things much easier for people with mobility issues, not to mention small children in buggies or heavy shopping bags.</p>
<p>This is a timetable for the planned work.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6424" src="http://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-1024x664.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="664" srcset="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-200x130.jpg 200w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-400x259.jpg 400w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-600x389.jpg 600w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-768x498.jpg 768w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-800x519.jpg 800w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-1024x664.jpg 1024w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable.jpg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<h2>One Day Travel Cards</h2>
<p>Transport for London has just announced that it is planning to scrap paper one day travelcards from outside London, which is likely to affect many people in our area. I will be lodging an objection to this, particularly as it is happening at the same time as the proposed ULEZ. If you want to find out more, they have published details at</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://haveyoursay.tfl.gov.uk/travelcards">https://haveyoursay.tfl.gov.uk/travelcards</a></p>
<p>Although the feedback form on this site is pretty limited, I would encourage you to share any opinions about the proposal via the link.</p>
<h2>Veterans Group</h2>
<p>In the last bulletin I gave you details of the support for veterans in Epsom and Ewell. I have been asked to remind those living in Mole Valley about the veterans hub for those living in the district, which is also providing valuable support locally. You can find out all the details at</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.molevalleyveteranshub.co.uk/">https://www.molevalleyveteranshub.co.uk/</a></p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris Grayling</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update on a few local matters. First of all, for those of you intending to vote in the local elections in May, a reminder if you did not know, that you will need to take photo ID with you to the polling station. This is part [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6425</id>
    <published>2023-04-21T19:38:42Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-21T19:38:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alcohol Labelling]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/04/26/alcohol-labelling/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1772</id>
		<updated>2023-04-21T08:25:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-04-26T08:24:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="alcohol"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="public health"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/04/26/alcohol-labelling/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>St Helens Mobile Pantry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2023/04/18/st-helens-mobile-pantry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7624</id>
    <published>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes school debaters to Downing Street</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/03/29/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-school-debaters-to-downing-street/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament before their visit to Number Ten. The day was rounded off by a Q&amp;amp;A session with Matt and the competition judges as well as guests from Parliament including House of Commons Library Director of Research Edward Wood. The panel passed on their careers advice as well as explaining some of the opportunities available in politics besides being an MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4189 aligncenter" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the visit &lt;strong&gt;Matt Warman MP commented&lt;/strong&gt; ‘I was keen to establish a debating competition to encourage students to think deeply about some of the issues facing our society and, crucially, to equip them with the skills to consider both sides of a complex argument. Today’s visit to the home of modern democracy was an excellent opportunity to see those skills in action with students having the chance to observe opposition MPs challenging Ministers at the despatch box. I look forward to next year’s programme and on a broader note, am always happy to welcome schools in my constituency to Parliament.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chair of Governors at Boston High School Lisa Smith&lt;/strong&gt; who accompanied the visit said ‘This was a wonderful opportunity for our students to see democracy in action – and to be inspired by the opportunities for careers in parliament. We are grateful to Matt for arranging the debate competition and the visit and look forward to defending our winner’s trophy next year!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4187 alignnone" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-768x576.png 768w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4188 alignright" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4186</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on new sanctions on Burmese Military</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_new_sanctions_on_burmese_military" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
          <strong>The UK Government has announced new sanctions targeting companies supplying aviation fuel, arms and aircraft parts to the Burmese military, after similar sanctions were announced in the US this month. Following the announcement, Rushanara Ali MP said:</strong>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_new_sanctions_on_burmese_military</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T09:44:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T09:44:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The truth about protecting our waterways</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/truth-about-protecting-our-waterways" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In contrast to misleading and false assertions made recently, the simple truth is that this Conservative Government is the first to set out our expectation that water companies must take steps to significantly reduce storm overflows. We are now delivering the largest programme to tackle storm…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/truth-about-protecting-our-waterways</id>
    <published>2023-01-27T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="pbs-main-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=cGuQG1-C" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6476bf0512bd1" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6476bf0512bd1').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6476bf0512bd1","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6476bf0512bd1" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6476bf0512bd1" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6476bf0512bd1" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6476bf0512bd1" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6476bf0512bd1" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6476bf0512bd1" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6476bf0512bd1" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6476bf0512bd1" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6476bf0512bd1" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6476bf0512bd1_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6476bf0512bd1 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dy-absVWd1kK9J1MMXUMDHLaM8YvBuPbjC2__3gEZOoXpS_ttEQbcskv7DsngNXg0MAcmrcLDi0-x5ocbWQsg' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>2</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
