<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-07-17T09:28:55Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Why we need growth to cut the deficit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/07/17/why-we-need-growth-to-cut-the-deficit/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Let me have another go at explaining the importance of growth  to all those who follow the Treasury/OBR static model. They  say we need to raise a tax every time we spend some more money. They miss the dynamics of growth bringing more  tax revenues and the dangers of higher tax rates slowing growth and cutting them.</p>
<p>In Budget 2021 the Treasury said the deficit for 2021-2 would be £233.9bn. They used this and related forecasts to insist on tax rises for the following year to bring it down. The outturn as reported in Spring Statement 2022 was a deficit of £127.8bn for 2021-2 . So they exaggerated the deficit by £106.9bn . They had made a similar error of overstating the deficit the previous year.</p>
<p>The main reason they got the deficit wrong was they underestimated growth in revenue. The HMRC reported that in 2021-2 total tax revenue rose by a massive 22.9%, far more than the OBR/Treasury model expected. Tax revenue is very sensitive to the growth rate, which outperformed their forecast. They had not put up tax rates that year.</p>
<p>The danger is the OBR/Treasury will lurch from greatly overstating the deficit to understating it as the economy is slowed by higher tax rates, the cost of living squeeze and the monetary tightening now underway. The paradox they need to grasp is higher tax rates could slow growth and so damage the natural growth in tax receipts which you get from a growing economy with a bit of inflation.</p>
<p>The government does need to rein in waste and less necessary spending, but it also needs to promote growth to get fast expanding revenues. 2021-22 shows us that fast growth can come with maintained tax rates and selective tax cuts, clearly assisted by the end of lockdowns. Slow growth or no growth comes from hiking taxes too high, making it more difficult to get the deficit down.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Let me have another go at explaining the importance of growth  to all those who follow the Treasury/OBR static model. They  say we need to raise a tax every time we spend some more money. They miss the dynamics of growth bringing more  tax revenues and the dangers of higher tax rates slowing growth and…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33114</id>
    <published>2022-07-17T04:06:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-17T04:06:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up 15 July 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/15/weekly-round-up-15-july-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-15-july-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="fb-root"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics right now is in turmoil because of the utter mess that the Conservative Party is in. Following last week’s drama of the Prime Minister resigning we now are forced to watch Tory MPs having a public slanging match over who should next wear their crown and become Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with them running the country into the ground: watching the public realm becoming tatty and underinvested. Then they realise the mess they’ve got themselves into so start to blame everyone around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come the 5 September we will know who Conservative Party members have elected as their leader and by extension our next Prime Minister.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Labour tried to hold a vote of no confidence in the Prime Minister and Government this week only for it to be blocked by Boris Johnson. This goes against the convention that all no confidence motions tabled by Her Majesty’s Loyal Opposition are accepted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a bizarre twist the Government then tabled their own no confidence motion for next week. I will be voting to have no confidence in this utter shower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of all these shenanigans I continued to do what MPs should be doing: holding the Government to account and putting forward alternative plans. The week started off with a speech at the Future of Social Care Workforce event in Parliament. I spoke about Labour’s plan for the future of care to ensure care workers get better pay, terms and conditions and full rights at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also a pleasure to meet children from local schools in Parliament. Not only does Parliament provide excellent tours, but they also ensure schools have tailor-made lessons in the world-class education centre. I joined them for three in-depth Q&amp;amp;A session about my job and the place I work. I can tell you for free that they were some stars of the future in that room!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday saw me attending the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee. Sir John Major – former Prime Minister – was our witness and I grilled him on the Government’s action on the Northern Ireland protocol, if it’s alright for governments to take illegal action knowingly and standards in public life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unison held an event in Parliament this week and I spoke as the Shadow Care Minister about Labour’s plans for social care. For me, the most important issue of care is making sure we acknowledge – and legislate – with one key fact in mind: the majority of care responsibility falls to women. If we fail to address this issue, we fail to support carers and those in receipt of care. I also talked about how levelling up is not being pushed within the care agenda and this is to the detriment of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I visited the new Hartcliffe Way Refuse and Recycling Centre with Cllr. Kye Dudd, Cabinet Member for Climate, Ecology, Waste and Energy. So important that we increase recycling in Bristol and this new centre will help us do just this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished off the week with my annual ‘Money Matters’ event at St. Augustine’s Church. This was great event helping people with the cost-of-living crisis. Thank you to all that came and supported this important event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575.&lt;/p&gt;The post &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/15/weekly-round-up-15-july-2022/"&gt;Weekly Round-Up 15 July 2022&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com"&gt;Karin Smyth&lt;/a&gt;.</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Politics right now is in turmoil because of the utter mess that the Conservative Party is in. Following last week’s […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/15/weekly-round-up-15-july-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 15 July 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3309</id>
    <published>2022-07-15T14:17:01Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-15T14:17:01Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins shows his support for people living with arthritis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/15/toby-perkins-shows-his-support-for-people-living-with-arthritis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/15/toby-perkins-shows-his-support-for-people-living-with-arthritis/">Toby Perkins shows his support for people living with arthritis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/15/toby-perkins-shows-his-support-for-people-living-with-arthritis/">Toby Perkins shows his support for people living with arthritis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5057</id>
    <published>2022-07-15T11:55:05Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-15T11:55:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John speaks with GBNews about why he is backing Penny Mordaunt to be the next PM]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/14/john-speaks-with-gbnews-about-why-he-is-backing-penny-mordaunt-to-be-the-next-pm/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5457</id>
		<updated>2022-07-14T13:49:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-07-14T07:47:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/14/john-speaks-with-gbnews-about-why-he-is-backing-penny-mordaunt-to-be-the-next-pm/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/2674-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">On Monday, the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Restorative Justice (RJ) held its AGM and I was honoured to be re-elected as vice-chair. Elliot Colburn MP was re-elected as chair, and I look forward to working with Elliot to complete our evidence collecting sessions which will form the basis of our report into the current state of RJ in the UK.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The business in the Chamber was the Northern Ireland Troubles (Legacy and Restoration) Bill Committee Stage which was debated for 6 hours. There were multiple votes from 8.12pm on opposition and Government amendments and clauses.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Labour voted for amendment 116 to stop disclosure of existing inquests into Troubles Deaths, and lost by 211 to 282 votes. And voted for amendment 114, to stop anyone given immunity from profiting from it, and lost by 209 by 282 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Labour voted against Government clause 39 which sets out the new process for Inquests, Investigations and Inquires, and lost by 211 votes to 282.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Labour voted against DUP New Clause 5 if a person is granted immunity from prosecution but later evidence is submitted which is conclusive evidence that the person’s account was not true, and it fell by 218 to 282 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Labour voted against DUP New Clause 4 which aimed to make receiving immunity an aggravating factor in sentencing for the offence of glorifying terrorism, and it fell by 220 to 283 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Labour voted against 3rd Reading, but it was passed by 217 to 282 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Draft Slavery and Human Trafficking (Definition of Victim) Regulations 2022 was taken in deferred division and we lost the final vote of the night by 217 to 282 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Tuesday morning I dropped into the River Bathing Waters event hosted by Surfers Against Sewage. They believe that there’s a strong case for designating 200 inland bathing waters by 2030, and call for the UK Government to focus on inland bathing waters in its Storm Overflow Action Plan. Only 14% of UK rivers reach good ecological status and none reach good chemical status. One of the major sources of pollution is sewage, and over 90% of all sewer outflows in England and Wales flow directly into rivers and seas with, 372,533 recorded instances. There is increasing popularity amongst the public for using inland blue spaces for swimming, paddling, kayaking, and more, there is a serious threat of people becoming ill. Polling by Surfers Against Sewage found that one in six have tried wild water swimming and 55% have become ill. And 52% are afraid of wild water swimming because they do not know whether the water will be clean. The campaign is encouraging local communities to apply to Government agencies for Bathing Water Designation of their wild waters.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a Labour and Co-operative MP, I attended the launch of the Co-op UK social mobility impact report with society Group Chief Executive Officer of Co-op UK Shirine Khoury-Haq, hosted by Jim McMahon MP, chair of the UK Co-operative Party and Shadow Secretary of State for Environment, Food and Rural Affairs. Since stepping down as an MP in 2019, Justine Greening has set up the Purpose Coalition which brings together organisations from across the country who are committed to making changes in order to boost social mobility and improve equality of opportunity. The coalition includes Adecco and Sage, BBC, Channel 4, NHS Trusts, over 20 Universities, including the University of Wales, and the Co-op Group. The report sets out the Co-op Group’s ambition to improve access to opportunities through apprenticeships, its academies, its transition from education to employment, and diversity reporting.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the weekly meeting of the Petitions Committee to discuss the petitions that have reached the threshold of 100,000 signatures required, and to schedule them to be debated at our usual Monday night Westminster Hall slot. Next Monday at 4.30pm petition 602285, relating to the use of real bearskins by the Queens Guards will be debated, followed at 6pm by petition 597171, hunting dolphins and whales in the Faroe Islands.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined the PCS Zoom call for an update on proposed staffing cuts and poor pay awards to civil servants in all Government departments across the UK, and how this will affect delivery of benefits, passport applications, asylum applications, and the border forces. We heard of proposed closures to DWP offices across the UK and the proposed voluntary redundancy scheme. But the work for civil servants in all departments has increased due to the cost of living crisis, which may result in UK Government outsourcing and using agency workers. The pay levels are so poor that many workers are getting jobs in Amazon, where the pay is better, and less stress. Some civil servants are in receipt of Universal Credit, and do not want to work overtime because their UC is then taken away. The PCS estimate that there are over 300,000 people waiting for PIP payments. The PCS have tried to engage UK Government in pay talks but the UK Government will not meet with them.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Wednesday morning I dropped into the Citizens Advice Bureau Cost of Living event to discuss how the Tory cost of living crisis is impacting on the people of Neath. Since October 2021, CAB has helped 573 people in Neath with cost-of-living issues. There is a 101% increase in people in Neath who say they cannot afford the increase in energy bills after April’s price increase, even after cutting back on other essential spending. The CAB have 3 key asks for the UK Government to get money into people’s pockets now, rather than later:</p>
<ul>
<li>Insulate households from record energy bills in the long term.</li>
<li>Encouraging action to crackdown on companies overcharging customers.</li>
<li>Maximise the support that the U.K. Government can already offer.</li>
</ul>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I am a huge supporter of CAB and have hosted a room in my office for CAB Cymru Swansea Neath Port Talbot for many years.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Then I attended the Royal Mail/CWU event as part of Dog Awareness Week. Dog attacks remain a hazard for postal workers across the UK, and the trend shows an increase as deliveries have increased after Covid. The objectives of the event is to remind the public to be aware of their responsibilities as a responsible dog owner, and remind post workers not to drop their guard and be alert and vigilant as they deliver to 30 million UK addresses daily. I met Dave Joyce, National Health and Safety Officer, CWU, who told me that there were 33,000 attacks on postal workers in the last 10 years, 6 every day, 450 dog bites through letter boxes, 80% take place at the front door or on the footpath or drive. Dog attacks costs the NHS £75 million a year.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Then I rushed to the Chamber in time for Welsh Questions and was fortunate to be called by the Speaker. I asked the Secretary of State for Wales, Simon Hart MP….”<em>The Global Centre of Rail Excellence being developed in Onllwyn, Neath, will become the first and the only rail infrastructure testing facility in the UK. It recently secured a Memorandum of Understanding with the Association of American Railroads subsidiary, US Venture MxVRail, to work together to advance global rail research and technology. The Welsh Government has provided £50 million, when will the UK Government provide the £30 million it promised so that this world class rail facility can be completed by 2025.</em>” The answer from Mr Hart was very disappointing as usual. He resigned from the cabinet later this evening. In his letter of resignation he said “Colleagues have done their upmost (sic) in private and in public to help you turn the ship around but it is with sadness that I feel that we are past the point where this is possible” He has been Secretary of State since taking over from Alun Cairns in November 2019.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">At the AGM of the APPG for Hairdressing, Barbering and Cosmetology I was delighted to be re-elected as chair. Keith Conniford, Registrar of the Hair Council, gave an update of the ongoing problems affecting the sector following Covid and the cost of living crisis. We shall continue to campaign for mandatory registration of practitioners in the hair sector, which we have been lobbying UK Government Ministers to implement by amending the Hair Act 1964, but so far they have not acted.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I had the pleasure of meeting Jenny Hopkins, Chief Crown Prosecutor of CPS Cymru-Wales, and we discussed her responsibilities which includes: carrying out prosecutions, setting and maintaining professional ethical standards, representing the CPS locally, contributing to national strategy and policy, and ensuring effective employee relations. CPS Cymru-Wales employees 280 members of staff – lawyers, paralegals, and administrators, in a range of locations in Wales, with three main offices in Mold, Cardiff and Swansea – and its duty is to prosecute the right people for the right offences. Jenny is supported by Deputy Crown Prosecutors Deborah Rogers, and Hugh Rogers, and Area Business Manager Mike Grist. Jenny has faced reductions in MOJ funding, court closures, backlog of cases listed for trial, and lack of judges to hear the trials. I look forward to working with Jenny in the future.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The business in the Chamber was the continuation of Estimates Debates. This afternoon was a debate on Education, followed by International Trade. There were no divisions at the end of the day.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Thursday morning I chaired the Fifth Delegated Legislation Committee in respect of the Draft Police Act 1996 (Amendment and Consequential Amendments) Regulations 2022. Under the provisions of section 31A of the Act, the Secretary of State may, by regulation, amend any name of a police area specified in Schedule 1. This Instrument will change the name of Hampshire Police Area to Hampshire and the Isle of Wight, following the request from the Police and Crime Commissioner. And replaces the name in articles 34 and 35 of the PCC elections order 2012. UK Government Minister Kit Malthouse moved the Motion and said that this would be his final act as Police Minister. The Motion was passed unopposed.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">A short time later, it was announced that Kit Malthouse was appointed to a new role as Chancellor of the Duchy of Lancaster.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Friday I visited Vortex, who have their offices and laboratory in the old Metal Box in Milland Road. I learned about the futuristic technology that they are developing to measure air pollution and met the directors and their staff, most of whom live locally.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Saturday, I was honoured to be at the opening of the constituency office of my friend and colleague Beth Winter MP for Cynon Valley. I met many old friends that I hadn’t seen since before lockdown, and I was encouraged to make many new friends. Beth’s office is well positioned on the high street in Aberdare and was opened by the First Minister Mark Drakeford. After the opening we visited the adjacent refurbished St Elvan’s church, which has a community cafe, to see the amazing display of recycled metal sculptures, including a massive red dragon called Gareth, made from old tv-dishes, and paper dragon hand puppets made by local primary schools.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On Sunday I attended my church St David’s in Neath to welcome our new deacon, the Reverend Lizzie Tremble who, with the help of our wonderful Reverend Norman Lea, conducted the Seafarers Service to pray for those who work on the sea throughout the world.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday, the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Restorative Justice (RJ) held its AGM and I was honoured to be re-elected as vice-chair. Elliot Colburn MP was re-elected as chair, and I look forward to working with Elliot to complete our evidence collecting sessions which will form the basis of our report into the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2674</id>
    <published>2022-07-13T16:16:53Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-13T16:16:53Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back the Track Walk!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/back-the-track-walk/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track.</p>
<p>In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which the team have been working on and to see the aqueduct where bridge repairs are being undertaken.</p>
<p>The ‘Back the Track’ team of volunteers continue to do a fantastic job locally and it is good to see the Mclean Way being used and enjoyed by so many.</p>
<p>I really enjoyed the walk and chat. Thank you.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track. In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4232</id>
    <published>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This morning we were notified by government that they are minded to appoint 
commissioners to oversee some parts of the City Council. The appointment of 
commissioners would be unjustified, and an attack on our local democracy. Under 
new leadership, Nottingham Labour have been making progress, being open about 
the difficulties we face and working hard to put things right. We have worked with the 
government appointed Improvement and Assurance Board to address all their 
concerns and they have reported positively to Government about our progress.</p>



<p>This work has resulted in the reduction in council debt, a transformation plan that will 
save the council £45m and improve services for Nottingham people. We have set a 
four year balanced budget, and have changed the culture and governance so that 
issues like the HRA are uncovered, shared transparently and sorted. The Council 
under the current leadership has made significant changes to the way it works, is 
open about the issues we face and is determined to get things right and this has 
been recognised by the Improvement and Assurance Board.</p>



<p>The Improvement and Assurance Board, headed by Sir Tony Redmond – the former 
Local Government Ombudsman – have described our progress positively to 
government and reported on our determination to succeed, so we are asking 
government what additional change they expect to achieve by bringing in people 
who know nothing of the City and our residents’ needs. Although we oppose the 
Governments’ intention to appoint commissioners the continuity provided by Sir Tony 
Redmond provides some assurance that our previous improvements are understood 
and can be built on.</p>



<p>But, we are asking what new actions would happen as a result of 
commissioners coming in that would improve the working of this council, or 
result in any changes that Nottingham people would want. We will use our 
opportunity to respond to this proposal from Government to ask these 
questions.</p>



<p>If it is the case that the government does take this action, this will be based 
not on what is best for the city, but what is best for the Conservative Party.</p>



<p>We will of course work positively and openly with commissioners, as we have with 
the Improvement and Assurance Board in the best interests of our city, but we will be 
straight with them, and straight with Nottingham people and will continue to fight for 
what Nottingham people need and have elected a Labour council to do.</p>



<p>The government cuts to our budgets means that it is more difficult to do everything 
we want to do to help our communities at this time but we have been fighting for 
Nottingham and protecting our services against the worst effects of Tory cuts. We 
made sure that Nottingham City Council – and our amazing staff – were there for you 
during the Covid crisis and we fought hard to get what we needed for our city to help 
keep people safe.</p>



<p>After more than a decade of Tory austerity – and the pandemic – we have managed  to set a four year balanced budget. This has not been easy, but Nottingham Labour:                                                                     Has retained 75 community protection officers                                                                                                     Are still building council houses and have improved private rented housing  through our licensing scheme                                                                                                                                                                        Has kept ownership of our outstanding care homes                                                                                                    Is still running six leisure centres                                                                                                                                 Is supporting Welfare Rights advice services across the city because we  defend what is needed by Nottingham people.</p>



<p>We are still supporting free events for families all year round, and you can still expect 
a regular bus service to get you there from our award winning city owned bus 
company. We have our own bus company because Labour protected it, when many 
others were sold off to private operators and they are now seeing more cancelled 
services and far higher fares. We invested in a tram that brings good jobs to the city 
and gets people to them. Our great public transport system has contributed to 
cleaner air than other cities in the UK and made people less reliant on a car.</p>



<p>The transformation of the Broadmarsh is underway after the shopping centre 
operator went into administration, a new central library will soon be fitted out, a green 
space in the heart of our city will be created and new developments creating jobs 
and homes will be coming in the next few years.</p>



<p>We are a city of hardworking people and Nottingham deserves better than 
intervention from an out of touch Tory government that is more concerned with 
protecting the profits of the energy companies than the people who can’t heat their 
homes or struggle to feed their families. We understand what twelve years of Tory 
austerity and now the cost of living crisis means to you, because we do not just 
represent our communities, we are part of them. We will carry on fighting for what 
Nottingham needs and will still be ready to help with the problems you are facing, or 
hear your views and hopes for the city.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/">Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This morning we were notified by government that they are minded to appoint<br/>
commissioners to oversee some parts of the City Council. The appointment of<br/>
commissioners would be unjustified, and an attack on our local democracy. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/">Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Aitken</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2731</id>
    <published>2022-06-23T13:32:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-23T13:32:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Government Finance"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="transport"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This week is #BikeWeek 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/06/09/this-week-is-bikeweek-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7430</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T16:00:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T16:00:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/april-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5551" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for April 2022</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for April 2022</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5550</id>
    <published>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dwuUilFXVFPpKwvW4ffhQknuGxQKZrqE9jSSm9OlXU_-AAL3D5d28qriDxsPVVAUyc1ZlRfkFWjwzaMyKvKvw' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
