<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-07-12T12:34:51Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>GUEST BLOG: Work experience student, Eve Hemingway, gives her view on the Government’s decision to exclude transgender people from the ban on conversion therapy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/12/guest-blog-work-experience-student-eve-hemingway-gives-her-view-on-the-governments-decision-to-exclude-transgender-people-from-the-ban-on-conversion-therapy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/12/guest-blog-work-experience-student-eve-hemingway-gives-her-view-on-the-governments-decision-to-exclude-transgender-people-from-the-ban-on-conversion-therapy/">GUEST BLOG: Work experience student, Eve Hemingway, gives her view on the Government’s decision to exclude transgender people from the ban on conversion therapy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/07/12/guest-blog-work-experience-student-eve-hemingway-gives-her-view-on-the-governments-decision-to-exclude-transgender-people-from-the-ban-on-conversion-therapy/">GUEST BLOG: Work experience student, Eve Hemingway, gives her view on the Government’s decision to exclude transgender people from the ban on conversion therapy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5053</id>
    <published>2022-07-12T10:53:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-12T10:53:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Electing a leader</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/07/12/electing-a-leader/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>There are many considerations in choosing a candidate to vote for. I see some on this site have already written off the full slate of 12 possible candidates. You need to live in the real world. The new PM will be an existing Conservative MP. The 12 include people with a wide range of talents and past successes and each would bring something different to the role. Choice involves compromise. No one gets everything they want in an ideal leader, or everything they support in the leader’s programme. We are choosing someone who needs to be right for the nation,  not just for us.</p>
<p>The assessment is a mixture of issues. Does the person broadly support the values you like? Do they have an outline programme of action to carry through those values? Does their past demonstrate an ability to overcome obstacles to seeing through important changes? Would they be able to earn the loyalty of enough support, and would they be confident enough to recruit a talented team of Ministers? Will enough of the public like or respect them?</p>
<p>The ability to communicate and carry people with them is important. It is no good having a good programme or great ideas if you cannot get elected to the leadership role or if you lack public support to retain office. Reading the public mood and making the right advances at the right time is a crucial leader’s skill.</p>
<p>It will be a demonstration of leadership skill to emerge victorious from this crowded field. It is important the MPs present two candidates to the membership and that both agree to fight a good campaign to give members a clear choice. It will be a test of character and political skill as well as a judgement on two competing programmes.</p>
<p>The truth is a lot is potentially up for change and that could be a good thing. The other truth is the unelected governing establishment will be looking to circumscribe or control an incoming Prime Minister. Some of them  see it as an opportunity to bin work on The Northern Ireland Protocol, human rights law reform, controlling our own borders, setting our own VAT and using the freedoms of Brexit.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There are many considerations in choosing a candidate to vote for. I see some on this site have already written off the full slate of 12 possible candidates. You need to live in the real world. The new PM will be an existing Conservative MP. The 12 include people with a wide range of talents…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=33080</id>
    <published>2022-07-12T04:05:36Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-12T04:05:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John contributes to a debate on the British Energy Strategy in Westminster Hall]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/06/john-contributes-to-a-debate-on-the-british-energy-strategy-in-westminster-hall%ef%bf%bc/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5447</id>
		<updated>2022-07-08T14:39:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-07-06T18:34:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/07/06/john-contributes-to-a-debate-on-the-british-energy-strategy-in-westminster-hall%ef%bf%bc/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Karin Smyth MP calls for a workforce plan to address staff shortages across the NHS and improve waiting times</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/08/karin-smyth-mp-calls-for-a-workforce-plan-to-address-staff-shortages-across-the-nhs-and-improve-waiting-times/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=karin-smyth-mp-calls-for-a-workforce-plan-to-address-staff-shortages-across-the-nhs-and-improve-waiting-times" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="fb-root"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has called for a workforce plan to address shortages in emergency care and across the whole NHS in a Westminster Hall debate on ambulance waiting times this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karin Smyth referred to the shocking waiting times being experienced by people across the NHS.  The average response time for an ambulance call out for a stroke or suspected heart attack is 51 minutes 22 seconds, whilst the target is 18 minutes.  There are cases of people waiting in agony on the road for an ambulance for more than 5 hours, and last winter 89.8% more ambulances than the previous year experienced delays of 30 minutes or more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At present, the Government has a total lack of plan to address workforce vacancies in social care.  Whilst there are such extreme staff shortages in the social care system, people who are medically fit enough to be discharged remain in hospital, taking up valuable bed space for new emergency arrivals who are left waiting in ambulances outside ER departments.  On a weekly basis, an average of 11,656 patients remained in hospital who no longer met the criteria to reside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These pressures in hospitals discharging are directly impacting waiting times in emergency departments, putting staff under pressure and patients in danger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, said: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Emergency department staff and paramedics show incredible courage and quick thinking on a daily basis.  They need more support from the Government, and a proper workforce plan that will address the staff shortages across the NHS and social care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Twelve years of austerity have led to an appalling state of affairs when it comes to waiting times in the health service, and the Government is not doing enough to address the crux of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Discharges from hospitals must be improved, and our social care system must be fit for purpose before we can resolve the issues at the front of the hospital.  To do this we need to see a comprehensive workforce plan and social care plan from the Government. The Government’s so-called ‘fix’ for social care is not due to come until October 2023.  This is too late and not a fix at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I will continue to press the Government to take action to alleviate pressures across the car system, from emergency departments to social care.  There is no quick fix, but if the Government is serious about improving waiting times they must look at the system as a whole.”&lt;/p&gt;The post &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/08/karin-smyth-mp-calls-for-a-workforce-plan-to-address-staff-shortages-across-the-nhs-and-improve-waiting-times/"&gt;Karin Smyth MP calls for a workforce plan to address staff shortages across the NHS and improve waiting times&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="http://karinsmyth.com"&gt;Karin Smyth&lt;/a&gt;.</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has called for a workforce plan to address shortages in emergency care and across […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/07/08/karin-smyth-mp-calls-for-a-workforce-plan-to-address-staff-shortages-across-the-nhs-and-improve-waiting-times/">Karin Smyth MP calls for a workforce plan to address staff shortages across the NHS and improve waiting times</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3305</id>
    <published>2022-07-08T12:33:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T12:33:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Back the Track Walk!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/back-the-track-walk/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track.</p>
<p>In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which the team have been working on and to see the aqueduct where bridge repairs are being undertaken.</p>
<p>The ‘Back the Track’ team of volunteers continue to do a fantastic job locally and it is good to see the Mclean Way being used and enjoyed by so many.</p>
<p>I really enjoyed the walk and chat. Thank you.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It’s always good to catch up with Brian and the team of ‘Back the Track’ volunteers. Last week I met up with them for a walk along the Mclean Way to see the great progress being made on the Track. In particular, it was good to see the map of track walks and connections which […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4232</id>
    <published>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T11:00:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-79/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Monday afternoon, as vice-chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Restorative Justice, I hosted the APPG Restorative Justice Evidence Session, together with Jim Simon, CEO of the Restorative Justice Council. We heard evidence from restorative justice projects within schools and healthcare sectors in England. Catherine Allard Headteacher of John Keble Primary School spoke about implementing restorative measures to change the culture in her school. Her school is in a very deprived, multicultural part of London. She said that choosing the staff leadership team was very important, and was essential so that children who are bullied or conduct the bullying are able to open up about their experiences and trust her staff. The support of parents and a multi-agency service was vital to the successful implementation of her project. The children go through the restorative script with staff and try and resolve the issues that are affecting their behaviour towards each other in school. Before restorative action was taken, there were many pupils excluded from school, but when Catherine became headteacher she was determined that her school would become inclusive. We heard from Simon Flowers, headteacher of Car Manor Community School, which has pupils from 4-19 years of age. Simon became headteacher in 2005 and grew up in the locality. When he took over, the school was a third full, with children with very complex needs. He decided to never permanently exclude a pupil and the values in school would be relationship led. He now has 700 children who meet in coaching groups of 8-10 pupils, of mixed age and gender. They meet every Monday, Wednesday and Friday, for 45 minutes, and sit in a circle to discuss the issues that are effecting them. Staff have coaching groups too. The groups self-regulate and make positive choices to improve their behaviour. The older pupils guide the younger to change their mindset to be tolerant and kind towards each other. It’s a family culture. The aim is to produce happy, mature, well-rounded children who progress to colleges or jobs. Feedback shows that this is being achieved. Now his school is oversubscribed and 35 of the 100 staff are alumni. Staff and pupil absences are very low.</p>
<p>We heard from Janine Carroll of Resolve, and Dan Reisel from University College London (UCL) who teamed up to implement restorative practices in maternity care. Janine is a training provider, and Dan works in maternity in the Royal Free Hospital and researches at UCL. Janine looked at relationships in a healthcare setting, and it’s about patients and workers being heard, empowered, and their needs met. Dan looked at the blame culture that has developed when maternity care goes wrong, and changing this to resolve patient and staff traumatic experiences, rather than litigate.</p>
<p>Our final witness was from the social care sector, Rebecca Rushton, who has worked in restorative justice in the childcare and families department for Torbay Council since February 2021. Rebecca comes from a criminal justice background where she implemented restorative practice into many sectors of the justice sector. Rebecca’s role is to embed the golden thread of restorative practice throughout the department. All new staff are trained in restorative practice, and partner organisations are trained too. Ofstead has produced a good report, and Rebecca hopes to continue restorative practice throughout all council departments with the assistance of the Chief Executive and councillors who have been very supportive.</p>
<p>The business in the chamber was Second Reading of the High Speed Rail (Crewe to Manchester) Bill and Labour abstained on the division.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, I chaired the Online Safety Bill Committee all day, when we continued line by line scrutiny and debated many more amendments which were tabled by the UK Government and Labour and SNP opposition parties.</p>
<p>The business in the chamber was the Official Opposition Day debates. The first debate was “Access to GP Services and NHS Dentists”. The second debate was “Replacing the Prime Minister’s Ethics Adviser (Cabinet Office)”. Lord Geidt resigned unexpectedly on Wednesday 15th June in a letter to the PM, in which he said that he had been asked to consider “measures which risk a deliberate and purposeful breech of the Ministerial Code” and he could not have any part in an action that would make a mockery of the Code. Labour’s Motion would amend the Standing Orders to say that if the Independent Adviser post is vacant for more than two months, the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee (PACAC) can appoint its own independent adviser on Ministerial Code breeches and begin its own investigation. Labour pressed a vote at the end of the debate at 6.47pm, which we lost by 161 to 252 votes.</p>
<p>The business in the chamber on Wednesday was Northern Ireland Oral Questions followed by PMQs and the Social Security (Additional Payments) Bill All Stages. The Chancellor announced his Cost of Living Package on 26th May, and this included: £650 cost of living payments, payable in two instalments to people in receipt of means-tested benefits such as Universal Credit; and a £150 Disability cost of living payment for those receiving non-means-tested disability benefits such as PIP. The UK Government recently changed the rules on the Warm Homes Discount (WHD) scheme so that those on DLA, PIP and AA are no longer eligible. For people on PIP this means that the UK Government are giving the £150 back to them that was taken off due to changes in the WHD scheme.</p>
<p>There was a deferred division on the Abortion (Northern Ireland) Regulations 2022 SI 2022 No 554, which was voted through by 215 to 70 votes.</p>
<p>APPG Sport, of which I am chair, held an online event during National School Sports Week 2022 to discuss the future of maximising PE and sport in schools for the benefit of children and young people in England. Baroness Tanni Grey-Thompson, vice chair of our APPG, and Honorary Life Ambassador for Youth Sport Trust was on the call. Over 50 sports stakeholders joined in the call to listen to guest speakers: Ali Oliver MBE, Chief Executive of Youth Sports Trust; Stephanie Hilborne, Chief Executive Women in Sport; Ashlea Smith, Head of Children, Young People and Families, UKactive; and Leigh Thompson, Head of Policy, Sport and Recreation Alliance. There was a lively session of questions from the stakeholders to the panellists, which culminated in agreement that sport is so important to the physical and mental health of children of all ages, and school sport is vital in this development.</p>
<p>On Monday 27th June I chaired the Petitions Debate in Westminster Hall “That this House has considered E-petition 597715 relating to the school week”, which was opened by the chair of the Petitions Committee, Catherine McKinnell MP. The petition “required to make Friday part of the school weekend, require schools to make Friday a day off, meaning there will be three days that children will get to stay off every week. Children can have a lot of stress at school due to exams and homework and with a 3 day weekend, children could have a longer time to relax and let off stress gained from school.”</p>
<p>The UK Government response provided on 21st April 2022, stated that it has no plans to require schools to make Friday part of the weekend and that regular attendance at school is vital for children’s education, well-being and long-term development.</p>
<p>I was honoured to listen to Reverend Professor D. Ben Rees speak about his fascinating book about Jim Griffiths, the former MP for Llanelli, titled “Jim: the life and work of Rt Hon James Griffiths”. The evening was opened by Lord John Morris, whose time as the former MP for Aberavon overlapped with Jim and he shared his memories of the great man. Jim was Minister for National Insurance in the 1945 Labour Government and founded the modern welfare state. Jim persuaded the then Labour Leader Hugh Gaitskill to build relationships towards Welsh devolution and Jim was known as the “architect of devolution”. The event was hosted by the current MP for Llanelli, Dame Nia Griffith.</p>
<p>On Monday evening at 10pm Labour voted against the Second Reading of the Northern Ireland Protocol Bill which had been debated for six hours in the chamber. The Bill was introduced on 13th June and is in response to the UK Government’s concerns over the Protocol (special arrangements for Northern Ireland so it is border free) and not being able to negotiate a settlement with the EU. The Bill empowers Ministers to dis-apply the Protocol and relevant parts of the EU-UK Withdrawal Agreement in domestic law, and make new domestic law in place of the Protocol. Ministers would do this for safeguarding, social and economic stability, the territorial or constitutional integrity of the UK, functioning of the Belfast Agreement, health, and environmental reasons. There are 5 areas where Ministers can act: movement of goods; regulations of goods; vat and excise; removing the jurisdiction of the CJEU; and state aid. The only parts protected would be individual rights, the common travel area, and North-South co-operation. The EU has said that if the Bill is passed then it will respond with all measures at its disposal. The European Commission has said that it will move ahead with legal action against the UK. Labour lost the vote by 221 to 295 votes.</p>
<p>On Tuesday I continued to chair the Online Safety Bill line by line scrutiny sessions. The hundreds of amendments were debated to conclusion last week, and this week we are considering new clauses to be added to the Bill.</p>
<p>In the evening I went to the world premier of the documentary about trophy hunting “Lions, Bones and Bullets” which told the heart-breaking story of trophy hunting captive-bred lions and its links to the Far Eastern lion bone trade. The authors were present, and told us about how they bravely went undercover in South Africa to infiltrate ranches that specifically breed lions who are then shot by trophy hunters whilst in a captive situation. The lion cubs are taken from their mothers when only a few weeks old, and are kept in small open air pens, with no shelter from the sun, and fed with cattle carcasses from abattoirs, which may be diseased. The bones from the killed lions are then sold to countries in the Far East, and are fraudulently used as tiger bones in Chinese medicine. The documentary will be released in the autumn.</p>
<p>On Wednesday morning I joined in a Zoom call with fellow officers of the APPG for Steel to discuss plans to keep pressure on the UK Government to support the UK steel sector.</p>
<p>The business in the Chamber began with Oral Questions to the Secretary of State for Scotland, followed by PMQs. The Prime Minister was at the NATO summit so Deputy Dominic Raab stood in, and by convention the Labour Deputy Angela Rayner opposed him across the despatch box.</p>
<p>After PMQs I attended a special event during Cecil Week, the anniversary of the killing of Cecil the Lion, and the launch of the new report of a UK ban on trophies, “Trophy Hunting and Britain: The case for a Ban”. Guest speakers were Rt Hon George Eustice MP, Secretary of State for DEFRA; Dr Jane Goodhall DBE; Founder of the Jane Goodhall Institute; HE SKI Khama, President of Botswana (2008-2018); Boniface Mpario, Senior Maasai Elder. The event was chaired by Eduardo Gonclaves, Founder of the Campaign to Ban Trophy Hunting, “For People, For Wildlife, For Ever”. The 117,000 word APPG report is the world’s most comprehensive about trophy hunting, and includes facts, figures plus case studies and testimonies of world experts. There were over 200,000 lions in the 1970s but there could be as few as 9,610 lions left in the world today. Trophy hunters shoot an animal every 3 minutes, and could kill up to 170 million this century. British trophy hunters have won prizes for single-handedly shooting over 100 different wild animals. Opinion polls show that 9 out of 10 British voters, conservationists, scientists, and African community groups back a ban.</p>
<p>The regulators – the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the Financial Ombudsman Service (FOS) and the Financial Services Complaints Service (FSCS) – addressed MPs who have constituents that work, or have worked, for British Steel and have been affected by unsuitable advice provided by financial advisers regarding the British Steel Pension Scheme (BSPS). The regulators discussed the proposed BSPS compensation redress scheme which is out to consultation. MPs fed back their concerns to the regulators, and we have collected our views in a letter written to the FCA, signed by 27 cross-party MPs.</p>
<p>On Wednesday evening I attended another world premier documentary “Land of the Free: Out of the Shadows” about how trophy hunting is thwarting efforts to protect endangered wildlife. There are many celebrities who have been campaigning against trophy hunting for many years, and some took part in the film, for example Virginia McKenna of Born Free, Priscilla Presley, Peter Egan.</p>
<p>There were votes from 7pm on the Northern Ireland Troubles (Legacy and Reconciliation) Bill at Committee Stage which was debated on the floor of the House. Labour voted against incorporation of Government New Clauses 18-25, losing by 273 to 205 votes. Labour voted amendment our 98 and lost by 175 to 271 votes. Labour voted for amendment 97 and lost by 191 to 271 votes.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday afternoon, as vice-chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Restorative Justice, I hosted the APPG Restorative Justice Evidence Session, together with Jim Simon, CEO of the Restorative Justice Council. We heard evidence from restorative justice projects within schools and healthcare sectors in England. Catherine Allard Headteacher of John Keble Primary School […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2670</id>
    <published>2022-07-07T09:28:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-07-07T09:28:10Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>This morning we were notified by government that they are minded to appoint 
commissioners to oversee some parts of the City Council. The appointment of 
commissioners would be unjustified, and an attack on our local democracy. Under 
new leadership, Nottingham Labour have been making progress, being open about 
the difficulties we face and working hard to put things right. We have worked with the 
government appointed Improvement and Assurance Board to address all their 
concerns and they have reported positively to Government about our progress.</p>



<p>This work has resulted in the reduction in council debt, a transformation plan that will 
save the council £45m and improve services for Nottingham people. We have set a 
four year balanced budget, and have changed the culture and governance so that 
issues like the HRA are uncovered, shared transparently and sorted. The Council 
under the current leadership has made significant changes to the way it works, is 
open about the issues we face and is determined to get things right and this has 
been recognised by the Improvement and Assurance Board.</p>



<p>The Improvement and Assurance Board, headed by Sir Tony Redmond – the former 
Local Government Ombudsman – have described our progress positively to 
government and reported on our determination to succeed, so we are asking 
government what additional change they expect to achieve by bringing in people 
who know nothing of the City and our residents’ needs. Although we oppose the 
Governments’ intention to appoint commissioners the continuity provided by Sir Tony 
Redmond provides some assurance that our previous improvements are understood 
and can be built on.</p>



<p>But, we are asking what new actions would happen as a result of 
commissioners coming in that would improve the working of this council, or 
result in any changes that Nottingham people would want. We will use our 
opportunity to respond to this proposal from Government to ask these 
questions.</p>



<p>If it is the case that the government does take this action, this will be based 
not on what is best for the city, but what is best for the Conservative Party.</p>



<p>We will of course work positively and openly with commissioners, as we have with 
the Improvement and Assurance Board in the best interests of our city, but we will be 
straight with them, and straight with Nottingham people and will continue to fight for 
what Nottingham people need and have elected a Labour council to do.</p>



<p>The government cuts to our budgets means that it is more difficult to do everything 
we want to do to help our communities at this time but we have been fighting for 
Nottingham and protecting our services against the worst effects of Tory cuts. We 
made sure that Nottingham City Council – and our amazing staff – were there for you 
during the Covid crisis and we fought hard to get what we needed for our city to help 
keep people safe.</p>



<p>After more than a decade of Tory austerity – and the pandemic – we have managed  to set a four year balanced budget. This has not been easy, but Nottingham Labour:                                                                     Has retained 75 community protection officers                                                                                                     Are still building council houses and have improved private rented housing  through our licensing scheme                                                                                                                                                                        Has kept ownership of our outstanding care homes                                                                                                    Is still running six leisure centres                                                                                                                                 Is supporting Welfare Rights advice services across the city because we  defend what is needed by Nottingham people.</p>



<p>We are still supporting free events for families all year round, and you can still expect 
a regular bus service to get you there from our award winning city owned bus 
company. We have our own bus company because Labour protected it, when many 
others were sold off to private operators and they are now seeing more cancelled 
services and far higher fares. We invested in a tram that brings good jobs to the city 
and gets people to them. Our great public transport system has contributed to 
cleaner air than other cities in the UK and made people less reliant on a car.</p>



<p>The transformation of the Broadmarsh is underway after the shopping centre 
operator went into administration, a new central library will soon be fitted out, a green 
space in the heart of our city will be created and new developments creating jobs 
and homes will be coming in the next few years.</p>



<p>We are a city of hardworking people and Nottingham deserves better than 
intervention from an out of touch Tory government that is more concerned with 
protecting the profits of the energy companies than the people who can’t heat their 
homes or struggle to feed their families. We understand what twelve years of Tory 
austerity and now the cost of living crisis means to you, because we do not just 
represent our communities, we are part of them. We will carry on fighting for what 
Nottingham needs and will still be ready to help with the problems you are facing, or 
hear your views and hopes for the city.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/">Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This morning we were notified by government that they are minded to appoint<br/>
commissioners to oversee some parts of the City Council. The appointment of<br/>
commissioners would be unjustified, and an attack on our local democracy. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/06/23/nottingham-labour-statement-on-further-intervention/">Nottingham Labour Statement on further intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Aitken</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2731</id>
    <published>2022-06-23T13:32:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-23T13:32:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Government Finance"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="transport"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>This week is #BikeWeek 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/06/09/this-week-is-bikeweek-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7430</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T16:00:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T16:00:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/april-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5551" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/6.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/9b24ce45c950/tulip-siddiq-mp-april-2022-enewsletter">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for April 2022</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for April 2022</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5550</id>
    <published>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T09:03:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year was the formation of the Menopause Task Force, of which Carolyn is co-chair, which will be holding its inaugural meeting in the coming weeks.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Through the Taskforce, Carolyn aims to totally transform menopause support and services for women right across Wales and the UK with three key aims- to improve diagnosis and treatment pathways; to ensure women have the understanding and support they need from doctors, employers and their families; and to develop the school curriculum so the next generation are better educated on the menopause. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Carolyn has also been working closely with the Welsh Labour Government, who have put the menopause high on the political agenda, to make the  improvements in healthcare and education so that women in Wales will be able to access the support and services they need when it comes to menopause care.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, said:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“2021 saw the menopause revolution really take off.  We have already achieved so much in breaking down the barriers and getting people talking about the menopause, putting the menopause high on the political agenda.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“In Wales, we are so lucky to be able to access HRT free of charge thanks to the Welsh Labour Government, but I’m looking forward to working with Welsh Government colleagues to make further improvements to menopause support and services to ensure women across Wales can always access the support and services they need.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;“Our combined efforts across the Senedd and Westminster are helping us revolutionise menopause care throughout the UK to help keep women wonderful.  There should be no politics in women’s health, and we must work together cross-party and with the devolved governments to make a difference to women’s lives and achieve our common goals.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_linkedin" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/linkedin?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="LinkedIn" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.carolynharris.org.uk%2Fcarolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate%2F&amp;#038;title=Carolyn%20Harris%20MP%20stands%20up%20for%20Menopause%20Warriors%20in%20Wales%20during%20Welsh%20Grand%20Committee%20debate" data-a2a-url="https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/carolyn-harris-mp-stands-up-for-menopause-warriors-in-wales-during-welsh-grand-committee-debate/" data-a2a-title="Carolyn Harris MP stands up for Menopause Warriors in Wales during Welsh Grand Committee debate" data-wpel-link="exclude"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Carolyn Harris, MP for Swansea East, stood up for the thousands of Menopause Warriors in Wales during the Welsh Grand Committee debate earlier this week as she discussed the work of the menopause revolution and how it is benefiting women across the nation.    A key success of Carolyn Harris’ Private Member’s Bill last year […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Carolyn Harris MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.carolynharris.org.uk/?p=2063</id>
    <published>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-21T11:06:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dy6Hb-f3Bgu9cD4GigzyUDN0nEF_KYiR29KrhE4otWm64GAS19fUjvobp-dT_jPXvTrZyY_C5V74LilUUBO2w' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="/4130/bailiffs-debate-5" rel="attachment wp-att-4132"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/bailiffs-debate3-150x150.png" alt="" title="bailiffs debate" width="150" height="150" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-4132"/></a>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences.<span id="more-4166"/></p>
<p>From June 2020 only households with a pensioner in receipt of Pension Credit will be eligible for a free TV licence. This follows a government move for the BBC to take on responsibility for funding the £745m cost of the scheme.</p>
<p>In Wolverhampton, 11,360 pensioners across the city’s three constituencies – two thirds of all households currently eligible for a free TV licence – will no-longer be eligible.</p>
<p>Wolverhampton North East MP Emma Reynolds previously met pensioners who would be affected by changes to the scheme, and joined the other city MPs – Eleanor Smith and Pat McFadden – in signing a letter to Culture Secretary Jeremy Wright against any change.</p>
<p>On the announced changes, Emma said:</p>
<p>“At the last election the Conservative Party stood on a platform to keep free TV licences for the over 75s. Now, 11,000 Wolverhampton pensioners have been betrayed by a government which promised to keep them.</p>
<p>“Two thirds of Wolverhampton’s pensioners are to lose their free TV licence as a direct result of the government forcing the BBC to take on the cost. The £745m cost of the universal scheme is around a fifth of the BBC’s entire budget, and the government were warned the BBC could not take on this cost and keep the scheme in full. When Labour brought in free TV licences, it was government policy so the government rightly covered the cost. </p>
<p>“It is plain wrong that Boris Johnson is championing big tax cuts for the wealthy, while all but the poorest of pensioners now face having to pay for their TV licence. According to Age UK, 400,000 over 75s neither meet nor speak to family and friends every week. When I met with local pensioners, they told me how essential a TV is. A TV is often their only form of companionship, and the only way of knowing what is happening outside their home.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A broken Conservative Party promise from the 2017 election will mean two thirds of Wolverhampton’s over 75s are set to lose out, after the BBC announced changes to eligibility for free TV licences. From June 2020 only households with a […] <a class="more-link" href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">↓ Read the rest of this entry...</a></p>
        <p>The post <a href="/two-thirds-of-wolverhampton-pensioners-lose-free-tv-licence">Two thirds of Wolverhampton pensioners lose free TV licence</a> appeared first on <a href="">Emma Reynolds MP</a>.</p>
      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>adminjames</name>
    </author>
    <id>/?p=4166</id>
    <published>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2019-06-11T12:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
