<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2020-12-23T05:03:15Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/christmas-2020" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It is usual for Members of Parliament at this time of year to reflect on the year and a suitable Christmas Message.
Certainly 2020 has been an extraordinary year.  For me personally the past year has flown by; I was selected to stand for Aberconwy in November 2019, elected by you the voters who…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/christmas-2020</id>
    <published>2020-12-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Christmas tale of our times</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2020/12/23/a-christmas-tale-of-our-times/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Father&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Christmas&amp;nbsp;always has to spend a lot of time planning all those presents and deliveries. It requires enormous skill and teamwork to get all the right presents to everyone on Christmas night, even though of course he is helped by the way the world spins on its axis, extending the night time around the world to a 24 hour period. It does mean a superhuman effort by him and his reindeers, famed for their speed and navigating skills.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;In 2020 his helpers came to him and said he did need to do some homework&amp;nbsp; for his&amp;nbsp; deliveries as there were so many new rules applying to all the people he was going to visit. There was a nasty virus spreading its way around the globe, so countries required limited social contact and proper sanitising of goods. The world was so much keener now on green policies, so many of his global family would expect him to watch his carbon output. Anyone&amp;nbsp; buying things today did want to know more about where they came from, who had made them and whether they were socially aware and well governed. Santa above all others must show he is a leader of these movements for the good.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Over the summer Father Christmas was advised that&amp;nbsp; he took some training courses so he was ready for the new management regime. They wanted him to do a general course&amp;nbsp; on Money Laundering. Then there was fraud and bribery to study, to be followed by cyber crime. He should gain&amp;nbsp; a grounding in socially aware present giving, environmentally benign gifts and a course on governance of the parcels business. He needed to ensure he did not&amp;nbsp; fall foul of the ever higher standards for animal welfare for the reindeers, so he needed a module on advanced Reindeer husbandry.&amp;nbsp; He should ask about any new restrictions on fast moving sleighs. Then of course owing to the pandemic everything he did this year has to be Covid compliant. How was he on all the differing rules around the world on social distancing, mask wearing and digital alternatives? He also had to get up to speed with the green necessities, ensuring all gifts were zero carbon and his sleigh ride did not generate too much carbon dioxide from himself and the animals. He needed to be more socially aware, so each gift would need a certificate to prove it had been made in good conditions for the staff, and he would need himself an approval certificate that he had achieved high standards of governance.&amp;nbsp;Then he should answer the stroppy email from the EU pointing out that giving lots of goods away was an infringement of single market rules. As it was a form of state aids or unfair competition he would need to apply &amp;nbsp;two months in advance for an exemption certificate, explaining why he should get away with undercutting properly regulated and taxed suppliers. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Father&amp;nbsp;Christmas&amp;nbsp;is a bit of a traditionalist, and was not sure he wanted to spend his summer slaving over all these worldly topics that might take the fun out of Noel. So he compromised with his advisers and agreed to a conference with&amp;nbsp; experts to see what if anything&amp;nbsp; was relevant to him.&amp;nbsp; At the meeting the Diversity Advuiser started asking lots of very personal questions about the elves. What was their background and how did they reflect differing attitudes towards society and the family? The Trade Union adviser warned him&amp;nbsp; that his workers even on Christmas night would need decent breaks. Was their a written guarantee that none of them were on zero hours contracts or were going to be sacked immediately after the public holiday? The anti Money Laundering Officer told him he could no longer get away with refusing to disclose who paid for all the presents he was dropping off. The Data Protection Officer said he was in possession of vital individual information which was both personal and commercially valuable. All those wish lists for present needed to&amp;nbsp; be better filed and password protected, preferably with a duo system and complex codes. The criminal lawyer told him he was especially vulnerable to suspicion of bribes, so he needed to keep a register of any mince pies, glasses of wine or tips he was offered during his work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The cyber expert told him that as many children now sent in text messages, emails or social media posts with all their details, he needed much better cyber protection. He also needed reliable and secure systems of ordering the gifts.&amp;nbsp; A&amp;nbsp;Christmas&amp;nbsp;Grinch could so easily crash his systems, wrecking the only day of the year when he could provide his service. Indeed, on&amp;nbsp; reflection there was a good case for him straddling&amp;nbsp;Christmas&amp;nbsp;over more days to lessen the risk. The Covid compliance officer told him he must wear a face mask in any house he visited, would have to self isolate for fourteen days before his journey, and should either use disposable gloves at each house or take plenty of hand gel. They thought he could probably argue his journey was necessary for work, but leaving the present on the doorstep was much safer. The Animal Welfare expert told him he could no longer rely on just one team of reindeers as the work was too great, so he should train and station relief teams around the world. The Green Adviser proposed a fully automated electric sleigh as a better option. The Social Awareness analyst said he could help supply print outs on the suitability of various gift suppliers which would need to be appended to each present. The Governance Adviser said he would need to be certificated himself as someone who had done a good job organising and leading the delivery service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Father Christmas was well aware that everything had to go like magic to fit it all into a single night. He was nervous about accepting too many changes to the tried and tested methods he used to deliver the lot. Nor did he welcome too many questions on the detail of how it was managed, as the whole point was its seemingly effortless magic that delivered. No-one must be let down and go without a present. He asked the Green adviser how would the electric sleigh work? Might it need recharging on what is a very long journey, and if so how long would that take? The lack of certainty about this led him to conclude he preferred his old sleigh. He said his reindeer had always managed before and knew the routine to perfection. If a vet certified they were fit&amp;nbsp; before and gave them a check over on return wouldn’t that suffice? He couldn’t see the point of all the financial requirements. It was after all a free service he offered, and part of the wonder&amp;nbsp; was not knowing how it was all paid for. As to him receiving bribes it was laughable. No-one left him&amp;nbsp; cash or large gifts. They were just being friendly with their mince pies. Given his weight problem it was not something he asked for or wanted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The advisers then changed their tone and said how delighted they were to get to meet him in person at last. In&amp;nbsp; order to save the postage they had brought their own family lists with them as that might help in his great task.&amp;nbsp;“So” said Santa, “when it comes to your family you do not seem to have the same worries about CV 19,&amp;nbsp; bribes or how green is my transport. Can I suggest that you and your Regulators turn a blind eye to how I do my job on this unique occasion each year? I doubt you would be happy if I told you that on reflection on all &amp;nbsp;your points it was just too difficult to do this on one special night, so the service was cancelled”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; So it transpired that the worried advisers thought this could after all be a rare &amp;nbsp;exception to all the rules.&amp;nbsp; Isn’t it good to know Father Christmas is Covid compliant after all? Happy Christmas everyone. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Father Christmas always has to spend a lot of time planning all those presents and deliveries. It requires enormous skill and teamwork to get all the right presents to everyone on Christmas night, even though of course he is helped by the way the world spins on its axis, extending the night time around the world to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=29237</id>
    <published>2020-12-23T05:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-23T05:02:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Seasons Greetings from Chi Onwurah MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/seasons-greetings-from-chi-onwurah-mp-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img data-attachment-id="10725" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2020/12/seasons-greetings-from-chi-onwurah-mp-2/xmas-pic/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?fit=380%2C535&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="380,535" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="xmas pic" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?fit=213%2C300&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?fit=380%2C535&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-10725 aligncenter" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?resize=380%2C535&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="380" height="535" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?w=380&amp;ssl=1 380w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/xmas-pic.jpg?resize=213%2C300&amp;ssl=1 213w" sizes="(max-width: 380px) 100vw, 380px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Merry Christmas from Chi Onwurah MP- The office is now closed for Christmas and will reopen on December 29th. In an emergency please call 0191 232 5838 and leave a message.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Merry Christmas from Chi Onwurah MP- The office is now closed for Christmas and will reopen on December 29th. In an emergency please call 0191 232 5838 and leave a message.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=10724</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T16:09:44Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T16:09:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>World-famous city author Alexander McCall Smith to receive 2020 Edinburgh Award</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13067/world-famous-city-author-alexander-mccall-smith-to-receive-2020-edinburgh-award" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Internationally-admired Edinburgh-based author Alexander McCall Smith CBE has been chosen as this year's recipient of the prestigious Edinburgh Award.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13067/world-famous-city-author-alexander-mccall-smith-to-receive-2020-edinburgh-award</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T12:09:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T12:09:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wishing everyone in Basingstoke a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/wishing-everyone-basingstoke-merry-christmas-and-happy-new-year" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As 2020 draws to a close I would like to wish everyone in Basingstoke a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year. This year’s celebrations will be different and it’s vital everyone continues to follow the restrictions, to keep our most vulnerable safe and not to give up the critical gains we have made…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/wishing-everyone-basingstoke-merry-christmas-and-happy-new-year</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>UK Government make 30,000 agricultural visas available</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/uk-government-make-30000-agricultural-visas-available" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The UK Government has announced that the number of visas available for next year’s fruit and vegetable pickers will increase to 30,000.
The 30,000 visas allow those who want to come to the UK to work on farms for a period of up to six months.
The workers will play a vital role in helping fruit and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/uk-government-make-30000-agricultural-visas-available</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Best wishes for Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/best-wishes-for-christmas/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Since the start of this month we've seen a rapidly deteriorating position with the regards to the spread of the COVID-19 virus. On the 1st of December the rolling seven-day average infection rate per 100,000 people in the Folkestone and Hythe district was 193, whereas three weeks later it is nearly 700. In other parts […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5476</id>
    <published>2020-12-22T05:18:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-22T05:18:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Urgent Covid Statement 14/12/2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/12/21/lateral-flow-tests/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I asked the UK Secretary of State for Health whether spending £43Bn on inaccurate lateral flow tests instead of improving access to proven PCR tests was a worthwhile investment. We know that lateral flow tests miss over half of positive Covid cases. They also miss 30% of cases with a high viral load.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;He responded in a typically rude and patronising manner. As a Doctor for 38 years, of course I&amp;#8217;m not against testing, as he suggests,  but tests which miss over half of Covid cases creates dangerous false reassurance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can watch my full contribution to the statement here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FWEKk5Pj3m0"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FWEKk5Pj3m0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="14/12 Covid Statement" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FWEKk5Pj3m0?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford MP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many public health experts have questioned the use of Innova lateral flow tests for mass community testing, especially as the manufacturer does not recommend them for detecting coronavirus in people who are asymptomatic. The Secretary of State must be aware of the paper from the University of Liverpool, based on his own Department’s quality assurance programme, which has raised serious concerns about their accuracy when used in the community testing project in Liverpool. A comparison of lateral flow tests with PCR tests in over 3,000 people revealed a sensitivity of just 48%, meaning that more than half of those with the virus&amp;nbsp;would be falsely reassured that they were negative. The test even missed 30% of those with a high viral load—those most likely to be infectious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I understand the wish to use quick tests for case finding, but surely the Secretary of State should now delay rolling them out to 67 other local authorities and should not proceed with plans to spend £43 billion for a test that is so inaccurate. Would it not be better to focus funding on easier and quicker access to PCR tests? With more than half of all positive cases being missed, does he accept that despite the proposal by Baroness Harding, these tests cannot be used to release people who are contacts from isolation? On the basis of that study, the Liverpool health protection board has abandoned plans to use lateral flow tests to check visitors to care homes, so will the Secretary of State be recommending that local authorities and providers should return to PCR testing for care home staff and family visitors to reduce the risk to the most vulnerable residents?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt Hancock&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;blockquote class="wp-block-quote"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that this argument against testing is wrong. I think that we should test, test, test, and that is what this Government are doing. We are working very closely with the Government in Scotland, from the same party that the hon. Lady represents, to make sure that we use testing as widely as possible to find people who have this virus. Yes, of course different tests have different characteristics. The lateral flow tests find around 70% of those who are infectious. That means that if we test people who would not otherwise have been tested, we find the positive cases, we can get them to isolate and we can break the chains of transmission. I strongly urge the hon. Lady to go back, to study the details and to back the testing programme that we have in this country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2020%2F12%2F21%2Flateral-flow-tests%2F&amp;#038;title=Urgent%20Covid%20Statement%2014%2F12%2F2020" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2020/12/21/lateral-flow-tests/" data-a2a-title="Urgent Covid Statement 14/12/2020"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/12/21/lateral-flow-tests/"&gt;Urgent Covid Statement 14/12/2020&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I asked the UK Secretary of State for Health whether spending £43Bn on inaccurate lateral ... <a title="Urgent Covid Statement 14/12/2020" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/12/21/lateral-flow-tests/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2020/12/21/lateral-flow-tests/">Urgent Covid Statement 14/12/2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Intern</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=1994</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T16:16:26Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T16:16:26Z</updated>
    <category term="Health, Wellbeing, &amp; Social Justice"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="COVID"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="Test-Trace-Isolate-Support"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Speaks Up for Traveling Showmen and Women</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-speaks-up-for-traveling-showmen-and-women/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-1024x682.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2969" srcset="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-980x653.jpg 980w, https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/web/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/ocean-beach-pleasure-park-1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled &lt;strong&gt;Future of fairs and Showgrounds&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and showmen community and steps in to provide vital support before it is too late. As a longstanding supporter and advocate for show people and a member of the All Party Parliamentary Group for Fairs and Showgrounds, I will continue to be a voice for this community and press the Government at every opportunity for better support and recognition. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the outset of the pandemic, many fairs were either cancelled or postponed – from summer fetes to Christmas Markets. As a result of the closures and postponing of fairs, many show people suffered huge financial loss, plunging them into financial insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The heart of the issue is that the financial support offered to the tourism industry during COVID-19 continually excluded the fairground community. Showmen and women also did not qualify for the assistance announced in the recent budget for retail, leisure and hospitality firms relating to business rates in the coming year, due to the way that the Show people operate, which falls outside the scope of static leisure providers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Show people across the UK and particularly those here in South Shields, now face losing their businesses and livelihoods if the UK Government does not step in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read my speech by clicking &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2020-12-17/debates/3B335883-D800-426D-ACAD-2204734ED4F7/FairsAndShowgrounds#contribution-374A337C-9576-467B-95F1-505F40A37FE0"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week I spoke in the Westminster Hall debate entitled Future of fairs and Showgrounds. I wanted to support those showmen and women here in South Shields which has a long history of welcoming traveling showmen and women that dates back almost 100 years. It is imperative that the Government stops ignoring the fairground and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=2971</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T14:39:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jon Cruddas MP Christmas Message 2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/jon-cruddas-mp-christmas-message-2020" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/DSC_1464_1_6.jpg?itok=7AUnc7Tv" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p> </p>
              <p>
                <em>This year has been unlike any other in our lifetime, and very few of us will find ourselves sorry to see the back of 2020. As we approach an altogether different Christmas from what we are used to, I think it is important to say thank you and pay tribute to all those that have made great sacrifices to keep us safe throughout the year.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>For many this has been a year of sadness and loss, loss of loved ones and a feeling that our futures have been put at risk with the economy taking such hard knocks. There will be thousands of businesses that closed their doors for good during the pandemic and a full social and economic recovery will undoubtedly be a long process.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>However, there are positives to take from 2020. In this unprecedented year full of challenges and unpredictability we have also seen the very best of people. A community spirit that many thought lost in time has been rejuvenated with mutual aid and citizens alliance networks across Barking and Dagenham and Havering. Neighbours looking out for one another and protecting the most vulnerable in our society.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>There are genuine signs of hope appearing as we come to the end of this difficult period. Scientists around the world have worked successfully to produce vaccines, and with a global roll out round the corner normality does not seem too far away. That is why it is all the more important that we do not give a platform to ‘Covid deniers’ or give way to the voices of anti-vaxxers.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>Despite the uncertainty and subsequent economic challenges, Dagenham and Rainham has not been without success stories and is in a strong position to weather the storm. Just last month Barking and Dagenham announced their delivery partner for London’s largest film studio which will bring Hollywood investment to Dagenham East, and plans were approved earlier in the year to relocate London’s three historic markets to Dagenham Dock.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>As we move into 2021, I will continue working to support local people, businesses, and voluntary organisations throughout Dagenham and Rainham. I also plan to keep the pressure on central government and will continue campaigning for greater investment in public services, improved healthcare and opportunities for our young people.</em>
              </p>
              <p>
                <em>Finally, I want to extend warm wishes to families across Dagenham, Rainham, South Hornchurch and Elm Park this Christmas, and all the best for a happy and healthy new year. Whilst guidance has now changed over the holidays, I would still urge caution and encourage residents to behave in a responsible way that keeps all in our community safe.</em>
              </p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/dagenham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Dagenham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/christmas" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Christmas</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/covid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Covid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/coronavirus" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Coronavirus</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-5">
              <a href="/tags/guidance" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Guidance</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-6">
              <a href="/tags/nhs" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">NHS</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-7">
              <a href="/tags/safety" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Safety</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-8">
              <a href="/tags/community" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">community</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1438 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T13:12:35Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T13:12:35Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Covid testing for offshore workers is most sensible and safest option, says Isles MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/21/local-covid-testing-for-offshore-workers-is-most-sensible-and-safest-option-says-isles-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil is reiterating his urgent call for Covid-19 testing to be available in the Western Isles for offshore workers prior to their journey to work.</p>



<p>Concerned oil workers from the islands have contacted Mr MacNeil regarding the situation which means they are being forced to travel to a Tier 4 area to be tested for Covid-19 before going on to offshore platforms.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil has now written again to Health Secretary Jean Freeman to stress the need for local testing of workers.</p>



<p>He said: “Again I’ve had the spectre of oil workers coming to me regarding this situation.</p>



<p>“It is worse now as they are having to leave the Tier 1 Hebrides to go to what will be Tier 4 areas for testing to go off on oil rigs on January 3 or 4, having to leave for testing on Hogmanay.</p>



<p>“Given the alarm that the Government has raised about the new strain of Covid, surely this means that the Government has to react to minimise the risk that people have of coming into contact with it.</p>



<p>“This is particularly so when we know we have capacity to test in the Hebrides with NHS testing.</p>



<p>“It would seem sensible to keep people out of harm’s way. Going to places where Covid is far more prevalent to get testing seems bizarrely daft.</p>



<p>“Testing in the islands would be far a safer and more sensible approach for people going away.</p>



<p>“I’ve written to Jeanne Freeman on this today as well as on the 23rd of November. I haven’t had a response yet but I am hoping for a quick response this time given the Government’s concern about the new strain of Covid.”</p>



<p/>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="3020" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/ab6-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg" data-orig-size="640,481" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="ab6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-3020" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg 640w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px"/></a></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar MP Angus MacNeil is reiterating his urgent call for Covid-19 testing to be available in the …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2020/12/21/local-covid-testing-for-offshore-workers-is-most-sensible-and-safest-option-says-isles-mp/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3287</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:56:52Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:56:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>David Evennett and Bexley Conservatives supporting local pubs, sports and social clubs this winter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bexley Council with funding support from the government has announced further Covid-19 support packages for local businesses across Bexleyheath and Crayford. 
These new grant schemes include a special winter support package of just under £1 million being made available for local independent pubs,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/david-evennett-and-bexley-conservatives-supporting-local-pubs-sports-and-social-clubs-winter</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-100" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It is becoming increasingly difficult to write this column with any hope of not having to rewrite it! This week was no exception. This is not just another Christmas column when I would normally start telling you parliament has risen for recess and that all is well with the world as it looks forward…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-100</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP calls for the immediate virtual recall of Parliament</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1387629/mp-calls-for-the-immediate-virtual-recall-of-parliament"/>
  <updated>2020-12-21T11:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2020/1387629/mp-calls-for-the-immediate-virtual-recall-of-parliament</id>
  <summary type="text">Local MP Tim Farron is calling for Parliament to be virtually recalled today following the news of the rapid spread of the new strain of coronavirus and countries across Europe closing their borders to the UK.
Tim said: "The events over the weekend constitute a national crisis.
"The Government's response to them will have profound impacts on lives and livelihoods so it's crucial that their decisions are scrutinised by Parliament.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Local MP Tim Farron is calling for Parliament to be virtually recalled today following the news of the rapid spread of the new strain of coronavirus and countries across Europe closing their borders to the UK.</p>
<p>Tim said: <em>"The events over the weekend constitute a national crisis.</em></p>
<p><em>"The Government's response to them will have profound impacts on lives and livelihoods so it's crucial that their decisions are scrutinised by Parliament.</em></p>
<p><em>"With London now in lockdown, it would be very wrong for MPs to travel to Westminster - that's why provisions must be put in place for Parliament to proceed virtually at once."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Labour selects Tracy Brabin as West Yorkshire metro mayor candidate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/2020/12/21/labour-selects-tracy-brabin-as-west-yorkshire-metro-mayor-candidate/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Marsden</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tracybrabinmp.com/?p=1261</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:39:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Weston&#8217;s MP Welcomes Cuts To Housing Targets &#038; Commitment to Building Up, Not Out]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/21/westons-mp-welcomes-cuts-to-housing-targets-commitment-to-building-up-not-out/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4537</id>
		<updated>2020-12-21T10:18:02Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-21T10:18:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Uncategorized"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose has welcomed news the Government will drop proposals to increase North Somerset’s housebuilding targets from 1,365 to 1,708 a year. This announcement comes just months after John wrote to Ministers raising concerns that the proposed new housebuilding targets were unrealistic and weeks after John and Liam Fox raised the issue in [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2020/12/21/westons-mp-welcomes-cuts-to-housing-targets-commitment-to-building-up-not-out/"><![CDATA[
<p>Weston&#8217;s MP John Penrose has welcomed news the Government will drop proposals to increase North Somerset’s housebuilding targets from 1,365 to 1,708 a year.</p>



<p>This announcement comes just months after John wrote to Ministers raising concerns that the proposed new housebuilding targets were unrealistic and weeks after John and Liam Fox raised the issue in a debate on housebuilding in North Somerset. John made the point that the algorithm being used&nbsp;encouraged environmentally damaging housebuilding over green fields rather than investment and regeneration in urban areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>John said: &#8220;It&#8217;s great that the Government has listened to what I, Liam Fox, North Somerset Council and others have been saying. This is a big step in the right direction, although the existing building targets are still pretty high. But if we Build Up Not Out in urban areas like central Weston or Bristol, and use local Council-approved Design Codes so the new builds match the best of what’s already here, we can build a lot more green, good-looking homes that local people can afford, that are close to work, transport-links, shops, schools and GP surgeries, and which revive our town centres and High Streets too.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coronavirus (COVID-19)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-25/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear constituent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very sorry to have to send you another update so soon after the last one, but most of you will now have seen the latest restrictions being introduced for our area. I know many of you will be very upset about what has happened and its impact on Christmas and on local businesses – I am as disappointed and unhappy as many of you will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be helpful for you to see all of the rules that now apply, as there are some differences from November. Apologies for the length of the email – there’s quite a lot of detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the Tier 4 guidance. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay at home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must not leave or be outside of your home except for where you have a specific purpose, or a ‘reasonable excuse’. A reasonable excuse includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work and volunteering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home for work purposes, where your place of work remains open and where you cannot work from home (including if your job involves working in other people’s homes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential activities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home to buy things at shops which are permitted to open in your area, but you should stay local. For instance you can leave home to buy food or medicine, or to collect any items &amp;#8211; including food or drink &amp;#8211; ordered through click-and-collect or as a takeaway, to obtain or deposit money (e.g. from a bank or post office), or to access critical public services (see section below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fulfilling legal obligations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also leave home to fulfil legal obligations, or to carry out activities related to buying, selling, letting or renting a residential property, or vote in certain elections taking place overseas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education and childcare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home for education (formal provision, rather than extracurricular classes such as music or drama tuition, or out of school settings) or training, registered childcare and supervised activities for children that are necessary to allow parents/carers to work, seek work, undertake education or training, or attend a medical appointment. Parents can still take their children to school, and people can continue existing arrangements for contact between parents and children where they live apart. This &lt;u&gt;includes &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-childcare-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;childcare bubbles&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting others and care&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 in 3 people who have coronavirus have no symptoms and will be spreading it without realising it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home to visit people in your &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;support bubble&lt;/a&gt;, or to provide informal childcare for children aged 13 and under as part of a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-childcare-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;childcare bubble&lt;/a&gt;, to provide care for vulnerable people, to provide emergency assistance, attend a support group (of up to 15 people), or for respite care where that care is being provided to a vulnerable person or a person with a disability, or is a short break in respect of a looked after child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise and recreation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can also exercise outdoors or visit some public outdoor places, such as parks, the countryside, public gardens or outdoor sports facilities. You can continue to do unlimited exercise alone, or in a public outdoor place with your household, support bubble, or one other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical reasons, harm and compassionate visits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home for any medical reason, including to get a COVID-19 test, for medical appointments and emergencies, to be with someone who is giving birth, to avoid injury or illness or to escape risk of harm (such as domestic abuse),or for animal welfare reasons – such as to attend veterinary services for advice or treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also leave home to visit someone who is dying or someone in a care home (if permitted under care home guidance), hospice, or hospital, or to accompany them to a medical appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communal worship and life events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can leave home to attend a place of worship for communal worship, a funeral or a related event for someone who has died, or to visit a burial ground or a remembrance garden, or to attend a wedding &amp;#8211; but funerals, linked events and weddings are all subject to limits on the numbers that can attend (see below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting others safely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, you must not meet with another person socially or undertake any activities with another person. However, you can exercise or meet in a public outdoor place with people you live with, your support bubble (or as part of a childcare bubble), or with one other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should minimise time spent outside your home. When around other people, stay 2 metres apart from anyone not in your household &amp;#8211; meaning the people you live with &amp;#8211; or your &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;support bubble&lt;/a&gt;. Where this is not possible, stay 1 metre apart with extra precautions (e.g. wearing a face covering).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must not meet socially indoors with family or friends unless they are part of your household or support bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can exercise or visit a public outdoor place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;by yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with the people you live with,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with your support bubble,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or, when on your own, with 1 person from another household.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children under 5, and up to two carers for a person with a disability who needs continuous care are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; counted towards the outdoors gatherings limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public outdoor places include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parks, beaches, countryside accessible to the public, forests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;public gardens (whether or not you pay to enter them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allotments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the grounds of a heritage site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outdoor sports courts and facilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;playgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot meet people in a private garden, unless you live with them or have formed a support bubble with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must wear a face covering in many indoor settings, such as shops or places of worship where these remain open, and on public transport, unless you are exempt. This is the law. &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/face-coverings-when-to-wear-one-and-how-to-make-your-own/face-coverings-when-to-wear-one-and-how-to-make-your-own"&gt;Read guidance on face coverings.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support and childcare bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is separate guidance for &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;support bubbles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-childcare-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;childcare bubbles&lt;/a&gt; across all tiers. You can form a support bubble with another household if any of the following apply to you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you are the only adult in your household (any other members of the household having been under 18 on 12 June 2020), or are an under 18 year old living without any adults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you live with someone with a disability who requires continuous care and there is no other adult living in the household&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you live with a child under 1, or who was under 1 on 2 December 2020&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you live with a child under 5, or who was under 5 on 2 December 2020, with a disability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may need to change your support bubble if your circumstances change. Find out more about &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household#changing-your-support-bubble"&gt;changing your support bubble&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where and when you can meet in larger groups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still circumstances in which you are allowed to meet others from outside your household or support bubble in larger groups, but this should not be for socialising and only for permitted purposes. A full list of these circumstances will be included in the regulations, and includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for work, or providing voluntary or charitable services. This includes picketing outside workplaces. This can include work in other people’s homes where necessary &amp;#8211; for example, for nannies, cleaners or tradespeople. See guidance on &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/working-safely-during-coronavirus-covid-19/homes"&gt;working safely in other people’s homes&lt;/a&gt;). Where a work meeting does not need to take place in a private home or garden, it should not &amp;#8211; for example, although you can meet a personal trainer, you should do so in a public outdoor public place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-childcare-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;childcare bubble&lt;/a&gt;(for the purposes of childcare only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for registered childcare, or for supervised activities for children where this enables a parent to work, seek work, attend education or training, or for respite care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;education or training &amp;#8211; meaning education related to a formal curriculum or training that relates to work or obtaining work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for arrangements where children do not live in the same household as both their parents or guardians&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to allow contact between birth parents and children in care, as well as between siblings in care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for prospective adopting parents to meet a child or children who may be placed with them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for birth partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide emergency assistance, and to avoid injury or illness, or to escape a risk of harm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to see someone who is dying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to fulfil a legal obligation, such as attending court or jury service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for gatherings within criminal justice accommodation or immigration detention centres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/coronavirus-covid-19-providing-unpaid-care/guidance-for-those-who-provide-unpaid-care-to-friends-or-family"&gt;provide care or assistance to someone vulnerable&lt;/a&gt;, or to provide respite for a carer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for a wedding or equivalent ceremony in exceptional circumstances, as set out below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for funerals &amp;#8211; up to a maximum of 30 people. Wakes and other linked ceremonial events can continue in a group of up to 6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to visit someone at home who is dying, or to visit someone receiving treatment in a hospital, hospice or care home, or to accompany a family member or friend to a medical appointment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for elite sportspeople (and their coaches if necessary, or parents/guardians if they are under 18) to compete and train&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to facilitate a house move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support groups that have to be delivered in person can continue with up to 15 participants where formally organised to provide mutual aid, therapy or any other form of support &amp;#8211; but they must take place at a premises other than a private home. This includes, but is not limited to, support to victims of crime, people in drug and alcohol recovery, new parents and guardians, people caring for those with long-term or terminal illnesses, or who are vulnerable, people facing issues relating to their sexuality or gender, those who have suffered bereavement, and vulnerable young people, including for them to meet youth workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parent and child groups can continue where they provide support to parent and/or child, and children under 5 will not be counted within the 15 person limit &amp;#8211; meaning parents and carers can attend such groups in larger numbers. These cannot take place in private dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where a group includes someone covered by an exception (for example, someone who is working or volunteering), they are not generally counted as part of the gatherings limit. This means, for example, a tradesperson can go into a household without breaching the limit, if they are there for work, and the officiant at a wedding would not count towards the limit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you break the rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The police can take action against you if you meet in larger groups. This includes breaking up illegal gatherings and issuing fines (fixed penalty notices).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can be given a Fixed Penalty Notice of £200 for the first offence, doubling for further offences up to a maximum of £6,400. If you hold, or are involved in holding, an illegal gathering of over 30 people, the police can issue fines of £10,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keeping you and your friends and family safe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When meeting friends and family you should also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;follow &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing"&gt;guidance on social distancing and letting in fresh air&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limit how many different people you see socially over any period of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Protecting people more at risk from coronavirus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are clinically vulnerable, you could be at higher risk of severe illness from coronavirus. You:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should be especially careful to follow the rules and minimise your contacts with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should continue to wash your hands carefully and more frequently than usual and maintain thorough cleaning of frequently touched areas in your home and/or workspace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinically vulnerable people are those who are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aged 70 or over (regardless of medical conditions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;under 70 with an underlying health condition listed below (that is, anyone instructed to get a flu jab each year on medical grounds):
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chronic (long-term) mild to moderate respiratory diseases, such as asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), emphysema or bronchitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chronic heart disease, such as heart failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chronic kidney disease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chronic liver disease, such as hepatitis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chronic neurological conditions, such as Parkinson’s disease, motor neurone disease, multiple sclerosis (MS) or cerebral palsy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diabetes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems with the spleen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a weakened immune system as the result of certain conditions or medicines they are taking (such as steroid tablets)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being seriously overweight (a body mass index (BMI) of 40 or above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pregnant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a further group of people who are defined, also on medical grounds, as &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/guidance-on-shielding-and-protecting-extremely-vulnerable-persons-from-covid-19"&gt;clinically extremely vulnerable&lt;/a&gt; to coronavirus – that is, people with specific serious health conditions. Over this period, we are advising the clinically extremely vulnerable to work from home. If you cannot work from home, you are advised not to go to work and may be eligible for the Coronavirus Job Retention Scheme (CJRS), Statutory Sick Pay (SSP), Employment Support Allowance (ESA) or Universal Credit. We are advising clinically extremely vulnerable people to stay at home as much as possible, except to go outdoors for exercise or to attend health appointments. You may wish to meet up with one other person from outside your household or support bubble, for example, to exercise in an outdoor public place, but we suggest that you always try to do so as safely as possible. &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/guidance-on-shielding-and-protecting-extremely-vulnerable-persons-from-covid-19/guidance-on-shielding-and-protecting-extremely-vulnerable-persons-from-covid-19"&gt;Please follow the guidance set out in the shielding section of the CEV guidance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travelling within a tier 4 area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in a tier 4 area, you must stay at home. You must not leave your home to travel unless for work, education or other legally permitted reasons. If you need to travel you should stay local &amp;#8211; meaning avoiding travelling outside of your village, town or the part of a city where you live &amp;#8211; and look to reduce the number of journeys you make overall. The list of reasons you can leave your home and area include, but are not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work, where you cannot work from home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;accessing education and for caring responsibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visiting those in your support bubble &amp;#8211; or your childcare bubble for childcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visiting hospital, GP and other medical appointments or visits where you have had an accident or are concerned about your health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;buying goods or services from premises that are open in Tier 4 areas, including essential retail, but these should be within your local area wherever possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spending time or exercising outdoors. This should be done locally wherever possible, but you can travel a short distance within your Tier 4 area to do so if necessary (for example, to access an open space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attending the care and exercise of a pet, or veterinary services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to travel, walk or cycle where possible, and plan ahead and avoid busy times and routes on public transport. This will allow you to practise social distancing while you travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid car sharing with anyone from outside your household or your support bubble. See the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-safer-travel-guidance-for-passengers#private-cars-and-other-vehicles"&gt;guidance on car sharing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to use public transport, you should follow the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-safer-travel-guidance-for-passengers"&gt;safer travel guidance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travelling out of a tier 4 area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must stay at home and not leave your Tier 4 area, other than for legally permitted reasons such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;travel to work where you cannot work from home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;travel to education and for caring responsibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visit those in your support bubble &amp;#8211; or your childcare bubble for childcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attend hospital, GP and other medical appointments or visits where you have had an accident or are concerned about your health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full list of exceptions will be published in the Regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travelling to a tier 4 area from a tier 1, 2 or 3 area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should not travel into a Tier 4 area from another part of the UK, other than for reasons such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;travel to work where you cannot work from home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;travel to education and for caring responsibilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to visit those in your support bubble &amp;#8211; or your childcare bubble for childcare&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to attend hospital, GP and other medical appointments or visits where you have had an accident or are concerned about your health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should continue to practise safe behaviours on public transport:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plan ahead, check for disruption before you leave, and avoid the busiest routes, as well as busy times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid making unnecessary stops during your journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avoid sharing a car with people not in your household&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep your distance from other people when you travel, where possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wash or sanitise your hands regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International travel to or from a tier 4 area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are in Tier 4, you should not be travelling abroad unless it is permitted. In addition, you should consider the public health advice in the country you are visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live outside a tier 4 area you may still transit into or through a tier 4 area to travel abroad if you need to, but you should carefully consider whether you need to do so. In addition, you should follow the public health advice in the country you’re visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do need to travel overseas from a tier 4 area (and are legally permitted to do so, for example, because it is for work), even if you are returning to a place you&amp;#8217;ve visited before, you should look at the rules in place at your destination and the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice"&gt;Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office (FCDO) travel advice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UK residents currently abroad do not need to return home immediately. However, you should check with your airline or travel operator on arrangements for returning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staying away from home overnight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot leave home for holidays or stays overnight away from your main home unless permitted by law. This means that holidays in the UK and abroad are not allowed. This includes staying in a second home or caravan, or staying with anyone you do not live with or are in a support bubble with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are allowed to stay overnight away from your home if you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are unable to return to your main residence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need accommodation while moving house&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need accommodation to attend a funeral or related commemorative event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;require accommodation for work purposes or to provide voluntary services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are a child requiring accommodation for school or care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are homeless, seeking asylum or a vulnerable person seeking refuge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are an elite athlete or their support staff or parent, if the athlete is under 18 and it is necessary to be outside of the home for training or competition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already on holiday in a Tier 4 area, you should return to your home as soon as practical&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guest accommodation providers such as hotels, B&amp;amp;Bs and caravan parks may remain open for the specific reasons set out in law, including where guests are unable to return to their main residence, use that guest accommodation as their main residence, need accommodation while moving house, are self-isolating as required by law, or would otherwise be made homeless as a result of the accommodation closing. Accommodation providers are also encouraged to work cooperatively with Local Authorities to provide accommodation to vulnerable groups including the homeless in tier 4 areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Businesses and venues&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Businesses and venues which must close&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To reduce social contact, the regulations require some businesses to close and impose restrictions on how some businesses provide goods and services. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non-essential retail, such as clothing and homeware stores, vehicle showrooms (other than for rental), betting shops, tailors, tobacco and vape shops, electronic goods and mobile phone shops, and market stalls selling non-essential goods &amp;#8211; these venues can continue to be able to operate click-and-collect (where goods are pre-ordered and collected off the premises) and delivery services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hospitality venues such as cafes, restaurants, pubs, bars and social clubs; with the exception of providing food and drink for takeaway (until 11pm), click-and-collect, drive-through or delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;accommodation such as hotels, hostels, guest houses and campsites, except for specific circumstances, such as where these act as someone’s main residence, where the person cannot return home, for homeless people, or where it is essential to stay there for work purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leisure and sports facilities such as leisure centres and indoor gyms, indoor swimming pools, indoor tennis and basketball courts, indoor fitness and dance studios, indoor climbing walls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entertainment venues such as theatres, concert halls, cinemas, museums and galleries, casinos, amusement arcades, bingo halls, bowling alleys, skating rinks, go-karting venues, indoor play and soft play centres and areas (including inflatable parks and trampolining centres), circuses, fairgrounds, funfairs, zoos and other animal attractions, water parks and theme parks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;indoor attractions at botanical gardens, heritage homes and landmarks must also close, though outdoor grounds of these premises can stay open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;personal care facilities such as hair, beauty, tanning and nail salons. Tattoo parlours, spas, massage parlours, body and skin piercing services must also close. It is also prohibited to provide these services in other people’s homes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;community centres and halls must close except for a limited number of exempt activities, as set out below. Libraries can also remain open to provide access to IT and digital services &amp;#8211; for example for people who do not have it at home &amp;#8211; and for click-and-collect services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These businesses and places will also be permitted to be open for a small number of exempt activities, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;education and training &amp;#8211; for schools to use sports, leisure and community facilities where that is part of their normal provision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;childcare purposes and supervised activities for children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hosting blood donation sessions and food banks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide medical treatment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for elite sports persons to train and compete (in indoor and outdoor sports facilities), and professional dancers and choreographers to work (in fitness and dance studios)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for training and rehearsal without an audience (in theatres and concert halls)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the purposes of professional film and TV filming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Businesses and venues which can remain open&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other businesses and venues are permitted to stay open, following COVID-19 Secure guidelines. This includes those providing essential goods and services, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;essential retail such as food shops, supermarkets, pharmacies, garden centres and Christmas tree retailers, building merchants and suppliers of building products and off-licences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;market stalls selling essential retail may also stay open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;businesses providing repair services may also stay open, where they primarily offer repair services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;petrol stations, automatic (but not manual) car washes, vehicle repair and MOT services, bicycle shops, and taxi and vehicle hire businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;banks, building societies, post offices, short-term loan providers and money transfer businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;funeral directors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;laundrettes and dry cleaners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;medical and dental services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;vets and pet shops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;animal rescue centres, boarding facilities, and animal groomers (may continue to be used for animal welfare, rather than aesthetic purposes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agricultural supplies shops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mobility and disability support shops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;storage and distribution facilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;car parks, public toilets and motorway service areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outdoor playgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outdoor gym, pools, sports courts and facilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;golf courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;archery/driving/shooting ranges (outdoors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;outdoor riding centres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of public services will continue and you will be able to leave home to visit them. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the NHS and medical services like GPs and dentists. We are supporting the NHS to carry out urgent and non-urgent services safely, and it is vital anyone who thinks they need any kind of medical care comes forward and seeks help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jobcentre Plus sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;courts and probation services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;civil registrations offices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;passport and visa services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;services provided to victims&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waste or recycling centres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going to work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help contain the virus, everyone who can work effectively from home should do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where people cannot do so &amp;#8211; including, but not limited to, people who work in critical national infrastructure, construction, or manufacturing &amp;#8211; they should continue to travel to their workplace. This is essential to keeping the country operating and supporting sectors and employers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public sector employees working in essential services, including childcare or education, should continue to go into work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where it is necessary for you to work in other people&amp;#8217;s homes &amp;#8211; for example, for nannies, cleaners or tradespeople &amp;#8211; you can do so. Otherwise, you should avoid meeting for work in a private home or garden, where COVID-19 Secure measures may not be in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk of transmission can be substantially reduced if &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/working-safely-during-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;COVID-19 secure guidelines&lt;/a&gt; are followed closely. Extra consideration should be given to those people at higher risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going to school, college and university&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools and colleges will remain open during term time in Tier 4 areas. The Government will continue to prioritise the wellbeing and long-term futures of our young people. It remains very important for children and young people to attend, to support their wellbeing and education and help working parents and guardians. Senior clinicians still advise that school is the best place for children to be, and so they should continue to go to school during term time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We expect that the majority of students, other than those who need or choose to remain at university, will now have returned to their family home during the ‘student travel window’. We have &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/higher-education-reopening-buildings-and-campuses/student-movement-and-plans-for-the-end-of-autumn-2020-term"&gt;published guidance on how they can do so safely.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have also published &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/higher-education-reopening-buildings-and-campuses/students-returning-to-higher-education-from-spring-term"&gt;guidance to universities and students on how students can return safely to higher education in the spring term&lt;/a&gt;. This guidance sets out how we will support higher education providers to enable students to return as safely as possible following the winter break, by staggering this process and to facilitate testing for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live at university, you should not move back and forward between your permanent home and student home during term time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universities should follow guidance on reopening buildings to ensure they have safety measures in place to minimise the spread of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a student, you can meet in groups of more than your household as part of your formal education or training. Students should expect to follow the guidance and restrictions. You should socially distance from anyone you do not live with wherever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Government has confirmed that all secondary schools and colleges in England will be offered help, support and facilities to implement an additional round of free coronavirus testing from the first week of January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be alongside a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/schools-and-childcare-settings-return-in-january-2021/schools-and-childcare-settings-return-in-january-2021"&gt;staggered return to face-to-face education&lt;/a&gt; in secondary schools, starting with exam years, vulnerable children and children of critical workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The offer of tests builds on the extensive protective measures already in place in schools and colleges to make them safe, as well as the government’s recent announcement that every secondary school and college in England will have access to &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/secondary-schools-and-colleges-to-get-weekly-coronavirus-testing"&gt;rapid testing&lt;/a&gt; from January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In schools and colleges where year 7 and above are educated, face coverings should be worn by adults (staff and visitors) and pupils when moving around indoors, such as in corridors and communal areas where social distancing is difficult to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/education-and-childcare"&gt;guidance for teachers, school leaders, carers and parents on education and childcare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Childcare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways that parents and carers can continue to access childcare in Tier 4 areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;early years settings and childminders remain open, and you can continue to use these settings as normal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can access other childcare activities (including wraparound care) where reasonably necessary to enable parents to work, seek work, attend education or training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nannies will be able to continue to provide services, including in the home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parents are able to form a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-childcare-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;childcare bubble&lt;/a&gt; with one other household for the purposes of informal childcare, where the child is 13 or under&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some households will also be able to benefit from being in a &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;support bubble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some youth services are able to continue, such as 1-1 youth work and support groups, but most youth clubs and groups will need to cease for this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visiting relatives in care homes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visits to care homes can take place with arrangements such as substantial screens, visiting pods, or behind windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close-contact indoor visits supported by testing, which are allowed in Tiers 1-3, will not be allowed in Tier 4. &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/visiting-care-homes-during-coronavirus/update-on-policies-for-visiting-arrangements-in-care-homes"&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; guidance will be updated shortly clarifying how visits in Tier 4 should be conducted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weddings, civil partnerships, religious services and funerals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weddings, civil partnerships, and funerals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weddings, civil partnership ceremonies and funerals must only take place in COVID-19 secure venues or in public outdoor spaces unless in exceptional circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funerals can be attended by a maximum of 30 people. Linked religious, belief-based or commemorative events, such as stone settings and ash scatterings can also continue with up to 6 people in attendance. Anyone working is not counted in these limits. Social distancing should be maintained between people who do not live together or share a support bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weddings and civil partnership ceremonies should not take place except in exceptional circumstances, for example where one of those getting married is seriously ill and not expected to recover (&amp;#8216;deathbed wedding&amp;#8217;) or due to undergo debilitating treatment or life-changing surgery. These weddings are limited to 6 people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in a tier 4 area and are going to a wedding, funeral or linked commemorative event outside the tier 4 area, the event must follow the tier 4 gathering limits on the events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live outside a tier 4 area and are going to a a wedding, funeral or linked commemorative even inside the tier 4 area, you must comply with the tier 4 gathering limits on the events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Places of worship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can attend places of worship for a service. However, you must not mingle with anyone outside of your household or support bubble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should follow the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/covid-19-guidance-for-the-safe-use-of-places-of-worship-during-the-pandemic-from-4-july/special-religious-services-and-gatherings-covid-19-checklist"&gt;national guidance on the safe use of places of worship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sports and physical activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indoor gyms and sports facilities will close. Outdoor sports courts, outdoor gyms, golf courses, outdoor swimming pools, archery/driving/shooting ranges, riding centres and playgrounds can remain open for individual exercise, and for people to use with others within your household, support bubble, or with one person from another household. Organised outdoor sport for under 18s and disabled people will be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can still move home. People outside your household or &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/making-a-support-bubble-with-another-household"&gt;support bubble&lt;/a&gt; should not help with moving house unless absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estate and letting agents and removals firms can continue to work. If you are looking to move, you can go to property viewings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/government-advice-on-home-moving-during-the-coronavirus-covid-19-outbreak"&gt;national guidance on moving home safely&lt;/a&gt;, which includes advice on social distancing and &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/face-coverings-when-to-wear-one-and-how-to-make-your-own/face-coverings-when-to-wear-one-and-how-to-make-your-own"&gt;wearing a face covering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-25/"&gt;Coronavirus (COVID-19)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am very sorry to have to send you another update so soon after the last one, but most of you will now have seen the latest restrictions being introduced for our area. I know many of you will be very upset about what has happened and its impact on Christmas and on [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-25/">Coronavirus (COVID-19)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6060</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T10:02:03Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T10:02:03Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus (COVID19)"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Goods Shed receives final funding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/goods-shed-receives-final-funding/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;img width="500" height="277" src="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=300%2C167&amp;amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?zoom=2&amp;amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="7937" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/goods-shed-receives-final-funding/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=1476%2C823&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1476,823" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1608137868&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="201213 celebrating funding for phase 1 (002)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=300%2C167&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=790%2C440&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Llanelli Railway Goods Shed has now secured the funding needed for phase one of the renovation of this listed building for community use.   &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Garfield
Weston Foundation has stepped in with £90k to add to the funding provided by
the Railway Heritage Trust, Carmarthenshire County Council and Welsh Government.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As Chair of the
Trustees of the Goods Shed, I am grateful to the Garfield Weston Foundation for
pledging these funds to us. This is the final piece of the funding jig-saw which
will enable us to get started.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a really
exciting time for this part of Llanelli. &amp;nbsp;The renovation will give a real boost to the
area. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Local schools
have already been involved with us in exploring the industrial heritage of the
area and the important contribution of the railway to the development of
Llanelli.&amp;nbsp; Through the opportunities in
the renovated building, once again the Goods Shed will be contributing to the local
economy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=300%2C167&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="7937" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2020/12/goods-shed-receives-final-funding/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=1476%2C823&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1476,823" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1608137868&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;1&quot;}" data-image-title="201213 celebrating funding for phase 1 (002)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=300%2C167&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/201213-celebrating-funding-for-phase-1-002.jpg?fit=790%2C440&amp;ssl=1"/>Llanelli Railway Goods Shed has now secured the funding needed for phase one of the renovation of this listed building for community use.   The Garfield Weston Foundation has stepped in with £90k to add to the funding provided by the Railway Heritage Trust, Carmarthenshire County Council and Welsh Government. As Chair of the Trustees of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=7936</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T09:59:02Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T09:59:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Government confirms Winter Fund payout</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/government-confirms-winter-fund-payout" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;West Worcestershire MP Harriett Baldwin has welcomed news that half of the £170 million fund has already been distributed to help local vulnerable families through the winter months. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harriettbaldwin.com/content/government-confirms-winter-fund-payout" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5016 at https://www.harriettbaldwin.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-21T09:58:22Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-21T09:58:22Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our response to Covid must be rational and balanced, not driven by panic</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2020/12/our-response-to-covid-must-be-rational-and-balanced-not-driven-by-panic/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The following article was submitted to the Mail on Sunday in our joint names. It was edited in ways which changed its meaning which we positively rejected. The following is the copy we provided as our final version. By Rt Hon Mark Harper MP (Chair of the Covid Recovery Group) and Steve Baker MP (Deputy Chair of the Covid Recovery Group) For those vulnerable to it, Covid is a dangerous disease so it’s vital we control it effectively.  That’s why we […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Baker</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18336</id>
    <published>2020-12-19T22:11:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T22:11:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="COVID19"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Changes to Christmas Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/changes-to-christmas-restrictions/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Prime Minister announced this evening tighter restrictions for over the Christmas period which is disappointing news for us all. A new coronavirus variant has emerged which spreads considerably more quickly. Cases are now on the rise again, including in Southampton. In the past week the number of cases has increased by over 50% [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/changes-to-christmas-restrictions/">Changes to Christmas Restrictions</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith - At the heart of Southampton</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=3015</id>
    <published>2020-12-19T17:41:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-19T17:41:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Lockdowns are not working, just destroying lives &amp; livelihoods! Tiers should be based on district areas around Covid hospital hubs</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1729-lockdowns-are-not-working-just-destroying-lives-livelihoods-tiers-should-be-based-on-district-areas-around-covid-hospital-hubs"/>
		<published>2020-12-19T16:56:53+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-19T16:56:53+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1729-lockdowns-are-not-working-just-destroying-lives-livelihoods-tiers-should-be-based-on-district-areas-around-covid-hospital-hubs</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lockdowns are not working, just destroying lives &amp;amp; livelihoods! I have contacted Matt Hancock again today urging him to split us from south Herts - our rates are 4-5 times lower with little population movement. Tiers should be based on district areas around Covid hospital hubs 🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1340339047479336963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 19, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Lockdowns are not working, just destroying lives &amp;amp; livelihoods! I have contacted Matt Hancock again today urging him to split us from south Herts - our rates are 4-5 times lower with little population movement. Tiers should be based on district areas around Covid hospital hubs 🤦‍♂️&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1340339047479336963?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 19, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Chippenham High Street Closure</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19.</p>



<p>High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market Place. Alternative route: via Market Place – The Causeway – A4 – Bath Road and vice versa.</p>



<p>The closure and diversion route will be clearly indicated by traffic signs and access will be maintained for residents and businesses where possible throughout the works period.</p>



<p>These works will commence on 21 December 2020 and are anticipated to be required for one day. This Notice will have a maximum duration of 21 days. </p>



<p>For further information regarding these works please contact Tracy Howell on behalf of Chippenham Town Council on 01249446699. Sustainable Transport Group, County Hall, Bythesea Road, Trowbridge BA14 8JN Ref: SH/DEC2020</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="722" src="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-33865" srcset="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1024x722.jpg 1024w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-300x212.jpg 300w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-768x542.jpg 768w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-710x501.jpg 710w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o-1030x726.jpg 1030w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/131990510_2272122249589030_9055211242561496602_o.jpg 1316w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>WILTSHIRE COUNCIL HEREBY GIVE NOTICE that on 21 December 2020, the following length of road shall be closed to all traffic in the interests of public safety to enable Social distancing regulations due to Covid 19. High Street (Part), Chippenham; from a point 50 metres from its junction Bath Road to its junction with Market...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/33864-2/">Chippenham High Street Closure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=33864</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T17:54:45Z</updated>
    <category term="Chippenham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Jack Gebhard</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Worcestershire Council to receive additional £20 million from government]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/worcestershire-council-to-receive-additional-20-million-from-government/"/>

		<id>https://www.walker4worcester.com/?p=2114</id>
		<updated>2020-12-18T17:19:35Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-18T17:19:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="Local Government"/><category scheme="https://www.walker4worcester.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worcester MP, Robin Walker, has welcomed the Government’s announcement that Worcestershire County Council will see its budget boosted by 5.3 per cent next year, as part of the Conservatives’ commitment to level up local services across the country and give them the resources they need to support their communities as we recover from the pandemic. [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/worcestershire-council-to-receive-additional-20-million-from-government/"><![CDATA[<p class="x_MsoNormal">Worcester MP, Robin Walker, has welcomed the Government’s announcement that Worcestershire County Council will see its budget boosted by 5.3 per cent next year, as part of the Conservatives’ commitment to level up local services across the country and give them the resources they need to support their communities as we recover from the pandemic.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Local authorities in England, including Worcestershire County Council, will receive a share of £51.2 billion local government funding next year – up £2.2 billion on this year. Funding for key public services will again be protected, with significant extra resources dedicated to areas where they are needed most. Thanks to the investment being made by the Conservatives, Worcestershire will have an extra £20.27 million to spend next year.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The local government finance settlement sets out how much councils have to spend vital local services each year, including social care which will see a £1 billion increase in funding next year as a result of the announcement. In total, local authorities across England will receive an extra £5 billion in support next year, including a further £1.55 billion in additional grant funding to cover costs relating to the pandemic and an extra £670 million to help families facing hardship with their council tax bills.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is on top of the more than £7.2 billion in additional funding given to local areas throughout the pandemic so far to protect vital services that have kept vulnerable people and communities safe.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Commenting, Robin said:  </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“Local authorities play a vital role in our communities, providing the crucial local services that people rely on every day. Worcester residents will benefit as their county council will have an additional £20 million in funding this year thanks to the Government. These funds will help our local leaders make positive change in the area.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“This builds on the significant funding boost the council received at the beginning of the year, underlying our determination to ensure all local authorities have the resources they need to drive forward our recovery in a way that works for our community as we build back better after the pandemic.”</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal"><b>Commenting, Local Government Secretary Robert Jenrick said:  </b></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“Councils have played a critical role leading their communities during the pandemic and delivering vital local services to vulnerable people and we have supported them with £7.2 billion extra funding to date.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">“That’s why I am announcing a financial package that will provide over £5 billion of extra support next year. This will give councils the resources they need to lead the recovery of their communities while delivering the services that people rely on.”</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">Thanks to measures introduced by the Conservatives, taxpayers in Worcester now have a stronger voice over council tax rises than ever before.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This means local residents have the power to veto excessive council tax rises, with a referendum being required if councils propose raising the tax by 2% or more; Councils with responsibility for adult social care will be able to set a further 3% increase, ring-fenced exclusively for adult social care. Anything above this level will also need to be voted on by local people. This strikes the right balance between addressing pressure on services and giving council-tax payers the final say on excessive increases.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/worcestershire-council-to-receive-additional-20-million-from-government/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.walker4worcester.com/2020/12/worcestershire-council-to-receive-additional-20-million-from-government/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=loneliness-and-our-communities" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="5663" class="elementor elementor-5663" data-elementor-settings="[]">
						<div class="elementor-inner">
							<div class="elementor-section-wrap">
							<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-27b274df elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="27b274df" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
							<div class="elementor-row">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-71d5ac96" data-id="71d5ac96" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated">
							<div class="elementor-widget-wrap">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-3b39d78c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="3b39d78c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
					<div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"><p><!-- wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p>
<p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances none of us would have imagined. As we look to the light provided by new vaccines and as we approach a new year, there is yet another nasty legacy sting in the tail of 2020 – a rise in feelings of loneliness.</p>
<p>Research from Age UK has shown that this Christmas is set to be the loneliest yet for older people. Over 160,000 people over the age of 65 will suffer from feeling lonely this festive season, with nearly 60% of them fearing that they won’t see any family and friends. Those are heartbreaking numbers, even one person feeling like this is one too many.</p>
<p>Our communities can carry another more positive legacy from 2020. The Age UK research also highlighted that over 100,000 older people were helped to get through the pandemic by the kindness of strangers. The simple act of checking on people made a life-enhancing difference for so many, we can never know for sure, but it’s probably safe to assume that in some instances, it was life-saving.</p>
<p>Of course, loneliness and isolation don’t discriminate; young people are also affected. The Office of National statistics were able to point out that, during the first month of the pandemic, 7. 4 million people, across the nations of the UK said that their wellbeing was affected through feeling isolated.</p>
<p>We all knew that these restrictions were essential to protect lives, but the collateral effect was, as predicted, substantial. Recently, we have become more aware of a problem that has existed for some time but rarely brought into public debate. Work undertaken for the charities MIND and Mental Health UK confirmed that young people are particularly affected by loneliness.</p>
<p>During the pandemic almost half of 18-24-year-olds experienced, and those aged 25-34 are twice – yes twice – as likely to be lonely at Christmas than older people. That’s a lot of lonely people out there feeling isolated.</p>
<p>While we cannot visit indoors, there are many other ways we can help people feel less isolated. Given that a third of people are too embarrassed to admit that they are lonely, it is small acts that make a difference; it might be a note through the door or a phone call to someone you haven’t spoken to in a while. Simple offers of contact, help with shopping, a chat a few steps back from the doorstep could mean a big deal to reassure folk that they are valued and to feel a little less alone.</p>
<p>If you need to talk to someone over the festive period, or any other time, the below contacts offer free and non-judgemental help;</p>
<p>MikeysLine 01463 729000</p>
<p>Breathing Space 0800 83 85 87</p>
<p>Samaritans 116 123</p>
<p>Mind 0300 123 3393</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Keep up to date with new articles at <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot">www.drewhendrymp.scot</a></p>
<p>Find out more about my work in parliament at <a href="http://www.theyworkforyou.com">www.theyworkforyou.com</a></p>
<p><!-- /wp:tadv/classic-paragraph --></p></div>
				</div>
				</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		</div>
								</div>
					</div>
		</section>
						</div>
						</div>
					</div>
		<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>2020 has left us with many legacies as we’ve coped with a set of circumstances...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/loneliness-and-our-communities/">Loneliness doesn’t discriminate, it’s all around us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=5663</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:56:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Better buses on their way? – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/better-buses-on-their-way-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=better-buses-on-their-way-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233184" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/Better-buses.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Over half of all bus journeys in England take place within just one city. It won’t surprise you to know that the city in question is London, but that statistic is still shocking. In 2018/19, 2.2 billion bus journeys were made in the capital compared to 2.12 billion in the whole of the rest of the country. And each year the gap in bus use between London and the rest of England grows. Over the past decade, bus use in London has decreased by just 1.4%, whilst elsewhere it has shrunk by an incredible 11.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;There are, of course, many reasons for this imbalance between London and the rest of the country, but they are all linked. The fact is that London has the best bus system in the country – the buses are cheaper, more frequent, there are more routes and they are integrated with other public transport. That London has better buses is no accident. It all comes back to Margaret Thatcher’s Tory Government in the 80s, which deregulated buses everywhere in England… other than London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;I’ve written about how immensely damaging this deregulation has been for Greater Manchester previously. Our buses are far too expensive (all bus journeys in London are just £1.50, including unlimited changes within 90 minutes), too irregular and we have to fight to keep vital routes running as some private operators focus on profit over service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Unfortunately, this deregulation has created something of a vicious circle. The worse our bus services become, the fewer people use them, which leads them to get even worse and even fewer people to use them, and so on and so on. We need to break this cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Luckily, our Metro Mayor Andy Burnham gets this and wants major reform of our buses, bringing them under local control. There is a consultation on the proposals for a new franchising system and I’d encourage you to take part at&lt;span class="apple-converted-space"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gmconsult.org/"&gt;www.gmconsult.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="apple-converted-space"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;before the 29 January deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;
&lt;p class="xmsonormal"&gt;Buses are a vital lifeline for those without access to private cars, but they should be much more than that. In the future for transport that I’d like to see, buses would be the preferred method of transport for local journeys by those both with and without cars. For this to become a reality though, we urgently need a better bus system where taking the bus is a cheap, convenient and pleasant experience. Thankfully, I think Greater Manchester is heading firmly in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/better-buses-on-their-way-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/"&gt;Better buses on their way? &amp;#8211; my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over half of all bus journeys in England take place within just one city. It won’t surprise you to know that the city in question is London, but that statistic is still shocking. In 2018/19, 2.2 billion bus journeys were made in the capital compared to 2.12 billion in the whole of the rest of […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/better-buses-on-their-way-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Better buses on their way? – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233183</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:44:09Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:44:09Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-38/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The last full week before Christmas is always a busy one in Parliament and the constituency and this year is no different. Firstly, this week saw me elected as Vice Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Archives and History. This is a really important APPG as it stands on a cross-party basis to push for the preservation of local history up and down the country. We all know the value of keeping our history alive and that means that we need all levels of government working together to preserve our archives for future generations. In these times of the COVID pandemic, one of the consequences is we are not having conversations with older members of the community and history is not being passed on to younger generations. I will be using my position as Vice Chair to push for decent funding for local history groups and increased awareness campaigns that show people the tremendous resources we have at our disposal to learn more.</p>
<p>As co-chair of the APPG Hairdressing, Barbering and Cosmetology I met virtually with the APPG officers to review our ongoing campaign to support those in this industry who have not received any help from the UK Government during the coronavirus pandemic, and plan the action we propose to take in 2021. We have written many letters to the Chancellor and the Secretary of State for BEIS, highlighting the plight of businesses and mobile practitioners, but the responses we have received make it clear that the UK Government has no respect for the many people employed in the hair and beauty industry who have contributed so much to the UK economy, £6 billion in the last year. We have been working with Keith Conniford, CEO and Registrar of the Hair Council, to secure a pledge from the UK Government to implement mandatory registration for the industry, which would have helped considerably in our campaign to obtain funding and grants for the dedicated members of this profession who have struggled to stay afloat during the past 9 months of the pandemic. But the UK Government are not interested.</p>
<p>Keeping our streets safe is so important to me and underpins everything I do in my role as your MP. That is why I attended a virtual meeting with the new Chief Constable of South Wales Police, Jeremy Vaughan, and Police and Crime Commissioner Alun Michael. I took this opportunity to welcome the new Chief Constable to his role and set out my aspirations for how community policing should be the bedrock of all activities undertaken by South Wales Police going forward.</p>
<p>I also took this opportunity to ask the Chief Constable to thank all the police officers in my constituency for all they do and wish them all the very best for 2021. We should not forget that our emergency responders will be working throughout this Christmas and New Year period. They will be keeping us safe, running towards danger and demonstrating all the values that make Neath such a special community. We should all be so grateful for the dedicated work they do.</p>
<p>I am also vice-Chair of the APPG on Gaps in Support, which exists to find solutions for those who have been excluded from UK Government support schemes during the Coronavirus pandemic. This cross-party group is currently gathering evidence to understand how people may have fallen through the gaps in support. We have been hearing from those whose lives and livelihoods have been negatively impacted and once we have collected all this evidence, we will be making our recommendations to the UK Government.</p>
<p>Our group has been extremely active over recent weeks, publishing our response to the Spending Review and the UK Government’s impact analysis into Covid-19. Being part of such an important All-Party Parliamentary Group ensures that we can have Neath’s voice heard at the highest levels of UK government.</p>
<p>The APPG Suicide and Self-Harm Prevention recently conducted an enquiry into support for young people who self-harm, and I joined in the follow up Zoom call meeting which looked at self-harm during Covid-19. We heard from experts who are gathering evidence, through research and surveys, which will form the basis of our recommendations to the UK Government. We listened to Professor Keith Hawton, Director of Oxford University Centre for Suicide Research and Consultant Psychiatrist at Oxford Health NHS Foundation Trust; Professor Nav Kapur, who leads the suicide work programme of National Confidential enquiry into suicide and homicide by people with mental illness; and Dr Lynne Green, Chief Clinical Officer at Koothplc, one of the biggest providers of digital mental health in the UK with one of the world’s largest anonymised data sets. The Samaritans provide the secretariat for the APPG.</p>
<p>The Speaker of the House of Commons Lynsey Hoyle and the Lord Speaker Rt Hon the Lord Fowler held the first ever virtual <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VpyoJkAqLnw">Parliamentary Carol Service</a> from Westminster Hall. The Most Reverend the Rt Hon Justin Welby gave his Christmas sermon about the pain and suffering endured this year, that Christmas brings comfort and joy, out of the darkness will come light and hope with the roll out of the vaccine. There were many bible readings from religious representatives in Parliament. We heard carols from St. Martin’s Voices and the Soul Sanctuary Gospel Choir. The Speaker’s Chaplain, Reverend Tricia Hillis, said prayers.</p>
<p>The Dogs Trust is a charity that I have long supported. Their campaigns have been really important for protecting the safety and welfare of dogs both at home and abroad. Their puppy smuggling campaign was relaunched this year to raise awareness of the illegal dog trade across Europe.</p>
<p>I was delighted to join the Dogs Trust ‘Puppy Smuggling Taskforce’ to raise awareness of and tackle the abhorrent puppy smuggling trade. At a time when the demand for dogs in the UK has never been higher, I want to urge my constituents to really do their research before buying a puppy advertised for sale online.</p>
<p>On Thursday afternoon I chaired the concluding stage of one <a href="https://parliamentlive.tv/Event/Index/04da0aba-f4d4-4811-8e69-38e8ab0529be">Westminster Hall debate</a> and the opening stage of the following debate. The first debate was about the future of Fairs and Showgrounds. Members discussed the lack of financial support for the many fairs and show-grounds that have had to close during the pandemic. The Minister responded with a long list of UK Government schemes set up by the Chancellor, which on the whole, members pointed out, were ineligible for showmen, who form part of the 3 million excluded. I found myself thinking about Donald Coleman, the former MP for Neath, who tragically and suddenly died in 1991. Donald was the only honorary member of the Showman’s Guild in Great Britain, and in my Maiden Speech, I told the story of Neath through the images contained in Donald’s stained glass window, which forms part of St Thomas’ Church.</p>
<p>The second debate was about UK Hydrogen Economy, which was secured by a backbencher who believed that the hydrogen economy will be transformative for the UK, enable decarbonisation across all sectors, achieving a net zero target, create skilled jobs and position the U.K. as a world leader. Members spoke about hydrogen transport, heating, gas network, renewable fuel, decarbonisation, green hydrogen and the Government’s Energy White Paper published on Tuesday which announced a £240 million hydrogen fund in its 10 point plan.</p>
<p>As always, if you have any questions or issues and want to get in touch about any matters that fall under my role as an MP, please do not hesitate to drop us an email on christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk or call us on 01639 630152. My staff are working from home to comply with the social distancing measures, but, as always, we remain there should you need to get in contact with us.</p>
<p>I hope you stay well, and remember – observe social distancing, wash your hands regularly and keep Wales safe.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The last full week before Christmas is always a busy one in Parliament and the constituency and this year is no different. Firstly, this week saw me elected as Vice Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Archives and History. This is a really important APPG as it stands on a cross-party basis to push […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2341</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T16:31:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T16:31:17Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Restrictions in Northumberland - FAQs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/restrictions-northumberland-faqs" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Please find below the answers to the most common questions I am receiving from people about the ongoing restrictions and how we can move out of them.
 
I know a lot of people are disappointed by the decision to place us in tier 3 in the first instance, and I will explain below why that decision has…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/restrictions-northumberland-faqs</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex&#8217;s 2020 Annual Report]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/12/alexs-2020-annual-report/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=13831</id>
		<updated>2020-12-18T10:50:14Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-18T10:50:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2020/12/alexs-2020-annual-report/">Alex&#8217;s 2020 Annual Report</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>West Mercia Police to receive an additional £13m next year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/west-mercia-police-receive-additional-ps13m-next-year" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="6863" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;18 December 2020&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;West Mercia Police to receive an additional £13m next year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Mercia Police is set to receive an additional £13m in its funding next year, thanks to the Government’s increase to police budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home Secretary Priti Patel has announced policing will receive up to £15.8 billion in 2021-22 – an increase of £636 million on last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes over £400 million to recruit 20,000 extra police officers by 2023, delivering on the promise made by the Conservatives in last year’s General Election. West Mercia has already benefited from an additional 105 officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funding will be also be used to bolster counter-terrorism policing, including money for armed policing and more officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conservative Government has been determined to support the police throughout the coronavirus pandemic, as officers have worked tirelessly to keep communities safe. The Government has provided £30 million to help forces step up coronavirus enforcement and has reimbursed forces for all additional PPE purchased between March and July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Dunne said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Officers and staff at West Mercia have been instrumental in keeping our community safe this year, and I pay tribute to them for their hard work and professionalism, particularly in this challenging year. I have engaged with Police leaders here in Shropshire throughout the pandemic, and commend local officers for the way in which they have applied their tact and good judgment to keep our community safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to see West Mercia getting an additional £13m next year. I know the presence of additional officers on our streets has already helped reassure local residents. I look forward to speaking to our Police &amp; Crime Commissioner, John Campion, to learn how he intends to deploy the extra resource in South Shropshire.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6863 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T10:08:34Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T10:08:34Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Over 100 Parliamentarians urge the UK Government to take action to protect the Rohingya against genocide</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p style="background: white;">
          <span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: black;">104 Parliamentarians from across parties are calling on the UK Government to take urgent action to protect the Rohingya Muslim minority from persecution from the Myanmar Government and military. </span>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/over_100_parliamentarians_urge_the_uk_government_to_take_action_to_protect_the_rohingya_against_genocide</id>
    <published>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-18T09:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas &amp; New Year office opening hours &amp; useful contacts</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-new-year-office-opening-hours-useful-contacts-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;"&gt;Information about office opening hours &lt;span style="color:#06396a;"&gt;and who to contact for support over the festive period&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_empty_space"   style="height: 20px" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_empty_space_inner"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " &gt;
		&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Due to the festive break, my office will close on Friday 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December and re-open on Monday 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an urgent query, such as homelessness, please email details to &lt;a href="mailto:abrahamsd@parliament.uk"&gt;abrahamsd@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;. This mailbox will be checked intermittently for urgent cases only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not have access to emails, you can call &amp;amp; leave a voicemail regarding your urgent matter with details on 07494553005 or 07495995509.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other enquiries will be dealt with when the office re-opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you have a safe break over the festive period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debbie Abrahams MP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham East &amp;amp; Saddleworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful contacts/information for the festive period:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/making-a-christmas-bubble-with-friends-and-family/making-a-christmas-bubble-with-friends-and-family"&gt;Government guidance&lt;/a&gt; for Christmas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Metropolitan Borough Council &amp;#8211; Full information about Oldham Council closures and contact numbers can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.oldham.gov.uk/christmasclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Homelessness Advice Team: Outreach Service 0161 770 4605&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Emergency 24 hour homelessness team: 0800 988 7061&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Coronavirus helpline: 0161 770 7007&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social services (out of hours emergency only) &amp;#8211;  0161 770 6936&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council First Response team &amp;#8211; 0161 770 2222&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police General Switchboard (24 hours) &amp;#8211; 101&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police emergencies (24 hours) &amp;#8211; 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical emergencies:  visit your local &lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/service-search" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hospital&lt;/a&gt; or call 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-urgent medical advice &amp;#8211; 111&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas (24 hour emergency helpline) – 0800 111 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity North West (24 hour emergency helpline) &amp;#8211; 105&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Utilities website and details &lt;a href="https://www.unitedutilities.com/emergencies/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizens Advice Bureau national phone service: &lt;a href="tel:08001448848"&gt;0800 144 8848&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater Manchester Law Centre: 0161 769 2244&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Foodbank: &lt;a href="tel:0161 622 1061"&gt;0161 622 1061&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Welfare Rights: 0161 770 6655&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcho.co.uk/contact-us/ways-to-contact-us/"&gt;First Choice Homes Oldham: &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact centre: 0161 393 7117&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For heating issues, ring SURE group: 03333 212797&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emergency repairs: 0161 770 2222.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="media island"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="media__body font--m"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"&gt;&lt;h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;"&gt;Feel strongly about this article? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"&gt;&lt;a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact"&gt;Contact Debbie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-new-year-office-opening-hours-useful-contacts-2/"&gt;Christmas &amp;#038; New Year office opening hours &amp;#038; useful contacts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk"&gt;Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-new-year-office-opening-hours-useful-contacts-2/">Christmas &amp; New Year office opening hours &amp; useful contacts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6726</id>
    <published>2020-12-17T17:32:17Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-17T17:32:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bill Wiggin MP pleased but urges caution as Herefordshire moves into Tier 1 restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/17/bill-wiggin-mp-pleased-but-urges-caution-as-herefordshire-moves-into-tier-1-restrictions/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bill Wiggin, MP for North Herefordshire, has given his reaction after Herefordshire was named in Tier 1 of the Government’s coronavirus restrictions. Mr Wiggin said: “We have been doing very well in Herefordshire because our population is responsible, careful and... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2020/12/17/bill-wiggin-mp-pleased-but-urges-caution-as-herefordshire-moves-into-tier-1-restrictions/#more-3746">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3746</id>
    <published>2020-12-17T14:32:06Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-17T14:32:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jonathan Djanogly writes to Health Secretary to seek lower tier for Huntingdonshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-writes-health-secretary-seek-lower-tier-huntingdonshire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Djanogly has written to the Secretary of State for Health and Social Care calling for Cambridgeshire’s district councils to be the geographical level at which tier-based restrictions are decided which would increase the chances of Huntingdonshire moving to tier 1. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/jonathan-djanogly-writes-health-secretary-seek-lower-tier-huntingdonshire" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5018 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2020-12-16T12:43:35Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-16T12:43:35Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP welcomes Covid-19 vaccine hub in his constituency</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-covid-19-vaccine-hub-in-his-constituency/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2020/12/10869/eovtwrvwmaegtuk/" rel="attachment wp-att-10870"><img loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-10870" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-740x416.jpg" alt="" width="740" height="416" srcset="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-740x416.jpg 740w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-300x169.jpg 300w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/EoVTWrVWMAEGtuk.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 740px) 100vw, 740px"/></a></p>
<p>The MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, has welcomed that Holderness Health in his constituency is one of the first GP practices to offer the Pfizer-BioNTech vaccination against Covid-19 to their most vulnerable patients.</p>
<p>The UK became the first country in the world to approve the vaccine on 2nd December, when the independent Medicines &amp; Healthcare products Regulatory Agency gave it the go-ahead. The NHS is now in the process of delivering the largest programme of immunisation in the country’s history, and subsequently announced that Castle Hill Hospital would act as a vaccine hub to protect the most vulnerable patients and healthcare staff in the region.</p>
<p>Now, GP practices are being added to the list of sites approved to administer the vaccine, despite health bosses having to contend with the practicalities of storing and transporting the vaccine, which must be stored between -80°C and -60°C and given to patients within six hours of being thawed.</p>
<p>As a result, Holderness Health has been chosen as one of four local Covid-19 vaccination centres in Hull and the East Riding, with more practices joining on a phased basis over the course of the coming months. The first GP-led vaccinations were carried out at Holderness Health yesterday afternoon (14th December).</p>
<p>Patients over the age of 80 with the greatest clinical risk are being offered appointments first, with priority groups determined by the Joint Committee on Vaccination &amp; Immunisation. Eventually, mass vaccinations will be offered in sports venues and conference centres once further vaccine supplies become available.</p>
<p>Graham commented, “This is fantastic news for vulnerable constituents in Beverley and Holderness, who will be among the first to be offered this vaccination by their family GPs.</p>
<p>“I know Holderness Health have plenty of experience in delivering safe and effective vaccination programmes, as they do every year with the flu jab, so I have every confidence that they will rise to the challenge despite its scale and complexity.</p>
<p>“The public can really help with this by not contacting the surgery to ask for a jab, because eligible people will be proactively contacted by phone, letter, or the national booking system.”</p>
<p>For it to be effective, people are required to have two doses of the vaccine 3 weeks apart and the NHS is urging people to ensure that they book their jabs when contacted and are emphasising the importance of attending both appointments: Dr Craig Dobson, medical advisor to the East Riding CCG (Clinical Commissioning Group) said, “The vaccine has been shown to be effective and it is fantastic news that in our local area we can start to vaccinate our more vulnerable residents, who need it most.</p>
<p>“If you are in one of the priority groups, I would urge that when your GP Practice contacts you, please make sure you book and attend your appointments when you arrange them.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The MP for Beverley and Holderness, Graham Stuart, has welcomed that Holderness Health in his constituency is one of the first GP practices to offer...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=10869</id>
    <published>2020-12-15T16:59:12Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T16:59:12Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="Covid-19"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Holderness"/>
    <category term="Holderness Health"/>
    <category term="Hospital"/>
    <category term="NHS"/>
    <category term="Vaccine"/>
    <category term="Withernsea"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE TO REMAIN IN LEVEL 3 COVID RESTRICTIONS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-to-remain-in-level-3-covid-restrictions/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has responded to the announcement that West Dunbartonshire is to remain in Level 3 restrictions along with 18 other local authority areas following this week’s review of Covid-19 protection levels. The Level 3 restrictions are expected … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-to-remain-in-level-3-covid-restrictions/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-to-remain-in-level-3-covid-restrictions/">WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE TO REMAIN IN LEVEL 3 COVID RESTRICTIONS</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1480442</id>
    <published>2020-12-15T15:12:21Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-15T15:12:21Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meeting Father Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I met Father Christmas in Marks and Spencers' Car Park on Sunday 13 December. He had been invited there by the Beckenham Roatary Club of which I an also a member. It was the first time I have seen him this year and he said would be delivering presents to children as normal what ever happened over…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/meeting-father-christmas</id>
    <published>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://lucianaberger.com/23/lambed/07/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man - Brexit </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As we approach the end of this terrible year I suspect I will not cheer anyone up by reminding them that the end of the Brexit transition period is very close. It is a matter of huge interest to the whole country but is of course of particular concern to us in Kent because of the possibility of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-brexit-0</id>
    <published>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-10T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WGC Becomes Location for First Ever Green Number Plate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=wgc-becomes-location-for-first-ever-green-number-plate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0 et_pb_bg_layout_light  et_pb_text_align_left"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_text_inner"&gt;
					&lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welwyn Hatfield MP and Transport Secretary Grant Shapps recently visited Halfords autocentres in Welwyn Garden City to have the first ever ‘green number plate’ fitted. This comes as the country prepares for the mass adoption of electric vehicles ahead of the UK ending its contribution to climate change by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number plate consists of a green coloured flash on the left-hand side of the plate to designate the vehicle as having zero emissions at tailpipe. The plates are now available to the general public and will be included with all new zero-emissions-vehicles unless customers choose to opt out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said the move “Underlined the Government’s commitment to tackling poor air quality in the UK’s towns and cities. It builds on last month’s announcement to end the sale of new petrol and diesel cars and vans in the UK by 2030, putting the UK on course to be the fastest G7 country to decarbonise these vehicles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of the new plates on UK roads will raise awareness of the growing number of zero emission vehicles, as well as helping motorists benefit from possible local initiatives such as special parking spaces and cost-free entry into zero-emission zones such as the one in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr Shapps said: “A green recovery is key to helping us achieve our net zero carbon commitments while also promoting economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Green number plates could unlock a number of incentives for drivers and increase awareness of cleaner vehicles on our roads, showing people that a greener transport future is within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt; &lt;!-- divi:paragraph --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re supporting small businesses to develop the transport tech of the future through a multi-million-pound investment, ensuring that&amp;nbsp;UK&amp;nbsp;businesses remain at the forefront of low carbon innovation and research.’’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video was produced during the visit, which can be viewed below:&lt;span style="font-size: 14px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- /divi:paragraph --&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_text --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_1 et_section_regular"&gt;
				
				
				
				
					&lt;div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1"&gt;
				&lt;div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1    et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0  et_pb_text_align_center"&gt;
				
				
				&lt;div class="et_pb_code_inner"&gt;
					&lt;iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=476&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F719013365401804%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=476" width="476" height="476" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code_inner --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_code --&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_column --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_row --&gt;
				
				
			&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- .et_pb_section --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=30910</id>
    <published>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T17:06:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Green Number Plates"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Garden City"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE WELCOMES DECISION TO EXCLUDE BABY AND TODDLER GROUPS FROM GATHERING LIMITS IN ALL COVID TIERS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-welcomes-decision-to-exclude-baby-and-toddler-groups-from-gathering-limits-in-all-covid-tiers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, MP for Newcastle North and Chair of the House of Commons Petitions Committee, has welcomed the news that the Government has updated Covid-19 guidance to exempt baby and toddler groups from gatherings limits in all tiers. The change follows a landmark report from the Petitions Committee which looked at the effect of the … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-welcomes-decision-to-exclude-baby-and-toddler-groups-from-gathering-limits-in-all-covid-tiers/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE WELCOMES DECISION TO EXCLUDE BABY AND TODDLER GROUPS FROM GATHERING LIMITS IN ALL COVID TIERS</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7017</id>
    <published>2020-12-09T16:42:36Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-09T16:42:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Women and Equalities"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="maternity"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[HAVE YOUR SAY ON THE FUTURE OF BUSES]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/"/>

		<id>http://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=341</id>
		<updated>2020-12-09T13:20:32Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-09T13:18:48Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2020/12/09/have-your-say-on-the-future-of-buses/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Vaccine Breakthrough!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/vaccine-breakthrough/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last week we were all delighted at the news that the UK became the first country in the world to approve the Pfizer-BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine.</p>
<p>I am therefore equally pleased that the vaccine has now arrived in the West Midlands and in the Borough of Walsall.</p>
<p>No one underestimates the extent of the challenge ahead of us to roll out the vaccine to the whole population, but we now have light at the end of the tunnel and a route map out of the pandemic.</p>
<p>It is important however to remember and recognise thought that whilst the vaccine is being rolled out it remains we must continue to follow the rules as a Tier 3 area and observe the basics of – Hands, Face and Space! It is incumbent upon us all to continue to play our part in tackling the Covid-19 pandemic.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week we were all delighted at the news that the UK became the first country in the world to approve the Pfizer-BioNTech Covid-19 vaccine. I am therefore equally pleased that the vaccine has now arrived in the West Midlands and in the Borough of Walsall. No one underestimates the extent of the challenge ahead […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3480</id>
    <published>2020-12-08T11:44:35Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-08T11:44:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bristol South MP warns constituents about electrical safety in the run-up to Christmas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/12/04/bristol-south-mp-warns-constituents-about-electrical-safety-in-the-run-up-to-christmas/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=bristol-south-mp-warns-constituents-about-electrical-safety-in-the-run-up-to-christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p><strong>Bristol South MP warns constituents about electrical safety in the run-up to Christmas</strong></p>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, is encouraging all constituents to put safety first when shopping online for their Christmas presents this year.</p>
<p>With online marketplaces not bound by the same laws as traditional retailers, fake and dangerous electrical products are being sold to unknowing customers. Containing sub-standard or counterfeit parts, they present a serious risk of fire or electric shock.  In research conducted by Electrical Safety First, 14 out of 15 sampled products from third-party sellers failed basic safety tests.</p>
<p>Electrical Safety First are encouraging consumers to make sure you buy from a recognisable and reputable seller, to check packaging and the item carefully for tell-tale signs that the product is not genuine, and to check for safety certifications on labelling.</p>
<p><strong>Karin Smyth said: </strong></p>
<p>“With Covid restrictions still affecting everyday life, many constituents will be doing their Christmas shopping online this year.</p>
<p>“If you are planning on buying electrical goods please make sure that you buy from a recognisable and reputable seller. Avoid third-party sellers for electrical goods and if you are unsure at all when your product arrives, do not use it.</p>
<p>“I know it’s been a tough year and finances are tight, but it’s not worth risking fire and electrocution to save a few pounds”.</p><p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/12/04/bristol-south-mp-warns-constituents-about-electrical-safety-in-the-run-up-to-christmas/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP warns constituents about electrical safety in the run-up to Christmas</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Bristol South MP warns constituents about electrical safety in the run-up to Christmas Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, is […]</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2020/12/04/bristol-south-mp-warns-constituents-about-electrical-safety-in-the-run-up-to-christmas/" target="_blank">Bristol South MP warns constituents about electrical safety in the run-up to Christmas</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/" target="_blank">Karin Smyth</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2823</id>
    <published>2020-12-04T13:12:58Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T13:12:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid-19 Tier Restrictions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2020/12/02/covid-19-tier-restrictions/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Yesterday (01/12/20), Parliament was presented with a simple, for or against, choice to vote on the renewed ‘Tier’ restrictions which have subsequently come into place this morning and the additional financial support package on offer to businesses, workers and households across Gateshead and the North East.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I wanted to take some time to explain my position on this matter and why I voted against the imposition of this package yesterday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>At the outset, I absolutely agree with experts here in Gateshead and Nationally that we must prevent the spread of Covid-19 throughout our communities.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>I also agree that the best way to do this is through limiting social interaction especially among meetings of multiple households.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The package of restrictions are not perfect, they appear to be ever more complicated and the allocation of tiers to different regions appears to be unequal at first glance, with areas in the North and North East subjected to greater levels of restrictions compared to other parts of the UK with similar or higher rates of incidence of Covid-19.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>To this end, I have formally requested the Government publish the criteria used and set out some clarity on how regions will move between tiers while we await the rollout of a number of vaccine programmes.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The restrictions in place since the spring, closing large numbers of businesses across Gateshead and limiting the trade of so many others, have had an incredibly damaging impact on the lives and livelihoods and overall wellbeing of so many people.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The Government has a duty and the means to provide proper financial support to these businesses and their employees, and to this end, I firmly believe they have failed. While the initial business rate grant scheme and the furlough scheme seemed generous, many millions of people have been left without any support whatsoever and continue to be ignored 9 months on.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>In addition, businesses in Gateshead which have either had to remain closed or have been once again forced to close – hospitality, fitness suites and retail particularly – alongside many self employed workers; have been left with meagre amounts of support, if any, as many businesses enter what would traditionally be their busiest trading period.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>The Government appear to have prioritised funnelling billions of pounds of tax payer money into, sometimes selective, elements of the private sector to provide inadequate PPE and an ineffective test, track and trace system. Instead, they should be prioritising financial support for businesses, employees and families affected.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>Failure to do so has not only had a detrimental impact on the health and wellbeing of so many people, but it has had a detrimental impact on adherence to the restrictions. The Government must understand that many people can not work from home and do not have ready access to utilities and food, and many can not afford to withstand repeated periods of self isolation without proper financial support – Statutory Sick Pay is simply totally inadequate.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span>Notwithstanding the urgent need to restrict the spread of Covid-19, I voted against the motion yesterday evening, as I firmly believe the Government can and must do more to provide adequate financial support for every person and business affected.</p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I have raised the inadequate financial support with the Government since the spring and will continue to do so until they meet their responsibility in full.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">Now that the North East is officially subject to tier 3 restrictions, I would urge all residents to follow the rules closely, as this is the only way we can reduce the spread of the virus enough to move down the tier system. With our infection rates declining, because of everyone’s efforts and with positive news of vaccinations in the very near future, it is imperative that we all do whatever we can to further drive down the spread of Covid-19.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;"> </span><span style="font-style: inherit; font-weight: inherit;">I hope this sets out my view clearly, however, if you have any further questions please do contact my office.</span></p>
<p>Stay safe,</p>
<p>Ian Mearns MP</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Yesterday (01/12/20), Parliament was presented with a simple, for or against, choice to vote on the renewed ‘Tier’ restrictions which have subsequently come into place this morning and the additional</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20754</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T10:10:07Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-02T10:10:07Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Ians votes"/>
    <category term="COVID-19"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I won’t be voting for Government restrictions today</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/NzcI-YaqHgI/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4760</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T13:01:38Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T13:01:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Blogs"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tier 2 Lockdown Rules</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2020/tier-2-lockdown-rules/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=tier-2-lockdown-rules" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;From the 2nd of December Hampshire will be in Tier 2, this means:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;you must not socialise with anyone you do not live with or who is not in your support bubble in any indoor setting, whether at home or in a public place&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you must not socialise in a group of more than 6 people outside, including in a garden or a public space&amp;nbsp;– this is called the ‘rule of 6’&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;businesses and venues can continue to operate, in a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/working-safely-during-coronavirus-covid-19"&gt;COVID-Secure&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;manner, other than those which remain closed by law, such as nightclubs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;pubs and bars must close, unless operating as restaurants. Hospitality venues can only serve alcohol with substantial meals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;hospitality businesses selling food or drink for consumption on their premises are required to:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;provide table service only, in premises which sell alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;close between 11pm and 5am (hospitality venues in airports, ports, transport services and motorway service areas are exempt)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;stop taking orders after 10pm&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;hospitality businesses and venues selling food and drink for consumption off the premises can continue to do so after 10pm as long as this is through delivery service, click-and-collect or drive-through&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;early closure (11pm) applies to casinos, cinemas, theatres, museums, bowling alleys, amusement arcades, funfairs, theme parks, adventure parks and activities, and bingo halls. Cinemas, theatres and concert halls can stay open beyond 11pm in order to conclude performances&amp;nbsp; that start before 10pm&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;public attendance at outdoor and indoor events (performances and shows) is permitted, limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;public attendance at spectator sport and business events can resume inside and outside, subject to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing/coronavirus-covid-19-meeting-with-others-safely-social-distancing?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae"&gt;social contact rules&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and limited to whichever is lower: 50% capacity, or either 2,000 people outdoors or 1,000 people indoors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;places of worship remain open but you must not socialise with people from outside of your household or support bubble while you are indoors there, unless a legal exemption applies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;weddings and funerals can go ahead with restrictions on numbers of attendees – 15 people can attend wedding ceremonies and receptions, 30 people can attend funeral ceremonies, and 15 people can attend linked commemorative events such as wakes&amp;nbsp; or stonesettings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;organised outdoor sport, and physical activity and exercise classes can continue&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;organised indoor sport, physical activity and exercise classes will only be permitted if it is possible for people to avoid mixing with people they do not live with (or share a support bubble with). There are exceptions for indoor disability sport, sport for educational purposes and supervised sport and physical activity for under-18s, which can take place with larger groups mixing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;you can continue to travel to venues or amenities which are open, but should aim to reduce the number of journeys you make where possible&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;if you live in a tier 2 area, you must continue to follow tier 2 rules when you travel to a tier 1 area. Avoid travel to or overnight stays in tier 3 areas other than where necessary, such as for work, education, youth services, to receive medical treatment, or because of caring responsibilities.You can travel through a tier 3 area as a part of a longer journey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;for international travel see the Foreign, Commonwealth and Development Office&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/foreign-travel-advice"&gt;travel advice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for your destination and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-travel-corridors"&gt;travel corridors list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">From the 2nd of December Hampshire will be in Tier 2; find out what this means here.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2819</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T21:50:11Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T21:50:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP - Barnsley Chronicle 27 November</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Yesterday, the Government announced that South Yorkshire will be in Tier 3 restrictions from 2 December. I’ve been clear that we must not stay there a moment longer than we have to, which is why I’m pushing for a clear roadmap out of restrictions and for fairer economic support package for our residents and businesses. This week’s Spending Review was a golden opportunity to provide that immediate support; deliver on the Government’s manifesto commitment to level up the North of England; and reward those workers who have kept our country going. It was an opportunity that the Chancellor failed to take.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/chron27nov</id>
    <published>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-27T10:11:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Amber Valley &amp; Derbyshire Tier update from the 2nd December 2020]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3042</id>
		<updated>2020-11-26T17:01:51Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-26T16:53:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2nd December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/"><![CDATA[<p>Amber Valley, along with the rest of Derbyshire and most of the East Midlands will move into Tier 3 restrictions next Wednesday 2<sup>nd</sup> December after the end of the national lockdown. It is disappointing that the highest level of restrictions will apply but this had been inevitable given the level of cases in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The last week of data shows a very welcome reduction with the new cases falling by over a third showing that the lockdown has been effective. Cases for the week to 20 November were 367, down from 580 the week before. This equates to 274 cases per 100,000 well above the national average. The local area of Openwoodgate and Holbrook with a rate of cases of nearly 600 per 100,000 was the 4<sup>th</sup> highest area in England. The overall average for Derbyshire was 248 cases per 100,000, and England 217. The decision by the Government was based on this data plus the relatively high level of cases in the over 60s and the occupation levels of local hospitals.</p>
<p>The move into tier 3 means that from Wednesday 2 December non-essential shops can re-open along with personal care providers like hairdressers and barbers. Indoor and outdoor leisure activities can resume but groups and classes cannot take place indoors. You can meet in groups of up to 6 in outdoor public spaces like parks, but not meet in private gardens or indoors. Sadly pubs and restaurants cannot reopen. The full details are available on the Gov.UK site as are the details of support for businesses affected by these restrictions.</p>
<p>The Tier 3 decision will be reviewed again in 2 weeks’ time. If the recent fall in the number of cases continues then there is a good chance the county can be moved into Tier 2 before Christmas allowing us all some more freedoms, and enabling hospitality venues to open.</p>
<p>I would like to thank everyone who has obeyed the rules during lockdown helping bring about the substantial reduction in cases last week. I would urge everyone  to stick to the rules  for the rest of the lockdown and then the tier 3 rules afterwards so that we can get the virus under control locally and left more restrictions in a couple of weeks’ time.</p>
<p>You can find the rules in full for tier 3 <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/local-restriction-tiers-what-you-need-to-know#what-tiers-mean">here</a> and you can still register for my zoom residents&#8217; meeting at 7.30pm on Friday (27th November 2020) by emailing nigel.mills.mp@parliament.uk.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/11/26/amber-valley-derbyshire-tier-update-from-the-2nd-december-2020/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Dear Prime Minister,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated
announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce
the spread of Covid-19 in England.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed
once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to
ensure we keep people safe and well. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, it is vital that careful consideration is given
to ensuring the right areas are placed in the right tiers. While we welcome the
way the three tiers recognise that different areas require different approaches
to managing the virus, we believe that Nottingham City Council is uniquely
placed to understand the best interests of its citizens.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last month, Nottingham was placed in tier 2 before being
stepped up to tier 3, alongside our partners in the neighbouring
Nottinghamshire County Council. At that time, we had one of the highest rates
of Covid-19 in the country. Since then, we have seen a significant and
sustained reduction in the rate of Covid-19 in Nottingham City, with 40
consecutive days of falling Covid cases and counting. We now sit below the
national average for rates per 100,000 population and are ranked 121&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;
Lower Tier Local Authority nationally. I’m sure you would agree this is a
dramatic and impressive turnaround.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our rate is now 50 per cent lower than when we were last
placed into tier 3. We believe our sustained lower rate of Covid-19 should be
reflected in the way Nottingham is allocated a tier this time around.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our fall in cases of Covid-19 is a reflection of the hard
work which has taken place, along with neighbouring councils, the police,
businesses and our city’s two universities – as well as with the local NHS. All
organisations have united in a shared response to reducing the spread of the
virus.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is also, of course, attributable to the efforts of our
local communities, and their support in adhering to the guidelines and
restrictions in place. We feel that people in Nottingham have worked hard to
bring down the rate of Covid-19 in our communities and among our older
population – and that our position in the tier system should reflect this
decrease.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We know that ongoing restrictions will continue to have a
significant impact on our businesses, our hospitality sector and our
communities. It is vital the right decisions are made for our city.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We would like the opportunity to build on Nottingham’s
successful partnership work in a way that allows us more freedom to reopen key
parts of our economy: to keep restaurants and indoor entertainment venues open
and to ensure our city can begin to reopen in a way that is safe, supported and
protected.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would welcome the opportunity to discuss this further.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely&lt;br&gt;Cllr David Mellen&lt;br&gt;Leader, Nottingham City Council&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/"&gt;Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear Prime Minister, I am writing ahead of the Government’s anticipated announcement on Thursday, allocating local areas to the new tier system, to reduce the spread of Covid-19 in England. It is clear that strong measures will continue to be needed once we come out of the current national lockdown restrictions on 2 December, to...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2020/11/25/letter-from-cllr-david-mellen-to-the-pm-on-covid-tiers/">Letter from Cllr David Mellen to the PM on COVID Tiers</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2569</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T10:56:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Preet questions the Foreign Secretary about cuts to UK Aid</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-questions-foreign-secretary-about-cuts-uk-aid" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet asks the Foreign Secretary The Rt Hon Dominic Raab MP about rumours the Government will break its own manifesto commitment to spend 0.7% of GNI on overseas aid. <a dir="auto" href="https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=%23SaveAid">#SaveAid</a></p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-blog-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-inline clearfix">
          <h3 class="field-label">Tags: </h3>
          <ul class="links inline">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/saved" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">saved</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/dfid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">dfid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/overseas-aid" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">overseas aid</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/portfolio-tags/international-development" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">international development</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/video" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Video</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Video</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Preet%20Kaur%20Gill.jpg" width="1920" height="1080" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-embed field-type-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/p_ohkKM9tUE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>873 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-24T18:08:27Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ashfield MP says track and trace was 'first class' for him - and the Prime Minister</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week, I was delighted to have had breakfast with the Prime Minister in Downing Street where we spoke about my hopes for Ashfield and Eastwood.
It was a productive meeting and I am confident that this Government will deliver the investment our area has been crying out for now for decades.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/ashfield-mp-says-track-and-trace-was-first-class-him-and-prime-minister</id>
    <published>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembrance Day]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"/>

		<id>http://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=451</id>
		<updated>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</updated>
		<published>2020-11-12T14:50:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2020/11/12/remembrance-day/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith tells Government ‘the people of the north will hold you to account’ on rebalancing the economy.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-tells-government-the-people-of-the-north-will-hold-you-to-account-on-rebalancing-the-economy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;This morning I took part in &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DanJarvisMP?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@DanJarvisMP&lt;/a&gt; debate on support for the economy in the North. We need a fundamental rebalancing of our economy after Covid. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this Government to account for their promises and their actions. &lt;a href="https://t.co/iCcp6jNBhp"&gt;pic.twitter.com/iCcp6jNBhp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1326541226452004864?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 11, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the
economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was
fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s handling of the Covid crisis, and in
particular their approach to local restrictions and regional packages of
financial support, has shown that too often the needs of the North are still an
after-thought or, worse, ignored altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Instead of
establishing a clear and transparent framework of support, proportionate to
need, the Government has employed a strategy of divide and rule.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We are now in a national lockdown of course, and the
furlough scheme has been extended until March, but the Government must set out
exactly what will happen at the end of this period. They have indicated we will
go back into the tiered system, but many businesses in Bradford will simply not
survive if we go straight back into tier 2 or 3 with the current level of
support.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the short term, the Government must ensure that whatever
the restrictions are after December 2nd, there is a fair set of financial
support that takes into account how long an area has been under local
restrictions. For each measure, the Government should produce an impact
assessment by region, which includes the impact on regional inequality and the
regional economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“In the longer term, we need a fundamental rebalancing of our
economy. Levelling up rhetoric and the odd project here and there will not be
enough. Trust is in short supply and the people of the North will hold this
Government to account for their promises and their actions.” &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith also called for reform of the Treasury’s ‘Green Book’
which is used to make decisions on Government investment, as it currently
“skews investment and therefore growth into where it already happens, rather
than where it needs to happen”. In response, the Government announced they
would be publishing the revised Green Book at this year’s spending review on
the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;91&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-raises-world-osteoporosis-day-in-parliament/" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/JCPMGshot200603-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" alt="Judith raises World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith was very pleased to raise the upcoming World Osteoporosis Day in Parliament and to call for more support for people with this condition as we come out of lockdown. We're looking to relaunch the APPG and I'm hoping to hold a debate on the issue soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, support, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;90&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-pm-to-allow-visits-from-loved-ones/" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/JC-portrait-150x150.jpeg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" alt="Judith urges PM to allow visits from loved ones" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday I urged the Prime Minister to do everything he can to keep care home residents &amp; staff safe and allow visits from loved ones where possible, including by testing family members. A lack of social contact is especially difficult for people with dementia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local, press&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/video-judith-hails-life-sentence-kill-dangerous-driving/" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/default-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" alt="Video: Judith hails life sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has welcomed the latest proposals for tougher sentences for those who kill through dangerous driving and urges the government to act on them without delay Responding in Parliament, Leader of the House Jacob-Rees Mogg said: " “I thank the hon. Lady for the campaigning she's done on this very&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, judith, will, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;69&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/local-lockdowns-require-local-furlough-schemes/" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/imgID149097243-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" alt="Local lockdowns require local furlough schemes" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A version of this article was first published in The Times Ever since I heard Matt Hancock, in a recent interview, extol the virtues of getting seven hours sleep a night through this pandemic, I’ve been thinking about what keeps me awake at night. At the top of my list&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: local, government, support, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;67&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: restrictions, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Just has called on the Government to fundamentally rebalance the UK economy in order to unlock the potential of the North. Speaking in a House of Common’s debate on support for the economy in the north of England, Judith Cummins MP said: “Even before the covid-19 crisis, the UK economy was fundamentally unbalanced. The Government’s […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2359</id>
    <published>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-11T13:51:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Press"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Questioning the Health Secretary about a Covid vaccine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/questioning-the-health-secretary-about-a-covid-vaccine/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the vaccine, and we can look safely towards an end to social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Today in Parliament I questioned the Health Secretary about the rollout of any approved Covid vaccine &amp;#8211; including how and when we will be able to safely bring an end to social distancing. &lt;a href="https://t.co/Waxavk42GD"&gt;pic.twitter.com/Waxavk42GD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Tulip Siddiq (@TulipSiddiq) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TulipSiddiq/status/1326225524964921346?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 10, 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in Parliament I pressed the Health Secretary Matt Hancock for answers on how the roll-out of an approved COVID-19 vaccine is likely to affect our lives and when it might be completed. I will continue to intervene in debates to ensure the government carefully review the progress of the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5258</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T18:55:59Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="coronavirus"/>
    <category term="covid"/>
    <category term="health secretary"/>
    <category term="parliament"/>
    <category term="vaccine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2020/11/10/39/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://conormcginn.laboursites.org/?p=39</id>
    <published>2020-11-10T11:15:39Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-10T11:15:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My current article on The Article: This US Election is a warning to us all</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">https://www.thearticle.com/this-us-election-is-a-warning-to-us-all?fbcl…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/my-current-article-article-us-election-warning-us-all</id>
    <published>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
