<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-05-17T15:28:52Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Star Column – Llanelli has a lot to shout about when it comes to attracting tourists to the area</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/05/llanelli-star-column-llanelli-has-a-lot-to-shout-about-when-it-comes-to-attracting-tourists-to-the-area/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to attracting visitors to Llanelli, we have a lot to shout about and be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are so
many places of interest and things to see.&amp;nbsp;
We need to use every opportunity to tell people what’s going on here and
why they should come and see it for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This week is
Welsh Tourism Week 2023, a chance to do exactly that.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tourism is a
vital part of our economy and something we should develop further to create
more jobs, more income and a more sustainable future for our communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Llanelli is the
gateway to West Wales.&amp;nbsp; We have a rich
cultural, sporting and industrial history and host some stunning urban and
rural landscapes.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; A stronger tourism
sector, supplemented by innovative marketing of what we have to offer, could
provide the basis for further expansion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Millennium
Coastal Path is one such feature that so many outside of our town do not know
about. The 13-mile path, linking Llanelli to Pembrey Country Park, gives access
to Llanelli beach, views over Gower and is a great way for visitors to get to
know the area better whilst grabbing a coffee or ice cream along the way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Llanelly House
in the town centre, a restored early 18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Century Georgian
townhouse, with its educational tours and popular bistro, is another landmark.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Add things like
Parc Howard, independent craft shops, Parc Y Scarlets, the world famous
Llanelli Wetlands Centre and so much else besides and we have the potential to
make so much more of what we have.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We can all
spread the word to others, by word of mouth, social media or other means.&amp;nbsp; It’s amazing what we might be able to achieve
with a little more self-confidence, greater co-ordination and a bit of good old-
fashioned ambition.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">When it comes to attracting visitors to Llanelli, we have a lot to shout about and be proud of. There are so many places of interest and things to see.  We need to use every opportunity to tell people what’s going on here and why they should come and see it for themselves. This week […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8845</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T14:51:22Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T14:51:22Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech can create big, powerful citizen-consumers to erode the power of online network monopolies]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/05/17/tech-can-create-big-powerful-citizen-consumers-to-erode-the-power-of-online-network-monopolies/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5733</id>
		<updated>2023-05-17T14:22:47Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-17T14:22:46Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Newspaper Articles"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m honoured to be this month’s ‘Parliamentary TechChampion’, because of the role technology can play in sharpening competition to create big, powerful citizen-consumers so markets work for people rather than the other way round. This is a key theme in my Government-commissioned report on Competition Policy, Power to the People which made the case for [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/05/17/tech-can-create-big-powerful-citizen-consumers-to-erode-the-power-of-online-network-monopolies/"><![CDATA[
<p>I’m honoured to be this month’s ‘Parliamentary TechChampion’, because of the role technology can play in sharpening competition to create big, powerful citizen-consumers so markets work for people rather than the other way round.</p>



<p>This is a key theme in my Government-commissioned report on Competition Policy, Power to the People which made the case for a strong, pro-competitive but tightly-ring fenced Digital Market Unit to erode the power of online network monopolies which have emerged in the last few decades, giving consumers more choice and better deals as well as opening up more opportunities for entrepreneurs and wealth-creators too.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">World-leading changes in Open Banking</h2>



<p>An example of what this means in practice is the UK’s world-leading changes in Open Banking, which are weakening the longstanding current-account stranglehold of incumbent high-street banks. By opening up data portability with APIs for third party payments providers (TPPs), banking customers suddenly have a growing choice of different and creative services to choose from, and we’ve created a thriving Open Banking FinTech eco-system in the process.</p>



<p>The next challenge is to extend this success from current accounts to the whole of the financial sector (Open Finance), and then on to other industries like online retailing and utilities too (Open Everything).</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Consumers can become more powerful</h2>



<p>Last but not least, consumers can become more powerful through transparency, partly because we can all make better-informed decisions about what we buy if the data is at our fingertips whenever we need it, and partly by shining a light on subsidies or sweetheart deals given to incumbents and special interests too.</p>



<p>The recent Subsidy Control Bill improves transparency significantly, and there’s another opportunity in the upcoming the Online Safety Bill if we grasp the opportunity to protect people from lies or only seeing one set of views about anything from products and services to vaccines and political campaigns.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree was a beneficiary of the programme which is backed by £1.8 billion of government funding over this financial year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps was thrilled to see that Peartree had benefited from this funding and looks forward to seeing their transformation. In the past, Mr Shapps helped free up playground space at Peartree by getting a disused Victorian loo block removed which has helped generations of pupils enjoy a little more&amp;nbsp;open&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps also met with student members of the school council who asked him an array of questions about his career, local issues and his life as the constituency&amp;#8217;s parliament member. The members of the school council are aged between five and eleven and are elected by their classmates to give them a voice in Peartree School’s vision, projects and events.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps commented on his visit and on his time with members of the school council:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to catch up with staff and visit pupils at Peartree School last week. The children are clearly enjoying their time there very much, and it was really helpful to get an insight from Miss Hardy and her team as to how everyone’s getting on. Plus, I enjoyed a brilliant sit-down with the School Council &amp;#8211; they really put me through my paces with their questions.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Megan Hardy, the Head of School at Peartree, thanked Mr Shapps for visiting and meeting with the staff and students:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to show Mr Shapps around Peartree and to talk to him about our plans for the school’s transformation over the coming years.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She continued:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The children were really excited to meet their MP and they came up with plenty of interesting questions to ask him. They were very inspired by his visit, so we may even have a future prime minister among us!”&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps thanks Peartree for having him visit and wishes the staff and students all the best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/"&gt;Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students. During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/">Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Yarwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=48284</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP teams up with pop royalty to call for end to Britain’s sewage scandal</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442076/mp-teams-up-with-pop-royalty-to-call-for-end-to-britain-s-sewage-scandal"/>
  <updated>2023-05-17T13:49:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442076/mp-teams-up-with-pop-royalty-to-call-for-end-to-britain-s-sewage-scandal</id>
  <summary type="text">Last night, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron chaired a meeting in Westminster alongside former Undertones frontman and environmental campaigner Feargal Sharkey, on how to tackle the scandal of sewage being dumped in Britain's lakes and rivers.
They were also joined by the founder of Surfers Against Sewage Hugo Tagholm, the Director of Communications and Advocacy for the Rivers Trust Tessa Wardley, and the journalist and television presenter Lucy Siegle.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Last night, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron chaired a meeting in Westminster alongside former Undertones frontman and environmental campaigner Feargal Sharkey, on how to tackle the scandal of sewage being dumped in Britain's lakes and rivers.</p>
<p>They were also joined by the founder of Surfers Against Sewage Hugo Tagholm, the Director of Communications and Advocacy for the Rivers Trust Tessa Wardley, and the journalist and television presenter Lucy Siegle.</p>
<p>During the meeting, Tim cited figures which showed that since 2020, there have 960 occasions of illegal sewage dumping in the UK - but only 16 prosecutions.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Tim also said there had been 1.4million events of legal sewage dumps for 10 million hours, in the same time period.</p>
<p>Tim also raised the issue of six of the top ten longest sewage discharges in England last year happening here in Cumbria.</p>
<p>Tim put forward three solutions to help tackle the scandal:</p>
<ol>
<li>A sewage tax on the profits of water companies to be used to fix Britain's creaking sewage system</li>
<li>Turn water companies into "public good companies", ensuring environmental goals are just as important as profit, whilst putting environmentalists on the company boards</li>
<li>A ban on bonuses for water company bosses and instead use that money to invest in keeping Britain's water clean and safe</li>
</ol>
<p>Speaking after the event, Tim said: "<em>I'm absolutely delighted to be working alongside Feargal Sharkey, who has been a vociferous campaigner on this issue for many years now.</em></p>
<p><em>"The dumping of sewage in our waterways has appalling consequences on our environment, on our local tourism economy, on our wildlife and on the health of people who swim in our lakes, rivers and seas.</em></p>
<p><em>"It's critically important that we all keep up the pressure on the Conservative Government to act and to tackle pollution in our lakes and rivers here in Cumbria and beyond."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Allergy Awareness Week 2023 in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/allergy-awareness-week-2023-parliament" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Allergy Awareness Week 2023 in Parliament</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-05-17T12:38:00+00:00">Wed, 05/17/2023 - 13:38</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1204 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T12:38:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T12:38:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cammy Day: Looking back on first year as Council Leader</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13727/cammy-day-looking-back-on-first-year-as-council-leader" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In today's Edinburgh Evening News Cllr Cammy Day reflects on his first 12 months as Council Leader and looks forward to the year ahead.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13727/cammy-day-looking-back-on-first-year-as-council-leader</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:03:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:03:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin calls for greater support for rural bus routes from Welsh Government</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-greater-support-rural-bus-routes-welsh-government" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The UK Government announced today that further cost of living support is being provided by investing £300 million to cap bus fares at £2 until October 2023 and then £2.50 until November 2024. In addition to making travel more affordable for millions of passengers each year, this funding is also…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-greater-support-rural-bus-routes-welsh-government</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Select Committee Update – Gambling Regulation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/select-committee-update-gambling-regulation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the CMS Committee held its first evidence session in our Gambling Regulation inquiry following the publication of the Government's gambling White Paper last month. In the session we heard from Anna Hargrave (Chief Commissioning Officer, GambleAware), Anna Hemmings (Chief Executive Officer,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/select-committee-update-gambling-regulation</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP calls on all Borough Councillors to honour residents wishes to slow down house building</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-calls-all-borough-councillors-honour-residents-wishes-slow-down-house-building" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Thursday, local Borough Councillors will meet to decide who leads Basingstoke and Deane Borough Council for the coming year following the elections on May 4th. 
Local MP Maria Miller said, "I know each Councillor will carefully question each candidate before they decide who will best reflect the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-calls-all-borough-councillors-honour-residents-wishes-slow-down-house-building</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>£2 Bus fare cap to be extended </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/ps2-bus-fare-cap-be-extended" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">£2 Bus Fares Extension - following the announcement that we’ve extended our £2 bus fare policy until 31 October 2023, with single fares capped at £2.50 until November 2024, I asked Transport Minister Richard Holden MP to confirm that without this cap, some single fares could have been as high as £6…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/ps2-bus-fare-cap-be-extended</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Homes of Multiple Occupation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/homes-multiple-occupation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">HMOs are a significant concern in my constituency.
For decades, we have seen former bed and breakfasts and hotels converted into HMOs, which means that an estimated 23,000 people across the town are now living in them.
Time and again, residents speak to me about the problems that those HMOs…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/homes-multiple-occupation</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dear Newcastle May2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/05/13545/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To view the full Newsletter for May click on the link below:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Dear-Newcastle-May-2023.pdf"&gt;https://chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Dear-Newcastle-May-2023.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="13546" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/05/13545/newsletter-page-1-may-23/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?fit=713%2C879&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="713,879" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Newsletter page 1 May 23" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?fit=243%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?fit=700%2C863&amp;amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="alignnone wp-image-13546 size-full" src="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?resize=700%2C863&amp;#038;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="863" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?w=713&amp;amp;ssl=1 713w, https://i0.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Newsletter-page-1-May-23.png?resize=243%2C300&amp;amp;ssl=1 243w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">To view the full Newsletter for May click on the link below: https://chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Dear-Newcastle-May-2023.pdf      </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13545</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T11:48:50Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T11:48:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne backs British farming</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-backs-british-farming" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7409" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">17 May 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne backs British farming</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne welcomes the new investment and support unveiled for British farmers at yesterday’s UK Farm to Fork Summit.</p>

<p>This significant gathering brought together representatives from the entire food supply chain at 10 Downing Street, aimed at identifying fresh opportunities to foster growth, drive innovation, and enhance sustainability.</p>

<p>The government has confirmed a series of measures to fortify the long-term resilience and sustainability of the agricultural sector. The Prime Minister outlined a new framework for trade negotiations that places farmers' interests at the core of trade policy, which Mr Dunne has been calling for with the Trade Secretary Rt Hon Kemi Badenoch MP. This commitment ensures the protection of the UK's food and welfare standards while actively prioritising new export opportunities.</p>

<p>The government has allocated an additional £5.6 million investment to bolster British food exports on a global scale. This investment will be channelled towards expanding trade shows, missions, the GREAT food campaign, the Seafood Exports Package, and establishing an export fund for the dairy sector.</p>

<p>The Government has also increased the number of VISA’s to be issued for the seasonal workers in the agriculture sector season to 45,000.</p>

<p>Recognising the importance of advancing agricultural technologies, the government has earmarked £30 million for the progression of precision breeding technologies. This investment will also establish a working group dedicated to farm-to-shelf production under the Genetic Technology Act.</p>

<p>To ensure fairness within the industry, new powers will be granted to guarantee equitable prices for farmers operating in the egg and horticulture sectors.</p>

<p>Finally, the government has confirmed its future support for horticulture. It plans to replace the EU Fruit and Vegetable Producer Organisation Scheme with an expanded offering in new farming payment schemes after 2026.<strong> </strong></p>

<p><strong>Philip Dunne said</strong>,</p>

<blockquote>
<p>“South Shropshire farmers work hard around the clock to keep great quality food on our plates, so it’s good to see the Prime Minister hosting this important summit today.</p>

<p>“Our farmers are the engine of our rural economy, bringing jobs and opportunity to Shropshire.  As a farmer myself I welcome the new investment and support for various sectors announced today”.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>NFU President Minette Batters said:</strong></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“I am absolutely delighted that the Prime Minister has honoured the commitments he made when he addressed our hustings event back in the summer to hold this food summit at Number 10, and we welcome the announcements made today. They show a recognition and an understanding of the strategic importance of British food and farming to the nation.</p>

<p>“These actions recognise the importance of coordinated action across government to support confidence, investment, and growth in British food. We look forward to working with the Prime Minister, the Defra Secretary, and the rest of the cabinet to Back British farming and bolster our domestic food security.”</p>
</blockquote></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7409 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T11:01:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T11:01:19Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, Member of Parliament for Newcastle North, has shown her support for people living with diabetes in Parliament alongside Diabetes UK.  Diabetes UK’s new “Diabetes Is Serious” campaign, highlights the challenges facing the five million people living with diabetes in the UK. The report includes shocking new figures showing that there were 7,000 excess deaths connected … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7946</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Health and Social Care"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/2023/05/17/april-newsletter-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>liamtaggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=333</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Addressing Highland Living Costs and Extending Support to Ukrainian Refugees Amid Crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/addressing-highland-living-costs-and-extending-support-to-ukrainian-refugees-amid-crisis/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=addressing-highland-living-costs-and-extending-support-to-ukrainian-refugees-amid-crisis" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content"&gt;&lt;div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"&gt;&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The biggest concern raised with me continues to be the cost of living. The mortgage rate hikes, triggered by the Liz Truss premiership, and inflation still running at over ten per cent means that the increasing casework coming through my office relates to helping people who are struggling, including those households with two or more working. In a series of recent online workshops I’ve held, in conjunction with the likes of Highland Council, Age Scotland, and Change Mental Health, constituents have been able to hear from and ask questions of experts to help them with a wide range of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The feedback has been that these organisations have provided invaluable support. As we always do, we are straining every sinew to reach as many people as we can to help. This also includes those who have sought sanctuary here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;The war in Ukraine has been active for over a year now, and it can be tempting to let it drift from our minds, but we mustn’t be tempted to do so. If Ukraine does not prevail, and Putin does, then the future will be starker for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I’m thankful that few of us will have faced hardship like that experienced by the displaced thousands who have had to flee Ukraine due to the illegal war there. Amidst this chaos, however, our local community has rallied, demonstrating exceptional empathy and unity, our true strength shining through, as it so often does in challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Not long ago, I held an event to provide support to our new Ukrainian friends. The response was overwhelming; the large group of attendees were grateful for the community spirit and friendship they had been shown here in the Highlands. Our new neighbours, however, are in an uncertain situation, to say the least. They are unable to plan for the future in Ukraine due to the war, and also here due to, frankly, inadequate support over visas from the Home Office and other agencies such as the DVLA &amp;#8211; for basic documents, such as car registration and driving licences. Despite the numbers, my team and I stayed on until we worked through the queues of people seeking support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;For those unable to attend, I’ve compiled an extensive list of available resources. This guide, prepared in both Ukrainian and English, should help our friends navigate the assistance available and is available on my website at &lt;a href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/support-for-ukrainians/"&gt;https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/support-for-ukrainians/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/addressing-highland-living-costs-and-extending-support-to-ukrainian-refugees-amid-crisis/"&gt;Addressing Highland Living Costs and Extending Support to Ukrainian Refugees Amid Crisis&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The biggest concern raised with me continues to be the cost of living. The mortgage rate hikes, triggered by the Liz Truss premiership, and inflation still running at over ten per cent means that the increasing casework coming through my office relates to helping people who are struggling, including those households with two or more …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/addressing-highland-living-costs-and-extending-support-to-ukrainian-refugees-amid-crisis/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Addressing Highland Living Costs and Extending Support to Ukrainian Refugees Amid Crisis</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/addressing-highland-living-costs-and-extending-support-to-ukrainian-refugees-amid-crisis/">Addressing Highland Living Costs and Extending Support to Ukrainian Refugees Amid Crisis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7463</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T07:00:31Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T07:00:31Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Ukraine"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Letter to the Prime Minister from the European Scrutiny Committee Chair, Bill Cash</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/05/17/letter-to-the-prime-minister-from-the-european-scrutiny-committee-chair-bill-cash/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Please find below Bill Cash’s letter to the Prime Minister:</p>
<p>European Scrutiny Committee<br/>
House of Commons London SW1A 0AA<br/>
Tel (020) 7219 3292 Email escom@parliament.uk Website www.parliament.uk/escom</p>
<p>From: Sir William Cash MP</p>
<p>15 May 2023</p>
<p>Rt Hon. Rishi Sunak MP<br/>
Prime Minister<br/>
10 Downing Street<br/>
London SW1A 2AA</p>
<p>Change in Government policy on Retained EU Law and the Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill</p>
<p>Dear Prime Minister</p>
<p>On 21 July last year, after a five month inquiry, my Committee reported on the future of Retained EU Law (REUL). During our inquiry, we heard in evidence from 13 expert witnesses and the (then) Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy, Rt Hon. Jacob Rees-Mogg MP.1 Shortly after we reported, the Government published the Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill (REUL(R&amp;R) Bill). The Government engaged with our work and we were pleased to see a number of our recommendations<br/>
given effect in the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill.</p>
<p>Recent Government engagement and the Secretary of State for Business and Trade’s non-attendance before the Committee</p>
<p>This experience stands in stark contrast to our more recent engagement with the Government on the Bill. On 24 February, we invited the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, Rt Hon. Kemi Badenoch MP, to give evidence to us on the Government’s progress on the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill and its ‘Brexit opportunities’ work.2 We have written twice since, requesting her attendance before the Committee. On Thursday 11 May, I asked her on the floor of the House if she would appear before us, as did Rt Hon. David Jones M.</p>
<p>The Secretary of State is yet to commit to appear before the Committee. This state of affairs is unacceptable: Select Committees are vital to effective scrutiny and good law- and policy-making. A Select Committee should not be put in the position where it has asked a Secretary of State to appear five times to give evidence, over three months, without a clear commitment being forthcoming. The Secretary of State’s failure to appear has frustrated our work on REUL and Brexit opportunities, and is not an issue I would ever have expected to be raising with a Prime Minister.</p>
<p>This situation has taken on a more concerning hue in recent days. As you are aware, on Wednesday the Government tabled amendments in the Lords to the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill. These amendments signal a significant change in the Government’s policy on REUL. The House was informed of this change in a Written Ministerial Statement on Wednesday afternoon and adequate explanatory materials, such as a White Paper, have not yet been forthcoming. This series of events was deemed so serious by Mr Speaker that he granted my Urgent Question (UQ) on the matter on Thursday morning. Save for my UQ, Members would not have had an opportunity to question the Secretary of State on the Government’s plans ahead of Lords Report Stage, which starts today. This approach to scrutiny is deeply concerning and a worrying parallel can be drawn with how the Government handled the Windsor Framework: a major policy announcement accompanied by artificially set deadlines with no meaningful opportunity for input by Members. We hope this is not a trend that will continue. Parliament and the scrutiny function entrusted to us by the electorate are too important to ride over roughshod.</p>
<p>On the content of the Government’s amendments to the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill, we have serious concerns about: (i) the removal of the ‘sunset Clause’; (ii) the Schedule of REUL to be revoked; and (iii) the Government’s policy on REUL and its Brexit opportunities work. i. The removal of the ‘sunset Clause’ Clause 1 of the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill, as introduced, would ‘sunset’ EU-derived domestic subordinate legislation and retained direct EU legislation on 31 December 2023. It would ensure that the majority of REUL would cease to exist on the domestic statute book as of the end of the year (unless specifically retained). The December 2023 sunset was justified by the Government as necessary to “accelerate reform and planning for future regulatory changes, benefitting both UK businesses and consumers sooner”. The Government also said upon the Bill’s publication:  HCWS764 [on Regulatory Reform Update], 10 May 2023 6 Explanatory Notes to the Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill [Bill 156 (2022-23)—EN], para 17.</p>
<p>The sunset will increase business certainty by setting the date by which a new domestic statute book, tailored to the UK’s needs and regulatory regime will come into effect. Clause 2 of the Bill would allow the sunset to be extended beyond 31 December 2023 “ensuring the efficiency of the REUL revocation process should a lack of parliamentary time, or external factors, hinder progress towards reform of retained EU law prior to the 2023 sunset date”. The Government amendment tabled in the Lords on Wednesday would remove the default sunset clause and, by virtue of this change, also remove the ability for it to be extended. Instead, only legislation listed in the Schedule would be revoked.</p>
<p>In a letter to the Committee on 10 May, the Secretary of State stated that the removal of the Bill’s sunset would “provide certainty for business by making it clear which regulations will be removed from our statue book”. This argument and that justifying the sunset clause on the introduction of the Bill are mutually contradictory.</p>
<p>The Secretary of State has referred to the Bill as pursuing a policy of ‘preservation’ of REUL. This is wrong. The Bill, as drafted, would revoke all EU-derived subordinate legislation and retained direct EU legislation on 31 December, apart from that explicitly singled out to be saved. The Government’s amendments on Report in the Lords would preserve all 4,000<br/>
plus instances of REUL identified, minus those covered in the proposed new Schedule (600) and those instances to be dealt with elsewhere (e.g. the under the Financial Services and Markets Bill). A well-resourced REUL identification programme, which was promised by the Government in January last year, coupled with effective Ministerial oversight, would deliver the certainty business rightly demand and the effective and nimble post-Brexit statute book they have been promised. Clause 2 of the Bill was a sensible inclusion that could be exercised should progress towards the reform of REUL not be as quick as anticipated. It is unclear why this safety net is now deemed insufficient.</p>
<p>Letter from Rt Hon. Kemi Badenoch MP to Sir William Cash MP, 10 May 2023</p>
<p>ii. The Schedule of REUL to be revoked<br/>
The Government amendment tabled in the Lords would replace the clause 1 sunset mechanism with a Schedule of around 600 pieces of REUL to be revoked at the end of December this year. It is important to remember the reasons why the Bill was introduced. In its ‘Benefits of Brexit’ policy paper, the Government said “[we] will now prioritise areas where reform of retained EU law can deliver the greatest economic gain”.10 In her letter of 10 May, the Secretary of State says “the Government are committed to lightening the regulatory burden for businesses and helping to spur economic growth”. It is clear that the vast majority of instances of REUL to be revoked under the Schedule would do no such thing.</p>
<p>Our initial assessment shows that, almost without exception, the REUL detailed in the Schedule relates to matters that are trivial, obsolete and are not legally and/or politically important. Revocation of this REUL cannot be construed as lightening the regulatory burden for businesses or spurring economic growth. This is a worrying mischaracterisation and begs the question as to what the real purpose of the Schedule is. Examples of REUL that would be revoked under the Schedule include:<br/>
• temporary exemptions to repealed EU rules on limits to working hours for drivers during the 2001 foot-and-mouth outbreak;<br/>
• authorisation for EU Member States to ratify the 2006 Maritime Labour Convention;<br/>
• quota rules for the import of 8,000 tonnes of wheat bran originating in the ACP States into the French overseas territory of Réunion;<br/>
• rules on the allocation of fishing opportunities for the Democratic Republic of São Tomé and Príncipe; and<br/>
• the setting of fishing opportunities for anchovy in the Bay of Biscay for the 2011/2012 fishing season (it is worth noting that in excess of 150 instances of REUL included in the Schedule relate to fishing).<br/>
iii. The Government’s policy on REUL and Brexit opportunities<br/>
The Government’s Benefits of Brexit paper was also clear that REUL would be reviewed to meet the UK’s priorities, with a view to “unlocking growth” and making sure it is “tailor-made for the UK market”.</p>
<p>The policy paper was published in January 2022—almost a year and a half ago—and states “the Government will now prioritise areas where reform of retained EU law can deliver the greatest economic gain.”13 This task was deemed sufficiently important by the Government that a dedicated ‘Brexit opportunities unit’ was setup working out of the Department of Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy and charged with coordinating and setting the methodology for the identification of REUL across Whitehall. The REUL(R&amp;R) Bill is the mechanism through which the Government’s Brexit opportunities work was to be delivered. We have been concerned since the start of the year that the Government’s Brexit opportunities work, including that identifying REUL, has not been progressing as promised. I restate our suggestion, which I made to the Secretary of State on 24 February, that the Government should appoint a REUL ‘Tsar’, tasked with ensuring the Government delivers on its commitments.</p>
<p>The Government must restate its plans for the substantive reform of REUL. This is necessary in light of the aforementioned uncertainty, the broad powers the Bill provides Ministers to amend REUL and the Government’s desire to provide clarity and certainty to businesses moving forward. We request a full update on the status of the Government’s Brexit opportunities work, the areas it is prioritising for reform through the Bill, and when these changes are now scheduled to take place. We also ask you to ensure the appearance of the Secretary of State before the Committee in good time.</p>
<p>I request a response to this letter as a matter of urgency, owing to the Government scheduling Report Stage of the REUL(R&amp;R) Bill in the Lords for today and Wednesday.</p>
<p>I am copying this letter to the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, Rt Hon. Kemi Badenoch MP.</p>
<p>Regards</p>
<p>Chair</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Please find below Bill Cash’s letter to the Prime Minister: European Scrutiny Committee House of Commons London SW1A 0AA Tel (020) 7219 3292 Email escom@parliament.uk Website www.parliament.uk/escom From: Sir William Cash MP 15 May 2023 Rt Hon. Rishi Sunak MP Prime Minister 10 Downing Street London SW1A 2AA Change in Government policy on Retained EU…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=35123</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T04:00:16Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T04:00:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Offshore Wind Infrastructure Campaign – Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/offshore-wind-infrastructure-campaign-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="2696" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">16 May 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Offshore Wind Infrastructure Campaign – Update</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span><span><span><span>As has been widely publicised in recent years, the East is at the forefront of the offshore wind revolution that is already strengthening our UK energy resilience and driving forward the decarbonisation of our energy network. </span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>That’s why, having been a leading figure over several years calling for a proper offshore solution for delivering this crucial Offshore Wind Infrastructure, I welcomed the opportunity on Monday to be involved in the latest meeting of OffSET MPs – this time with Andrew Bowie MP, the Minister for Nuclear and Networks at the new Department for Energy Security and Net Zero.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Together, the OffSET team reaffirmed the need for the Government to do everything it can (as well as encourage key stakeholders like National Grid, National GridESO, OFGEM and developers) to ensure the Offshore Transmission Network that it previously agreed to commit to is delivered as soon as possible – and in a manner that encompasses as much infrastructure as possible. The group also made clear it was vitally important that people and local communities are properly included in, and given a say in, consultations about how electricity infrastructure is delivered both onshore and offshore – most notably in the case of East Anglia Green.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>While the news that the ESO have opened a new public consultation on East Anglia Green is very positive indeed (see more </span></span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/east-anglia-green-offshore-alternative-consultation-0"><span>here</span></a><span><span>), there remains much more to be done. The Minister himself acknowledged that, praising the work of the OffSET team and local campaigners thus far – making clear that it has focussed the minds of the key stakeholders, who are taking the points being raised very seriously indeed. </span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>The Minister also reassured us that, while there will always be a need for a certain amount of electricity infrastructure onshore, the Government is committed to the Offshore Transmission Network concept it has agreed to (see more </span></span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/offshore-wind-infrastructure-debate"><span>here</span></a><span><span>) and believes that the work to achieve that is moving forward positively. He also emphasised his belief that the communities hosting major pieces of Nationally Significant Infrastructure should also be fairly recompensed in terms of community benefits by the relevant developers.</span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>Rest assured, this remains a key campaign for me here in Norfolk – and I will also continue to do all I can to support local communities now engaging in the community benefit discussions being held by Vattenfall. </span></span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span><span>To read more about my ongoing campaign on this, please visit my website </span></span><a href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/offshore_wind_infrastructure"><span>here</span></a>.</span></span></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/sites/georgefreeman.co.uk/files/2023-05/andrew_bowie_orm_meeting.jpg" width="1000" height="600" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2696 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T21:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Borders school pupils enjoy food and farming day out </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borders-school-pupils-enjoy-food-and-farming-day-out" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I had the pleasure of joining around 1200 school children from 60 schools across the Scottish Borders on Tuesday as they sampled first-hand the experience of running a farm, producing food, and working in the rural economy.
The event from the Border Union Agricultural Society at Springwood Park in…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borders-school-pupils-enjoy-food-and-farming-day-out</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Debate on Dentistry in the East of England</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/debate-dentistry-east-england" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Debate on NHS Dentistry</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/debate-dentistry-east-england</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg meets with Alzheimer's Research UK for briefing on new treatments</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-meets-alzheimers-research-uk-briefing-new-treatments" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We're on the cusp of the first generation of treatments for Alzheimer's Disease, but there's a great deal to do to prepare the UK for new dementia treatments. 
Two treatments have been approved in the US and one of these, lecanemab, is under consideration by UK and European regulators. A third,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-meets-alzheimers-research-uk-briefing-new-treatments</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3374</id>
		<updated>2023-05-16T11:22:21Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-16T11:22:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; Dear Constituent, Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve been on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Illegal migration bill update:</u></strong></p>



<p>The main piece of legislation that has been going through the House of Commons in the last few weeks is the Illegal Migration Bill. I’ve heard from a number of constituents with a diverse range of views on this topic. On the 26<sup>th</sup> of April the bill completed its remaining stages in the Commons and is now moving through the House of Lords, before it will return to the Commons for a final review.</p>



<p>This Bill is set to enhance the powers of the Government to tackle illegal migration, including the ability to remove illegal migrants from the UK to safe countries, new ways to determine ages of migrants without formal identification, additional protections for child migrants, and tougher sentences for those found guilty of people smuggling. The Bill was also amended during its remaining stages to include the Government’s commitment to review the safe and legal routes that are available.</p>



<p>It is clear that we need an asylum system that does work for those families truly in need, but is also tough on those who are trying to exploit the process to gain entry to the UK and on human traffickers who are exploiting vulnerable people and worsening the crisis. The new bill tackles the latter problems, while leaving open safe and legal routes for those in need.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sewage &amp; storm overflows update:</u></strong></p>



<p>Another key development in Parliament was new plans to further increase water quality targets and reduce sewage being released into our waterways.</p>



<p>The Government has announced its plan to enshrine the Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published last August, into law through the Environment Act. This will make its target to reduce storm overflows legally binding. The Government’s Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published in August 2022, set out stringent targets to protect people and the environment and is backed up by up to £56 billion capital investment, which is the largest infrastructure programme in water company history.</p>



<p>Further, the Government is now consulting on proposals for unlimited fines to be imposed on water companies that break the rules. More than £142 million has already been levied in fines since 2015 and I am aware that money from fines and penalties will now be channelled back into the environment.</p>



<p><strong><u>East Midlands APPG:</u></strong></p>



<p>Outside the Chamber, the focus seemed to be local issues over the last few weeks, and we had another meeting of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on the East Midlands. This group brings together MPs from across the Chamber to discuss issues that are especially important to our region.</p>



<p>The most recent meeting was on the future of Infrastructure in the East Midlands. We heard from the East Midlands Chamber of Commerce and East Midlands Councils on infrastructure in our area and the need for infrastructure investment to fulfil our environmental commitments, to make it easier for people living here to travel and get to work, and to encourage businesses to move here.</p>



<p>Moving forward, we will continue to push for our region to receive funding in the future, by collecting evidence on the wider benefits of infrastructure projects to the local economy and local businesses and use this in future proposals for funding.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ferrero sustainable palm oil event:</u></strong></p>



<p>I was also able to welcome Ferrero, who own the Thornton’s factory in Somercotes, to Parliament. They hosted an event alongside Chester Zoo and the Orangutan Land Trust on Sustainable Palm Oil, where they discussed the damage palm oil farming has inflicted on jungles and local habitats of orangutans around the world. While many food producers have moved away from palm oil for these reasons, the same problems of deforestation and habitat destruction continue to persist regardless of the plant used.</p>



<p>Because of this, Ferrero highlighted the use of certified sustainable palm-oil to that avoids these poor practices by working with local wildlife experts, stopping further deforestation for farming land, and reducing the impact on the environment.</p>



<p>It was great to hear from a business that operates locally in our area that is tackling global issues and to talk to the charitable organisations that were supporting these efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="667" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3376" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg 1000w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Amber Valley Borough Council elections 4th May 2023 &amp; Parish/Town Council elections:</u></strong></p>



<p>On the 4th May 2023, elections were held for Amber Valley Borough Council. For the first time in a long time, elections were held for all 42 councillors over 18 wards (rather than the previous recent system of electing a third of councillors each year).</p>



<p>As a result of the election, the Labour Group took control of the Council and have 26 councillors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all who were elected and I look forward to working with the new Borough Council where needed and holding them to account where necessary too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find your borough councillor <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All the parish and town councils in Amber Valley were also up for election. You can find the results of these <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections/parish-and-town-councils/">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Access to Cash &#8211; Nationwide Heanor:</u></strong></p>



<p>I know for many constituents a key concern has been the closures of bank branches in our area.</p>



<p>Although banking is increasingly moving online, in-person branches are still relied upon by many in our communities and are staples in our high streets. People need access to bank branches so that they can speak to someone in person about their accounts and finances.</p>



<p>I was able to visit Nationwide in Heanor to discuss this issue and was reassured that they understood the important role they play on our high streets and intend to stay open for the foreseeable future.</p>



<p>I was also able to discuss the work they are doing to help vulnerable people more broadly, including their cost-of-living helpline, fraud prevention and work to teach useful financial skills to young people.</p>



<p>I’ll continue to support maintaining access to bank branches and cash in our communities and town centres.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="636" height="791" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3375" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg 636w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-241x300.jpeg 241w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Nieper Foundation visit:</u></strong></p>



<p>In Alfreton I joined Robert Halfon, the Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education, in a visit related to the Christopher Nieper Education Trust. The Trust was set up to allow David Nieper Ltd to invest in local education and help young people into long-term, rewarding employment.</p>



<p>We visited David Nieper Ltd and met with Dr Hobbs, the Headteacher of David Nieper Academy, others who are supporting the work of the Trust and met with a student to do an interview for the Spirit of Alfreton. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684233937.JPG" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong><u>Local primary school visits:</u></strong></p>



<p>I have also able to visit both Mundy Junior School and Heage Primary School to speak to teachers and school leaders about funding.</p>



<p>With schools also being hit with high energy bills, there was concern that planned increases to teacher’s salaries and additional provisions for students would not be fully funded if prices for heating stay high. I was able to talk to teachers about the worry this is causing.</p>



<p>It is only right that any increases to staff pay are properly covered by increased investment into schools and it is important that the Government has contingency plans and funding in place to reassure schools that they will be supported should energy bills stay high.</p>



<p><strong><u>Windows for Ukraine:</u></strong></p>



<p>I also took part in a visit to CPR Manufacturing in Alfreton, who are supporting a project called Windows for Ukraine. Cromwell Polythene is manufacturing polyethylene film used to make effective temporary windows as part of a project called Insulate Ukraine. The company have donated some of the film being used, which is an alternative to glass and insulates homes better than double-glazing. The local business usually manufactures bin liner products.</p>



<p><strong><u>Collis engineering visit &amp; 5G masts:</u></strong></p>



<p>To look at their new 5G masts I&#8217;ve also been to see Collis Engineering Ltd. They&#8217;re manufacturing a new mast and tower system to support the rollout of 5G and which has a high headload capacity, meaning several operators can share the same structure and system. Collis are an important local employer and it was good to learn more about this innovation that is being manufactured right here in the heart of Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that access to telephone and broadband signal remains an issue for many residents, so hopefully this innovation will help with that, and I&#8217;ll continue to pursue solutions for areas where there are concerns or problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684234142.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Street Watch:</h1>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-90/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">I am a member of the All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Choice at the End of Life, so I attended the <a href="https://www.mydeath-mydecision.org.uk/">My Death My Decision</a> (MDMD) campaign for Assisted Dying event held in the Pierhead Building in Cardiff Bay, hosted by Jayne Bryant MS for Newport West and James Evans MS for Brecon and Radnorshire. MDMD believe that assisted dying is a Welsh Issue because health care is devolved and the Senedd can legislate on matters such as palliative care, which is intrinsically linked to assisted dying. 93% of the public in Wales support assisted dying.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Under s2 of the Suicide Act 1961, assisting or encouraging a suicide is a criminal offence in England and Wales. In February 2022, a Welsh resident was arrested, interrogated by police, detained for 19 hours, and subjected to a 6-month investigation for accompanying Sharon Johnston, a tetraplegic from Cardigan, to have an assisted death in Switzerland. The investigation was dropped but it cost Dyfed Powys police force over £7,000 in overtime and IT.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The BMA survey found that 59% of doctors favoured legalising a right to die for those terminally ill and those who are incurably suffering, and 88% of the public favour this too. It is supported by The Royal Colleges of Physicians, Medicine, Nursing and Psychiatrists, and 96% of 140 UK disability rights organisations do not oppose reform. Limiting the option of assisted death only to those with 6 months left to live would be discriminatory because people with incurable conditions do not suffer less than terminally ill, and they deserve to be treated with the same dignity and respect. Austria, Canada, Belgium, Germany, The Netherlands, and other countries have already legislated for assisted dying for both the terminally ill and the incurably suffering.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">90% of the public in UK want a law to allow adults of sound mind who are terminally ill and suffering intolerably from an incurable condition the option of a peaceful, painless, and dignified death. The UK Assisted Dying Coalition found that more than one person a week who is terminally ill or incurably suffering is now forced to end their life abroad. But many cannot afford the £10,000 costs of travelling abroad. The right to die should not be limited to those with means.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a member of <a href="https://www.unitetheunion.org/what-we-do/unite-in-your-region/wales/">Unite the Union</a> I was honoured to be a part of the Unite Wales Women’s Network Launch of its “<a href="https://www.unitetheunion.org/campaigns/get-me-home-safely-campaign/">Get Me Home Safely (GMHS)</a>” campaign which was held in the Unite Building in Cardiff. The event was organised by my dear friend, Unite Wales Equalities Officer Jo Galazka and chaired by the Women’s Network chair Caroline Price. Speakers included Alison Spencer-Scragg, Unite National Women’s Officer, who extolled the benefits of getting involved in the Network and the priorities for Unite women. Irina Do Carmo, Unite Researcher and GMHS Lead, spoke about the success of the campaign, which was launched online in the UK in March 2022, and is now an international campaign. I took part in the online launch in March 2022 when we heard from Caitlin Lee, who was sexually assaulted walking home from work after a late Friday night shift working for a multinational hotel in Glasgow. Her employer denied that it had a duty of care towards Caitlin, and wouldn’t help her, so Caitlin and young Unite activists started the GMHS campaign. Caitlin is Unite Glasgow Hospitality branch chair, and she said that many workers in the hospitality industry are forced to choose between affording a week’s shopping or getting a taxi home, even if taxis were available. The GMHS campaign has 8 demands which include: a legislative change to extend an employer’s duty of care to cover a worker’s transport; free transport home for staff as a condition of granting a liquor licence; mandatory training for bus operators on gender-based violence; municipal ownership of buses to improve the shortage of night buses; and a national minimum standard for taxis and private hire. The GMHS campaign has secured support from Abellio in London, National Express in West Midlands, and the European Transport Federation, made up of pan-European trade unions, unanimously adopted it and will roll it out in all its nations. I am delighted that the campaign is now a global campaign and I am committed to help it become a success in Wales. The campaign will encourage employers in Wales to provide safe, free transport for its workers who finish their shifts late at night or in the early hours of the morning in the hospitality and tourism industries.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The inspirational Unite Welsh Women’s Officer, Jos Andrews, delivered an interactive learning session on “Getting Your Voice Heard” where all the many women at the meeting worked together in roleplaying exercises, which were very enjoyable, and we all got to know each other really well in a short space of time.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Sue Da’Casto, Unite Wales Learning Fund Officer, led a session on learning and development opportunities through the Women’s Network specifically through the Wales Union Learning Fund (WULF). Unite in Wales is present in over 2,000 workplaces across all sectors and has over 75,000 members. WULF is a Welsh Government funded programme that has a 20 year legacy. It is designed to encourage wider participation in lifelong learning, support bespoke workplace training, provide a best practice approach to essential skills such as literacy and numeracy, and remove barriers for vulnerable workers. WULF works in partnership with union networks, employers, statutory organisations, stakeholders, training providers and FE/HE partners to help future proof Welsh workplaces and support Unite members. Unite Skills Academy provides 12 different online and accessible training courses which include administrative and secretarial, IT, conflict resolution and social prescribing. Contact Sue at <a href="mailto:Learnwithunite.WULF@unitetheunion.org">Learnwithunite.WULF@unitetheunion.org</a> for more details.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended St David’s Church Service on 7th May to celebrate the coronation of King Charles III in Westminster Abbey on 6th May. Our Rector Lynda prayed that the King has the strength to serve our worldwide family of nations, the courage to defend the Faith in word and deed, and the grace to care for his people.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was pleased to support the annual <a href="https://aslef.org.uk/about/political-work">ASLEF Parliamentary reception</a> in Westminster and met its Leader Mick Whelan, of whom I am a great admirer.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="https://hopenothate.org.uk/">Hope not Hate</a> drop-in event in Westminster was about the rise of far-right anti-migrant activism. The MPs and Peers that attended heard that Hope not Hate research has shown that far-right activity around asylum accommodation has increased by at least 102% in 2022 from the previous year, with 253 separate incidents, which included – creating shared content online, leafleting and demonstrating, turning up at asylum accommodation to protest, harassing residents, filming content to boost their online profiles and encouraging anti-migrant activism. The far-right has attempted to generate outrage by drawing on a range of tropes, such as, disgust at the “luxury” accommodation given to “foreigners” compared with UK homeless people, particularly veterans, opposition of using taxpayers’ money during a cost-of-living crisis, and fear for the safety of women and children due to the “invasion” of young men. Some protests and opposition groups are being organised by the far-right locally. In Llantwit, local residents were upset that a site was going to be a new healthcare centre, and potentially become temporary housing for asylum seekers. The Patriotic Alternative, Britain’s most active fascist group, began leafleting in the Llantwit area to inflame local opposition, using the healthcare centre as a Trojan Horse for their extreme ideology.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was proud to be elected as a vice-chair of the <a href="https://www.appglgbt.org/">APPG Global LGBT and Rights</a> at its AGM, after being a member for many years. Dame Angela Eagle MP and Elliot Colburn MP were re-elected as co-chairs, and I look forward to working to improve the well-being of the LGBT community in countries around the world.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I have been a supporter of the <a href="https://www.dogstrust.org.uk/">Dogs Trust</a> for many years, and I was delighted to attend its drop-in to highlight the illegal import of puppies. In 2021, the UK Government made a commitment to tackle puppy smuggling via the proposed Animal Welfare (Kept Animals) Bill, including reducing the number of puppies that can enter the UK under the <a href="https://www.gov.uk/bring-pet-to-great-britain">Pet Travel Scheme (PETS)</a>, but the UK Government has not made available parliamentary time to progress this Bill. Whilst we wait, PETS continues to be abused by smugglers who find new ways to avoid detection to illegally import pregnant dogs and puppies who are often underage, unvaccinated, and in poor welfare condition. Since relaxation of PETS in 2012, Dogs Trust has cared for over 2256 illegally imported puppies, if sold to unsuspecting members of the public, would have made over £3 million for illegal importers. Over 75 dogs have had their ears cropped, despite it being an illegal procedure in the UK and EU. The UK Government should make parliamentary time available to debate and progress this Bill as soon as possible.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As chair of the APPG for Rail in Wales, I was very grateful that the Speaker granted me a 90-minute <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-05-10/debates/53E458C4-E5AD-4B01-9F4E-8CFA8534ED13/RailInfrastructureWales">Westminster Hall debate on Rail Infrastructure in Wales</a>. I opened the debate speaking about the history of my passion for trains, which started when I was about three years of age and suffered terribly with travel sickness every time that my mother took me on a bus journey. We didn’t have a car, so my mother tried taking me on a train, and I loved it and I wasn’t travel sick. I spoke about my dream that one day the freight lines in my Neath constituency would become available for passenger travel again. And I paid tribute to Banwen’s famous historian George Brinley Evans, who shared my dream and that he had long advocated reopening the passenger line from Swansea to Brecon. We all miss Uncle George who sadly passed away last year at the age of 96. I miss his friendship, advice, and long stories about his life. I emphasised how important railways are to the UK and Wales, but the lack of funding from the UK Government has resulted in the very poor state of many tracks, stations, and signalling systems, which desperately need repair and replacement. The fragmented nature of the rail sector in Wales leads to lack of coordination and accountability – the UK Government via Network Rail own it – Transport for Wales and other rail companies operate services. Despite these challenges, the Welsh Labour Government has made significant investments. The South Wales Metro is being built, a plan for the Swansea Metro is under way, and the North Wales Main Line upgrade will improve connectivity between Crewe and Holyhead, increasing capacity and shortening journey times. I praised the Welsh Labour Government for leading on the <a href="https://www.gcre.wales/">Global Centre of Rail Excellence</a> (GCRE) being developed in my Neath Constituency, which will be the UK’s first net zero testing facility, and will include a campus for rail innovation, R&amp;D, testing and verification, training, and train storage. By coincidence, on the morning of the debate, the GCRE announced that it had signed a deal with Transport for Wales for TfW to use all GCRE facilities, which follows a recent agreement with Hitachi. Great news. I spoke at length about the disappointment that HS2 will not bring benefits to Wales, and I suggested ways in which the rail infrastructure may become fit for purpose in the future. I concluded by thanking the MPs that spoke in the debate for their excellent contributions and for their unanimous support for every aspect of my speech. And I invited the UK Government Rail Minister, Huw Meriman MP; Shadow Minister, Tan Dhesi MP; all MPs in the debate, and the chair Judith Cummins MP for Bradford South, to visit the GCRE.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I supported Holly Lynch MP and Greg Smith MP at their Westminster event with the Directors of the proposed <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gratitudegames/?hl=en">Gratitude Games</a>, co-founders Mike Downard and Simon Rider. The games will be multi-sport, with over 20,000 competitors from 17 emergency service organisations, and the NHS, across 20 sports. The games will highlight and raise funds to help treat the profound mental health challenges and consequent poor mental health experienced by the UK responders. The plan is to stage the games in 2024, but it needs UK Government financial support to establish the games, and create a sustainable long-term funding infrastructure to support ongoing mental health. We listened to Sam Rider and Mike Downard make the case for the games, and from representatives from the emergency services including: Benjamin Pearson, who has retired because of mental health issues from serving as a police officer with West Yorkshire Police, and has since strived to make a difference as to the way people see and deal with mental health issues in the workplace; Ricky Nuttall, serving firefighter with London Brigade for 18 years, and one of the 250 first responders at Grenfell Tower on 14th June 2017, has suffered from PTSD as a result of the life-changing decisions he made that night, and now is an advocate for raising awareness of social and workplace mental health. I was one of the MPs and Peers at the meeting who signed individual letters to the UK Government asking for funding to be allocated for the establishment of the Gratitude Games.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was pleased to attend a meeting to support Anna Firth MP for Southend West, who will be having the first reading of her 10-Minute Rule Bill in the chamber on 23rd May which will criminalise fatal dog-on-dog attacks and hold irresponsible dog owners to account. The Bill will be informally called <a href="https://www.express.co.uk/news/politics/1768222/anna-firth-dog-on-dog-attacks-specific-criminal-offence">Emilie’s Law</a> after the late partner of Anna’s constituent Michael Joannou, whose dog Millie was fatally injured when attacked by another dog in 2021. Under current law, dog owners are not liable for any prosecution following an attack by their dog on another dog unless the injured dog is an assistance or service dog, or a human being is injured in the attack. Between 2016 and 2021, there was a 700% increase in dog-on-dog attacks from 1700 to 11559. I will be in the chamber on 23rd May to support Anna’s Bill.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a member and vice-chair, I attended the AGMs for both the APPG on Legal Aid, chaired by Karen Buck MP, followed by the APPG for Pro Bono and Public Legal Education, chaired by Laura Farris MP, meeting to formally reconstitute the APPGs before dissolving them. Both APPGs will, in the next few weeks, merge to form a new APPG on “Access to Justice”. Karen and Laura will become co-chairs and I agreed to become a vice-chair of the new APPG. It was great to catch up with Baron Willy Bach who chaired the Bach Commission which was founded at the end of 2015 with 13 commissioners, who held evidence sessions to identify key areas of LASPO that severely restricted legal aid access to justice. I was Willie’s vice chair and took over as chair when Willie became the PCC for Leicester in May 2016. The Fabian Society acted as secretariat to the Commission and the final report can be read <a href="https://fabians.org.uk/about-us/our-projects/previous-projects/the-bach-commission/#:~:text=The%20Fabian%20Society%20provided%20the,fundamental%20and%20enforceable%20public%20entitlement.">here</a>.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a long-time vice chair of the APPG on Acquired Brain Injury, chaired by Sir Chris Bryant MP, I attended a reception in the Jubilee Room off Westminster Hall to talk about better support for those with a brain injury and the strategy which continues to be worked on with officials from the Department for Health and Social Care. The event was so well attended by constituents with brain injuries eager to meet their MPs that the Jubilee Room was packed and there were queues extending into Westminster Hall.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">An old friend Rob Palmizi, who now works as Policy and Public Affairs Manager for the <a href="https://www.heritagefund.org.uk/in-your-area/wales">National Lottery Heritage Fund in Wales</a>, invited me to attend their Young People, Skills and the Future of the Heritage Sector at Westminster. The National Heritage Lottery Fund is the largest dedicated funder of heritage, and has invested over £8.2 billion in more than 45,000 projects since 1994. The event showcased two projects: the New to Nature programme supporting more than 70 full-time temporary work placements in nature and landscape organisations across the UK aiming to increase diversity and enrich the environmental sector, delivered through partnerships with Groundwork, The Prince’s Trust, Disability Rights UK, and Mission Diverse; and the Kick the Dust programme, which was named by young people with an aspiration to stir up heritage. 12 grants of between £5000 and £1 million have been allocated to projects across the UK that will involve more young people and where they can enjoy, learn and lead heritage-based activities in their communities.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was re-elected a vice chair at the AGM of the APPG for Sport, and we discussed suggestions for Parliamentary events to raise the profile of sport across the recreation sector.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I ended the week by watching the very brave Sue Andrews, Neath MA Reader and President of Churches Together, who had her <a href="https://twitter.com/StDavidsNeath/status/1657340264229289984?cxt=HHwWgIC2lY-Mh4AuAAAA">head shaved to raise money</a> for Christian Aid Week in St David’s Church.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am a member of the All-Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Choice at the End of Life, so I attended the My Death My Decision (MDMD) campaign for Assisted Dying event held in the Pierhead Building in Cardiff Bay, hosted by Jayne Bryant MS for Newport West and James Evans MS for Brecon and Radnorshire. MDMD believe […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2735</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T10:25:13Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T10:25:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why mental health matters – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-mental-health-matters-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-mental-health-matters-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236586" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/mh-matters.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">This week is mental health awareness week, a national week where we raise awareness of mental health and look at how we can improve support for people right across the country.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">I have made no secret of my own struggles with mental ill-health. I suffer from depression, and at certain periods this has made it tremendously difficult to get out bed in the morning, let alone do my job and tackle the day to day responsibilities of adult life. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">As a Member of Parliament, I have been chosen to represent people right across Tameside. That representation means speaking out about things like mental ill-health, and letting people know that there is absolutely no shame in seeking help.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">We have made huge strides in eliminating some of the stigma around mental health, but there is still so much more to do. It’s estimated that 1 in 6 adults experience symptoms of a common mental health problem at any given time, and the demand for mental health services is fast outstripping the resources offered to them, with 4.6 million mental health referrals issued in 2022 alone.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">So, raising awareness of the problem is vital, but I’m conscious that this must come with action.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">That’s why I’ve been so proud to support Labour’s mental health pledge, which would see mental health treatment guaranteed within a month, thousands more mental health professionals recruited, and an open access hub for young people in every community.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">This unprecedented investment would be paid for by closing tax loopholes which the Government have allowed to be exploited for far too long.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">I have no doubt that this pledge will have a truly transformative impact on people right across Tameside. Mental ill health can be debilitating, and its incredibly important that the infrastructure is in place to support local people.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">So, my message for this mental health day is clear; if you’re struggling, please talk to someone. Reach out to friends or family, your GP, or call helplines like the Samaritans (116 123) who will pick up the phone 24 hours a day, 365 days a year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">This week also serves as a reminder to check-in on your loved ones. It costs nothing, but I know from first-hand experience that it can make a world of difference if you’re struggling.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Open Sans,sans-serif;">Let’s keep talking, and build a health service where people can access the support they need, when they need it.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-mental-health-matters-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why mental health matters – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This week is mental health awareness week, a national week where we raise awareness of mental health and look at how we can improve support for people right across the country. I have made no secret of my own struggles with mental ill-health. I suffer from depression, and at certain periods this has made it […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-mental-health-matters-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why mental health matters – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236584</id>
    <published>2023-05-16T09:03:42Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-16T09:03:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>BBC Newsnight Asylum &amp; the Backlog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/bbc-newsnight-asylum-the-backlog/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>joshuatuck</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3418</id>
    <published>2023-05-15T19:17:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-15T19:17:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE HOUSEHOLDS HAMMERED BY INTEREST RATES RISES</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/05/15/west-dunbartonshire-households-hammered-by-interest-rates-rises/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes says local families are paying a heavy price for Westminster’s failure – as interest rates rise to their highest level in 15 years.</p>



<p>Following the Bank of England’s decision to hike interest rates to 4.5%, the UK government has been slammed by the SNP for failing to tackle the rising costs of living.</p>



<p>With inflation (CPI) at 10.1%, food and non-alcoholic drink inflation at 19.1%, and interest rates rising for the 12<sup>th</sup> time in a row – charities are warning that households facing soaring costs for food, rent and mortgage payments are struggling to make ends meet.</p>



<p>Local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes is working closely with advice charities and organisations in West Dunbartonshire to help hard-pressed families.</p>



<p>The SNP has repeated calls for the UK government to deliver additional support to prevent households falling into arrears.</p>



<p><strong>Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:</strong></p>



<p>“The Westminster government has trashed the economy and families here are being forced to pay a heavy price.</p>



<p>“Homeowners and renters across West Dunbartonshire are being hammered by rising food prices and the Bank of England’s rate increases. As costs soar, the situation is becoming more desperate for families struggling to make ends meet.</p>



<p>“I work closely with local advice charities and food banks – for anyone falling into arrears it’s important to reach out as early as possible.</p>



<p>“The UK government needs to get a grip and deliver the urgent action required to support families and prevent people losing their homes.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes says local families are paying a heavy price for Westminster’s failure – as interest rates rise to their highest level in 15 years. Following the Bank of England’s decision to hike interest rates to 4.5%, the UK government has been slammed by the SNP for failing to tackle the rising ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE HOUSEHOLDS HAMMERED BY INTEREST RATES RISES" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/05/15/west-dunbartonshire-households-hammered-by-interest-rates-rises/#more-1821728" aria-label="More on WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE HOUSEHOLDS HAMMERED BY INTEREST RATES RISES">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821728</id>
    <published>2023-05-15T16:23:06Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-15T16:23:06Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Bank of England"/>
    <category term="Cost of living Crisis"/>
    <category term="Food Prices"/>
    <category term="Inflation"/>
    <category term="Interest Rates"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Mortgage costs"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A new York to Hull Rail Link would boost connectivity, opportunities and the environment, say people of the East Riding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/new-york-hull-rail-link-would-boost-connectivity-opportunities-and-environment-say-people-east" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, today announces the results of his survey about the proposed new York to Hull Rail Link, which he has long advocated.
In his survey of 196 residents of the East Riding of Yorkshire, 98% of respondents expressed support for the scheme…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/new-york-hull-rail-link-would-boost-connectivity-opportunities-and-environment-say-people-east</id>
    <published>2023-05-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP Bill Wiggin reacts to Herefordshire Council election results </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/05/15/mp-bill-wiggin-reacts-to-herefordshire-council-election-results/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sir Bill Wiggin, Member of Parliament for North Herefordshire, has expressed his delight at the recent Herefordshire Council election results, which saw the Conservative Party gain 8 seats to become the largest party in Herefordshire, with 21 seats in total.... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/05/15/mp-bill-wiggin-reacts-to-herefordshire-council-election-results/#more-4703">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4703</id>
    <published>2023-05-15T09:47:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-15T09:47:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Elections and Levelling Up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/local-elections-and-levelling-up/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The elections for our district, town and parish councils this month have led to some big changes. Many well-known and long serving councillors have departed, and new candidates from all parties have stepped up to take their places. Before discussing the outcome of those elections, I would like to say thank you to all of […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6286</id>
    <published>2023-05-15T09:27:26Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-15T09:27:26Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[UP FOR THE CHALLENGE]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=494</id>
		<updated>2023-05-15T08:45:13Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-15T08:45:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/05/15/up-for-the-challenge/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-up :: 12 May 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/12/weekly-round-up-12-may-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-12-may-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>I was pleased to start the week speaking at the Health and Care Forum to talk to charities and patients’ groups about the work they do on behalf of patients being useful to parliamentarians. Good policy can only come after an understanding of the situation on the ground. But more than that, long-lasting policy can only be secured if we put patients first. We must redouble our efforts to improve patient satisfaction with the NHS. </p>
<p>This week I also joined Purpose Health Coalition in Parliament, who aim to encourage more people across the country to take up careers in their local NHS. We heard from Wes Streeting MP, the Shadow Secretary of State for Health and Social Care. Our NHS is built on the wonderful, caring people who run it and care for us when we most need it. Without tackling the retention crisis in the health service or having a workforce plan we will continue to see patient care fall short of what is expected. The Labour Party has shown time and time again that we understand how to run your public services. We must help the NHS continue on its march forward in reform and support the medical profession to deliver the breakthroughs needed in preventative care. More money alone into NHS won’t fix 13 years of Tory mismanagement. </p>
<p>Diabetes is a health condition that affects more and more people in the UK. That’s why I made time to pop into the Diabetes UK drop-in session this week. Untreated diabetes can be serious and even fatal. That’s why it’s important that residents visit their local GP to check their symptoms and discover preventative measures to halt the onset of diabetes. If you want to learn more just visit Diabetes UK’s website.</p>
<p>As you can already see, this week has been heavily focused on health matters. But on Wednesday morning I took up my seat on the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee to consider our investigation on “The Scrutiny of International Treaties and other international agreements in the 21st century”. A bulky title for a hefty subject! This was our 7th meeting on the issue and we heard from leading academics in international law and public policy on examples of international best practice and potential reforms to the current mechanisms for scrutinising of international agreements. It’s key to note that since the UK left the EU, we have lost the previous scrutiny mechanisms for international agreements reached by the UK. This was an active choice taken by the Tory Government. I believe we need more scrutiny, not less and Parliament should be at the heart of this process.</p>
<p>The session looked at how the UK can bring its treaty-making and scrutiny process in line with today’s international best practice. To better understand this, we compared the UK system for negotiating, agreeing, and implementing international agreements with other countries.  </p>
<p>I ended my parliamentary week how I started: being very busy. On Thursday I secured a question to the Cabinet Office on the steps the Government is taking to support small and medium-sized businesses bidding for public contracts. SMEs are fundamental to the economy of Bristol South and the wider South-West region as a whole, and for the provision of local jobs in the area. I asked the Government to work on closing the gaps in the Procurement Bill to enforce payment deadlines so that money is filtered down through the supply chain to help those vital SMEs. </p>
<p>An Urgent Question was also granted on Thursday regarding the Retained EU Law, the Revocation and Reform Bill. A title I’m sure is designed to make people lose interest on this vital aspect of our post-Brexit relationship with the EU. I criticised the Government for their flippant approach to this Bill and the haste with which the Tories have brought this forward. Simply put: it’s demonstrated their ill-preparedness. It’s clear to me, through my work with the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee, that the system through which we look at international treaties is not up to scratch and this debacle exemplifies the failures in our current system.</p>
<p>I was pleased to speak in a Westminster Hall debate this week on allergy awareness. We are seeing a rise in allergies in the UK, with the third highest incidences of allergies in the world. Allergies are stressful and costly conditions, which require adjustments to everyday life. It is terrifying for families to experience allergy reactions, particularly for parents of children who are rushed to hospital. There are just 40 allergy consultants in the UK – that equates to one consultant for every 1.3 million adults in the UK. The provision is wholly inadequate. It is vital that we ensure that there are allergy services across all areas so that people are adequately supported across the UK.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/12/weekly-round-up-12-may-2023/">Weekly Round-up :: 12 May 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to start the week speaking at the Health and Care Forum to talk to charities and patients’ […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/05/12/weekly-round-up-12-may-2023/">Weekly Round-up :: 12 May 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3504</id>
    <published>2023-05-12T14:08:21Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-12T14:08:21Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HMRC delays in paying Rural Fuel Duty Relief to fuel retailers is unacceptable, says Isles MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/05/12/hmrc-delays-in-paying-rural-fuel-duty-relief-to-fuel-retailers-is-unacceptable-says-isles-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HMRC delays in paying Rural Fuel Duty Relief to fuel retailers is unacceptable, says Isles MP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Isles MP, Angus Brendan MacNeil has contacted HMRC on behalf of local fuel retailer, Gordon Diesel Services Ltd who are experiencing ongoing delays in receiving their monthly Rural Fuel Duty rebate.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="4184" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/05/12/hmrc-delays-in-paying-rural-fuel-duty-relief-to-fuel-retailers-is-unacceptable-says-isles-mp/fuel/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg" data-orig-size="3782,2207" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="fuel" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-4184" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2023/05/fuel.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rural Fuel Duty Relief gives support to motorists by compensating fuel retailers in some rural areas with high road fuel prices and fuel retailers need to submit a claim each month.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Angus MacNeil MP said:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“HMRC state that they aim to process claims 30 days from its receipt and it is frustrating to hear that Gordon Diesel Service Ltd are having difficulties in getting their fuel rebate claims paid monthly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Fuel retailers have enough to do without having to chase HMRC for money due to them.&amp;nbsp; We cannot have a situation where businesses are struggling because of delays within HMRC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Since contacting HMRC yesterday for Gordon Diesel Services Ltd, I understand that other fuel retailers are also affected by this delay.&amp;nbsp; I am keen to hear from any other fuel retailers who are impacted by this, so please get in touch either by email at &lt;a href="mailto:angus.macneil.mp@parliament.uk"&gt;angus.macneil.mp@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt; or by calling my office on 01851 702272.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">HMRC delays in paying Rural Fuel Duty Relief to fuel retailers is unacceptable, says Isles MP Isles MP, Angus Brendan …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/05/12/hmrc-delays-in-paying-rural-fuel-duty-relief-to-fuel-retailers-is-unacceptable-says-isles-mp/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4182</id>
    <published>2023-05-12T13:58:30Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-12T13:58:30Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meeting with Chiltern Railways Managing Director</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/meeting-chiltern-railways-managing-director" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was really useful to catch up with the Managing Director of Chiltern Railways, Richard Allan, at Banbury Station last week.
I was able to highlight a number of issues constituents have been experiencing recently, including overcrowding on carriages, disruption caused as a result of the Oxford-…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/meeting-chiltern-railways-managing-director</id>
    <published>2023-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Monthly Column – May 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/monthly-column-may-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last weekend marked the historic celebration of His Majesty King Charles III’s Coronation – a wonderful moment of joy and unity in our national story.
I hope you had the opportunity to come together with others, whether at one of the fantastic local events here in our constituency – for example at…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/monthly-column-may-2023</id>
    <published>2023-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-200" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Coronation of King Charles III and Queen Camilla was a great spectacle. It was Britain at its best. The Ceremony, the Coronation procession (which had almost 4,000 members of the armed forces take part), and the concert at Windsor on Sunday really put on display the rich history we have as a…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-200</id>
    <published>2023-05-11T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-11T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Coronation of King Charles III and Queen Camilla celebrated across Aldridge-Brownhills</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/the-coronation-of-king-charles-iii-and-queen-camilla-celebrated-across-aldridge-brownhills/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">Celebrations for the Coronation of King Charles III and Queen Camilla brought out the very best across the Nation, the Commonwealth, and of course across the Constituency, as we came together to mark this historic and memorable occasion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">The response to the call for bunting flags to decorate the window s of my office was overwhelming, with almost 1,000 amazing designs received. A large selection went on display in the Constituency office windows and in my office in Parliament for all to see. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">A huge thanks to everyone who has participated, and especially to our local schools and nurseries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">My weekend started with visits to Ryders Hayes School and Rushall Primary School to join in their Coronation Assemblies on Friday morning. It was a wonderful start to the Celebrations of the weekend.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">With a big emphasis on communities, volunteering, and encouraging people to come together for the Coronation Celebrations it was a pleasure to then be able to join a very special ‘Thank You’ event organised by Jan Davies at Pelsall Village Centre, whilst enjoying a wonderful Sprinkles Tearoom afternoon tea! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">On the eve of the Coronation, which is a deeply religious ceremony, St Michael and All Angels Church in Pelsall led an Ecumenical Vigil Service, together with Pelsall Methodist Church. For me this set the scene for the Coronation of King Charles III.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">As the world watched as King Charles III was crowned at Westminster Abbey I joined Rev Nancy Ndoho and others at Aldridge Methodist Church to watch the Coronation Ceremony. It was a wonderful way to come together with the Nation for this truly historic and memorable occasion.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">My Coronation weekend was then an action packed few days of attending community events, events with friends and family – My Coronation Memories.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">On Saturday afternoon I was able to call in to the Friends of Streetly Library at the Streetly Library Fun Day, before heading to St Thomas Church in Aldridge, and then The Boathouse in Rushall, all of whom had organised Coronation activities, before ending the day lighting the Beacon in Aldridge.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">Many will remember how volunteers from Aldridge Shed, and Aldridge Rotary, together with support from local businesses and individuals created a Beacon to celebrate Queen Elizabeth’s Platinum Jubilee. The Aldridge Shed and Manor Farm Community Association Electronics Club then transformed the Beacon for the Coronation of HM King Charles III, and it now stands proudly back at the top of the High Street.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">Joined by Town Crier Stephen Green, Tim Bickley on the Trumpet, and members of 425 Aldridge Squadron RAF Cadets who provided the Guard of Honour, it was an honour to be invited to light the beacon once again. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">As always, special thanks to all who supported the event and to those who were involved in the organisation including Rotary, North Aldridge Neighbourhood Watch, Street Watch, Russell Smith and Jewellery &amp; Gifts Aldridge. And a big thank you to Aldridge Social Club too. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">Sunday’s weather was very much on our side. With the sun shining and a big focus on communities and neighbourliness it was a pleasure to drop by many more events. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">From Blackwood Pavilion and Park in Streetly to St Michael &amp; All Angels Church, Pelsall, Whitehorse Road, Stewart Road and Ryders Hayes Lane – Street Parties to Tea Parties, Picnics to Garden Parties, and lots of games and activities, it was a wonderful day and one in which I caught up with many of you.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">On Sunday evening like so many people I watched the Coronation Concert together with friends as we sang along and felt part of this spectacular event, as all eyes were on Windsor Castle. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">As the Coronation Celebrations continued on Monday with a focus on The Big Help Out to encourage volunteering in communities it was lovely to meet up with some of our own local organisations who do so much to support our communities, and to do my bit, alongside Cllr Amanda Parkes, joining the St Thomas Church litter pick.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">My day started by having breakfast with the Aldridge British Legion branch ( great bacon bap – thank you ) followed by calling in to the funday at St James’ Church, Brownhills, a Coronation funday in Catshill and catching up with volunteers at The THOMAS Project in Aldridge. The day was rounded off with a cream tea at Christ the King Church, Rushall.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">We are very fortunate to have many organisations and many volunteers who support our local communities in many ways, and on a personal level I was so pleased and honoured to be able to join in the Big Help Out as we continued our Coronation Celebrations. Thank You.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">Many of us have never seen a Coronation before. This weekend was truly historic and memorable. Each of us will have our own memories and reflections. We have truly lived a moment in history, and we owe a huge debt of gratitude and thanks to all those involved.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-family: Verdana, sans-serif; color: #000000;">God Save the King!</span></p>

<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0015.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0015.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0015-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0015-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0030.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0030.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0030-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0030-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0169_1.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0169_1.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0169_1-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0169_1-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0169_1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="720" height="540" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/FB_IMG_1683555518523.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/FB_IMG_1683555518523.jpg 720w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/FB_IMG_1683555518523-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) 720px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0028.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0028.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0028-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0028-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0034.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0034.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0034-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0034-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="2560" height="1708" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0014_1-scaled.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0014_1-scaled.jpg 2560w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0014_1-1280x854.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0014_1-980x654.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0014_1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 2560px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0025.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0025.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0025-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0025-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0025-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0118.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0118.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0118-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0118-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0118-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0012.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0012.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0012-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0012-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0020.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0020.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0020-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0020-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="881" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0019.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0019.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0019-980x843.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230505-WA0019-480x413.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0074.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0074.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0074-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0074-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0074-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="2560" height="1708" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0999-scaled.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0999-scaled.jpg 2560w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0999-1280x854.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0999-980x654.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0999-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 2560px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0126.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0126.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0126-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0126-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0126-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0198.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0198.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0198-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0198-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0198-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0131_1.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0131_1.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0131_1-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0131_1-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0131_1-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0033.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0033.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0033-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230507-WA0033-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1024" height="768" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0014.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0014.jpg 1024w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0014-980x735.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/IMG-20230508-WA0014-480x360.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1024px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1620" height="1080" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0146.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0146.jpg 1620w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0146-1280x853.jpg 1280w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0146-980x653.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0146-480x320.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) and (max-width: 1280px) 1280px, (min-width: 1281px) 1620px, 100vw"/>
<img width="1080" height="1620" src="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0080-rotated.jpg" class="attachment-full size-full" alt="" decoding="async" loading="lazy" link="none" size="full" columns="4" type="divi" ids="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" orderby="rand" include="4668,4669,4670,4671,4672,4673,4674,4675,4676,4678,4679,4680,4681,4682,4683,4684,4685,4686,4687,4688,4689" srcset="http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0080-rotated.jpg 1080w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0080-980x1470.jpg 980w, http://wendymorton.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/DSC_0080-480x720.jpg 480w" sizes="(min-width: 0px) and (max-width: 480px) 480px, (min-width: 481px) and (max-width: 980px) 980px, (min-width: 981px) 1080px, 100vw"/>

</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Celebrations for the Coronation of King Charles III and Queen Camilla brought out the very best across the Nation, the Commonwealth, and of course across the Constituency, as we came […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4667</id>
    <published>2023-05-09T15:14:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-09T15:14:48Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-49" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My good friend, John Hatton and his son Tim, came down to visit Parliament this week to watch PMQs. I took them both for a tour around the place whilst we caught up. I met John 20 years ago when we both volunteered at Ashfield Citizen’s Advice Bureau. Getting to show old friends where I work and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-49</id>
    <published>2023-05-09T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-09T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>God Save the King</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/54-uncategorised/2181-god-save-the-king"/>
		<published>2023-05-06T14:28:12+01:00</published>
		<updated>2023-05-06T14:28:12+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/54-uncategorised/2181-god-save-the-king</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;God Save the King &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Coronation?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Coronation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4hWbeAa60E"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4hWbeAa60E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1654832795678654464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;God Save the King &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Coronation?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Coronation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/4hWbeAa60E"&gt;pic.twitter.com/4hWbeAa60E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1654832795678654464?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;May 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Uncategorised"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Election success for Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/05/election-success-for-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour is celebrating retaining all 50 of the seats that they have held for the last four years at the local elections on 4 May 2023. In addition to this Labour gained a seat from the Conservatives in Clifton West. There are now no Conservatives on the Council for the first time. The people of Nottingham have recognised that Labour remains the best party to lead this city moving forward and have endorsed their manifesto with an overwhelming mandate earlier today.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This evening Nottingham Labour group has re-elected Cllr David Mellen as Leader of Nottingham City Council, while Cllr Audra Wynter has been elected as Deputy Leader.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the past four years have not always been easy, under the strong leadership of Cllr Mellen, Cllr Adele Williams and Cllr Sally Longford, Nottingham City Council has continued on its journey of improvement while maintaining the services that matter most. Cllr Williams has held the portfolio for Finance for the last year and led the delivery of a four-year balanced budget earlier this year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While Cllr Wynter is newly elected as deputy, she has previously served on the executive for the last year as Portfolio Holder for Highways, Transport and Parks. She was previously Chair of the Audit committee. Cllr Wynter has also led and supported social housing providers in building affordable homes and more temporary accommodations for the homeless. She has served the people of Bestwood Ward for 4 years and was re-elected earlier today.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour has great plans for the city, and under this new mandate Nottingham Labour will seek to deliver on the five key promises made at the election as well as the pledges in the full manifesto.&lt;br&gt;Following the election victory and his own re-election Cllr Mellen said:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“By once again voting for the Labour Party, the people of Nottingham have told us that they want a council that can deliver on jobs and houses, cut anti-social behaviour and clean up your neighbourhoods. Nottingham Labour has a strong track record in this, and we will continue this record.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We know this won’t be easy. We face ongoing financial challenges – from both the lack of investment from the Government, but also as we continue to recover from the pandemic. Our council is also currently on a journey of improvement – but I believe this will require us to be even more innovative and even more creative in the way we make changes for the better.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“We know the people who live in Nottingham have so much potential and we believe we can unlock that potential with an active, well-run City Council that supports and develops people, encourages growth and investment and provides people with security through essential public services. I am honoured to once again, have been given the responsibility of leading the council and will work with Cllr Wynter and those elected in the coming days as Portfolio Holders and all councillors elected today to repay the trust given to us by Nottingham People.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour is celebrating retaining all 50 of the seats that they have held for the last four years at the local elections on 4 May 2023. In addition to this Labour gained a seat from the Conservatives in Clifton West. There are now no Conservatives on the Council for the first time. The people… <a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/05/election-success-for-labour/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More »<span class="screen-reader-text">Election success for Labour</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=3071</id>
    <published>2023-05-05T17:59:20Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-05T17:59:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Arboretum"/>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="election"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>CH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Time To Put Children First]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6927</id>
		<updated>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Education"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="education"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership. It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Time To Put Children First</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" width="870" height="179" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership.</p>



<p>It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school success. Labour understands this. In the 60s and 70s the Wilson government created Educational Priority Areas and after 18 years of Tory rule, the last Labour government introduced Education Action Zones to once again boost the chances of children from poorer backgrounds.</p>



<p>It’s by working with parents and carers and putting schools at the centre of communities that we build the solid foundations from which children succeed. Over 13 years of Tory rule, we’ve seen teachers abused and experts ridiculed and an attempt to return schools to teaching models experienced by too many government ministers, in private schools, over the past 50 years. It’s not structures like free schools or academisation or gimmicks about a smattering of Latin that matter. We need support for parents and programmes to attract the best teachers to disadvantaged areas.</p>



<p>Almost every successful person has a story about the teacher who influenced their direction and put them on a path to success. We need to rediscover an ambition and love for education.</p>



<p>At Kings Heath Boys they’re not planning to rest on their laurels but open up choice and opportunity by changing to an intake of boys and girls. We’re blessed with several outstanding schools in south Birmingham, they do a remarkable job despite squeezed budgets, teacher retention problems and children’s mental health issues. These are all things the government should be addressing.</p>



<p>I hope the local community will get behind plans for Kings Heath Boys which will give more children a chance to attend a school that’s best for them. I’m hungry for a Labour government that treats teachers with the respect they deserve and puts our children first.</p>



<p>It’s time to focus on a system where the talents of every child can be nurtured and where their achievements are the priority.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/04/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-38/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Pleased to meet pupils from West Wycombe Combined School when they visited Parliament and answer their questions. Raised the concerns of Pine Trees’ residents at the Taylor Wimpey AGM. Accompanied the Secretary of State for Work and Pensions on a visit to Wycombe Marsh-based company Bradbury Tracks, to learn about how our Job Centre Plus is helping local people. Welcomed the announcement of £2.9 million extra investment for schools in Wycombe in […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18655</id>
    <published>2023-04-28T15:59:01Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-28T15:59:01Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="#Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz gives speech at ADASS Spring Seminar]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-gives-speech-at-adass-spring-seminar/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=12887</id>
		<updated>2023-04-28T12:12:43Z</updated>
		<published>2023-04-28T12:12:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was delighted to be invited to speak at the ADASS Spring Seminar this week. When I think about everything councils have faced – the repeated Government cuts to council budgets, the horrors of Covid19, the endless restructuring of the NHS and u-turns on social care reform &#8211; I sometimes [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-gives-speech-at-adass-spring-seminar/">Liz gives speech at ADASS Spring Seminar</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-gives-speech-at-adass-spring-seminar/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference.jpg"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12888" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-540x405.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-540x405.jpg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-260x195.jpg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-184x138.jpg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-768x576.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference-800x600.jpg 800w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-Spring-Conference.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></a></p>
<p>I was delighted to be invited to speak at the ADASS Spring Seminar this week.</p>
<p>When I think about everything councils have faced – the repeated Government cuts to council budgets, the horrors of Covid19, the endless restructuring of the NHS and u-turns on social care reform &#8211; I sometimes wonder how they keep going.<span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>But then I look at my own city, and Leicester’s Director of Adult Social Services Martin Samuels and his team, and I see that it’s the passion for improving the lives of older and disabled people, the commitment to making our communities better places to live, and the leadership on social care that has helped keep the show on the road.</p>
<p><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/ADASS-SPRING-SEMINAR-APRIL-2023-SPEECH.pdf">You can read my speech in full here.</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-gives-speech-at-adass-spring-seminar/">Liz gives speech at ADASS Spring Seminar</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HMRC and scam tax rebates</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="MortgageSmiths 27 04 23" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f9bgDDcDJnQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f4cd.png" alt="📍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; A constituent of mine discovered in November that HMRC had handed over £972 to the company MortgageSmiths, who took almost half of that in commission fees.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As he hadn&amp;#8217;t commissioned this company in the first place, he demanded to see the application form, which was such a poor forgery that both his and his wife&amp;#8217;s signature were clearly in the same handwriting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With the government repeatedly warning the public not to fall for financial scams, it&amp;#8217;s incredible that the HMRC fell for this one.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So can we have a Treasury statement, so we can understand the extent of this problem, what&amp;#8217;s being done to prevent it in the future, and when constituents like mine will actually get their money from the HMRC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Government response&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;br&gt;Well, I thank the Honourable Lady for raising this case. I&amp;#8217;m very sorry to hear that. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She may of course wish to raise it at Treasury questions on the 9th of May.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But given this is a sizable chunk of money for them to be out of pocket with, I will certainly raise this today with HMRC and ask them to contact the Honourable Lady with regard to this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;amp;linkname=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F04%2F27%2Fhmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates%2F&amp;#038;title=HMRC%20and%20scam%20tax%20rebates" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/" data-a2a-title="HMRC and scam tax rebates"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/"&gt;HMRC and scam tax rebates&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>  📍 A constituent of mine discovered in November that HMRC had handed over £972 ... <a title="HMRC and scam tax rebates" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/04/27/hmrc-and-scam-tax-rebates/">HMRC and scam tax rebates</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Parliamentary Assistant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2737</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T14:58:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T14:58:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="HMRC"/>
    <category term="Scam"/>
    <category term="Tax Rebate"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Stewart welcomes 3,468 extra police officers for Met Police</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has welcomed the announcement that 3,468 extra police officers have been recruited for the Metropolitan Police since September 2019, bringing the total number of officers up to 35,411.
 
The recruitment drive is part of the Government’s Beating Crime…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Social Security Health Assessments System <span style="color:#06396a;">Has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>The cross party Work and Pensions Select Committee responsible for scrutinising the Department for Work and Pensions’ (DWP) policies, has published a damning report on the Government’s health assessments system which is used to screen whether sick and disabled people should have access to vital social security payments.</p>
<p>These payments provide financial support to a working age person who is unable to work because of their health condition or disability; the assessment for this is the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) and is for either Employment Support Allowance or Universal Credit Limited Capability to Work. In addition there is also the Personal Independence Payment (PIP) assessment process to access support to cover the extra costs disabled people face because of their disability which are estimated at over £580 a month on average; this is for the Personal Independence Payment.</p>
<p>The report exposed the detrimental impact of the assessment process itself on the health and well being of claimants.</p>
<p>Giving evidence to the Committee, Professor Ben Barr, from the University of Liverpool, was asked about research he carried out in 2015 which looked at the impacts of the WCA as claimants were reassessed to move onto Employment Support Allowance. His analysis estimated that across England, the WCA had caused an additional 600 suicides, 300,000 additional cases of mental health problems and a large rise in the prescribing of antidepressants over a nine-year period.</p>
<p>“We looked at whether it could be explained by other factors or other economic trends, but there was quite a unique pattern in the increase in mental health problems, and the most likely explanation was that it was due to the reassessment process”, he told the committee. He said it is difficult to assess improvements since this study as “there are no systems in place” to monitor the impact of the health assessments and the potential adverse outcomes.</p>
<p>A survey by the University of Kent last year found half of claimants who have been through the WCA process said it made their mental health worse. Dr Ben Baumberg Geiger, who led the research, told the committee: “It is not sufficient to say that this is a historical problem and that everything is fine now. If there was more transparency, it would be easier to know a bit more about it, but the evidence suggests that there are still major problems with the WCA that could lead to an increased risk of poor mental health.”</p>
<p>Debbie Abrahams the Member of Parliament for Oldham East and Saddleworth and a Member of the Work and Pensions Select Committee said:</p>
<p><em>“The evidence is clear – the current system is not fit for purpose. The DWP’s own figures show that <strong><u>274 people a month</u></strong> <strong><u>die 6 months after being found fit for work </u></strong>and <strong><u>60 people a month die 3 months after having PIP refused. </u></strong>These are poorly people not the shirkers and scroungers that some Conservatives refer to when discussing social security claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“We heard evidence during the inquiry that when people were being reassessed between 2010 and 2013, there were 600 additional suicides. In 2020, National Audit Office has said that the claimant deaths that the DWP had investigated were the tip of the iceberg. The current approach is contributing, directly and indirectly, to the physical and mental health harm of claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“Last year the Equality Watchdog, The Equality and Human Rights Commission, issued a Section 23 order against the Department of Work and Pensions over their discriminatory treatment of disabled claimants.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Government itself has effectively acknowledged a different approach is needed when they announced that they would abolition the Work Capability Assessments, something I have been calling for years, but the detail of the future process is too opaque and doesn’t provide reassurance. Given it will take place several years to replace, what happens until then?</em></p>
<p><em>“I remain deeply concerned about these health assessments but also about the punitive nature of the sanctions regime, introduced in 2012 and, once again, on the rise. </em></p>
<p><em>“I believe it is these social security policies, as well as the inadequacy of the social security support especially for working age people, and the dehumanising culture that claimants too often experience that collectively contribute to the adverse health effects is the It is so detrimental to vulnerable people especially, but to all people as well.</em></p>
<p><em>“Given the failure of the Government to make many of the changes recommended in our predecessor Committee in 2018, I hold little hope in them taking on board the improvements set out in the report.”</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7098</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
    <category term="Department for Work and Pensions"/>
    <category term="Health Assessment"/>
    <category term="Social Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP shows support for home-grown cider makers during British Cider Week</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/04/24/mp-shows-support-for-home-grown-cider-makers-during-british-cider-week/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/04/24/mp-shows-support-for-home-grown-cider-makers-during-british-cider-week/">MP shows support for home-grown cider makers during British Cider Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/04/24/mp-shows-support-for-home-grown-cider-makers-during-british-cider-week/">MP shows support for home-grown cider makers during British Cider Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5218</id>
    <published>2023-04-24T10:39:20Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-24T10:39:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Visit to the Thames Tideway Tunnel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/04/24/visit-to-the-thames-tideway-tunnel/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to visit the Thames Tideway tunnel which will work as a capture and store for raw sewage and rainwater that currently overflows when the London sewerage system cannot cope. It's a really impressive project and one that is vitally needed to reduce the environmental impact from untreated dirty water. A similar scheme [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/04/24/visit-to-the-thames-tideway-tunnel/">Visit to the Thames Tideway Tunnel</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5141</id>
    <published>2023-04-24T10:13:24Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-24T10:13:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bexleyheath Branch host Spring Lunch at The Boathouse </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/bexleyheath-branch-host-spring-lunch-boathouse" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">On Sunday 23rd April, Bexleyheath Branch of the Bexleyheath &amp; Crayford Conservative Association hosted a Spring Lunch at the Boathouse, Danson Park.  The event was organised by the Ward Chairman, Maureen King and Association Deputy Chairman (Membership &amp; Fundraising), Janet Power. 
The…</content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/bexleyheath-branch-host-spring-lunch-boathouse</id>
    <published>2023-04-23T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-23T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update on a few local matters.</p>
<p>First of all, for those of you intending to vote in the local elections in May, a reminder if you did not know, that you will need to take photo ID with you to the polling station. This is part of a new approach to avoid people impersonating someone else by voting in their name.</p>
<p>There are details on Council websites for Epsom and Ewell, Mole Valley and Reigate and Banstead and what to do if you do not have a suitable form of ID.</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.epsom-ewell.gov.uk/council/elections-and-voting/voter-id-elections</a></p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.molevalley.gov.uk</a></p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://">www.reigate-banstead.gov.uk</a></p>
<h2>Stoneleigh Railway Crossing</h2>
<p>For those of you living in the Stoneleigh area, work is due to start soon on the new step free crossing over the railway at the station. I hope this will make things much easier for people with mobility issues, not to mention small children in buggies or heavy shopping bags.</p>
<p>This is a timetable for the planned work.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-6424" src="http://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-1024x664.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="664" srcset="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-200x130.jpg 200w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-300x195.jpg 300w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-400x259.jpg 400w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-600x389.jpg 600w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-768x498.jpg 768w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-800x519.jpg 800w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable-1024x664.jpg 1024w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Timetable.jpg 1170w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<h2>One Day Travel Cards</h2>
<p>Transport for London has just announced that it is planning to scrap paper one day travelcards from outside London, which is likely to affect many people in our area. I will be lodging an objection to this, particularly as it is happening at the same time as the proposed ULEZ. If you want to find out more, they have published details at</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://haveyoursay.tfl.gov.uk/travelcards">https://haveyoursay.tfl.gov.uk/travelcards</a></p>
<p>Although the feedback form on this site is pretty limited, I would encourage you to share any opinions about the proposal via the link.</p>
<h2>Veterans Group</h2>
<p>In the last bulletin I gave you details of the support for veterans in Epsom and Ewell. I have been asked to remind those living in Mole Valley about the veterans hub for those living in the district, which is also providing valuable support locally. You can find out all the details at</p>
<p><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.molevalleyveteranshub.co.uk/">https://www.molevalleyveteranshub.co.uk/</a></p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris Grayling</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update on a few local matters. First of all, for those of you intending to vote in the local elections in May, a reminder if you did not know, that you will need to take photo ID with you to the polling station. This is part [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-12/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6425</id>
    <published>2023-04-21T19:38:42Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-21T19:38:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alcohol Labelling]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/04/26/alcohol-labelling/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1772</id>
		<updated>2023-04-21T08:25:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-04-26T08:24:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="alcohol"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="public health"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/04/26/alcohol-labelling/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Kirsty Watson</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Press release: Argyll &#038; Bute MP fears HPMA plan will accelerate depopulation crisis]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/04/18/argyll-bute-mp-fears-hpma-plan-will-accelerate-depopulation-crisis/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10823</id>
		<updated>2023-04-18T15:43:20Z</updated>
		<published>2023-04-18T15:31:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Argyll &#38; Bute MP, Brendan O’Hara has written to the First Minister, Humza Yousaf, urging him to ditch the controversial proposals to introduce Highly Protected Marine Areas in the waters off the West Coast of Scotland, saying that the plan would “have a devastating impact …on the future economic viability of our already economically fragile ... <a title="Press release: Argyll &#038; Bute MP fears HPMA plan will accelerate depopulation crisis" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/04/18/argyll-bute-mp-fears-hpma-plan-will-accelerate-depopulation-crisis/" aria-label="More on Press release: Argyll &#038; Bute MP fears HPMA plan will accelerate depopulation crisis">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>St Helens Mobile Pantry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2023/04/18/st-helens-mobile-pantry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7624</id>
    <published>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes school debaters to Downing Street</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/03/29/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-school-debaters-to-downing-street/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament before their visit to Number Ten. The day was rounded off by a Q&amp;amp;A session with Matt and the competition judges as well as guests from Parliament including House of Commons Library Director of Research Edward Wood. The panel passed on their careers advice as well as explaining some of the opportunities available in politics besides being an MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4189 aligncenter" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the visit &lt;strong&gt;Matt Warman MP commented&lt;/strong&gt; ‘I was keen to establish a debating competition to encourage students to think deeply about some of the issues facing our society and, crucially, to equip them with the skills to consider both sides of a complex argument. Today’s visit to the home of modern democracy was an excellent opportunity to see those skills in action with students having the chance to observe opposition MPs challenging Ministers at the despatch box. I look forward to next year’s programme and on a broader note, am always happy to welcome schools in my constituency to Parliament.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chair of Governors at Boston High School Lisa Smith&lt;/strong&gt; who accompanied the visit said ‘This was a wonderful opportunity for our students to see democracy in action – and to be inspired by the opportunities for careers in parliament. We are grateful to Matt for arranging the debate competition and the visit and look forward to defending our winner’s trophy next year!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4187 alignnone" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-768x576.png 768w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4188 alignright" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4186</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP statement on new sanctions on Burmese Military</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_new_sanctions_on_burmese_military" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
          <strong>The UK Government has announced new sanctions targeting companies supplying aviation fuel, arms and aircraft parts to the Burmese military, after similar sanctions were announced in the US this month. Following the announcement, Rushanara Ali MP said:</strong>
        </p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_new_sanctions_on_burmese_military</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T09:44:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T09:44:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Judith Cummins MP on Tuesday called for the government to step up and provide 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services in England.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Osteoporosis is a long-term health condition characterised by weak bones prone to breaking or fracture. It affects 3.5m people across the UK: a fifth of men and half of women over 50.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A report by the Royal Osteoporosis Society found that 90,000 people miss out on the treatment every year and some 2.2 million people in the UK are left with undiagnosed spinal fractures. Fracture Liaison Services&amp;nbsp;are an essential means of identifying and treating osteoporosis early. Yet, only 57% of people in England have access to this quality of life improving service.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in the Chamber, Judith called on the government to provide the necessary services, which could prevent over thirty thousand hip fractures by identifying bone problems early:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“An investment of just £27 million per year in Fracture Liaison Services would deliver over £600 million in savings over five years for the NHS.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Will the Minister meet with me and the Royal Osteoporosis Society, to discuss our report, and commit to ending the postcode lottery by providing 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services for over-50s in England?”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Secretary of State for Health Steve Barclay MP agreed: “Obviously, she sets out a very compelling case in terms of the return on investment. Clearly, we will need to scrutinise that in more detail.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/2023_03_07-FLS-ROS-Health-Q.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Judith hears from the Health Secretary there is a &amp;#8216;compelling case&amp;#8217; for investing in FLS&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking afterwards, Judith emphasized the need to act now to ensure that the NHS is not overwhelmed, and people are not unnecessarily left in pain with debilitating fractures:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Bradford has an exemplary fracture liaison service, but almost half of the country must do without. When these early opportunities to prevent fractures are missed there is a greater pressure on ambulances, acute hospital bed days, and greater stress on the NHS.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“By acting now to provide full Fracture Liaison Services coverage right across England, we can save people unnecessary pain, save the NHS vital resources, and give all patients the level of care they deserve.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-must-have-access-to-nhs-services-they-need/" title="People must have access to NHS services they need"&gt;People must have access to NHS services they need&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/people-must-have-access-to-nhs-services-they-need/" title="People must have access to NHS services they need"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="People must have access to NHS services they need" alt="People must have access to NHS services they need" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In her latest column, Judith writes about the impact of the cost of living and lack of access to NHS Services: Originally printed in the Telegraph and Argus, Weds 31 August 2022: "When I speak to residents across Bradford South, it is clear that the cost-of-living crisis is a huge&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, people, government, services, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, called, service, services, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;78&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" alt="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, secretary, judith, health, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-must-act-now-to-end-crisis-in-dentistry/" title="Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry"&gt;Government must act now to end crisis in dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;78&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has warned the government that if it does not act now, NHS dentistry in England faces collapse. Speaking in a debate on Access to NHS Dentistry which Judith co-sponsored, Judith told the government they were trying to solve long-term issues with short-term fixes: “The current&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, government, judith, england, year, service, speaking, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP on Tuesday called for the government to step up and provide 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services in England.   Osteoporosis is a long-term health condition characterised by weak bones prone to breaking or fracture. It affects 3.5m people across the UK: a fifth of men and half of women over 50.   A […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2717</id>
    <published>2023-03-07T15:45:24Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-07T15:45:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Funding for a new hospital not photo-ops, demands Alex of Rishi Sunak after PM’s visit to North Tees Hospital]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/funding-for-a-new-hospital-not-photo-ops-demands-alex-of-rishi-sunak-after-pms-visit-to-north-tees-hospital/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14630</id>
		<updated>2023-01-31T09:45:51Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-31T09:45:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham has called on Prime Minister Rishi Sunak to “reflect on his photo opportunity” at North Tees Hospital and “commit to fund a new hospital” for Stockton on Tees. The Prime Minister visited North Tees Hospital this morning as part of his regional tours (30 Jan. 23) alongside the Health Secretary [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/funding-for-a-new-hospital-not-photo-ops-demands-alex-of-rishi-sunak-after-pms-visit-to-north-tees-hospital/">Funding for a new hospital not photo-ops, demands Alex of Rishi Sunak after PM’s visit to North Tees Hospital</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The truth about protecting our waterways</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/truth-about-protecting-our-waterways" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In contrast to misleading and false assertions made recently, the simple truth is that this Conservative Government is the first to set out our expectation that water companies must take steps to significantly reduce storm overflows. We are now delivering the largest programme to tackle storm…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/truth-about-protecting-our-waterways</id>
    <published>2023-01-27T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-27T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="pbs-main-wrapper"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=vpIeI5cF" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-6464f28d80485" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-6464f28d80485').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"6464f28d80485","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-6464f28d80485" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-6464f28d80485" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="6464f28d80485" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_6464f28d80485" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_6464f28d80485" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_6464f28d80485" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_6464f28d80485" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_6464f28d80485" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_6464f28d80485" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_6464f28d80485_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-6464f28d80485 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dykH1lgWst4Kg02jFW-sZNJYsDiVEXM7XwvsrCs0rcSayUzThSikM_3UzisYWabMiXYCwcoAdhIF7BFa6q4Tg' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>2</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
