<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-01-18T09:29:47Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>The Northern Ireland Protocol negotiations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/01/18/the-northern-ireland-protocol-4/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>There is considerable discussion and much misinformed commentary on a possible EU/UK deal on this outstanding disagreement.</p>
<p>The Protocol itself was an agreement to disagree, a temporary holding position pending the full Trade and Co-operation Agreement between the UK and NI. Then there was the failure to resolve the outstanding issues even at that later stage. It left unclear the interactions of EU and UK law and of the respective internal markets.</p>
<p>The Protocol does make clear the primacy of the Good Friday Agreement, which the opening of the Protocol says “must be protected in all its parts.” Yet the Protocol now is the main cause of dissent, preventing the resumption of devolved government and cross community working which lies at the heart of the Good Friday Agreement. . The Protocol does not enjoy the consent of the Unionist community, yet the Good Friday Agreement requires the consent of both communities to important matters covered by the Protocol. Most people of good will want the Good Friday Agreement to continue to provide a secure future for NI, and are worried by the current impasse over attendance at the Stormont Assembly.</p>
<p>The Protocol states support for the “shared aim of avoiding controls at the ports and airports of NI to the extent possible in accordance with applicable legislation” . It is to have regard to “the importance of maintaining the integral place of NI in the UK’s internal market”. Article 1 “respects the essential state functions and territorial integrity of the UK”. NI is recognised as part of the customs territory of the UK. Article 6 is dedicated to the protection of the UK single market.</p>
<p>The truth is the EU negotiating mandate does not allow a solution, because it violates these crucial features of the Protocol and does not respect the legitimate concerns of the Unionist community. So far we read the UK may share more of our trade data with the EU concerning internal trade within the UK, with no reciprocation. We hear the UK is considering border control points at ports and airports in violation of the Protocol to avoid checks on internal UK trade into NI. None of this makes any sense, as it will annoy the Unionist community more.</p>
<p>Those wishing to help resolve this need to understand these simple points. Nothing can work in NI without the consent of both communities. The Protocol does not have Unionist consent. It is not just a matter of trade issues. The Unionist Community does not wish to be subjected to EU law with no rights to reject or amend it. The EU and UK should not seek to force a solution on NI that one community rejects.</p>
<p>The UK has been very generous is seeking to meet the legitimate concern of the EU, namely the protection of their single market. The UK could secure this for them by the method of UK legislating to say it would be an offence for anyone in NI to seek to export into the EU products that do not meet EU laws and regulations. There is no case to justify barriers to GB to NI trade, nor the imposition of EU laws on NI now the UK has left the EU. Of course the UK should supply all data concerning exports to the EU that the EU wishes to see. The checks and controls on exports to the EU need not be made at the border but can  be made at the farm, factory or warehouse from which the consignment is despatched.</p>
<p>Article 13.8 envisages the amendment or ending of this  Agreement. Article 16 allows either side to take unilateral remedial action in a wide range of problem circumstances, and seeks to outlaw trade diversion which imposing barriers on internal GB/NI trade can create.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There is considerable discussion and much misinformed commentary on a possible EU/UK deal on this outstanding disagreement. The Protocol itself was an agreement to disagree, a temporary holding position pending the full Trade and Co-operation Agreement between the UK and NI. Then there was the failure to resolve the outstanding issues even at that later…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=34266</id>
    <published>2023-01-18T05:01:42Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-18T05:01:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy Questions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/parliament/business-energy-and-industrial-strategy-questions-5" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="2592" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;17 January 2023&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy Questions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Freeman, Minister for Science, Research and Innovation answers MPs’ questions on the development of onshore wind farms, the forced installation of prepayment electricity meters, the reporting of greenhouse gas emissions and encouraging international R&amp;D investment into the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-45629" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LGpAtB3EZgI?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Onshore Wind Farms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3928"&gt;Nick Smith (Blaenau Gwent) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. What assessment he has made of the adequacy of the number of onshore wind farms developed in England since 2015. (903113)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister for Science, Research and Innovation (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onshore wind in the UK has been a great success. It generates 25% of our total renewables, and since 2015 around 10 onshore wind projects, totalling 30 MW, have been given consent in England. We have made it clear that onshore wind is an important part of the energy mix and that we will now need more, which is why we are consulting on making changes to the national planning policy framework in England so that local authorities can better respond to the views of their local communities when they wish to host onshore wind infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=3928"&gt;Nick Smith &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New onshore wind has been stymied since 2015, even though it is our cheapest renewable. Shire-counties conservatism has been put ahead of our national interest; weak policy has undermined the UK’s energy security, leaving us wide open to international shocks. Does the Minister not accept that all this has helped to cause family bills to skyrocket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a word, no. What has caused family bills to skyrocket is the international pressure on energy supply chains, the war in Ukraine and the economic sanctions in respect of Russia. I accept the point that the costs of onshore wind have fallen dramatically through our contracts for difference round 4. This is a UK success story, which is why we are keen to do more. The public-opinion data show that 78% of the public support onshore wind. We want to make sure that we do not impose it on local authorities and are giving them more freedom to make sure they can reflect local demand so that it is renewable energy led by communities with community benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1559"&gt;Sir James Duddridge (Rochford and Southend East) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking out from the east of my constituency, one can see a number of offshore wind farms, which are more efficient and cheaper. The Government have done really well over the past 10 years by increasing the renewable generation of electricity fivefold; does the Minister agree that that not only helps to cut emissions but pump-primes new jobs markets in the generation of clean energy around the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a BEIS Minister and as an East Anglian Member of Parliament, I absolutely agree with my hon. Friend. The southern North sea is becoming the Saudi Arabia of wind energy, and the Norfolk and Suffolk coast and the new hydrogen freeport at Felixstowe and Harwich are part of the way in which we are growing the infrastructure for smart advanced wind and a linked hydrogen economy in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-01-17/debates/793fedf4-0250-4438-97c1-7195e94eae23/CommonsChamber#contribution-4377C187-DB67-4AF2-BC62-33971B5FF628"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Topical Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4432"&gt;Patrick Grady (Glasgow North) (SNP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The calls that we have already heard to take action to support people on prepayment meters are echoed by more than 40 Members of both Houses on the all-party parliamentary group on fuel poverty and energy efficiency. They, too, are calling for a ban on forced installation of prepayment meters by court warrant and an end to unfair standing charges and price differentials. It is not good enough just to hear nice words from the Government; they have to require action from the energy suppliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister for Science, Research and Innovation (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree that the most vulnerable consumers in this country should be protected. Those duties already lie with Ofgem. I shall repeat what my right hon. Friend the Secretary of State said earlier: it is completely unacceptable that vulnerable patients leave hospital and find that they have been automatically disconnected. We are convening a roundtable meeting and my right hon. Friends the Secretary of State and the Minister for Energy and Climate are putting pressure on Ofgem to make sure that vulnerable consumers are looked after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-01-17/debates/793fedf4-0250-4438-97c1-7195e94eae23/CommonsChamber#contribution-0A56B30E-87FC-4144-BB59-4625D383F884"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=1524"&gt;Dame Meg Hillier (Hackney South and Shoreditch) (Lab/Co-op)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an inconsistency in how the public sector is required to report greenhouse gas emissions. That makes it difficult to keep a track on progress as we approach net zero, and difficult for citizens to hold the public sector to account on delivery. What is the Minister doing to rectify that so that we can keep a proper track on what is happening?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May I take this opportunity, on behalf of the Department, to thank the hon. Member and the Public Accounts Committee for their report, to which we will very shortly reply? I am delighted to say that the public sector has reduced emissions by 44% since 1990 and the Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy by 70% since 2010. We appreciate her Committee’s point that the data—the metrics—have to be clear and coherent, and we are taking that on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-01-17/debates/793fedf4-0250-4438-97c1-7195e94eae23/CommonsChamber#contribution-1582AA42-3C21-4B65-B2AB-49B2C48660B7"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4767"&gt;James Sunderland (Bracknell) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T8. The UK is a hub of privately driven research and development. I am proud that my Bracknell constituency is the silicon valley of the Thames valley and the home of fantastic companies such as 3M, Dell, Honda and Panasonic, which is also great for local employment. What steps are being taken to encourage more international R&amp;D investment into the UK? (903105)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hon. Friend makes a good point. We have the groundbreaking commitment to move from £15 billion to £20 billion a year of investment in public R&amp;D over this comprehensive spending review, the creation of the National Science and Technology Council, the recent launch of our international science partnership fund, the ISPF, which I announced in Japan with a first tranche of £119 million, a series of strategic bilats and multilats, and, of course, our £7 billion ring-fenced for Horizon for three years—if we cannot deploy it through Horizon, we will deploy it in other ways to support UK R&amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-01-17/debates/793fedf4-0250-4438-97c1-7195e94eae23/CommonsChamber#contribution-7E556ED1-C05A-4218-A5CC-2132538EF9DF"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2592 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T22:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill Wiggin MP supports Guide Dogs’ Open Doors campaign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/01/17/sir-bill-wiggin-mp-supports-guide-dogs-open-doors-campaign/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sir Bill Wiggin, MP for North Herefordshire has pledged his support to all people living with vision impairment through Guide Dogs’ Open Doors campaign. At a parliamentary event hosted in December by the charity Guide Dogs, Sir Bill Wiggin MP... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/01/17/sir-bill-wiggin-mp-supports-guide-dogs-open-doors-campaign/#more-4571">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4571</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T17:08:39Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T17:08:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We Cannot Afford To Lose The British Steel Industry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/we-cannot-afford-to-lose-the-british-steel-industry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3285</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T15:46:06Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T15:46:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Take part in RSPB Big Schools' Birdwatch 2023! Local MP Maria Miller MP is urging all Basingstoke schools to sign up today to the Royal Society for the Protection of Birds (RSPB) Big Schools' Birdwatch 2023! </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/take-part-rspb-big-schools-birdwatch-2023-local-mp-maria-miller-mp-urging-all-basingstoke" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maria said, “This is a fun, annual science project for schools that encourages children to count how many bird species they see in a day at school. Taking part is as easy as 1,2,3 at RSPB’s website.
"All the resources support curriculum learning, including for the first time providing schools with…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/take-part-rspb-big-schools-birdwatch-2023-local-mp-maria-miller-mp-urging-all-basingstoke</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Wages Growing at the Fastest Rate in 20 Years</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/wages-growing-fastest-rate-20-years" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today we welcomed news that a record number of people are in work and wages are growing at the fastest rate in 20 years – creating jobs and helping grow the economy. 
Even in the face of global economic challenges the UK labour market remains resilient, and we are determined to support families…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/wages-growing-fastest-rate-20-years</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title> Graham Stuart MP welcomes Councillors’ Victory on Mobile Mast</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-councillors-victory-mobile-mast" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart MP’s inbox is regularly full of people complaining about poor mobile service in the area.
 
Graham is delighted that, following intervention from Cllrs David Elvidge and Kerri Harold, a mast has been installed on County Hall, which should help to alleviate the problems with mobile…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-councillors-victory-mobile-mast</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg visits Waddesdon Church of England School</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-visits-waddesdon-church-england-school" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Last Friday morning Greg Smith MP visited Waddesdon Church of England School where he spoke to the whole school assembly about his role as the local Member of Parliament, followed by a more detailed Q&amp;A session with Year 8 pupils about democracy and our constitutional arrangements.
Commenting,…</content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-visits-waddesdon-church-england-school</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Special Education provision is inadequate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/01/special-education-provision-is-inadequate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Special educational needs matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many parents contact me because either they can&amp;#39;t access it or the provision is inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One school&amp;#39;s SEND policy did not even mention &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Autism?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Autism&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/neurodiversity?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#neurodiversity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the Minister if the standards in the govt&amp;#39;s review would be enforced. &lt;a href="https://t.co/a7lokPuIL5"&gt;pic.twitter.com/a7lokPuIL5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f499.png" alt="💙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1615052236299829249?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 16, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;amp;memberId=4124"&gt;Chi Onwurah &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special educational needs provision in school matters. So many parents contact me either because they cannot access such provision or because it is inadequate. One family with two neurodiverse children suffering from bullying and self-harm found that their school’s SEN policy did not even mention autism or neurodiversity. The Minister said this morning that the Government’s response to the review will be published imminently. Can she confirm that it will be published within the month and that the clear standards she mentioned will be enforced?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HANSARD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-01-16/debates/C00B19B7-6849-4519-AEC8-ACA5AF94CC9A/TopicalQuestions#contribution-1B1807A3-D261-459E-8133-9FAB08A73A81"&gt;https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-01-16/debates/C00B19B7-6849-4519-AEC8-ACA5AF94CC9A/TopicalQuestions#contribution-1B1807A3-D261-459E-8133-9FAB08A73A81&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Special educational needs matters. Many parents contact me because either they can't access it or the provision is inadequate. One school's SEND policy did not even mention #Autism or #neurodiversity I asked the Minister if the standards in the govt's… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13149</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T11:21:19Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T11:21:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex welcomes news that Stockton on Tees is getting a new Community Diagnostic Centre]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/alex-welcomes-news-that-stockton-on-tees-is-getting-a-new-community-diagnostic-centre/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14618</id>
		<updated>2023-01-17T10:59:33Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-17T10:59:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m delighted with the news that a diagnostic centre based in Stockton town centre was approved by Ministers several weeks ago. Securing this centre has been a years’ long dream of North Tees and Hartlepool NHS Foundation Trust and our Labour-led Stockton on Tees Council, and it’s great to see their joint work pay off. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/01/alex-welcomes-news-that-stockton-on-tees-is-getting-a-new-community-diagnostic-centre/">Alex welcomes news that Stockton on Tees is getting a new Community Diagnostic Centre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins raises the financial troubles at Staveley Town Council in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/17/toby-perkins-raises-the-financial-troubles-at-staveley-town-council-in-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/17/toby-perkins-raises-the-financial-troubles-at-staveley-town-council-in-parliament/">Toby Perkins raises the financial troubles at Staveley Town Council in Parliament</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/01/17/toby-perkins-raises-the-financial-troubles-at-staveley-town-council-in-parliament/">Toby Perkins raises the financial troubles at Staveley Town Council in Parliament</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5166</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T10:40:14Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T10:40:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why the Government’s strike bill is wrong on every level – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-the-governments-strike-bill-is-wrong-on-every-level-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-the-governments-strike-bill-is-wrong-on-every-level-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235998" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Strike-Bill.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0 x_elementToProof">On Monday, Tory MPs voted through the first stages of a Bill to impose minimum service levels on workers across England, Scotland and Wales. Under these proposals, Ministers would be handed new power to order compulsory ‘work notices’ on striking workers, who could then be sacked for going on strike.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0 x_elementToProof">I proudly voted against these measures and have made no secret of the fact that I think they’re unnecessary, unworkable and all-in-all pretty shoddy.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">The Government has claimed that they’re rushing through this undemocratic legislation to guarantee public safety, but that just doesn’t wash.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">Take NHS staff, for example. Unions already work with Trusts across the country to agree emergency cover during strike action. We’ve all seen the footage of staff breaking picket lines to care for unwell people. If the Government is so concerned about patient safety, what is it doing to tackle soaring ambulance waiting times and A&amp;E waiting lists on non-strike days? Why isn’t it recruiting and retaining more staff?</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">Strike action is a last resort for our public service workers. Not only do they lose pay, but – and as I know from my own interactions with NHS staff in Tameside – our public services are staffed in the main by people who are wholly committed to supporting the public. The Government could have averted NHS staff strikes if they had met with nurses and discussed – just discussed – pay. They refused. It’s time we saw some minimum service levels from this Government.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">In the darkest days of the pandemic, I stood on the doorstep of my home in Denton and clapped NHS staff. I saw families emerge from their homes brandishing pots and pans and banging them as loudly as they could to thank people working around the clock to save lives. It is totally beyond belief that the Prime Minister has now gone from clapping to sacking our NHS staff.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">Put aside the moral issues with this strategy. Think about the practical ones, too. The NHS is suffering an acute workforce shortage – why on earth would sacking essential staff help?  The answer is it wouldn’t.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal x_FluidPluginCopy x_ContentPasted0">The people I represent here in Tameside deserve serious solutions to a serious problem. Proper investment in our NHS, a transport system that works for them, and access to high-quality education for their kids. This Bill is simply a distraction tactic from a Tory Government out of road and out of ideas, and I won’t fall for it.<span class="x_Apple-converted-space"> </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-the-governments-strike-bill-is-wrong-on-every-level-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why the Government’s strike bill is wrong on every level – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On Monday, Tory MPs voted through the first stages of a Bill to impose minimum service levels on workers across England, Scotland and Wales. Under these proposals, Ministers would be handed new power to order compulsory ‘work notices’ on striking workers, who could then be sacked for going on strike. I proudly voted against these […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-the-governments-strike-bill-is-wrong-on-every-level-my-weekly-article-for-the-tameside-reporter/">Why the Government’s strike bill is wrong on every level – my weekly article for the Tameside Reporter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235997</id>
    <published>2023-01-17T10:35:12Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-17T10:35:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-7774544376901163283</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T15:38:00.001+00:00</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T15:38:28.065+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Mr Grant, one Chestnut Grove, Clayton-le-Moors, Valuation Office, revaluation of property.</title>
    <summary type="text">Open my shared note:Mr GrantNotesSent from my iPhone</summary>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/7774544376901163283"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/7774544376901163283"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2023/01/mr-grant-one-chestnut-grove-clayton-le.html" title="Mr Grant, one Chestnut Grove, Clayton-le-Moors, Valuation Office, revaluation of property."/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Jays Juniors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/jays-juniors" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Jays Juniors</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/14" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Ione</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-01-16T14:25:00+00:00">Mon, 01/16/2023 - 14:25</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ione</name>
    </author>
    <id>1176 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T14:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T14:25:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz speaks to media about the NHS, energy bills and Labour&#8217;s progress]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-to-media-about-the-nhs-energy-bills-and-labours-progress/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=12002</id>
		<updated>2023-01-16T14:16:07Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-16T14:16:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“People will look at the Tory’s and say: what have the last twelve years been for?”@leicesterliz says that Labour need to show they have a credible plan for the future, as under the Tories the basics- seeing a GP, getting from A to B, good schools- “have gone”.#Peston pic.twitter.com/dw0sSgtYDI<br />
&#8212; Peston (@itvpeston) January 11, 2023</p>
<p>Last Wednesday,&#160; I was a guest on ITV&#8217;s Peston show. I was also on Sky&#8217;s PMQs Panel and BBC Radio 5 Live.<br />
Amongst other things, I talked about the crisis in the NHS, the Government&#8217;s failure to prevent ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-to-media-about-the-nhs-energy-bills-and-labours-progress/">Liz speaks to media about the NHS, energy bills and Labour&#8217;s progress</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-to-media-about-the-nhs-energy-bills-and-labours-progress/"><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">“People will look at the Tory’s and say: what have the last twelve years been for?”<a href="https://twitter.com/leicesterliz?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@leicesterliz</a> says that Labour need to show they have a credible plan for the future, as under the Tories the basics- seeing a GP, getting from A to B, good schools- “have gone”.<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Peston?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Peston</a> <a href="https://t.co/dw0sSgtYDI">pic.twitter.com/dw0sSgtYDI</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Peston (@itvpeston) <a href="https://twitter.com/itvpeston/status/1613314338940669952?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 11, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Last Wednesday,&nbsp; I was a guest on ITV&#8217;s Peston show. I was also on Sky&#8217;s PMQs Panel and BBC Radio 5 Live.</p>
<p>Amongst other things, I talked about the crisis in the NHS, the Government&#8217;s failure to prevent strikes and the soaring cost of energy bills. On each of these issues, the Government could be taking more effective immediate action, but I also argued we need to move beyond sticking plaster politics and adopt long term solutions to the issues we face. Whether this is investing in renewables to bring down energy bills for good or delivering investment and reform in the NHS to make it fit for the future.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Long term thinking is central to Labour&#8217;s vision under Keir Starmer. Under his leadership Labour has made huge progress, throughout 2023 we will keep working to show the public our positive vision and plan for the future.&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can see a clip of me on Peston above and catch the whole programme <a href="https://www.itv.com/watch/peston/2a4458">here. </a>You can listen to the BBC Radio 5 Live show <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001gwcj">here.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-8691" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/glenfield-patient-takes-lizs-invite-trip-around-parliament/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Liz-Kendall-Ben-Stead-Lewis-Parliament-241017-150x150.jpg" alt="Glenfield patient takes up Liz’s invite to a trip around Parliament" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/glenfield-patient-takes-lizs-invite-trip-around-parliament/" class="wp_rp_title">Glenfield patient takes up Liz’s invite to a trip around Parliament</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-11458" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-sunflowers-nursery-2/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/sunflowers-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz visits Sunflowers Nursery" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-sunflowers-nursery-2/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz visits Sunflowers Nursery</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-5722" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-west-health-and-social-care-forum/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/15.jpg" alt="Leicester West Health and Social Care Forum" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-west-health-and-social-care-forum/" class="wp_rp_title">Leicester West Health and Social Care Forum</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-8583" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-holds-meeting-in-parliament-on-childrens-heart-unit/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Glenfield-meeting-photo-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz holds meeting in Parliament on children’s heart unit" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-holds-meeting-in-parliament-on-childrens-heart-unit/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz holds meeting in Parliament on children’s heart unit</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-3429" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-presses-for-council-rethink-on-gypsy-and-traveller-sites/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/16.jpg" alt="Liz presses for Council rethink on gypsy and traveller sites" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-presses-for-council-rethink-on-gypsy-and-traveller-sites/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz presses for Council rethink on gypsy and traveller sites</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-to-media-about-the-nhs-energy-bills-and-labours-progress/">Liz speaks to media about the NHS, energy bills and Labour&#8217;s progress</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-43" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I started this week with a visit to the Taste sandwich shop in Kirkby. Meeting hardworking businessowners like Fiona is exactly what makes me proud to be the MP for this great area. 15 years ago, Fiona was a single parent to twins and was struggling to make ends meet. Rather than feeling sorry for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-43</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brendan Clarke-Smith MP - Strikes (Minimum Service Levels) Bill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-strikes-minimum-service-levels-bill" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today we voted on legislation to ensure minimum service levels in vital areas during strikes.
I asked Labour’s Deputy Leader to explain if they didn’t think the pay offers were adequate then how much do they think these pay rises should be? Could they give a figure?
They couldn’t answer it, because…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-strikes-minimum-service-levels-bill</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Endoscopy Unit for PRU Granted Planning Permission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/new-endoscopy-unit-pru-granted-planning-permission" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">At a meeting of Bromley Council’s Development Control Committee in January, Councillors voted to allow planning permission for a new Endoscopy Unit at the Princess Royal University (PRU) hospital.
 
The new unit will help to reduce wait times for local cancer patients, speed up diagnostic time and…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/new-endoscopy-unit-pru-granted-planning-permission</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blackpool MP praised by Commons Leader in Blackpool funding debate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/blackpool-mp-praised-commons-leader-blackpool-funding-debate" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local MP Scott Benton calls for update on results for levelling up funding bids.
Since Scott was elected, he has helped to secure over £262 million in additional Government investment for Blackpool
He is now looking for an extra £40 million for a multiversity, which will provide the next generation…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/blackpool-mp-praised-commons-leader-blackpool-funding-debate</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Question to Claire Coutinho on Norfolk County Council's Ofsted Result for Children's Services</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-claire-coutinho-norfolk-county-councils-ofsted-result-childrens-services" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Children’s Services in Norfolk have been judged as requiring improvement all the way back to 2008.  But, following their recent inspection, the local authority has been judged to be 'good' in the areas of responsibility under Children's Services.  I'm pleased that the Minister for Children has…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/question-claire-coutinho-norfolk-county-councils-ofsted-result-childrens-services</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>I will vote against this shameful bill</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2159-i-will-vote-against-this-shameful-bill"/>
		<published>2023-01-16T10:34:02+00:00</published>
		<updated>2023-01-16T10:34:02+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2159-i-will-vote-against-this-shameful-bill</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I will vote against this shameful bill today. It does nothing to stop strikes - but individual NHS Staff, teachers &amp;amp; workers can be targeted &amp;amp; sacked if they don’t betray their mates. Fine the unions if they won’t provide minimum service levels but don’t sack individuals &lt;a href="https://t.co/3SLl6YDiLE"&gt;https://t.co/3SLl6YDiLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1614904371925422081?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 16, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I will vote against this shameful bill today. It does nothing to stop strikes - but individual NHS Staff, teachers &amp;amp; workers can be targeted &amp;amp; sacked if they don’t betray their mates. Fine the unions if they won’t provide minimum service levels but don’t sack individuals &lt;a href="https://t.co/3SLl6YDiLE"&gt;https://t.co/3SLl6YDiLE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1614904371925422081?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 16, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith demands tougher action on spiking</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-tougher-action-on-spiking/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP has called for spiking to be made a specific criminal offence.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate in Parliament on the Prevention of Spiking Incidents Judith, raised serious concerns about the chronic under-reporting of spiking and the ‘black hole’ of safeguarding in outdoor music festivals:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith said: “Recent figures point to almost 5,000 spiking incidents in just one year. Those figures are shocking, but they are likely to be the tip of the iceberg.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;She then revealed that her own research of police forces shows just 10 spiking reports from a decade of festivals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith continued: “It is unrealistic that it is just 10. The same data recorded 193 sexual offences, almost a third of which were against children under 18—the youngest was just 12 years old. The incidents were nearly exclusively against women and girls.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Festivals are huge pop-up towns, but the police and emergency service presence there is often minimal – police stick to traffic calming rather than policing as festival organisers provide event security and medical facilities.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this can lead to gaps in reporting that mean spiking is never explored with the victim, and reporting is not easily available. Recent recommendations were made by the Home Affairs Committee to provide all staff working at festivals with safeguarding training but these proposals were not taken forward by the Government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Tom Tugendhat, Minister for Security claimed that the government worked “closely with festivals and festival organisers and the outdoor events sector last summer to ensure that the necessary protocols, training, communications and guidance were in place ahead of events.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking afterwards, Judith said more needed to be done, concluding: “There is some good practice at some good festivals, more needs to be done to protect festival goers – and especially young people.&amp;nbsp; Action is needed, including a specific criminal offence of spiking so that all the data of this offense is accurately recorded, and making sure that victims have the continuity of care and support they need.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Government needs act to protect young people from spiking – wherever this crime occurs.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Recent figures point to 5,000 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/spiking?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#spiking&lt;/a&gt; incidents in one year &amp;#8211; but that&amp;#39;s just the tip of the iceberg.&lt;br&gt;Action is needed, including a specific criminal offence of spiking so crimes are properly recorded and make sure victims have continuity of care and support. &lt;a href="https://t.co/ATb79xx6DC"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ATb79xx6DC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1613948923772559361?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;January 13, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, action, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-campaigns-for-more-to-be-done-to-protect-young-girls-and-women-from-spiking-and-assault/" title="Judith campaigns for more to be done to protect young girls and women from spiking and assault"&gt;Judith campaigns for more to be done to protect young girls and women from spiking and assault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith challenged the government on their response to young girls and women being spiked. There has been a rise in the reporting of needle spiking in the media and on social networks in recent months. Across September and October of last year, the National Police Chief’s Council&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: spiking, judith, safeguarding, government, police, young, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-presents-her-bill-to-tackle-the-menace-of-nuisance-quads/" title="Judith presents her bill to tackle the menace of nuisance quads"&gt;Judith presents her bill to tackle the menace of nuisance quads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;81&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-presents-her-bill-to-tackle-the-menace-of-nuisance-quads/" title="Judith presents her bill to tackle the menace of nuisance quads"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/FDDmVfBWQAUQFEu-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith presents her bill to tackle the menace of nuisance quads" alt="Judith presents her bill to tackle the menace of nuisance quads" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith brought forward a bill to tackle nuisance quads. Speaking on the Bill, Judith said: “Anti-social quads are a growing problem in our towns and cities. They create a massive noise nuisance, and their reckless, dangerous and illegal use is a threat to other road users and&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, police, protect, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/a-cost-of-living-crisis-needs-a-bold-government-with-fresh-ideas/" title="A cost-of-living crisis needs a bold Government with fresh ideas"&gt;A cost-of-living crisis needs a bold Government with fresh ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;80&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/a-cost-of-living-crisis-needs-a-bold-government-with-fresh-ideas/" title="A cost-of-living crisis needs a bold Government with fresh ideas"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/SDP3245-0255-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="A cost-of-living crisis needs a bold Government with fresh ideas" alt="A cost-of-living crisis needs a bold Government with fresh ideas" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;After the last few years, chaos has become the new normal when it comes to our politics. It seemed the transition out of the EU and the disruption from the pandemic were becoming part of our past and we were all finding a new sense of optimism with hope and&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, people, protect, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP has called for spiking to be made a specific criminal offence. Speaking in a debate in Parliament on the Prevention of Spiking Incidents Judith, raised serious concerns about the chronic under-reporting of spiking and the ‘black hole’ of safeguarding in outdoor music festivals: Judith said: “Recent figures point to almost 5,000 spiking […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2693</id>
    <published>2023-01-16T09:44:04Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-16T09:44:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mid-January e-newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/mid-january-e-newsletter" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to read my mid-January e-newsletter
 
I weld yr e-gylchlythyr hwn yn Gymraeg cliciwch yma</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/mid-january-e-newsletter</id>
    <published>2023-01-15T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-15T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up :: 13 January 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/13/weekly-round-up-13-january-2023/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-13-january-2023" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Parliament returned this week and it was a pleasure to join the Fawcett Society for the launch of their report “A House for Everyone”. Their report has looked into the experience of female. We need women in Parliament. We need people from different classes, different religions, different races. Because that is Britain today and our Parliament should be representative of Britain today. Being an MP, or an elected politician at any level is great! Being able to help your community, stand up for what you believe in and be the change you want to see is so rewarding. The report highlighted the many areas we must look at and work harder in to encourage more women to take part. If you are considering taking part in politics, no matter your political persuasion, then do! I love every single minute of it and I know you will too.</p>
<p>A new year means new duties in scrutinising legislation. One such piece of law that I have been working on was in the Delegated Legislation Committee regarding the NHS Payment Scheme Consultation Act. Delegated Legislation Committees may not seem the most energetic aspect of politics, but they are vital to ensuring that our laws are fit for purpose. This is particularly important at the moment with legislation passed relating to healthcare. We need to ensure that the health service is funded properly but also that the funding is used efficiently and gives the best possible outcome for patients within the service. We need a system that allows flexibility for NHS managers across the different regions that are facing different challenges and strains on the health system. We need a system that will incentivise quality of service and that will offer taxpayers’ value for money. It is also important that community and mental health services are considered at the same time as hospitals and GPs’ surgeries because these are vital to improving cost efficiency and outcomes across the sector. Mental health must no longer be secondary to physical health; the two are interlinked and must be considered as such in planning.</p>
<p>Labour’s Opposition Day debate focused on the NHS and the Government’s long-term strategy or apparent lack thereof. The Government have promised time and time again to fix social care, to fix the NHS, to fix mental health care and time and time again they have failed and reneged on those promises. They have spent colossal amounts of money but we cannot see where that money has gone – it certainly hasn’t been efficiently spent on frontline services. They have failed to ensure that capacity has kept up with demand and they have run down our staff until they are at breaking point. Nurses using food banks, junior doctors exhausted after ridiculously long shifts, patients lining corridors because there aren’t enough beds – this is the result of a failure of long-term strategy and a failure to work closely with NHS managers to ensure that money is spent efficiently and where it is needed most. We need transparency first of all and we need efficiency. This Government is not known for its transparency but that needs to change now if we are to get to grips with the problems facing the NHS and come up with a long-term strategy that will work in 21st century Britain.</p>
<p>This morning I very much enjoyed taking part in the Bedminster Lantern Parade by raising the flag. When the parade starts proper, I know many of you will have a fantastic evening – so make sure you are available for what will be a great event.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575. </p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/13/weekly-round-up-13-january-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 13 January 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Parliament returned this week and it was a pleasure to join the Fawcett Society for the launch of their report […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/01/13/weekly-round-up-13-january-2023/">Weekly Round-Up :: 13 January 2023</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3428</id>
    <published>2023-01-13T16:35:26Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-13T16:35:26Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/01/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-29/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Visited RH Amar in the Cressex Business Park to learn about the investment Railpen is making to regenerate the Castle Estate Set out the Government’s work to address pressures on the NHS Received a briefing on future industrial action and how it may affect those in Wycombe Held my regular catch-up with the Superintendent of Thames Valley Police in Wycombe Pledged my support to the LGBT+ community in Wycombe and beyond, […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18612</id>
    <published>2023-01-13T16:30:42Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-13T16:30:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Council and Changeworks insulate homes in Oxgangs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13631/council-and-changeworks-insulate-homes-in-oxgangs" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In partnership with the leading environmental charity Changeworks, the City of Edinburgh Council is helping homeowners transform the energy efficiency of their homes.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13631/council-and-changeworks-insulate-homes-in-oxgangs</id>
    <published>2023-01-13T16:06:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-13T16:06:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Progress Meeting with East West Rail CEO and Local Councillors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/progress-meeting-east-west-rail-ceo-and-local-councillors" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I was pleased to welcome Beth West, East West Rail CEO, and her team back to Bicester today for a progress meeting with a cross-party group of local councillors. This follows an earlier meeting last summer when I took Beth to see the London Road crossing for herself.
East West Rail are continuing…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/progress-meeting-east-west-rail-ceo-and-local-councillors</id>
    <published>2023-01-13T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Marches LEP launches £1.5million energy grants scheme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/marches-lep-launches-ps15million-energy-grants-scheme" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7333" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">13 January 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Marches LEP launches £1.5million energy grants scheme</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne encourages local businesses to apply for a new region-specific energy grant scheme, being run in Shropshire, Telford, Herefordshire, and Worcestershire by Marches Local Enterprise Partnership. </p>

<p>This week Marches LEP announced the opening of a scheme to help local businesses with energy efficiency and cutting emissions, to support those affected by current high energy costs.</p>

<p>Under the scheme businesses in South Shropshire will be able to receive a free energy efficiency audit and thereafter apply for funding up to £20,000 towards energy efficiency equipment.</p>

<p>The scheme was designed as part of a wider £4million package intended by the local enterprise partnership to safeguard the region's energy security and to help develop a more sustainable footing for the long term. Energy cost volatility remains higher than normal due to continuing challenges around gas supply and the after- effects of Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.</p>

<p>The grant aims to support businesses with a 40% contribution towards improved energy efficiency management of a company’s individual energy usage.</p>

<p>For those wishing to apply or find out more details about the scheme, please visit:  <a href="https://www.marchesgrowthhub.co.uk/marches-energy-grant/">https://www.marchesgrowthhub.co.uk/marches-energy-grant/</a>.  </p>

<p>Commenting on the scheme Dunne said </p>

<blockquote>
<p>“Following this week’s announcement of the Government's Energy Bills Discount Scheme extension for the next twelve months, I am pleased Marches LEP has come forward with this timely further support for our local economy. The provision of free audits to inform businesses where they can save capital and running costs could be of real help.</p>

<p>Businesses of all kinds can apply to this scheme for free advice, and then bid to receive a contribution to up to.  40% of the cost of energy saving measures. Orr equipment. I hope many businesses o South Shropshire will explore the options available.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This is a successor fund to the previous EU funded Business Energy Efficiency Programme.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7333 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-01-13T10:15:38Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-13T10:15:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Spectator: John Penrose urges DWP transparency]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/13/the-spectator-john-penrose-urges-dwp-transparency/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5639</id>
		<updated>2023-01-13T05:28:55Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-13T05:28:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Press Cuttings"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This article was published in The Spectator. Welfare reform is back in Westminster, with both Labour and the Tories now seeking solutions to deal with the 5.2 million on out-of-work benefits – a figure which The Spectator was first to pick up on. The Times today splashed on possible government proposals with Labour’s Jon Ashworth now accusing his opposite number Mel Stride [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/01/13/the-spectator-john-penrose-urges-dwp-transparency/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong>This article was published in</strong> <em><strong><a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/tory-mp-urges-dwp-transparency/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Spectator</a></strong></em>.</p>



<p>Welfare reform is <a href="https://www.spectator.co.uk/writer/james-heale/">back </a>in Westminster, with both Labour and the Tories now seeking solutions to deal with the 5.2 million on out-of-work benefits – a figure which <em>The Spectator</em> was first to pick up on. The <em>Times </em>today splashed on possible government proposals with Labour’s Jon Ashworth now accusing his opposite number Mel Stride of ‘stealing’ his proposals. In such circumstances, the Department for Work and Pensions could do worse than consider an intriguing proposal put forward by John Penrose MP, the UK’s long-time Anti-Corruption Champion.</p>



<p>Now confined to the backbenches, Penrose is channelling his reforming zeal into new avenues instead. The Weston-super-Mare MP has written to Stride, urging him to improve the transparency of his department&#8217;s employment support schemes and the performance of third-party suppliers. Some £2.5 billion a year is currently spent on initiatives like the flagship &#8216;Restart&#8217; programme, with suppliers required to report performance data as part of their contracts. Yet such information is not published by the department, with even MPs and Select Committees struggling to obtain the necessary figures.</p>



<p>Penrose is backed by an intriguing coalition of interests ranging from the Fabian Society, the Campaign for Freedom of Information and Spotlight on Corruption to the ASI and CPS think tanks. Among their suggestions include publishing detailed performance data on &#8216;Restart&#8217; – including outcomes, customer satisfaction and complaints data, broken down by region, ethnicity and education to identify potential disparities and encourage the best allocation of resources. Other ideas include central collation of performance figures to better evaluate supplier performance on the Flexible Support Fund.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s easy to see why Whitehall mandarins might not relish such ideas. In June, it was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2022/jun/05/uk-governments-restart-scheme-fails-to-find-work-for-93-per-cent-of-people">reported&nbsp;</a>that the Restart scheme had managed to find jobs for just seven per cent of people while the &#8216;Way to Work&#8217; scheme was labelled as a failure thanks to a lack of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2022/aug/20/boris-johnson-way-to-work-jobs-scheme-failure">transparency&nbsp;</a>around its targets. But with money tight, supply-side reforms will be one of the few ways for the Sunak government to distinguish itself during the next 18 months. It&#8217;s certainly a theme Penrose intends to champion in the coming months, having&nbsp;<a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-01-10/debates/8AB65A7E-CB7D-4396-BB53-584A088F4758/OffenderRehabilitationProgrammesEffectiveness#contribution-3FB05C00-ED2D-4AB4-B9E7-EDB1DBAE108F">pressed&nbsp;</a>Dominic Raab at Justice Questions on Tuesday &#8216;to publish the outcomes and success rates of all publicly commissioned programmes to prepare offenders for work.&#8217;</p>



<p>The question is: will ministers oblige?</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SMRs in Dungeness &amp; Upcoming Jobs Fair</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/smrs-in-dungeness-upcoming-jobs-fair/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday this week I attended a meeting of the Cabinet of Kent County Council, at the invitation of the Leader, Cllr Roger Gough, to discuss the future of nuclear power at Dungeness. Along with Kent, and Folkestone and Hythe District Council, I am determined to do all I can to secure the long-term future […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6229</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T17:05:05Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T17:05:05Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MARTIN WELCOMES DATE SET FOR REOPENING OF DUMBARTON CASTLE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/01/12/martin-welcomes-date-set-for-reopening-of-dumbarton-castle/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has welcomed the announcement that Dumbarton Castle is set to reopen to the public in early Spring.</p>



<p>Access restrictions have been in place at the castle grounds at Dumbarton Rock since early 2022, to allow for high level masonry inspections and repairs to be completed.</p>



<p>Historic Environment Scotland (HES), the public body responsible for managing the site, has said it hopes to welcome visitors back to the 800-year-old stronghold by March 2023.</p>



<p>Scotland’s Culture Minister Neil Gray visited Dumbarton Castle last year at the request of local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes, after being invited to view the conservation and inspection works undertaken by HES.</p>



<p><strong>Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:</strong></p>



<p>“It’s good news that Dumbarton Castle is finally set to reopen to visitors after its temporary closure.</p>



<p>“Dumbarton Castle is one of Scotland’s most important historical landmarks. It has great potential for the area and I’ve been in discussions with officials for some time about efforts to improve the on-site visitor experience.</p>



<p>“I was pleased to welcome Scotland’s Culture Minister to Dumbarton Castle last year. We had a productive meeting alongside Historic Environment Scotland about the important ongoing conservation works. </p>



<p>“The castle’s reopening in Spring is something to look forward to. I intend to visit again soon and will continue working to ensure this iconic site receives the investment it deserves.”</p>



<p><strong><em>Details of the reopening of Dumbarton Castle available here: <a href="http://www.historicenvironment.scot/about-us/news/dumbarton-castle-set-to-reopen-to-the-public/">www.historicenvironment.scot/about-us/news/dumbarton-castle-set-to-reopen-to-the-public/</a></em></strong></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has welcomed the announcement that Dumbarton Castle is set to reopen to the public in early Spring. Access restrictions have been in place at the castle grounds at Dumbarton Rock since early 2022, to allow for high level masonry inspections and repairs to be completed. Historic Environment Scotland (HES), the ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="MARTIN WELCOMES DATE SET FOR REOPENING OF DUMBARTON CASTLE" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/01/12/martin-welcomes-date-set-for-reopening-of-dumbarton-castle/#more-1821510" aria-label="More on MARTIN WELCOMES DATE SET FOR REOPENING OF DUMBARTON CASTLE">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821510</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T12:59:59Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:59:59Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Dumbarton"/>
    <category term="Dumbarton Castle"/>
    <category term="Historic Environment Scotland"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[We Deserve a Lot Better]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/12/we-deserve-a-lot-better/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6665</id>
		<updated>2023-01-12T12:28:44Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-12T12:28:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Employment"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="NHS and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="debt"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="immigration"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="inflation"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="labour"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="NHS"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="pledges"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="prime minister"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="rishi sunak"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="tories"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="unemployment"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In his first public address of the New Year, the Prime Minister made five pledges which he says are the foundations for a better future. After thirteen years, aren’t we entitled to more than laying the foundations? He says he’ll half inflation before the end of the year which, as Chancellor, he let rip. Of<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/12/we-deserve-a-lot-better/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">We Deserve a Lot Better</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/12/we-deserve-a-lot-better/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>In his first public address of the New Year, the Prime Minister made five pledges which he says are the foundations for a better future. After thirteen years, aren’t we entitled to more than laying the foundations?</p>



<p>He says he’ll half inflation before the end of the year which, as Chancellor, he let rip. Of course, it will fall if, as many experts predict, we’re plunged into recession. He’s also promised to grow the economy. When his predecessor said that she almost bankrupted the country. The independent Office of Budget Responsibility predicts our economy will shrink by 1.4% this year, with a rise in unemployment of half a million.</p>



<p>There’s also a promise to reduce the National Debt which gets the hairs on the back of my neck standing because, last time the Tories became obsessed with debt, we suffered 10 years of austerity which wrecked our public services and has ended with the National Debt rising to a staggering £2.48 trillion.</p>



<p>There’s a claim he’ll stop small boats and tackle smuggling gangs. His four immediate predecessors all made similar claims as smuggling and channel crossings continued to expand. There was also a reference to anti-social behaviour which he apparently thinks can be a gateway activity leading to further criminality. Pity the Tories have ignored it for so long.</p>



<p>Finally, he promises to cut NHS waiting lists. They’re now at a record 7 million, almost three times what they were when the Tories came to power in 2010. In his most recent comments, the Secretary of State for Health seems to be pinning his hopes on ‘virtual wards’. My fear is that might lead to virtual care. As veteran Tory MP Sir Edward Leigh put it, Labour has a long-term plan and the Tories don’t.</p>



<p>I wish the PM well with his pledges. The five or is that six, worrying that he has a problem with numbers, are the minimum we should expect, but after thirteen years we’re entitled to demand much more. My New Year message is that if he can’t do better, he should make way for a party that can.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/12/we-deserve-a-lot-better/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/01/12/we-deserve-a-lot-better/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - The 2021 Census &amp; Ashford </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-2021-census-ashford" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The exam question this morning is how much do we know about our local community? The data from the 2021 Census is becoming available, and it shows how the constituency of Ashford is not only growing but changing.
To start with the basics, there are 51,400 households, with a population of 127,300.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-2021-census-ashford</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Support - Guidance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/cost-living-support-guidance" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">During the current cost-of-living crisis, I know that many local people are struggling with rising bills. The Government has put a wide range of support in place to assist, and it is important that everyone should be able to access everything they are entitled to.
The Government has put together a…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/cost-living-support-guidance</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Payments – Spring 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/cost-of-living-payments-spring-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Details for the next round of cost-of-living payments were announced by The Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) last week, with low-income houses set to receive new Cost of Living Payments from Spring 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These payments, initially unveiled in the Chancellor’s Autumn Statement, could provide low-income households with up to £1,350 from the Government in 2023/4 to help with the cost of living. I’m pleased that this extra cash will be available to support the most vulnerable across Aldridge-Brownhills, including extra support for disabled people and the elderly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the link to find out more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/millions-of-low-income-households-to-get-new-cost-of-living-payments-from-spring-2023?fbclid=IwAR1gogmHWtm0_sFw-i4k0TXHhxD7zY6KGFklNbYYctLQqMipuxCjT9JLAFY"&gt;Millions of low-income households to get new Cost of Living Payments from Spring 2023 &amp;#8211; GOV.UK (www.gov.uk)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Details for the next round of cost-of-living payments were announced by The Department for Work and Pensions (DWP) last week, with low-income houses set to receive new Cost of Living […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4481</id>
    <published>2023-01-12T09:51:23Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-12T09:51:23Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP and Cumbria’s hospitality leaders meet with Immigration Minister to discuss staffing crisis</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439275/mp-and-cumbria-s-hospitality-leaders-meet-with-immigration-minister-to-discuss-staffing-crisis"/>
  <updated>2023-01-11T15:45:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1439275/mp-and-cumbria-s-hospitality-leaders-meet-with-immigration-minister-to-discuss-staffing-crisis</id>
  <summary type="text">South Lakes MP Tim Farron and leaders from Cumbria's hospitality and tourism industry met with the Minister for Immigration, Robert Jenrick, in Parliament yesterday to discuss the staffing crisis in the sector.
Tim was joined by the Chair of Cumbria Tourism Dan Visser, the Managing Director of Windermere Lakes Cruises Nigel Wilkinson, and the Executive Manager of Lake District Country Hotels, Joe Cobb.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">South Lakes MP Tim Farron and leaders from Cumbria's hospitality and tourism industry met with the Minister for Immigration, Robert Jenrick, in Parliament yesterday to discuss the staffing crisis in the sector.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Tim was joined by the Chair of Cumbria Tourism Dan Visser, the Managing Director of Windermere Lakes Cruises Nigel Wilkinson, and the Executive Manager of Lake District Country Hotels, Joe Cobb.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">A recent study by Cumbria Tourism found that 73% of businesses say recruitment is a problem, with more than half citing it as a 'significant problem'. Meanwhile 89% of businesses said a lack of affordable housing for staff was an issue, and 84% said the cost of travel for employees was also a barrier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">The Minister heard about the serious challenges facing Cumbrian businesses and was challenged to look at extending the Youth Mobility Visa Scheme to countries in Europe to allow more young people to come and work in the county's hospitality sector.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">The group also encouraged the Minister to work with his colleagues in the Ministry of Housing and the Department for Transport to address the challenges around expensive housing and travel.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Tim said: <em>"I'm grateful to the minister for taking the time to meet with us and for a very constructive conversation</em></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"He was very receptive and clearly understood the significant pressures that local businesses are under due to this staffing crisis.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"If action is not taken then many businesses risk going to the wall, and the local staff they employ will be put out of work."</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Dan Visser, Chair of Cumbria Tourism said: <em>"Our research has clearly shown that issues around recruitment, retention and skills in Cumbria and the Lake District continue to be a serious concern for many businesses.</em></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"We were pleased to get the opportunity to stress to the Minister the need for urgent action to tackle these ongoing issues. The meeting was constructive and we hope for a positive outcome.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"In the meantime, we will continue to fight Cumbria's corner through our ongoing lobbying work with MPs, key government departments and national industry bodies including The Tourism Alliance and UK Hospitality."</span></em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Star Column – NHS Pressures</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/01/llanelli-star-column-nhs-pressures/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Uppermost in many people’s minds at the moment will be
concerns about the pressures on our NHS, and a recognition that this is not
just a winter emergency. It is almost three years now since the beginning of
the Covid Pandemic, and the pressure has been relentless, both on our hospitals
and GPs, with chronic staff shortages. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I meet regularly with the Hywel Dda Health Board to discuss what
they are doing to tackle the problems, and at our meeting before Christmas,
they told me they are currently advertising some 460 vacancies, which gives you
an idea of the scale of the problem. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They also told me some 140 patients across the four main
hospitals (Llanelli, Carmarthen, Haverfordwest and Aberystwyth) in the Hywel
Dda Health Board area, were medically ready to be discharged but waiting for
suitable care packages. More care staff are being recruited, and hopefully the
Welsh Labour Government insistence that all care staff are paid at least the
Real Living Wage will help.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although Welsh Labour Government has tried to maximize
resources available to the NHS, we have to face the fact that the scale of
resources needed calls for more UK Government funding, with a proportionate
share for Wales. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s why Labour has pledged that a UK Labour Government
would put the 45p tax rate back up to 50p and use the money to resource
the NHS better and fund one of the biggest NHS workforce expansions in history,
doubling the number of medical school places, doubling the number of district
nurses qualifying every year, training more than 5,000 new health visitors and
creating an additional 10,000 nursing and midwife placements every year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And that’s why in Parliament, we will keep
urging the current Tory Government to resource our NHS better.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Uppermost in many people’s minds at the moment will be concerns about the pressures on our NHS, and a recognition that this is not just a winter emergency. It is almost three years now since the beginning of the Covid Pandemic, and the pressure has been relentless, both on our hospitals and GPs, with chronic […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8699</id>
    <published>2023-01-11T14:25:11Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-11T14:25:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: A New Year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-new-year/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-a-new-year" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">The Highlands, throughout its proud and long stretching history, has always been a place of strong community bonds. We have a tradition, borne out in front of us all in real-time during the Pandemic, of caring for and helping our neighbours. 2023 will, in all likelihood, be a year when that sense of community will be of the utmost importance to us all. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">With the festivities over, we return to our normal daily concerns, and many more folk than before will be looking at their household finances with a sense of worry, maybe even dread. It is almost impossible to stay positive when facing the pressures of trying to pay the bills with little or no ability to do so, and this will be a stressful time for the many affected people and families. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">I have written before, at length, on the reasons why we face such a daunting crisis. About the folly and self-harm of a Brexit that we in Scotland didn’t want or ask for, and about the scant disregard for people’s needs in the energy market whilst the cash cow of Scotland’s energy resources was milked and squandered by Westminster, so I won’t go into further detail on that here. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">We are where we are. We can change our future and choose a different path. That is a choice that you should have and one which I am determined you will have. But, for now, we will need to rally round as individuals, families, and communities. In the year ahead, my hope, indeed my expectation, is that as we see people struggle, we will also see the best of us as neighbours and as friends. In days gone by, during periods of immense struggle, folk in the Highlands stood strong together, and I suspect this sense of resolute togetherness in the face of adversity will endure throughout the challenges we face this year.</span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">With Scotland’s disproportionately enormous natural wealth and resources, we shouldn’t have to live in a society where we are so dependent on food banks to help folk eat and on vital support volunteers to help with the basics. But whilst we are, I would urge those who can to donate and support those who run them. A quick search on Google will tell you where they are and how to help them. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">Naturally, I will keep up the pressure on the UK Government to live up to its responsibilities. To do the simple and right things, like matching the £25 per week Scottish Child Payment and other support, to help those in the other nations of the UK get this support too, but also to, by Barnett consequentials, allow us to do more here. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">That being said, whilst being kind to others, we also must remember to be kinder to ourselves. To find the time to understand that each and every one of us needs to have moments of peace, appreciation and joy. So, take the opportunity to have a laugh when you can, you deserve it. </span></p>
<p style="margin: 9.0pt 0cm 9.0pt 0cm;"><span style="font-family: 'Maison Neue',serif; color: #212121; letter-spacing: .75pt;">There is a lot of hard work to be done in the year ahead, but there are also a lot of great people who will do great things, both big and small, amongst us. Thanks in advance to them, to you. All the best for 2023. </span></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-new-year/">ARTICLE: A New Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Highlands, throughout its proud and long stretching history, has always been a place of strong community bonds. We have a tradition, borne out in front of us all in real-time during the Pandemic, of caring for and helping our neighbours. 2023 will, in all likelihood, be a year when that sense of community will …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-new-year/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: A New Year</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-a-new-year/">ARTICLE: A New Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7366</id>
    <published>2023-01-11T12:21:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-11T12:21:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[January 2023 Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/01/10/january-2023-newsletter/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10686</id>
		<updated>2023-01-10T11:12:36Z</updated>
		<published>2023-01-10T10:15:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/><category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="Newsletter"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I hope that everybody had an enjoyable and relaxing Christmas and New Year Period. Please find below my most recent newsletter, with information on what I have been busy doing both in the constituency and in Parliament throughout the past couple of months. There are also details of my upcoming advice surgeries contained within the ... <a title="January 2023 Newsletter" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/01/10/january-2023-newsletter/" aria-label="More on January 2023 Newsletter">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottingham Labour proposes to keep all local libraries open</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/01/09/nottingham-labour-proposes-to-keep-all-local-libraries-open/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Revised proposals to transform local library services and achieve savings for the City Council are being recommended for approval by the authority’s Executive Board ( 17 January).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Initial plans involved among other things the closure of three libraries, with Aspley being turned into a distribution hub for the library service but closing to the public. Some savings have already been achieved through a staffing restructure in the libraries service. The decision to put forward the closure of the libraries was not one that was proposed lightly, but was due to pressure to balance the council budget from the Government’s austere economic measures. The laws around local government and the requirements made from the Tories for all councils around the country are not fit for purpose leading to a situation whereby the closure of the three libraries had to be considered. No Labour politician would ever want to bring such proposals forward, but the budget is an ongoing challenge and so it will remain until the Conservatives are removed from office.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The proposals now due to be considered by members of the Executive Board involve keeping all existing libraries open, with some shortened opening times across the library network, and retaining Aspley as a publicly accessible library, whilst fitting in it a stock distribution centre for Nottingham Performing Arts Library. Different libraries currently have different opening times and the proposal is to align them to an updated core, satisfying communities’ use. This proposal protects the library buildings if slightly altering opening times and delivers the required saving at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a response to strong feedback from residents against the closure proposals, coupled with emerging factors such as the integral role that libraries continue to perform during the ongoing cost-of-living crisis, for example as warm hubs. The conditions of people living in our city and around the country have worsened significantly as a result of the Government’s inadequacy to bring inflation under control and to support public services at all levels over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report to Executive Board states: “The transformation principles and revised recommendations provides a positive response to the views and concerns raised by individuals and communities and the strong opposition to closures. The recommendations still enable the transformation to create a modern library service that remains relevant, whilst still responding to financial pressures facing the local authority and the specific delivery of the savings requirement.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Cllr Pavlos Kotsonis, Portfolio Holder for Leisure, Culture and Planning, said: “Our ability to bring forward proposals to protect all three libraries constitutes a positive response to the needs of people in Nottingham including the most vulnerable in our communities. Their voices from the extensive consultation have been heard.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“No matter how much the Government threatens our public services we need to continue doing all we can to fight for them, and even though we still have to operate under a Conservative Government that has created a difficult financial environment &amp;#8211; and we will still be asked to make disproportionate amounts of savings in the future &amp;#8211; we still need to keep doing all we can to mitigate the impact to all our communities.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The report to the Executive Board can be read here: &lt;a href="https://committee.nottinghamcity.gov.uk/ieListDocuments.aspx?CId=177&amp;amp;MId=9491"&gt;Agenda for Executive Board on Tuesday, 17th January, 2023, 2.00 pm &amp;#8211; Nottingham City Council&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Revised proposals to transform local library services and achieve savings for the City Council are being recommended for approval by the authority’s Executive Board ( 17 January). Initial plans involved among other things the closure of three libraries, with Aspley being turned into a distribution hub for the library service but closing to the public.… <a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/01/09/nottingham-labour-proposes-to-keep-all-local-libraries-open/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More »<span class="screen-reader-text">Nottingham Labour proposes to keep all local libraries open</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2955</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T16:16:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T16:16:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Libraries"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="Radford"/>
    <category term="Wollaton East &amp; Lenton Abbey Labour Team"/>
    <category term="aspley"/>
    <category term="basford"/>
    <category term="libraries"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scottish Borders MP visits local ice rink</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-visits-local-ice-rink" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">John Lamont MP has encouraged local people to get involved in curling and skating in 2023 after visiting the Border Ice Rink in Kelso.
The Scottish Borders MP said the Kelso centre was a “fantastic day out” and the local curling club was a “brilliant fun activity for people of all ages.”
The rink …</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/scottish-borders-mp-visits-local-ice-rink</id>
    <published>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>East Lindsey District Council moves to limit further Home Office use of coastal hotels</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/01/05/east-lindsey-district-council-moves-to-limit-further-home-office-use-of-coastal-hotels/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;main&gt;&lt;/main&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;article id="maincontent"&gt;
&lt;div class="wrapper"&gt;
&lt;p class="a-intro a-intro--default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Lindsey District Council has formally submitted a pre-action letter to the Home Office, indicating it is considering pursuing a Judicial Review to prevent the Home Office from continuing to promote the unlawful use of hotels in Skegness as hostels for those seeking asylum.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="a-body a-body--default"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council&amp;#8217;s letter argues the Home Office has persistently, repeatedly and unlawfully encouraged and procured breaches of planning control by instructing SERCO Group Plc, to purchase hotel accommodation in Skegness for those seeking asylum in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council&amp;#8217;s case is that the use the Home Office is encouraging is a material change of use which requires planning permission, which has not been applied for or obtained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The letter states: &amp;#8220;Those unauthorised changes of use have caused substantial harm.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council, while monitoring successful legal action obtained by Great Yarmouth Borough Council, has been trying to seek an assurance from the Home Secretary, Suella Braverman MP, and the Minister of State for Immigration, Robert Jenrick MP, that the Home Office will not procure the use of any more hotels as hostels for asylum seekers in Skegness or East Lindsey as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both have failed to give those assurances and now the Council has taken the first step towards officially seeking legal action to prevent further harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Council says that any more changes of use of this kind should be subject to an application for planning permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, five hotels in the prime tourist area of Skegness have been procured for hostel use without the grant of planning permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The harm that has been caused by the Home Office&amp;#8217;s policy is to deplete Skegness&amp;#8217;s stock of hotel accommodation for tourists and harm its reputation as a family resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The harm that has been, and will continue to be, caused to Skegness&amp;#8217;s hotel sector and its tourism economy more generally directly conflicts with the policy SP19 of the adopted Local Plan for Coastal East Lindsey, which specifically aims to boost tourism and restrict the loss of hotels to other uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the Home Office&amp;#8217;s failure to consult with the Council and its partners has placed a substantial and potentially unsustainable burden on providers of primary healthcare in Skegness as well as beginning to undermine social cohesion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cllr Craig Leyland, Leader of East Lindsey District Council, said: &amp;#8220;Skegness is the fourth most visited coastal resort in the UK. It depends on maintaining a thriving tourism economy driven by holidaymakers and people who choose to holiday in the town and on day trippers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The unlawful use of hotels as hostels, which goes against planning policy, is depleting the supply of accommodation on offer for tourists and this use is not helping our reputation as a family holiday resort which is a vital part of the local economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;We understand the national pressures faced by the Home Office in finding suitable accommodation for those seeking asylum in the UK but we call for a halt to the procurement of any more hotels in Skegness and wider East Lindsey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;This pre-action letter indicates the Council&amp;#8217;s intentions to seek a Judicial Review if the Home Office will not agree to stop purchasing more hotels for hostel use unless it is authorised by the grant of planning permission.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Warman, MP for Boston and Skegness, said&lt;em&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/strong&gt;I have repeatedly urged the Prime Minister, the Home Secretary and the Immigration Minister to end the use of tourist hotels in Skegness to accommodate people seeking asylum. As I said recently at a public meeting in Skegness, it is unacceptable and wholly inappropriate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have been clear throughout on my three &amp;#8216;asks&amp;#8217; of Government &amp;#8211; deter people from making journeys across the channel in the first place, process people more quickly and look at alternative forms of accommodation to the inappropriate use of hotels needed for tourism.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Britain is an immensely compassionate country but we need to address the issue of asylum seekers coming in such numbers. It&amp;#8217;s right that we&amp;#8217;re now working more closely with France to stop people making perilous voyages. It&amp;#8217;s right that we are imposing tougher penalties for the criminal people smugglers who exploit the vulnerable, including life imprisonment. It&amp;#8217;s right that we have done a new deal with Albania to make sure we return those from that country who do not qualify as rapidly as possible.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will continue to press the point that these hotels are needed to support our local tourism economy and offer my full support to ELDC in bringing this legal challenge.&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secretary of State will now have time to consider East Lindsey District Council&amp;#8217;s letter which calls for the Home Office to engage with the Council to agree a resolution as an alternative to a claim for Judicial Review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">East Lindsey District Council has formally submitted a pre-action letter to the Home Office, indicating it is considering pursuing a Judicial Review to prevent the Home Office from continuing to promote the unlawful use of hotels in Skegness as hostels for those seeking asylum. The Council’s letter argues the Home […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4137</id>
    <published>2023-01-05T09:17:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-05T09:17:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-85/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted to meet their daughter Catherine, Acting Principal of NPT College Group, chair of Welsh Netball, and their son-in-law Mark Dacey (married to another daughter, Alison), Principal of Neath College, in 2014 and we have become close friends. Crid was a pillar of the local community wherever they lived all over the world. A socialist, feminist, Alan’s office manager, member of Cefn Hengoed Ladies Choir (who sang at her funeral) and so much more. Gelligaer Church was full of Crid’s family, friends, and members of community organisations. RIP my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;As part of the Stonegate Group’s annual investment programme, it has invested £174,000 into the Castell-Nedd Arms in Neath town centre. I was delighted to take my staff to visit and see the improvements. We met with the operator of the pub Kayleigh Strinati, the Group’s area manager Danny Cross, and the bar staff. Kayleigh told us that she had worked in the pub trade for a number of years, and she felt that it was time to take that step up to managing the Castell-Nedd. She completed the training requirements, and then Covid struck. But when the pub re-opened again, the customers gradually came back to what had become a social hub for many people who live in Neath. The new challenge is the “cost of living crisis”, but Kayleigh is providing a very warm welcome for people to gather, talk, listen, watch TV, use the Wi-Fi, as well as great refreshments. The refurbishment includes new windows and seating area overlooking Angel Street, a pool and darts section, and many more facilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2712"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2712" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/1D2F4A81-ED7E-449E-8944-5797D4A54227-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I visited the Churches Together Nativity Scene which this year is displayed in the Greyhound Trust Charity Shop Window, instead of in the Town Square. It is secure and able to be seen by all passers by. Massive thanks to the charity shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I met with Mark Fisher, NPT Council Unison Representative, to discuss Fair Funding for the council. Mark has always done a fantastic job representing Unison members, and although it was announced this week that NPT has received a better than anticipated settlement of 7.1% from Welsh Government, he shared his concerns about pressure on future budgets, and the continuing “cost of living” challenges faced everyday by every one of his members. Mark will be holding a Fair Funding Event at NPT Council for local elected representatives and his Unison members on Friday 13th January 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;After the meeting, Mark and I joined the Royal Mail workers who are striking for a fair pay settlement and no diminishing of their terms and conditions, on their Picket Line which was outside the Royal Mail Sorting Office in Neath. There was a great turnout, and many passers-by supported the strike. People were dropping off food to keep the workers going in the freezing, sub-zero temperatures. In solidarity, I bought all the strikers coffee from our superb local coffee shop, Brew &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2713"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2713" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/71AD8D08-F334-4B81-ADF0-2D1614C1BD81-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Mynydd Fforch Dwm Windfarm is a proposal by &lt;a href="https://mfdwindfarm.co.uk/about-us/"&gt;Naturalis Energy&lt;/a&gt; to provide clean, carbon free energy to homes and businesses across South Wales, including a renewable energy park near Tonmawr. Naturalis is a joint venture between Falck Renewables and REG Windpower energy companies. A number of constituents have contacted me regarding the proposal, asking me to call into the one of the Naturalis public consultation sessions. I dropped into the one held at Neath Little Theatre to view the plans and listen to a presentation by Naturalis staff. As part of the Development of National Significance (DNS) planning process Naturalis are required to undertake a comprehensive programme of pre-application engagement consultations. As an MP I have no remit over Welsh Government or Local Authority Planning applications. My role is to pass on the views and concerns of all my constituents to the stakeholders involved in a particular planning application. Please email me and I shall make sure that your questions are passed onto the stakeholders involved in this application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;My brother James was suddenly taken seriously ill and was rushed to Basingstoke Hospital. My daughter Angharad and I visited him in hospital, but James died following his fight against his illness which turned into pneumonia. My big brother was always there to look after me, after the death of my father, when I was seventeen. James was an industrial pharmacist, worked all over the world, and had many friends and colleagues. James was brought up by my grandparents who owned the Walnut Tree Pub in Kenfig Hill. He was a product of Bridgend Grammar School, Loughborough and Cardiff Universities. James organised the old boys network for former pupils of his old school. My grandfather was a founder of Kenfig Hill RFC, and my parents managed the bar. Rugby was part of James’ life, and he was proud to play number 8 at schoolboy rugby for Wales. I have lived with my brother all over the world at various times during my life. He was my mentor, my hero, my rock. I am devastated at the passing of my beloved brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;Being a member of the congregation of St David’s Church Neath has been a great source of comfort to me. The people who go to my church are genuine, caring, supportive, never forget that life is very challenging, and we are always there to help each other through the good and the not-so-good times. It was so good to see my friends at the Choir Coffee Morning at St David’s Church, Neath. Many thanks to everyone who came to help and support. Coffee, cake, festive music with loyal friends in the beautifully Christmas decorated church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It’s an honour to be a patron of YMCA Neath and I really enjoyed the Christmas Fayre. There were stalls, arts and crafts, jewellery, face painting, glitter tattoos, pottery painting, tombola, lucky dip, raffle prizes, and refreshments. It was so good to catch up with Centre Manager Claire Hicks, and Admin Officer Jessica Kennedy. As a lifelong vegan, it was good to meet YMCA staffer Rhys Oliver who has recently started her delivery business “Vegan Kitchen – Food with a conscience – Made in Wales”. Rhys was selling a taste of her produce, vegan sausages, pasties, and chocolate cakes. Her menus are changed weekly and are made freshly on the day of delivery. And all packaging is environmentally friendly. Please email Rhys on DaffodilBach@gmail.com or telephone 07947715435 to place your orders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;I dropped into The Haven to meet my dear friend Major Mary Wolfe, her successor Major Neil Duquemin, and Skills Coordinator Christina Davies. On the day of my visit, The Haven had provided 48 Christmas lunches to their regular clients, but their door is always open to anyone who wants to call in and have a substantial breakfast for 50 pence, and a choice of lunch for a pound. On Wednesdays, agencies are based in The Haven for the day to offer help and advice, including Citizens Advice, the Wallich, Medical Staff, and Jobcentre Plus. Christina delivers skills courses including “budgeting on benefits”, and “cooking on a limited income”. My heartfelt thanks to Mary, Neil, Christina and all the volunteers who give up their time everyday for the homeless and people in need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2714"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2714" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/F5AD216A-2D09-4C5D-A382-D5F671130946-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;It was an absolute delight to meet the winner of my Christmas Card 2022 Competition Caitlin Vaughan, aged 6, and her mother Hannah. Thank you to all the children who sent in their designs. It is always a very difficult task to select a winner, but Caitlin’s card was exceptional for one so young. Special mention for Gorazd Trajkovski from Skopje, Macedonia, aged 10 who won the International Prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2715"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2715" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/8E3138C3-FA2C-4191-A3BE-698499C533AB-560x420.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight: 400;"&gt;On the last day in the Neath Office, I took my wonderful Neath Office staff for Christmas lunch. This is our first Christmas lunch since the onset of the pandemic in 2020. My I take this opportunity to wish all my constituents a very merry Christmas and a happy, healthy New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.christinarees.org/?attachment_id=2716"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2716" src="https://www.christinarees.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/BB5F61DE-C53B-4E60-98D7-9EC5CC5EE178-560x560.jpeg" alt="" width="560" style="display:block;margin:10px auto;max-width:560px;max-width:100%;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I attended the funeral of my dear friend Ceridwen Rogers, known as Crid. Many years ago I met Alan Rogers, former MEP and former MP for the Rhondda, and his wonderful wife Crid. We saw one another often from 1983 until 1998, but we have lost touch over the subsequent years. However, I was delighted […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2711</id>
    <published>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-22T11:43:28Z</updated>
    <category term="My Weekly Round-up"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Royal British Legion Christmas Support Line</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/21/royal-british-legion-christmas-support-line/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Royal British Legion are keen for members of the Armed Forces community to know that they are here for them over Christmas. Pressures of life are often exacerbated during the festive season, with feelings of loneliness and isolation and financial worries increased. The Royal British Legion are here to offer assistance, companionship, and a [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/21/royal-british-legion-christmas-support-line/">Royal British Legion Christmas Support Line</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5086</id>
    <published>2022-12-21T13:44:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T13:44:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PM ACCUSED OF ‘IGNORING THE WARNINGS’ ON £6.7B WASTED ON COVID FRAUD</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/pm-accused-of-ignoring-the-warnings-on-6-7b-wasted-on-covid-fraud/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine questioned the Prime Minister over the failure to prevent and tackle Covid fraud, during his time as Chancellor and Prime Minister. Catherine questioned the Prime Minister during the Liaison Committee hearing on Tuesday 20th December, the exchange is below. Catherine McKinnell: I appreciate that you cannot comment on ongoing legal proceedings, but do you … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/pm-accused-of-ignoring-the-warnings-on-6-7b-wasted-on-covid-fraud/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">PM ACCUSED OF ‘IGNORING THE WARNINGS’ ON £6.7B WASTED ON COVID FRAUD</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7823</id>
    <published>2022-12-21T12:14:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-21T12:14:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="Covid"/>
    <category term="economy"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
    <category term="latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Southfield School leads the way in their teaching of over 80 pupils with learning difficulties via the priority they give to communication, self-regulation and independence.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps had the pleasure of meeting both teachers and pupils to see the achievements of the school and thank the staff for their tireless and crucial work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I am very grateful for all the work the staff do for the school and their pupils” Mr Shapps commented, “and I know that my gratitude is shared both by parents and the wider community”.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The teachers thanked Mr Shapps for his visit and expressed their gratitude to him for his support with the headteacher, Angela O’Rourke, saying:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The pupils and the staff very much enjoyed having Mr Shapps on the site and were thrilled to be able to share with him the incredible role that Team Southfield play in the lives of our children. We are very grateful for Mr Shapps making the time for us”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/"&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>On one of his recent constituency days, Welwyn Hatfield’s MP Grant Shapps visited Southfield School.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/southfield-school-thanks-local-mp-for-visit/">&lt;strong&gt;Southfield School Thanks Local MP for Visit&lt;/strong&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ross Crabtree</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=46138</id>
    <published>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-20T13:27:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP celebrates Christmas in Fulmer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Always love stopping by the Black Horse at Christmas time.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-celebrates-christmas-fulmer</id>
    <published>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Article on Space in Scotland</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I was recently invited to write an article showcasing the space sector in Prestwick and Scotland for <em>House</em> magazine. </p>



<p>You can read the article <a href="https://library.myebook.com/thehouse/destination-space/4526/#page/8" target="_blank" aria-label="undefined (opens in a new tab)" rel="noreferrer noopener">here</a></p>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;linkname=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2022%2F12%2F16%2Farticle-on-space-in-scotland%2F&amp;title=Article%20on%20Space%20in%20Scotland" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/" data-a2a-title="Article on Space in Scotland"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Article on Space in Scotland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was recently invited to write an article showcasing the space sector in Prestwick and ... <a title="Article on Space in Scotland" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2022/12/16/article-on-space-in-scotland/">Article on Space in Scotland</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2667</id>
    <published>2022-12-16T11:52:14Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-16T11:52:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Central Ayrshire at Westminster"/>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="space sector; SpacePort"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Upate</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update on the support being provided locally for those struggling with energy bills this winter, particularly now that things have turned colder.</p>
<h2>Epsom &amp; Ewell Energy Support Scheme</h2>
<p>Firstly, the Epsom and Ewell Energy Support scheme has been making great progress. I am grateful to all of you who have supported the appeal, which is to help those who are struggling with bills to make their homes more energy efficient. The scheme is in operation across the whole of the constituency, including Epsom and Ewell Borough, plus the Nork and Tattenhams area on Epsom Downs and in Ashtead and Leatherhead.</p>
<p>So far the appeal has raised around £36,000 and the money is already making a huge difference. The money is being used by the Good Company, which runs local food banks, and Citizens Advice in Epsom to help people reduce their bills.</p>
<p>The Good Company has been running a package of support for those needing help, including free energy advice – delivered by an expert adviser from Surrey Community Action – and energy saving appliances to help reduce their energy usage, as well as a gas/electricity top-up to help relieve the immediate financial pressure on them. All of the money you have contributed has been used to provide the top-up and energy saving appliances like air fryers, heated drying racks and LED light bulbs. In total they have helped around 250 people so far.</p>
<p>The response from those being helped has been really positive. This is one example:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 40px;"><em>“The workshop was so helpful and we would definitely want to come to any more you have, so useful, and you’re all so nice! The electric drying rail would be amazing, thank you so much. And the hooded blankets sound great. Really appreciate all the support you guys are giving out.”</em><br/>
<em>(Maria, group workshop)</em></p>
<p>Citizens Advice have also been providing top-ups for those struggling with bills, and then providing energy saving advice and lower cost appliances. They say that air fryers are by far the most popular option and have been their biggest means of help so far. One of the people they helped said he felt “stronger, more in control and more able to cope with future problems.”</p>
<p>I am again really grateful to those who have helped out. The scheme aims to get those people who do not need the £400 top up being provided for bills this winter by the Government to contribute it to the fund instead. If you are in that position and have not yet supported the scheme, please do consider doing so now.</p>
<p>You can donate via this Justgiving page, which also has more details about the scheme.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme">www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme</a></strong></p>
<h2>Warm Hubs</h2>
<p>Secondly there is now a county-wide network of warm hubs which provide people who are worried about their bills with a place to go during the day if they need one. Several of our local churches are taking part as well as some other organisations. I am really grateful to all those who are doing so.</p>
<p>There is a full list of all the venues and when they are open on the Surrey website, and you can access the detail via this link.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="www.surreycc.gov.uk/health-and-welfare/support/welfare-support/everyday-living/warm-hubs/list-of-warm-hubs-in-surrey">www.surreycc.gov.uk/health-and-welfare/support/welfare-support/everyday-living/warm-hubs/list-of-warm-hubs-in-surrey</a></strong></p>
<h2>Pension Credit</h2>
<p>If you are retired and living off the state pension alone or are on a low income you may be entitled to pension credit. The Government is running a campaign to help people understand more about what they may be entitled to. There is also an extra cost of living payment of £324 available for people entitled to pension credit, but you need to apply before December 18th. The details are here.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="gov.uk/pension-credit/how-to-claim">gov.uk/pension-credit/how-to-claim</a></strong></p>
<p>There is more information here available from the charity Independent Age.</p>
<p><strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="https://www.independentage.org/get-advice/advice-guides-factsheets-leaflets">https://www.independentage.org/get-advice/advice-guides-factsheets-leaflets</a></strong></p>
<h2>Citizens Advice Volunteers</h2>
<p>Finally thank you to all of those who came to my volunteer fair in October and particular to those who have signed up as volunteers.</p>
<p>Citizens Advice have asked me to advertise the fact that they are still looking for a retired lawyer to help them co-ordinate their work with local firms providing pro bono support for people in difficulties. They have also asked me to say that they are short of volunteers to help with the energy support scheme and a range of other roles, and if you would like to help there are details at <strong><a class="x1fey0fg xmper1u x1edh9d7" href="www.caee.org.uk/volunteer/">www.caee.org.uk/volunteer/</a></strong></p>
<p>Best wishes</p>
<p>Chris Grayling</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/">Local Upate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update on the support being provided locally for those struggling with energy bills this winter, particularly now that things have turned colder. Epsom &amp; Ewell Energy Support Scheme Firstly, the Epsom and Ewell Energy Support scheme has been making great progress. I am grateful to all [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-upate/">Local Upate</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6366</id>
    <published>2022-12-15T15:03:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-15T15:03:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A major step forward to unlock islands renewables potential says Isles MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/15/a-major-step-forward-to-unlock-islands-renewables-potential-says-isles-mp/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says today’s announcement that approval has been granted from energy regulator Ofgem for the need to build a 1.8GW interconnector to export renewable energy from the Western Isles to the mainland grid is a major step forward.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil has continually lobbied for the interconnector and today’s announcement is a long-awaited breakthrough.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mr MacNeil said: “This has been the work of many years and is extremely welcome news for Na h-Eileanan an Iar. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“This opens up the islands to fulfil its renewable energy potential bringing massive benefits to the islands’ economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“For so long we wanted Ofgem to green light a 600MW connection and they were insisting on 450WM. &amp;nbsp;Now Ofgem have green lighted a 1.8GW connector.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Years have been lost and things could be a lot better had this been built years ago.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As it is, construction is expected to be ongoing in 2025/26 with the project finished in 2030.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/20221125_115626-1.jpg"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" data-attachment-id="4078" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/20221125_115626-2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg" data-orig-size="1816,1362" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G780F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1669377386&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.00091996320147194&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;58.189085452778&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-6.3795056&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="20221125_115626" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/12/20221125_115626-1-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4078" width="904" height="616" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil says today’s announcement that approval has been granted from energy regulator Ofgem …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/15/a-major-step-forward-to-unlock-islands-renewables-potential-says-isles-mp/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4075</id>
    <published>2022-12-15T12:00:04Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-15T12:00:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas 2022 Office Hours</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
	&lt;div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element " &gt;
		&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;Due to the festive break, my office will close from 23 December &amp;#8211;  3 January. From 3rd January, my team and I will be here to help you with any issue you may have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be periodically checking my email and voicemail over Christmas and the New Year, so if you have a very urgent query you can contact me as below. All other correspondence will be dealt with on our return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a very urgent query, please email details to &lt;a href="mailto:abrahamsd@parliament.uk"&gt;abrahamsd@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;. If you do not have access to emails, you can call &amp;amp; leave a voicemail regarding your urgent matter with details on 0161 624 4248 or 0207 219 1041&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All other enquiries will be dealt with when the office re-opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team and I would like to wish you all a very Merry Christmas and a happy &amp;amp; healthy 2023!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debbie Abrahams MP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham East &amp;amp; Saddleworth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Useful contacts/information for the festive period:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Cost of Living support &amp;#8211; &lt;em&gt;https://www.oldham.gov.uk/wecanhelp&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Metropolitan Borough Council Helpline &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 7007&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welfare Support &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 6655&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(www.oldham.gov.uk/welfarerights)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citizens Advice Oldham &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0808 278 7803&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Credit support &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0800 144 8444&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get Oldham Working &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 4674&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Foodbank &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 7007&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(www.oldham.foodbank.org.uk)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Credit Union &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0161 678 7245&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm Homes Scheme &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;0800 019 1084&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council Emergency 24 hour homelessness team: &lt;strong&gt;0800 988 7061&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social services (out of hours emergency only) –  &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 6936&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oldham Council First Response team – &lt;strong&gt;0161 770 2222&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police General Switchboard (24 hours) – &lt;strong&gt;101&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Police emergencies (24 hours) – &lt;strong&gt;999&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical emergencies:  visit your local &lt;a href="http://www.nhs.uk/service-search" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;hospital&lt;/a&gt; or call 999&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-urgent medical advice – &lt;strong&gt;111&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas (24 hour emergency helpline) – &lt;strong&gt;0800 111 999&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electricity North West (24 hour emergency helpline) – &lt;strong&gt;105&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United Utilities website and details &lt;a href="https://www.unitedutilities.com/emergencies/"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greater Manchester Law Centre: &lt;strong&gt;0161 769 2244&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fcho.co.uk/contact-us/ways-to-contact-us/"&gt;First Choice Homes Oldham &amp;#8211; Multiple contacts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_empty_space"   style="height: 20px" &gt;&lt;span class="vc_empty_space_inner"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"&gt;&lt;div class="vc_column-inner"&gt;&lt;div class="wpb_wrapper"&gt;&lt;div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"&gt;&lt;h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;"&gt;Feel strongly about this article? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"&gt;&lt;a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact"&gt;Contact Debbie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/"&gt;Christmas 2022 Office Hours&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk"&gt;Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/christmas-2022-office-hours/">Christmas 2022 Office Hours</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7072</id>
    <published>2022-12-14T09:18:58Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-14T09:18:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Christmas"/>
    <category term="Office"/>
    <category term="Opening"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Heart Hero awards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/12/07/green-heart-hero-awards/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7576</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[NHS Surgery Waiting List]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1716</id>
		<updated>2022-12-07T14:48:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-12T14:44:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Bolton Hospital"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="cancer"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Department of Health and Social Care"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="health"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="healthcare"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="NHS"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Surgery"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/12/nhs-surgery-waiting-list/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett continues campaign against Southeastern timetable changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford, is continuing to campaign for changes to the new Southeastern railway timetable, which will be implemented from Sunday 11 December.
To date, Sir David has held meetings with Southeastern Managing Director, Steve White, the Rail Minister,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>November 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/november-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/697fbaf4ce7e/tulip-siddiq-mp-november-2022-enewsletter-5275806"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5603" width="282" height="147" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews-300x157.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews-768x402.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews-105x55.png 105w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews-669x350.png 669w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/novnews-630x330.png 630w" sizes="(max-width: 282px) 100vw, 282px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/697fbaf4ce7e/tulip-siddiq-mp-november-2022-enewsletter-5275806">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for November 2022</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for November 2022</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5601</id>
    <published>2022-11-30T15:54:52Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-30T15:54:52Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="november"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[GIVING TUESDAY]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=469</id>
		<updated>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3358</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:46:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Constituent, Welcome to my November&#160;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&#160; Autumn Statement: Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my November&nbsp;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Autumn Statement:</h1>



<p>Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. In which he detailed how the Government intends to restore economic stability and tackle inflation.</p>



<p>Like many countries around the world, the UK is facing profound economic challenges. Supply disruption caused by the world’s economies emerging from lockdown has been compounded by Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine and deliberate interference with Europe’s energy supply to create massive increases in the cost of energy. This has led to high inflation and high interest rates across many of the world’s major economies, and the UK is no different.</p>



<p>I welcome the proposals in the Autumn Statement. To achieve long-term, sustainable growth we need to grip inflation, balance the books, and get debt falling as a share of GDP. The plan presented by the Chancellor yesterday takes the tough decisions to face up to this situation without passing the buck onto future generations. What’s more, it protects the hard-working majority by enacting no headline tax increases, and protects the most vulnerable by maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation – something I have personally been campaigning for. All while protecting and maintaining public spending for the next two years at the levels set out in 2021.</p>



<p>The plan involves a roughly equal split between tax rises and spending cuts, with the greatest burden falling on those who can afford it most. Specifically, the plan:</p>



<p><strong>Increases taxpayer funding for our NHS and schools by an extra £11 billion over the next two years.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Government will provide £4 billion in additional funding to schools and £7.7 billion in additional funding to the NHS and social care sector over the next two years. Prioritising the public services that matter most.</p>



<p>&#8211; £2–3 billion in additional funding for the NHS in each of the next two years so we can bring down ambulance waiting times, tackle the Covid backlog, and improve access to GPs. Also providing £2.8 billion next year and £4.7 billion the year after for adult social care, which aims to double the number of people leaving hospitals on time and into care by 2024, addressing unmet needs and boosting low pay in the sector.</p>



<p>&#8211; £4 billion in additional funding for schools over the next two years. We are increasing the schools budget by £2 billion this year and £2 billion next year to help schools with rising costs as a result of inflation. Which is more than Labour has pledged to give schools.</p>



<p><strong>Introduces no headline tax increases.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Autumn Statement raises £25 billion in additional taxes over the forecast period but there are no increases in the headline rates of tax. By targeting tax rises toward businesses, wealthier households, and the oil and gas industry, the Government has ensured that it can honour its manifesto commitment not to increase Income Tax, National Insurance, or VAT.</p>



<p>&#8211; Instead of raising rates, the Government is freezing personal tax thresholds for a further two years. There are also reforms to the Additional Rate threshold, so that a taxpayer who earns more than £150,000 will pay £1,200 more in tax per year.</p>



<p>&#8211; It is only fair that companies who have made genuine windfall profits as a result of the war in Ukraine make an additional contribution to pay for the support we have outlined. So from 2023, the Energy Profits Levy rate will rise from 25per cent to 35per cent and will continue until the end of March 2028. A 45per cent Levy will be applied to extraordinary returns made by electricity generators. In total these windfall taxes will raise £52 billion over six years. This is more ambitious than Labour’s proposal.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting and maintaining public spending.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; For the next two years public spending will remain at the levels set out in 2021 and then increase by one per cent in real terms each year until 2027–28.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting every household with their energy bills.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Energy Price Guarantee will continue to support everyone for another year. This winter, the price households pay for the energy they use will be capped, so that a typical household will pay £2,500. From April 2023, the price cap will rise so that a typical household will pay £3,000. The Energy Price Guarantee will then end in April 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting the most vulnerable through maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; I have been publicly campaigning for benefits and pensions to be increased in line with inflation for some time now, and so was very pleased to see the Chancellor yesterday confirm that this would be part of the Government’s plan.</p>



<p>&#8211; To protect the most vulnerable, benefits will now be increased in line with inflation for 2023–24. More than 10 million households in receipt of working-age and disability benefits will see an increase in their benefit payments.</p>



<p>&#8211; The pensions triple lock will also be protected. Because of the difficult but necessary decisions the Government has taken elsewhere, the triple lock for pensions will be protected in full. This means that in April, the State Pension will increase in line with inflation, which is the biggest cash increase in the State Pension ever.</p>



<p><strong>Additional support for the most vulnerable.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Over £12 billion of additional targeted support is assigned to help the most vulnerable households. The Government will continue providing this year’s cost of living payments and next year it will provide extra one-off payments of £900 for the 8 million households on means-tested benefits, £300 to pensioners, and £150 for disability benefit recipients. The Government is also providing £1 billion of extra funding by extending the Household Support Fund for another year.</p>



<p>The OBR has confirmed that these plans will restore the public finances to a sustainable position and help reduce inflation and unemployment. And I look forward to engaging with my ministerial colleagues as these policies are rolled out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Remembrance Sunday:</h1>



<p>This year for Remembrance Sunday on 13th November, I was honoured to lay wreaths in Ripley and Kilburn in memory of those who have served our county, and in honour of those who are still serving. There are a multitude of remembrance services held across our constituency every year, so it is unfortunately impossible for me to attend all of them. However, every year I try to rotate which services I attend. This year it was a memorial service at Ripley War Memorial in the morning and another in Kilburn in the afternoon.</p>



<p>This has been a particularly important period of remembrance as we mark 40 years since the end of the Falkland’s war, and we commemorate the 255 British personnel who lost their lives in defence of the islands. Their courage and sacrifice must never be forgotten. Thank you to everyone who organised or supported the remembrance services and parades across Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Alfreton Solar Farm Update:</h1>



<p>On 21st October, I spoke at the public inquiry into plans from Kronos Solar to build a 50-megawatt solar farm between Alfreton and Oakerthorpe. Many of you will remember that Amber Valley Borough Council’s (AVBC) planning authorities rejected the proposal last December, stating that the project’s scale and impact on the landscape outweighed any environmental benefits the site would provide. However, Kronos Solar have since filed an appeal to overturn the decision of AVBC and get the site approved, resulting in this enquiry.</p>



<p>I have been opposing the project on behalf of local residents and businesses throughout the process, a great many of whom have contacted me about the proposals. I very much support the expansion of our clean energy network, and in the right place a solar farm would be an asset. However, there are good reasons why this site was refused planning permission. We all want renewable energy expansion but not at any cost.</p>



<p>To begin with, much of the land is north facing, which means the site would need to be overly large. The impact on the amenity of local residents, the impact on the countryside area, and the impact on the various heritage assets is just too great. And that is before we consider Alfreton Park and Alfreton Park Community School, which looks after children with the very highest level of need, very close in the vicinity.</p>



<p>It is clear to me that this is a totally unsuitable site for this intensity of development. Frankly, I believe this proposal was not based on a thorough search for suitable land for a solar farm, instead, it looks to me to be based on a search for a suitable sub-station, with the proposal then trying to force some land to suit.</p>



<p>I will continue to keep residents updated on any developments. And at present, a decision is expected at some point in the next few months.</p>



<h1>Pollution and our waterways:</h1>



<p>I have recently welcomed the Department for Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs’ (DEFRA) plans to raise the civil penalty for water companies who pollute our environment by one thousand times, from £250,000 up to £250 million. I am hopeful that increasing the penalties the Environment Agency can enforce without a lengthy and costly court process will enable swifter and stronger action to be taken against water companies that illegally pollute our environment.</p>



<p>Many residents have contacted me about pollution and the use of storm drains in our sewage system. There has also been a great deal of misinformation circulating on social media regarding the Government’s campaign to address these issues.</p>



<p>Last year, the Government introduced the Environment Act 2021 which was a bill designed to tackle this problem and reduce sewage pollution ignored by previous Governments. When the Environment Act was going through Parliament the Duke of Wellington, a hereditary peer, introduced an amendment that would legislate the complete elimination of storm drains and therefore of storm overflow sewage into our waterways. This of course sounds admirable, and indeed is something I support in principle. However, this amendment came without a plan for how it could be delivered and how such a vast project could be funded.</p>



<p>Initial assessments suggested elimination would cost between £150 &#8211; £650 billion. To put those figures in perspective, £150 billion was more than the entire schools, policing, and defence budgets put together. Therefore, the Government did not support the amendment, and I did not vote for it. In my view, the last thing people wanted was for their water bill to go through the roof.</p>



<p>Twitter mis-informers seized this opportunity and claimed we had all voted in favour of water companies dumping raw sewage into our rivers. Which was totally false, and ironically punished the Government for actually trying to do something about the problem ignored by previous Governments.</p>



<p>With this most recent announcement by DEFRA, I am glad to see the Government continuing the campaign to improve the quality of our waterways. To hold water companies to account, and ensure any polluter pays for the environmental harm they cause, the Environment Agency must take advantage of these new powers.</p>



<h1>Illegal crossings over the Channel:</h1>



<p>Many of you have contacted me about the number of small boats illegally crossing the English Channel in recent months. I appreciate the strength of feeling on this alarming issue and want to outline my position to you and explain some of the challenges we face in tackling this problem.</p>



<p>The number of illegal entries into the United Kingdom via small boats crossing the English Channel is too high. It endangers the lives of those making the journey, puts money into the pockets of ruthless and brutal people smuggling gangs, and puts undue pressure on our existing asylum system as well as our public services. I remain committed to an immigration policy that welcomes people to the UK through safe and legal routes, and an immigration policy that allows us to provide asylum to those in genuine need. However, it is clear many of those arriving in small boats are not here in genuine need of asylum, and as a result, the current situation cannot go on.</p>



<p>One reason for small boat crossings increasing in frequency is the success the Government has had in tackling other forms of illegal immigration. Such as increased checks and security for lorries and freight crossing the channel, effectively reducing the number of illegal entries into the UK through these means, and increasing the number of people turning to small boats as a way to enter the UK. The problem that now presents itself is how to police and secure hundreds of miles of coastline 24/7.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Parliament passed the Nationality and Borders Act which overhauled our approach to asylum and illegal migration. The legislation includes fairness towards those who need our help, and in welcoming people through safe and legal routes, but firmness in tackling abuse of the system and expediting the removal of those who have no legitimate claim for protection. It is worth noting that Labour opposed this Act designed to toughen our immigration system.</p>



<p>Further to changing the law in this country, the Government has recently signed a joint UK-France arrangement on tackling small boat crossings in the Channel which includes a 40% increase in the number of UK-funded officers patrolling French beaches. The new agreement lays the foundations for deeper UK-French co-operation to tackle illegal migration. The arrangement means, for the first time, specialist UK officers will be able to observe French officials at work in control rooms and on the ground patrolling the coastline.</p>



<p>It is clear, however, that big challenges still lie ahead, and that the number of small boats currently crossing the channel is unacceptable. The Prime Minister speaking recently on GB News said that tackling illegal immigration was a huge priority for his Government, and that while the recent joint UK -France arrangement was a big step in the right direction there was more that needs to be done. I share the Prime Minister’s view, and will continue engaging with my ministerial and Parliamentary colleagues to make the case for further measures to reduce cross channel migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on why Iran should be removed from UN commission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=V9wDfpUx" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-63c7bb32186a5" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-63c7bb32186a5').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"63c7bb32186a5","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-63c7bb32186a5" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-63c7bb32186a5" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="63c7bb32186a5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_63c7bb32186a5" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_63c7bb32186a5" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_63c7bb32186a5" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_63c7bb32186a5" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_63c7bb32186a5" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_63c7bb32186a5" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_63c7bb32186a5_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-63c7bb32186a5 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dwVP3FEVYo7K437DQyMM421I1r1CagFG-x5_fX1Ista2Aup97xhuXcZwu-rn2lxkjO8wp942FX9awdyCLHDUQ' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
