<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2023-06-15T09:25:38Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Karin Smyth MP slams another monthly increase in unemployment in south Bristol</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/15/karin-smyth-mp-slams-another-monthly-increase-in-unemployment-in-south-bristol/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=karin-smyth-mp-slams-another-monthly-increase-in-unemployment-in-south-bristol" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has called out the Conservative Government for its inability to tackle unemployment in the constituency and accused them of being “more concerned about internal battles than solving the cost of living crisis.”</p>
<p>Bristol South has seen a 6% increase this month (155 people) and 28% increase (615 people) since March 2020 in total unemployment. There are now 2,840 individuals in the constituency now out of work, education of training.</p>
<p>There has also been an 8% rise (40 people) this month and a 19% rise (85 people) since March 2020 in unemployment among 18–24-year-olds. This means there are 535 young people not in work or education in the area.</p>
<p>These figures represent the highest rise in all four of the Bristol constituencies. Bristol West comes a distant second with a 2% month-on-month increase in total unemployment and -2% decrease in youth unemployment.</p>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, said:</p>
<p>“The Tories are more concerned about internal battles than solving the cost of living crisis. They are riven with divisions and have become so distracted by personality differences they are failing everyone in Bristol.</p>
<p>“It is particularly worrying to see the rise in youth unemployment, a cohort that are vulnerable to the challenges of being out of work and who then have to find themselves a way into the market without work experience in those formative years. I know that there is fantastic work happening in places such as the City of Bristol College to support young people into apprenticeships and work, but there needs to be a stronger emphasis on the importance of these programmes from central Government and support for them to reach a wider range of people.</p>
<p>“Education and work go hand-in-hand and is the way to allow families to support themselves and to live with dignity. The Tory Government must do the right thing: call a General Election and let the Labour Party deliver a fairer economy for all.”</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/15/karin-smyth-mp-slams-another-monthly-increase-in-unemployment-in-south-bristol/">Karin Smyth MP slams another monthly increase in unemployment in south Bristol</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, has called out the Conservative Government for its inability to tackle unemployment in the […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2023/06/15/karin-smyth-mp-slams-another-monthly-increase-in-unemployment-in-south-bristol/">Karin Smyth MP slams another monthly increase in unemployment in south Bristol</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3541</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T09:12:58Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T09:12:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Tory Mortgage Mess</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2023/06/tory-mortgage-mess/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;A typical household&amp;#39;s mortgage payment has risen threefold in the last 2 years. Yet in the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/NorthEast?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#NorthEast&lt;/a&gt; wages are lower now than when the Tories came into power, 13 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked the Minister why my constituents should carry on paying the price of conservatism. &lt;a href="https://t.co/q87V306rO6"&gt;pic.twitter.com/q87V306rO6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah ???? (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1668656909623209992?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 13, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;amp;memberId=4124"&gt;Chi Onwurah &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;amp;memberId=4124"&gt;(Newcastle upon Tyne Central) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The typical household’s mortgage payments have risen threefold in the last two years, yet in the north-east the typical wage packet is lower than when the Conservatives came to power 13 years ago. The Minister refuses to take any responsibility for the economic misery his Government are inflicting, despite having flagrantly and blatantly crashed the economy less than a year ago. Will he tell my constituents why they should carry on paying the price of Conservatism?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-13/debates/7DDEBAD2-C377-426C-8D31-9DB9047B68DF/MortgageMarket#contribution-90F65B8C-4DFB-4634-ADA5-04F52E52C088"&gt;https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2023-06-13/debates/7DDEBAD2-C377-426C-8D31-9DB9047B68DF/MortgageMarket#contribution-90F65B8C-4DFB-4634-ADA5-04F52E52C088&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A typical household's mortgage payment has risen threefold in the last 2 years. Yet in the #NorthEast wages are lower now than when the Tories came into power, 13 years ago. I asked the Minister why my constituents should carry… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13629</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T08:22:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T08:22:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Constituency Corner"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Written Answers from the Department for Business and Trade</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2023/06/15/written-answers-from-the-department-for-business-and-trade/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">Department for Business and Trade provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (187008):</span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">Question:</span></b><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"><br/>
To ask the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, how much the Government spent on subsidies to high energy using industries last year. (187008) </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">Tabled on: 02 June 2023</span></p>
<p><b><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">Answer:</span></b><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;"><br/>
<b>Ms Nusrat Ghani</b>: </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">Over £450 million was provided across the Energy Intensive Industry schemes in 2022. This was in addition to support provided by the Energy Bill Relief Scheme (EBRS) for businesses and other non-domestic customers. The EBRS ended on 31 March 2023 and provided around £7 billion of support to businesses, including high energy using industries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 11.5pt; font-family: 'Tahoma',sans-serif; color: black;">The answer was submitted on 07 Jun 2023 at 16:29.</span></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Department for Business and Trade provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (187008): Question: To ask the Secretary of State for Business and Trade, how much the Government spent on subsidies to high energy using industries last year. (187008) Tabled on: 02 June 2023 Answer: Ms Nusrat Ghani: Over £450 million was provided…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=35347</id>
    <published>2023-06-15T04:00:49Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-15T04:00:49Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Science, Innovation and Technology Questions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/parliament/science-innovation-and-technology-questions-1" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="2725" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;14 June 2023&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Science, Innovation and Technology Questions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;George Freeman, Minister of State for Science, Research and Innovation answers MPs’ questions to the Department for Science, Innovation and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-90781" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/D4Iar1hOvno?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Regional Innovation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4358"&gt;Wendy Morton (Aldridge-Brownhills) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. What steps her Department is taking to support innovation in all regions of the UK. (905383)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=345"&gt;Sir Edward Leigh (Gainsborough) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. What steps her Department is taking to support innovation in all regions of the UK. (905391)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister for Science, Research and Innovation (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support innovation across the whole of the UK, a central pillar of our innovation nation mission, the UK Government are investing £52 billion in public research and development over these next three years. We have made a groundbreaking commitment in the levelling up White Paper to increase the percentage of Government R&amp;D outside of the greater south-east, which is, of course, home to some of our historic research institutes, by 40%. We have an active programme—through the Catapults, the innovation accelerators and cluster support—all around the UK to that end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4358"&gt;Wendy Morton &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation is in the DNA of the businesses in my constituency, including Surespan, a leading manufacturer of roof access hatches, and Phoenix Tooling and Development—after all, our region was the birthplace of the industrial revolution. I support the Government’s levelling-up mission, but will the Minister bring forward individual regional targets for rebalancing research and development funding, as recommended by a House of Lords Committee report?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first pay tribute to Surespan and Phoenix. Two weeks ago, my right hon. Friend the Secretary of State and I were in Coventry in the west midlands with the Chancellor, and I have been working closely with Mayor Andy Street on his excellent programmes. We have an advanced manufacturing Catapult in the west midlands. Coventry and Warwick are rapidly becoming world-recognised centres in a whole raft of materials and in robotics. We are working on the Birmingham innovation district, and we have put one of our three innovation accelerators—£30 million—into the west midlands. My right hon. Friend the Member for Aldridge-Brownhills (Wendy Morton) makes an important point, though, about regional R&amp;D clusters; that is public and private sector money. We will set out this autumn our digital cluster map showing all the private and public funding, and how we intend to increase it by region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=345"&gt;Sir Edward Leigh &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Government recently launched a call for space infrastructure projects, and West Lindsey District Council has proposed plans to work with the Satellite Applications Catapult, which the Minister mentioned, at RAF Scampton, as part of a £300 million levelling-up deal. What is the logic of one part of Government talking about levelling up and innovation and another part talking about putting a migrant camp in the middle of it, preventing all that infrastructure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My right hon. Friend will appreciate that, as the Minister for Science, Research and Innovation, I cannot comment on Home Office plans to deal with refugees, but I can pay tribute to the work of Scampton Holdings Ltd and the very innovative proposal for the regeneration of that site with a whole raft of facilities, including in innovation support. I very much look forward to coming up in due course, once the refugee issue is sorted, to support him in taking that forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4243"&gt;Dan Jarvis (Barnsley Central) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metro Mayors have an important role to play in driving innovation in the regions. Can the Minister give an assurance that he will work closely with them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am absolutely delighted to do so. The Metro Mayors are key parts of our innovation ecosystem, and the three innovation accelerators that have we put in place are fundamentally co-created and led from the bottom up in Glasgow, Manchester and the west midlands. I am actively reaching out to work with the Metro Mayors, as well as with devolved Science Ministers, on extending our science investment to unify all regions of this country and strengthen those urban economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=410"&gt;Jon Trickett (Hemsworth) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the problem is that in my constituency in the Yorkshire coalfield, there are 20 times fewer people employed in science and technology innovation than in Cambridge. We can be proud of what Cambridge has achieved, but why should areas such as mine be so left behind? There is no economic reason why the golden triangle between Greater London, Cambridge and Oxford should be preferred over the rest of the country, so is it pure politics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am afraid that the hon. Gentleman could not be more wrong; it is quite the opposite. The truth is that the Oxford-Cambridge-London triangle is golden for a reason: it is home to two of the world’s top three universities and five of top 15. Our central mission is to ensure that we grow an R&amp;D economy all around the country that nurtures and invests in research, including a fantastic cluster in Yorkshire: the Yorkshire bioeconomy, advanced manufacturing in Sheffield, and Doncaster. We are investing in all that, but one does not create the Oxford-Cambridge triangle overnight; it requires us to invest with local leaders, as they are doing across the north-east in County Durham and Northumbria, in the innovative companies of tomorrow. This is a historic moment for the former coalfields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=467"&gt;Mr Speaker &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call the Scottish National party spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4443"&gt;Carol Monaghan (Glasgow North West) (SNP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I declare an interest as the chair of the all-party group on photonics and quantum. The Fraunhofer Centre for Applied Photonics at the University of Strathclyde has played a leading role in the industrial strategy challenge fund, collaborating with more companies and projects than any other organisation, and it has been praised as a key strength in the national quantum strategy. The centre is supported by the Scottish Government and Scottish Enterprise, but despite its being established at the UK Government’s invitation, the UK Government have provided no core funding. What discussion has the Minister had with Treasury colleagues on providing that core funding to a vital part of the quantum technology landscape?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say, that is a bit rich given that the incredible strength of Scottish science and research is built largely on long-term UK block funding across life sciences and other areas. As I said, I have just been in Glasgow, where we put one of our three innovation accelerators. That has been transformational, particularly in quantum, where we have set out our plans for the £2.5 billion quantum strategy. It is just not fair or true to say that the UK Government are not investing in the Glasgow cluster; we are, and it is transformational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-14/debates/4c74a28e-4412-4cea-9850-bc284abf2415/CommonsChamber#contribution-A55BD479-8627-42F8-A294-866600EEB4A3"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Brexit: Science and Technology Sector&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4463"&gt;Chris Stephens (Glasgow South West) (SNP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. What assessment she has made of the potential impact of the UK's departure from the EU on the science and technology sector. (905386)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister for Science, Research and Innovation (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past six or seven years since 2016, this country has seen extraordinary growth in investment in our science and technology sector. Members do not need to take it from me: they can take it from those who track the investment. The UK has nearly 20 times more venture capital than its level of funding in 2011, and I am delighted to say that a majority of that—the fastest growth—is around the country. The east midlands and Northern Ireland have seen the sharpest increases in investment in the past four years, with growth in the east midlands topping at 300%. Something extraordinary is going on in this economy, and far from using Brexit as an opportunity to talk the country down, we intend to use it as an opportunity to lead in the smart regulation of the economies and sectors of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4463"&gt;Chris Stephens &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thank the Minister for that answer, but the UK Government are pushing for a discount on membership in the Horizon programme, arguing that UK researchers have been disadvantaged by two years outside that programme. Does that not amount to the Conservative party openly admitting that cutting the UK off from Europe was damaging, and that we must return as a matter of urgency to European projects such as Horizon?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be very clear, we negotiated membership of Horizon, Copernicus and Euratom specifically in our Brexit deal—it was the EU that held us out. Secondly, while we have been waiting, we have deployed over £1 billion of extra funding here in the UK to support our sector, and now that the Prime Minister has secured the Windsor framework, the negotiations are actively going on. I know that the Secretary of State will want to say something about that later. We intend to collaborate deeply with Europe and use our regulatory freedoms in the new sectors of tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=69"&gt;Sir Oliver Heald (North East Hertfordshire) (Con)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does my hon. Friend agree that it is as important to the EU as it is to the UK to have good science co-operation, and that the benefits of our wonderful companies such as Johnson Matthey in Royston and the big companies we have in Stevenage demonstrate the importance of international co-operation in business? That should happen in universities as well. It is for the EU as well as us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My right hon. and learned Friend makes an important point. One of the attractions of Horizon is that we get back most of what we put in, and it funds research collaborations across our system, but the negotiations are important. We have been out of the system for two years; we need to get a fair deal, as the Prime Minister has made clear, and to make sure that the UK is not paying for stuff that it has not been able to access over the past two and a half years. I am sure that His Majesty’s Treasury is well equipped to have that negotiation on our behalf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=467"&gt;Mr Speaker &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call the shadow Minister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4124"&gt;Chi Onwurah (Newcastle upon Tyne Central) (Lab)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now 127 weeks of uncertainty, delay and broken promises since the Conservatives took us out of the world’s biggest and most prestigious science fund, Horizon Europe. Our scientists, universities and businesses have paid the price in lost jobs and investment, so will the Minister confirm or deny the reports that negotiations to rejoin Horizon have stalled because his Government are pushing for a reduced fee to reflect what they believe is a lasting reduction in grants won by UK scientists? If they have permanently damaged our success rate, should the Minister not be trying to fix that, rather than claim a discount?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;George Freeman &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I refer the hon. Member to the answer I gave a few moments ago. We have negotiated access to Horizon—it was the EU that kept us out. The Prime Minister has unblocked that through the Windsor framework. We have invested substantially through the funding guarantee for all Horizon programmes and through £850 million-odd of additional UK expenditure. We have also increased UK research and development to record levels. We will be at £52 billion by the end of this three years. There is no cutting of UK R&amp;D as a result of this issue. We are actively negotiating to make sure that we get a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-14/debates/4c74a28e-4412-4cea-9850-bc284abf2415/CommonsChamber#contribution-80A62589-BA07-401C-B716-66691FB00699"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Topical Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4870"&gt;Florence Eshalomi (Vauxhall) (Lab/Co-op)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T3. This London Tech Week, I pay tribute to King’s Maths School in my constituency, which provides tutoring for 16 to 19-year-olds. The Government promised £300 million for mathematical research in 2020, but now, despite that, they are abandoning the commitment. When does the Minister expect Britain to stay competitive and when can the Government guarantee that funding? (905399)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/search/MemberContributions?house=Commons&amp;memberId=4020"&gt;The Minister for Science, Research and Innovation (George Freeman)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Prime Minister has made clear, we are putting maths at the heart of our curriculum. I am ensuring that maths is properly funded to our research ecosystem. I will happily meet the hon. Member and talk to her about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-06-14/debates/4c74a28e-4412-4cea-9850-bc284abf2415/CommonsChamber#contribution-D2A0A821-51E8-4D29-BA7A-353CD632F4FE"&gt;Hansard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2725 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T21:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Sadly today marks 6 years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower"/>
		<published>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</published>
		<updated>2023-06-14T20:19:24+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2183-sadly-today-marks-6-years-since-the-tragic-events-at-grenfell-tower</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Sadly, today marks six years since the tragic events at Grenfell Tower. Alongside &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Royston_Smith?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Royston_Smith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; many brave leaseholders we have campaigned to improve Building Safety with billions of pounds committed, but progress is too slow for so many leaseholders. We must do better as Govt&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1668938118588776450?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 14, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New crackdown on vapes targeting our children</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/new-crackdown-on-vapes-targeting-our-children/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I am pleased that the Government have announced a clampdown on the sales of vapes to children. For too long rogue businesses have shamefully been promoting the use of colourful and flavoured vapes marketed to appeal to children.</p>
<p>So, I am pleased that the Government’s new measures will include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Making it easier to fine shops selling to under 18s</li>
<li>Reviewing the sale of nicotine free vapes to under 18s</li>
<li>Updating the school curriculum to teach kids about harmful effects of vaping</li>
<li>Giving new resources for local police to kick vapes out of schools</li>
</ul>
<p>The health and wellbeing of all of our children is a top priority and I welcome these measures to tackle the issue of underage vaping.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am pleased that the Government have announced a clampdown on the sales of vapes to children. For too long rogue businesses have shamefully been promoting the use of colourful […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4754</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T16:13:24Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T16:13:24Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;iframe title="OppDay proposing Cost of Living Committee 14 06 23" width="770" height="433" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o-LlRhpaDPg?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;  &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f4cd.png" alt="📍" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; We now come to the Opposition Day Motion in the name of Dr Phillipa Whitford on Cost of Living and Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much, Madam Deputy Speaker. I rise to move the motion in my name and those of my colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cost of living crisis is the number one issue for most of our constituents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;How to keep a roof over their heads with the rising cost of mortgages or rent. How to put food on the table when food inflation in the UK is the highest in Europe. How to pay energy bills that doubled in just a year. And how to cope with overall inflation, which is far outstripping wage growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It therefore deserves serious focus by this parliament to find solutions. The government are already patting themselves on the back, that inflation has eased from 10.1% to 7.8%. Of course, that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean prices are falling, just that they are increasing at a slightly slower rate. Now, there&amp;#8217;s no question that the Covid pandemic and the war in Ukraine have contributed to the current crisis, particularly the latter&amp;#8217;s impact on global energy prices.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the UK is the only G7 country not to have recovered to pre pandemic economic health. And consumers in the UK have faced the biggest energy price rises in Europe. . Despite the current easing of the inflation rate, it&amp;#8217;s still higher than the OECD the EU, and the US. So why does the UK have the highest inflation and poorest growth projections among similar economies?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s simple. The disaster that dare not speak its name Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we approach the seventh anniversary of the referendum, one of its key architects may have just left the stage, but Brexit&amp;#8217;s disastrous legacy will impact people across the nations of the UK for years to come. I know as a doctor that the first step in dealing with any problem is to admit that you have one. But both this government and the Labour Party appear to be in complete denial about the contribution of Brexit to the cost of living crisis. And until I will, yes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;J&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;oanna Cherry:&lt;/strong&gt; Just on the point about the Labour Party. Labour Party are obviously keen to regain seats in Scotland from the SNP, obviously we hope they don&amp;#8217;t. But why does she think the Labour Party are ignoring the impact of Brexit even in Scotland when the overwhelming position of the Scots is they want to remain in the European Union?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I thank my Honourable friend for her contribution. I think it&amp;#8217;s quite clear we saw the discomfort of the Labour party on Brexit for really quite a number of years. Because their approach to Brexit had flip flopped backwards and forwards, so they simply avoid the topic. And until recently, you would also think that there&amp;#8217;d been an omerta in the mainstream media whenever discussing the UK&amp;#8217;s economic performance.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite previously campaigning against Brexit, as I said, the Labour leader is now clear that he won&amp;#8217;t consider rejoining the EU, the Customs Union, or the single market. He claims he can somehow reduce trade friction, which has cut exports by 15% and cost 4% of G D P. But just as Brexiters claim the problems are just that the Brexit isn&amp;#8217;t Brexity enough, we now have Labour claiming that they will make Brexit work. It can&amp;#8217;t work. But if he wants to reduce some of the damage of Brexit, the Labour leader should support the idea of a committee to identify proposals that could be put to the EU prior to the review of the trade and cooperation agreement in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, what&amp;#8217;s the plan? Close his eyes, click his red heels together and make a wish. Talk about not reading the room. Just as polls show a majority across the UK recognise Brexit&amp;#8217;s a mess and would support rejoining the EU, the supposedly official opposition have lashed themselves to the mast of the floundering Tory Brexit ship.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not quite sure why they&amp;#8217;re called the official opposition when they don&amp;#8217;t seem to do much opposing and just go along with the policies of this Tory government. Whether it&amp;#8217;s on Brexit, on immigration, outsourcing the NHS in England to private companies, or denying the right of the Scottish people to choose their own future. Labour may have abandoned almost all of their previous pledges, and don&amp;#8217;t offer much real change after the next election, but the politicians who have caused the current damage to the UK economy are those with their bahookies squarely planted on the government benches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tory austerity may initially have made the Treasury balance sheet look better. But 13 years of benefit cuts and public sector pay freezes have sucked money out of local economies, leading to dead high streets and rising poverty, particularly among children, pensioners and disabled people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Austerity also meant that health and care services were already struggling when Covid hit. And the workforce shortages that hamper all four UK health services have been exacerbated by the loss of freedom of movement, meaning they&amp;#8217;re all struggling to catch up the backlog. The cost of energy is a major contributor to the cost of living crisis, but while global energy prices have risen due to the Ukraine war, the problem is also exacerbated by Tory policy over decades.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It was their poster girl, Mrs. Thatcher, who put the profits of oil, gas, and electricity into private hands. This has left the UK fully exposed to global price rises, despite the UK and Scotland&amp;#8217;s energy potential. Also, unlike France with its nationalized power supplier, which has been able to limit price increases to 4%, the UK has been unable to do this. While the energy support payments were welcome, they had a limited impact on energy bills, which had doubled in a year. And the UK government didn&amp;#8217;t follow other European countries such as Germany, Spain, Ireland, and the Netherlands, in substantially cutting VAT on energy bills. Even though rising prices means such a VAT cut could have been revenue neutral.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Brexiters actually promised cheaper food. Hard to believe. But that has turned out to be a complete crock with food inflation in the UK at over 19%, as I say, the highest in Europe. The cost of basic foods and supermarket brands are rising even faster, meaning that those on lower incomes are facing a dramatic surge in food costs with more people resorting to food banks or missing meals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Almost 30% of the UK&amp;#8217;s food comes from the EU, so there will be another surge in food prices next winter, when the UK introduces the full customs checks on food stuffs, which will be imported from the EU.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mairi Black: &lt;/strong&gt;Would she agree with me that it&amp;#8217;s also an absolute scandal that during a cost of living crisis where we&amp;#8217;re seeing prices such as she&amp;#8217;s described, that we have produce going to waste in Scotland because we don&amp;#8217;t have enough people to actually pick the fruit in.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I thank my Honourable friend for that point, and it&amp;#8217;s an issue, while soft fruit is a particular issue in Scotland, this is actually an issue right across the UK cause of the lack of European staff in harvesting. And, and we are seeing, as you, she says, food rotting in the fields. But we&amp;#8217;re also seeing it in other sectors, there&amp;#8217;s hardly a sector that isn&amp;#8217;t struggling for workforce.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With regards the income checks on incoming food stuffs from the EU, the former ill- named Brexit Opportunities Minister delayed the checks for the fourth time last year. At the time, he suggested that they would cost a billion pounds and described them as an act of self-harm. Duh. And I could have told them that in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;On top of this, the now infamous mini budget, which tanked the pound and the stock market while the chancellor was still on his feet, sent mortgage costs spiraling.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The current relentless rise in interest rates in response to inflation is making home ownership unattainable for young families as well as pushing up rents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Grant: &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;m grateful to Honourable friend for giving way, she&amp;#8217;s rightly appoint to disastrous mini budget that was imposed on us by our previous Prime Minister. Does she think the leader of the Scottish Conservative Party Group in the Scottish Parliament can have any credibility, having initially demanded the Scottish Government implement those disastrous policies and now demanding that spend billions of pounds tighten tox too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;re, I, I think more appropriately getting down on their knees in the Holyrood chamber to apologize would be an appropriate response. Despite the abuse they gave the Scottish government for not following such crazy policies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I thank the Honourable lady for giving away. I was, had the honour to be a member of the Scottish Parliament for some 12 years, and the minister opposite served in Scottish Parliament and I know a good deal about the committee system. Indeed, I chaired it. And members who were not members, members of Scottish Parliament who were not members of the committee, could come and speak at the committee in fact, or was never, never not allowed. I am not a member of any committee in this place. There are only three members of my party are members of committees, cause of the size. This means, but with the structure of this committee, the door is locked against me applying for a place on this committee, and I feel disenfranchised, and I do not see why my constituents should not be given the chance of their representative to have a voice. So I cannot vote for the structure of committees as it stands. No, look at it&amp;#8217;s sloppy work. Very sloppy work.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In actual fact, that&amp;#8217;s incorrect. There will be members from the three devolved nations. It will be as is described, a significantly large committee, which might indeed provide place for the Honourable member or one of his other colleagues from a devolved nation who would have space. So it&amp;#8217;s, it&amp;#8217;s nonsense. There is no, there is no exclusion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Linden:&lt;/strong&gt; Forgive me, I wonder if she might lend me her order paper cause mines might be out of date, but the one I&amp;#8217;ve got doesn&amp;#8217;t show any amendment from the Honourable Gentleman or indeed from his party to try and change the composition of that committee. Am I reading the order paper wrong or is the Honourable gentleman just perhaps a little bit of touch?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think the Honourable member is reading the order paper wrong.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The combination of rising energy, food, and housing costs on top of years of benefit cuts and stagnant wages means the sums simply don&amp;#8217;t add up for many families. The Scottish Government is trying to use the now very limited powers of devolution to mitigate the crisis, particularly for those on the lowest incomes. However, the Scottish budget for day-to-day running of services is less in real terms than in 2010 with no uplift for inflation. And as we all know, no significant borrowing powers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite this, the Scottish Government has provided additional funding for the Fuel Insecurity Fund and Scottish Welfare Fund. Low income families are now supported through five childhood grants, including the Scottish Child Payment, which together provide 10,000 pounds of support during the early years and will provide over 20,000 by the age of 16.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wonder, would she not agree with me that the way to improve the situation for everyone, not just in the devolved nation, throughout the United Kingdom as a whole, is for those who are elected in Scotland, to the Scottish Parliament, to work hands in glove with those of us who are elected here, and particularly the other government for Scotland and the United Kingdom. Rather than set up another cumbersome committee, which is a process. Would it not be better to work together for the benefit of everyone in the United Kingdom?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, I think the Honourable lady knows well that on things like trade deals, Brexit, we see very little consultation, genuine consultation, between the government here and the devolved government.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the Honourable lady is also well aware of how devolution is being rolled back and hollowed down legislation undermined. And that has been passed. No, I&amp;#8217;m sorry. I&amp;#8217;ve just given way to the Honourable lady.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Institute of Fiscal Studies analysis of the Scottish Tax and Benefit System showed that it was more progressive. . With almost 30% of low income families 2000 pounds a year better off in Scotland. But Scotland aspires to something more radical than just mitigating Westminster austerity, such as the two child limit or the six year benefit freeze. Our vision is to be a fairer, greener nation. Scottish government founded the Wellbeing Economy Governments Group in 2018 with Iceland and New Zealand, and Finland and Wales joined later.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A wellbeing economy doesn&amp;#8217;t just focus on GDP, which includes the profits of damaging sectors such as the tobacco industry, but invests in the physical and mental health, social economic, and environmental wellbeing of every citizen. It&amp;#8217;s a holistic approach, which recognizes that our society and economy depends on the success of every individual, every family, and every community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in addition to the targeted anti-poverty measures, the Scottish government invests in the wellbeing of all those living in Scotland. From the baby box, which welcomes the birth of a child. University tuition, which allows our young people to reach their full potential. To the free personal care, which allows older people to stay in their own homes for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But with the tightening limitations of devolution, the Scottish government doesn&amp;#8217;t have power over its own economy. . Or control of taxation and social security, that are required to deliver the wellbeing economy we aspire to. We all know we need a different type of economy by the end of this decade, or we will leave our grandchildren to face climate collapse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The pandemic brought everything to a standstill. Which gave us a unique opportunity to decide what kind of economy and society we wanted to rebuild.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stewart Hosie: &lt;/strong&gt;Before my Honourable friend goes on to talk about the kind of economy we want to see, I wonder if she&amp;#8217;d make an observation. That in an important debate on the cost of living and its evil twin Brexit, the day after an urgent question on the Tory&amp;#8217;s mortgage crisis, that here we are in this chamber with one Tory back bencher, two Labour back benchers. Does that not tell the Scottish people everything they need to know about how little unionism really cares for ordinary people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;. Well, the proposal for this economy, as I said at the beginning, is not just for the people of Scotland. It&amp;#8217;s actually for the people of the Four Nations of the UK. The review of the TCA will come up in 2026, and while it&amp;#8217;s not possible to make Brexit work, it is possible to mitigate some of its worst effects. But for that, you need to understand what Brexit&amp;#8217;s doing to the UK&amp;#8217;s society and economy, and have proposals that you can bring to the EU and ask for change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the opportunity to change to a different economy and society hasn&amp;#8217;t been taken. We already see poverty and inequality rising. And the climate emergency being pushed off the action list, including by Labour, who have just U-turned on their pledge to invest 28 billion pounds in the transition to a green economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the climate crisis can&amp;#8217;t wait. Scotland is blessed with extensive green energy potential. From wind and tidal power to green hydrogen and pump storage hydro. The current government has failed to support Scotland&amp;#8217;s green energy potential. And sadly, there is now little reason to expect much change under Labour either.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drew Hendry: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank you. I&amp;#8217;m grateful to my Honourable friend for giving way. She talks about Scotland&amp;#8217;s energy opportunities and indeed green hydrogen is one of the key ones. There does she agree with me? It&amp;#8217;s perhaps illuminating that the Foreign Secretary himself doesn&amp;#8217;t even know about those opportunities or has taken the opportunity to engage with the US in their Inflation Reduction Act in terms of the supply pipeline for that, does she think it&amp;#8217;s absolutely indicative of the state of the government of this place in terms of the relationship with the needs of the Scottish people?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, I sit on the Scottish Affairs Committee and we have done an inquiry into hydrogen and we&amp;#8217;ve also covered some of the other issues around green energy. And it&amp;#8217;s been clear from the UK Minister that they do not support the Scottish vision of actually being able to export green hydrogen. We know Germany is desperate for green hydrogen, particularly with the Ruhr area in North Rhine-Westphalia because it&amp;#8217;s crucial for heavy industry, but the UK government are not interested in that, and therefore, Scotland&amp;#8217;s potential for such a lucrative export is going to be held back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I, I&amp;#8217;m grateful for the honourable member giving away, particularly as she&amp;#8217;s raised an issue that we&amp;#8217;ve discussed at some length in the Scottish Affairs Committee, that, that of the future of hydrogen, carbon capture and storage, and such like. But does the Honourable member agree, or does she, does she believe that it&amp;#8217;s appropriate, given that energy policy and international national trade are both reserved functions, that it is appropriate for Scottish government ministers to be having direct discussions with, and officials, with federal German government ministers and officials on that matter?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously, obviously we&amp;#8217;re just continuing the Scottish Affairs Committee diatribe from Monday, but the job of the Scottish government, Scottish Ministers, Scottish MSPs, and those of us who are here, is to promote Scotland in the world, to make sure we extract as much business into Scotland and as much investment. And because of that because of the efforts of Scottish ministers and MSPs, Scotland is second only to London in foreign direct investment, and that&amp;#8217;s how we intend to keep it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I would say that the key reasons for independence can be summarized in having the powers to tackle the problems that we have. It&amp;#8217;s not that independence itself just sprinkles fairy dust. We could tackle things like poverty, but we don&amp;#8217;t have the levers. But also being able to invest in our incredible natural resources for the benefit of all of our citizens. And most importantly, to be in control of our own future.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Being independent would mean that we would never again have a disaster like Brexit, forced on us against our will. . . Those living in Scotland would get to choose their own governments. And therefore drive decisions about our future. And with over 70% of Scots supporting membership of the EU, I have no doubt that our most prosperous future is as a modern, independent European country, just like many of our very successful neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;amp;linkname=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2023%2F06%2F14%2Fcost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023%2F&amp;#038;title=Cost%20of%20Living%20Committee%20debate%2014%20June%202023" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/" data-a2a-title="Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/"&gt;Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot"&gt;Dr Philippa Whitford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>  📍 We now come to the Opposition Day Motion in the name of Dr ... <a title="Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2023/06/14/cost-of-living-committee-debate-14-june-2023/">Cost of Living Committee debate 14 June 2023</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Parliamentary Assistant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2755</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T15:51:37Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T15:51:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Questions, Speeches &amp; Motions"/>
    <category term="Westminster"/>
    <category term="Cost of Living Crisis"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali at Urgent Question on Mortgages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_at_urgent_question_on_mortgages" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_at_urgent_question_on_mortgages</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T15:52:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T15:52:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex urges Ministers to rethink Wynyard secondary school application in light of further housing developments]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/alex-urges-ministers-to-rethink-wynyard-secondary-school-application-in-light-of-further-housing-developments/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14678</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T13:36:04Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T13:36:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ministers have been urged by Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham to rethink their decision to reject an application for a new secondary school to serve the Wynyard area following an increase in house building in the area – and with proposals for more homes in the pipeline. An application for a secondary school was submitted [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2023/06/alex-urges-ministers-to-rethink-wynyard-secondary-school-application-in-light-of-further-housing-developments/">Alex urges Ministers to rethink Wynyard secondary school application in light of further housing developments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP calls on Health Minister to intervene over hospice funding crisis in South Cumbria and Lancashire</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442389/mp-calls-on-health-minister-to-intervene-over-hospice-funding-crisis-in-south-cumbria-and-lancashire"/>
  <updated>2023-06-14T13:28:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2023/1442389/mp-calls-on-health-minister-to-intervene-over-hospice-funding-crisis-in-south-cumbria-and-lancashire</id>
  <summary type="text">This morning in Parliament, local MP Tim Farron urged the Health Minister Helen Whately to intervene over a funding crisis facing hospices in Cumbria and Lancashire.
It comes as Lancashire and South Cumbria hospices have been informed that the local Integrated Care Board has offered them a 0% uplift on their 2022-23 funding.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>This morning in Parliament, local MP Tim Farron urged the Health Minister Helen Whately to intervene over a funding crisis facing hospices in Cumbria and Lancashire.</p>
<p>It comes as Lancashire and South Cumbria hospices have been informed that the local Integrated Care Board has offered them a 0% uplift on their 2022-23 funding.</p>
<p>This stands in contrast to other regions where hospices have received an average uplift of 2.7%</p>
<p>Speaking during a Westminster Hall debate, Tim read out a letter from the Chief Executive of St Mary's Hospice in Ulverston, Val Stangoe, which said that the "0% uplift equates to almost 10% in cuts" and that the decision has "left our hospices in a state of financial deficit, with potential loss of hospice beds and services".</p>
<p>Speaking in Parliament, Tim said: <em>"St Mary's Hospice at Ulverston, St John's at Lancaster, and the Eden Valley Hospice at Carlisle provide between them tender, professional specialist, expert care for those with life-limiting conditions and their loved ones.</em></p>
<p><em>"Something which we are so grateful for proving that life has dignity from beginning to end.</em></p>
<p><em>"And hospitals, however marvellous they are, do not have the resources to replicate that care if it is not provided in hospice situations.</em></p>
<p><em>"What we need to remember is that the costs of running a hospice have gone through the roof in recent times.</em></p>
<p><em>"The disproportionate treatment faced by hospices in our community is unfair and must be addressed.</em></p>
<p><em>"Of course ICBs aren't elected and the minister is.</em></p>
<p><em>"So my fundamental ask of the minister is will she directly get herself involved in that situation to prevent our hospices in Cumbria suffering the way they do?</em></p>
<p>In response, Helen Whately MP, the Minister responsible for end of life care said: <em>"Well I'm not going to commit to getting involved in a specific conversation between a specific hospice and a specific ICB. I don't think that would be appropriate or the right thing for me to do as a minister.</em></p>
<p><em>"I have been seeking transparency about the extent to which some of that funding has or has not gone to hospices.</em></p>
<p><em>"And I have been seeking the data on what is going on with the rates that are being paid to hospices, the extent to which they have or have not gone up so we can have the transparency of the extent to which the funding that has gone to Integrated Care Boards to support with inflation, is going to hospices to help with services."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why community matters – my monthly article for the Heaton’s Post</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-community-matters-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=why-community-matters-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236627" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/HP-Article.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></p>
<p>I’ve always been a strong believer in the power of community. None of us live isolated lives, and it’s vital to recognise that and make the most of the things that bind us together.</p>
<p>Community is about more than living on the same street. It’s about shared spaces, decent homes, good jobs and looking out for one another. This last principle has been particularly important over the last few years.</p>
<div>Here in Stockport, there have been some great progress in things that define us as a community. This led to Stockport recently being recognised as one of the ‘Best Places to Live’ in the Sunday Times annual list for 2023.</div>
<div dir="ltr"/>
<div>I’ve written before about the exceptional re-generation scheme – pioneered by local representatives like my late friend Cllr Shiela Bailey – which saw the creation of 1,500 affordable homes across the borough. This has come alongside huge investment in our town centres, which has given a new lease of life to many areas.</div>
<div dir="ltr"/>
<div>Similarly, across Reddish and the <span class="mark4gihfgeiy" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heaton</span>s, I’ve been really impressed by the campaigning of local councillors who have called for improved investment in our neighbourhood centres.</div>
<div dir="ltr"/>
<div>Community centres are exceptionally important. They provide resources for local residents, host food banks, provide childcare and much more. It’s been a real tragedy to see these kind of centres close across the country over the last decade, something that I’ve spoken out regularly in Parliament. However, I’m glad that here in Stockport there is a concerted effort to not only protect them, but to invest to make them even better.</div>
<p>It’s so important that this progress continues across Reddish and the <span class="mark4gihfgeiy" data-markjs="true" data-ogac="" data-ogab="" data-ogsc="" data-ogsb="">Heaton</span>s, and I look forward to working closely with local representatives, volunteers and residents to make that a reality.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-community-matters-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Why community matters – my monthly article for the Heaton’s Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I’ve always been a strong believer in the power of community. None of us live isolated lives, and it’s vital to recognise that and make the most of the things that bind us together. Community is about more than living on the same street. It’s about shared spaces, decent homes, good jobs and looking out […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/why-community-matters-my-monthly-article-for-the-heatons-post/">Why community matters – my monthly article for the Heaton’s Post</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=236626</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:20:14Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:20:14Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John Penrose discusses the importance of his Procurement Bill amendment to deliver value for money]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/14/john-penrose-discusses-the-importance-of-his-procurement-bill-amendment-to-deliver-value-for-money/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5750</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T13:08:11Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T13:08:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Anti-Corruption"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2023/06/14/john-penrose-discusses-the-importance-of-his-procurement-bill-amendment-to-deliver-value-for-money/"><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/@johnpenrose8893"></a></p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne welcomes funding for Ukraine Homelessness Prevention</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-welcomes-funding-ukraine-homelessness-prevention" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7426" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">14 June 2023</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne welcomes funding for Ukraine Homelessness Prevention</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne welcomes the allocation of funding for individuals who arrived in the UK under the Homes for Ukraine scheme.</p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--image paragraph--view-mode--default">
              
      <div class="image-container">
        
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-image field--type-entity-reference field--label-hidden field--item">  <img src="https://www.philipdunne.com/sites/philipdunne.com/files/2023-06/philip_dunne_kristina.jpg" width="1000" height="600" loading="lazy" typeof="foaf:Image" class="img-responsive"/></div>
      
        <div class="caption">
          <div class="svg">
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
          </div>
</div>
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p>The government is allocating a further £150 million towards the Ukraine Homelessness Prevention Grant, which will be distributed to local authorities, empowering them to support Ukrainian families. The aim is to prevent homelessness and foster a sense of community among Ukrainians residing in the UK.</p>

<p>As part of the Homes for Ukraine initiative, Shropshire Council will receive a funding allocation of £417,283. This funding will enable the local authority to assist Ukrainian families in accessing privately rented accommodation and finding employment. The allocation reflects the number of Ukrainians living in Shropshire currently being looked after by local residents.</p>

<p>Since the launch of the Homes for Ukraine Scheme, over 163,500 Ukrainian nationals have been accepted into the UK, with a significant proportion successfully finding employment.</p>

<p>The availability of employment rights, access to benefits, and public services such as school places from the beginning has greatly facilitated integration of Ukrainian families. In addition, the Department for Transport has extended the period in which Ukrainian refugees can drive on their home nation's license from one year to three.</p>

<p><strong>Philip Dunne said,</strong></p>

<blockquote>
<p>“I am pleased the government is recognising the importance of supporting Ukrainian families have in Shropshire through the Homes for Ukraine funding. I recently met the mother and daughter, Olga and Kristina, from Kharkiv, staying in Church Stretton with Cllr Hilary Luff, and was pleased to see they were getting on well.</p>

<p>“This funding for Shropshire will help Ukrainian families secure their own homes and prevent homelessness.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Photo: </strong><em>Philip Dunne MP meets Ukrainian Family Kristina and her daughter 7 living in Church Stretton with Cllr Hillary Luff</em></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7426 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T12:59:38Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T12:59:38Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Electric Refuse Collection Vehicles to hit the streets of the Capital </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13750/new-electric-refuse-collection-vehicles-to-hit-the-streets-of-the-capital" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Electric rocked down to Waterfront Avenue this morning as the Council’s new Electric Refuse Collection Vehicles (eRCVs) were unveiled for the first time. </div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13750/new-electric-refuse-collection-vehicles-to-hit-the-streets-of-the-capital</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:53:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:53:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin calls for support for hospices </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-support-hospices" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">During a debate in Parliament today on support for hospices, Robin paid tribute to the teams at St David's Hospice and Tŷ Gobaith hospices and called for greater financial support for hospices.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-calls-support-hospices</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Select Committee Update – The Work of ITV</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/select-committee-update-work-itv" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today the CMS Committee held a session on the work of the ITV. We heard from Dame Carolyn McCall OBE (Chief Executive, ITV), Kevin Lygo (Managing Director, Media and Entertainment, ITV), and Kyla Mullins (General Counsel and Company Secretary, ITV).
 
The purpose of this session follows the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/select-committee-update-work-itv</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Basingstoke MP visits new homes for homeless</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-visits-new-homes-homeless" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maria said after visiting the new properties, “Tackling homelessness and rough sleeping has been a priority of Basingstoke Council and it is great to see these two properties put to such good use. Providing accommodation to residents in need and enabling them to receive the support they need.
“Two…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/basingstoke-mp-visits-new-homes-homeless</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nottinghamshire Attacks - Remembering those who have perished</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/nottinghamshire-attacks-remembering-those-who-have-perished" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> I am shocked and horrified at the tragic events in Nottingham. More details will emerge, but in the meantime my thoughts, prayers and sincere condolences go out to all those affected.
Nottingham is the city of my birth, the city I was raised in and the city I have called home for most of my life.…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/nottinghamshire-attacks-remembering-those-who-have-perished</id>
    <published>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WHIT FRIDAY FUN]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=498</id>
		<updated>2023-06-14T09:11:06Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-14T09:10:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2023/06/14/whit-friday-fun/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Susie Burpee</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz speaks out about rocketing mortgage interest payments]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-out-about-rocketing-mortgage-interest-payments/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=13039</id>
		<updated>2023-06-13T17:28:19Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-13T17:28:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I took part in an Urgent Question to the Economic Secretary to the Treasury about the turmoil in the mortgage markets this week, with multiple banks pulling their deals for new borrowers. Homeowners are being stung by a massive £7,000 increase in their yearly mortgage interest payments, as rates [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-out-about-rocketing-mortgage-interest-payments/">Liz speaks out about rocketing mortgage interest payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-out-about-rocketing-mortgage-interest-payments/"><![CDATA[<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-13039-1" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/UQ-13.06.2023-compressed.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/UQ-13.06.2023-compressed.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/UQ-13.06.2023-compressed.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Today, I took part in an Urgent Question to the Economic Secretary to the Treasury about the turmoil in the mortgage markets this week, with multiple banks pulling their deals for new borrowers. Homeowners are being stung by a massive £7,000 increase in their yearly mortgage interest payments, as rates increase by more than three times what they were two years ago.</p>
<p>I urged the minister to acknowledge the fact that inflation in particular is being felt much more severely here than in similar countries. You can watch me ask my question above, and see my tweet <a href="https://twitter.com/leicesterliz/status/1668661021874040842">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-speaks-out-about-rocketing-mortgage-interest-payments/">Liz speaks out about rocketing mortgage interest payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/UQ-13.06.2023-compressed.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="11484892" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Toby Perkins’ question to the Tresury Minister regarding soaring mortgage rates.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/13/toby-perkins-question-to-the-tresury-minister-regarding-soaring-mortgage-rates/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/13/toby-perkins-question-to-the-tresury-minister-regarding-soaring-mortgage-rates/">Toby Perkins’ question to the Tresury Minister regarding soaring mortgage rates.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2023/06/13/toby-perkins-question-to-the-tresury-minister-regarding-soaring-mortgage-rates/">Toby Perkins’ question to the Tresury Minister regarding soaring mortgage rates.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5228</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T15:56:04Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T15:56:04Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>OPINION: NO CHILD IN SCOTLAND SHOULD HAVE TO LIVE IN POVERTY</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/13/opinion-no-child-in-scotland-should-have-to-live-in-poverty/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>In a wealthy country like Scotland, no child should have to grow up in poverty. But that’s the grim reality facing too many families in West Dunbartonshire as households pay a heavy price for Westminster’s failures.</p>



<p>At my advice surgeries, and out on the doorsteps, I hear heart-breaking stories from constituents being forced into hardship by soaring food prices. The latest figures from the British Retail Consortium put food inflation at more than 15% – pricing people out of basic staples like bread, butter and cheese.</p>



<p>Homeowners and renters are also being hammered by the Bank of England’s interest rate rises, which are at their highest level for 15 years.</p>



<p>Local food banks in West Dunbartonshire have been a lifeline for many, but the increasing demand being placed on these volunteer-led services isn’t sustainable.</p>



<p>Worrying, there’s likely worse to come, as the UK’s dire economic forecasts continue. Analysis by OECD shows Britain faces one of the highest rates of inflation in Europe heading into 2024.</p>



<p>It’s inexplicable that the UK government sits on its hands as hard-pressed households struggle to put food on the table.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, in independent Ireland – which has a similar population to Scotland – they’re taking definitive action to keep food inflation under control. Ireland’s economy is thriving as part of the European Union – with plans to set up an Irish sovereign wealth fund modelled on the success of other countries like Norway (which enjoys a trillion-dollar oil wealth fund).</p>



<p>Scots can only look on with envy, having had our vast energy wealth squandered by successive UK governments – and now forced to endure the consequences of a damaging Brexit we didn’t vote for.</p>



<p>Research shows that Brexit alone has added upwards of £200 to the average food bill. Families here have been left to pay the price for a cost-of-living crisis made worse by the UK’s exit from the EU.</p>



<p>It’s no wonder then that polling shows only 6% of voters in Scotland believe Brexit has been a success.</p>



<p>Yet the Labour party under Keir Starmer proudly declares that it backs Brexit. So desperate are Labour to appeal to Tory voters in England, they care little about being out of touch with voters in Scotland.</p>



<p>With Scottish democracy under attack, it’s no surprise Labour sits silently complicit as the Tories undermine the sovereignty of our parliament.</p>



<p>Blue Tories or red Tories – it makes no difference. As always, it’s left to the SNP to stand up for Scottish interests.</p>



<p>Only a vote for the SNP will deliver the real change Scotland needs with independence.</p>



<p>If Ireland and Norway can thrive as sovereign nations, then why not Scotland?</p>



<p><em><strong>This article was written for publication in the <a href="https://www.clydebankpost.co.uk/">Clydebank Post</a> and <a href="https://www.dumbartonreporter.co.uk/">Dumbarton &amp; Vale of Leven Reporter.</a></strong></em></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In a wealthy country like Scotland, no child should have to grow up in poverty. But that’s the grim reality facing too many families in West Dunbartonshire as households pay a heavy price for Westminster’s failures. At my advice surgeries, and out on the doorsteps, I hear heart-breaking stories from constituents being forced into hardship ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="OPINION: NO CHILD IN SCOTLAND SHOULD HAVE TO LIVE IN POVERTY" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2023/06/13/opinion-no-child-in-scotland-should-have-to-live-in-poverty/#more-1821764" aria-label="More on OPINION: NO CHILD IN SCOTLAND SHOULD HAVE TO LIVE IN POVERTY">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821764</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T12:48:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T12:48:17Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Cost of living Crisis"/>
    <category term="Food Prices"/>
    <category term="Ireland"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="Norway"/>
    <category term="Scottish Independence"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne-Marie visits Embleton Quarry Nature Reserve</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-visits-embleton-quarry-nature-reserve" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">One of our constituency’s unique and beautiful green spaces is the revamped Embleton Quarry Nature Reserve.
I met some of the generous volunteers who look after this special environment on my recent visit, plus some of the local Parish Councillors on the quarry working group, to hear more about…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/anne-marie-visits-embleton-quarry-nature-reserve</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton MP welcomes four million more people in work since Conservatives came to power in 2010, giving 326,337 more people in North West the security of a job</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-four-million-more-people-work-conservatives-came-power-2010-giving" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scott Benton MP welcomes four million more people in work since Conservatives came to power in 2010, giving 326,337 more people in North West the security of a job
New figures show there are four million more people in work since the Conservatives came to power in 2010 and 326,337 more people in a…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-four-million-more-people-work-conservatives-came-power-2010-giving</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg questions Foreign Secretary on Iranian militarisation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-questions-foreign-secretary-iranian-militarisation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Greg Smith MP's question to Foreign Secretary James Cleverly on the increasing and concerning militarisation happening in Iran, citing the concerning unveiling by the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) earlier this month of Iran’s first hypersonic ‘Fattah’ missile. The missile purportedly…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-questions-foreign-secretary-iranian-militarisation</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-203" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The global challenges over the past few years have shown us just how important it is to have a strong farming sector, and resilient farmers are essential for a resilient food chain in Britain. Taking mental health seriously ought to be a priority for everyone. But we know farmers are particularly…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-203</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MPs gather to celebrate British cider on World Cider Day 10th anniversary</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/13/mps-gather-to-celebrate-british-cider-on-world-cider-day-10th-anniversary/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Pictured above: Sir Bill Wiggin MP, Member of Parliament for North Herefordshire and President of the All-Party Parliamentary Cider Group; Mark Hopper, Public Affairs Director (NACM); and Fenella Tyler, Chief Executive (NACM). The success of British cider in the global... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2023/06/13/mps-gather-to-celebrate-british-cider-on-world-cider-day-10th-anniversary/#more-4764">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4764</id>
    <published>2023-06-13T11:08:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-13T11:08:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MacNeil calls for compensation for Uist businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses in Uist affected by the lack of Lochboisdale sailings in the month of June.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said: “People&amp;#8217;s jobs and livelihoods have been badly affected. The increased ferry traffic since RET has brought greater economic activity and as a result people have risen to meet the opportunities presented, and therefore cannot afford the financial hit when expected services don&amp;#8217;t materialise.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Given that practical alternatives to provide a ferry service, admittedly lesser than was timetabled, did not materialise, then the only other course of action is for businesses to be compensated for their loss.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Increased demand is placing greater strain on the ferry service with more people travelling in recent years, but that is not a fault the people in Uist should bear with a hit to their back pocket.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“I do hope the Scottish Government will do the right, fair and decent thing, and compensate businesses.&amp;nbsp; It would be to their great credit if they did.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure data-carousel-extra='{"blog_id":29149039,"permalink":"https:\/\/angusmacneilsnp.com\/2023\/06\/12\/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses\/"}'  class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex"&gt;
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="3780" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/angus/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png" data-orig-size="768,1024" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="angus" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=529" data-id="3780" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-3780" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png 768w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=113 113w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/angus.png?w=225 225w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus Brendan MacNeil is writing to the Scottish Government calling for compensation for businesses …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2023/06/12/macneil-calls-for-compensation-for-uist-businesses/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4205</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T14:03:39Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-52" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I stood up in the Commons on Monday to raise my ongoing concerns about illegal immigration to the Home Secretary. We are still waiting on the courts to approve the flights to Rwanda, but as soon as this is done, then these flights must leave immediately. We cannot waste any more time in this fight…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mps-weekly-column-52</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sturgeon must be suspended from the SNP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following the arrest of Nicola Sturgeon on Sunday, and given the scale of the police investigation and the potential repercussions, the former First Minister should really be suspended from the SNP.
SNP MSP Michelle Thomson has said Sturgeon should lose the SNP whip, joining calls from the Scottish…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/sturgeon-must-be-suspended-snp</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Consultation</h2>
<p>Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the County Council, Surrey has launched a consultation to seek views about three different potential options for the village.</p>
<p>The proposals are pretty wide-ranging, and it is important that everyone in Ewell gets the chance to give their views about the options, and indeed can suggest things that might be done as well or instead. You can find details of the consultation by following this link.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled">https://news.surreycc.gov.uk/2023/06/01/ewell-village-residents-invited-to-have-their-say-on-the-future-of-their-village/#:~:text=Ewell%20residents%20are%20being%20asked,of%20drop%2Din%20events%20scheduled</a>.</p>
<p>I am afraid that I am a little late to alert you about the drop in events, but you have the whole of June to make your views known.</p>
<h2>Charities Fair – Friday 23rd June</h2>
<p>For those of you who are looking for an opportunity to volunteer for a local charity, a reminder that my latest Charity Volunteers Fair is being held at St Paul’s Church, Howell Hill, between 4pm and 6pm on Friday June 23<sup>rd</sup>. For those of you who do not know the church, it is beyond Ewell East station on the road to Cheam.</p>
<p>Please do come along. There will be a wide range of local charities presenting what they do and looking for help.</p>
<h2>The Horton Arts Centre</h2>
<p>The Horton Arts Centre – Epsom’s beautifully renovated former chapel – has asked me to tell you that it is celebrating being open for one year. The award-winning heritage venue is planning a wide range of performances, courses and events this summer and the café-bar is open all day Tuesday to Saturday plus every Friday night.</p>
<p>A free photography exhibition by Epsom Camera Club is now running until 17 June and highlights coming up include a series of authentic Spanish classical music and dance concerts, performed in the round, 18-19 July.</p>
<p>See their website for more details: thehortonepsom.org or call 01372 747662.</p>
<h2>Ewell Village Day</h2>
<p>And one more date for your diary. The organisers have asked me to let you know that Ewell Village Fair this year is on the 15<sup>th</sup>. It’s always a good day out. And many thanks and congratulations to everyone involved in Ashtead Rotary for organising another really good Ashtead Village Day on Saturday.</p>
<p>I hope you are well and have a good summer.</p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with an update about some local events and other matters. Ewell Village Consultation Firstly, some of you will be aware that there has been a long-running debate about how best to improve the centre of Ewell Village. After extensive discussions between local residents and businesses, councillors and the [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/local-update-13/">Local Update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6430</id>
    <published>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-12T07:40:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span data-contrast="auto">Small and micro businesses in our community are feeling the weight of the economic crisis. The dual impact of rising inflation and the cost-of-living crisis is putting a strain on their small operations, and it’s clear they need our support more than ever.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">One of the most significant challenges many of our smaller businesses face is the VAT threshold, currently set at £85,000. In practical terms, this means that once a business hits this turnover, it must register for VAT, which brings with it a host of additional costs. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Understandably, this is causing a lot of worry for our business owners, many of whom are hesitant to expand their operations because of these potential costs.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">The Federation of Small Businesses (FSB) has come up with a solution that I wholeheartedly support – they’re calling for an increase in the VAT threshold from £85,000 to £100,000. This isn’t just about numbers on a balance sheet. It’s about giving our local businesses the confidence to grow and continue to support our local economy.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Previous studies by the FSB indicate that 24% of small businesses perceive the VAT limit as an obstacle to expansion, as they try to prevent the abrupt expenses associated with exceeding this limit in an effort to maintain customer affordability. The predicament has become more acute due to the rising inflation and ongoing impacts of Brexit, making growth a costly endeavour for small businesses.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">I’ve thrown my full weight behind this campaign, and <a href="http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Small-Business-VAT-UK-Letter.pdf">I’ve written to the Minister for Small Business</a> and the Chancellor urging them to do the same. This isn’t a complex issue – it’s a straightforward intervention that could make a world of difference to our small businesses.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">These are not just any businesses – these businesses are operating out of homes, markets, and local shops, providing services that range from personal care to home assistance. They are the entrepreneurs who take that bold step to start their own businesses, providing the day to day services that keep our families and our communities on track. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">They need our support, and they need it now.</span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">If you’re a small business owner in Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch, and Strathspey, I want to hear from you. I want to know your concerns and how I can best represent you. </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-contrast="auto">Let me know if you want to keep in touch: </span><a href="https://mailchi.mp/drewhendrymp/small-business"><span data-contrast="none">https://mailchi.mp/drewhendrymp/small-business</span></a><span data-contrast="auto"> </span><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
<p><span data-ccp-props="{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}"> </span></p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Small and micro businesses in our community are feeling the weight of the economic crisis. The dual impact of rising inflation and the cost-of-living crisis is putting a strain on their small operations, and it’s clear they need our support more than ever.  One of the most significant challenges many of our smaller businesses face …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/small-business-support-addressing-vat-threshold-challenges/">Small Business Support: Addressing VAT Threshold Challenges</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=7507</id>
    <published>2023-06-11T06:01:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-11T06:01:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
    <category term="Business"/>
    <category term="Economy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It is with a with a heavy heart and after much consideration, that I announce my decision not to stand again as your Member of Parliament at the next election. Serving as your representative has been an honour and a privilege, especially as it allowed me to serve the city in which I was born, [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2023/06/09/royston-smith-announces-his-intention-to-stand-down-at-the-next-election/">Royston Smith announces his intention to stand down at the next Election</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5157</id>
    <published>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-09T16:59:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Proposed Closure of Girlguiding Activity Centres]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1785</id>
		<updated>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</updated>
		<published>2023-06-09T13:58:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2023/06/09/proposed-closure-of-girlguiding-activity-centres/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Welcomes Government's Plans to Unleash Rural Opportunities Across Beverley and Holderness </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-welcomes-governments-plans-unleash-rural-opportunities-across-beverley-and-holderness" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Graham Stuart, Member of Parliament for Beverley and Holderness, has welcomed the Government’s strategy to unleash rural opportunities across Beverley and Holderness. 
The Government’s new rural strategy, titled Unleashing Rural Opportunity, will be split across four broad themes of housing,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-welcomes-governments-plans-unleash-rural-opportunities-across-beverley-and-holderness</id>
    <published>2023-06-08T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-08T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health Secretary Guests at Conservatives 40th Anniversary Fundraising Dinner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/health-secretary-guests-conservatives-40th-anniversary-fundraising-dinner" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Steve Barclay MP Secretary of State for Health and Social Care was the Guest Speaker at a fundraising dinner to celebrate the 40th Anniversary of Sir David Evennett’s Election to Parliament for Erith and Crayford in June 1983.
The Dinner was held on Thursday evening at the Boathouse, Danson…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/health-secretary-guests-conservatives-40th-anniversary-fundraising-dinner</id>
    <published>2023-06-08T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-08T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Welcoming Local School Funding </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/welcoming-local-school-funding" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As part of the £450 million investment to improve schools across the country including Sir William Borlase's Grammar School and the Gerrards Cross CofE school. It is great to see our very own Lent Rise School is set to undergo significant improvements, which include:
 Upgraded mechanical systems…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/welcoming-local-school-funding</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>An Update on Small Boat Crossings</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/an-update-on-small-boat-crossings/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Prime Minister Rishi Sunak visited the Kent coast to meet with members of the Border Force team at Dover. Stopping illegal migration from small boat crossings in the Channel is one of the top priorities for the government. We must bring to an end these dangerous journeys that have led to loss […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6306</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T11:16:44Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Star Column – on proposals to house asylum seekers in Stradey Park Hotel</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2023/06/llanelli-star-column-on-proposals-to-house-asylum-seekers-in-stradey-park-hotel/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;We have all been shocked by the proposal by the Conservative UK Government to use the Stradey Park Hotel as emergency accommodation for 200 asylum seekers from July. Tory Ministers are scrabbling around looking for more hotel accommodation, because of their monumental failure to process the backlog of asylum claims, so those from safe countries could be sent home.   &lt;a&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This proposal
shows the utter arrogance of Tory Ministers who have failed to properly consult
surrounding communities, the Welsh Government, Carmarthenshire County Council,
the police and many others and, following secretive talks with the hotel
owners, rejected all other alternatives and&amp;nbsp;run roughshod over local
opinion.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Wales is a
welcoming country and, here in Llanelli, we have proudly played our part down
the years in supporting those who have fled war and persecution elsewhere in
the world in pursuit of safety.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;However, this
proposal is unworkable, risks putting extra pressure on local services and
creates a situation that could prove problematic for nearby residents and for
the asylum seekers themselves.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I will continue
to vigorously oppose this plan for those reasons.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Together with
local councillors, I am actively campaigning to reverse this plan and we are
doing everything we can to stand up for the communities we represent.&amp;nbsp; We
have offered our support to the Action Committee set up by local residents and
are urging people to sign their petition, either online or in person.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Parliament, I
have already questioned the Minister for Immigration directly to emphasise the
strength of opposition against this and requested urgent meetings with him,
Clearsprings (an intermediary that manages the accommodation) and the hotel
owners themselves to keep up the pressure for this proposal to be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I know that the
County Council are also exploring all options open to them too.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a fast
moving situation and I will do my best to keep people informed of what is
happening and to let them how they can get involved to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">We have all been shocked by the proposal by the Conservative UK Government to use the Stradey Park Hotel as emergency accommodation for 200 asylum seekers from July. Tory Ministers are scrabbling around looking for more hotel accommodation, because of their monumental failure to process the backlog of asylum claims, so those from safe countries […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8868</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T10:36:35Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T10:36:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/data-reveals-long-mental-health-waiting-lists-dagenham-rainham" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;span property="schema:name"&gt;Data reveals long mental health waiting lists in Dagenham &amp; Rainham&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span rel="schema:author"&gt;&lt;span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang=""&gt;Andrew&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2023-06-07T10:19:00+00:00"&gt;Wed, 06/07/2023 - 11:19&lt;/span&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1208 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-07T10:19:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>To save lives, the Government must set new targets to tackle the ‘silent disease’</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/to-save-lives-the-government-must-set-new-targets-to-tackle-the-silent-disease/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith has been vocal on the issue of Osteoporosis, which affects half of all women and a fifth of all men over 50. It is characterised by a loss of bone density, leaving people vulnerable to breaks and fractures. Because symptoms often aren’t noticed until a serious break, osteoporosis has been called the ‘silent disease’.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Raising the issue in Parliament, Judith highlighted the shocking reality of the condition:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Many of these will be serious hip fractures, and as many people will die from these fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Questioning the Minister, Judith asked why such a serious condition is so often overlooked in healthcare:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Can the Minister explain why not even one of the 63 key performance indicators set by NHS England for Integrated Care Boards sets a target for fracture prevention?’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding, Maria Caulfield MP, Minister for Women’s Health Strategy, thanked Judith for her longstanding work on bone health. The Minister also highlighted measures the Government is undertaking to tackle Osteoporosis:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘NHS England is expanding fracture services for higher risk women who do have Osteoporosis to prevent falls in the first place.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Despite the Government’s claims to be stepping up fracture services, the limits of the current services mean that 74,000 preventable fractures will occur over the next five years, costing the NHS £665 million.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Making fracture prevention a key performance target could lead to stronger delivery of these services, preventing unnecessary pain, giving patients the level of care they deserve, and saving vital NHS resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Following the exchange, Judith said that Government support for fracture prevention was still inadequate:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘Whilst Bradford offers a trailblazing service for those with Osteoporosis, this is not always the case nationally.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;‘The argument for investing in the prevention of fractures is clear: To save money and save lives, we need a government with the sense to invest in the future of women’s health in this country.’&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;???? As many people die from hip fractures as from lung disease or diabetes &amp;#8211; but osteoporosis is often overlooked in healthcare.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; While Bradford &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/BTHFT?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@BTHFT&lt;/a&gt; has a trailblazing service, this isn&amp;#39;t the case nationally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;????This needs to improve. &lt;a href="https://t.co/c4MTw9LtoB"&gt;pic.twitter.com/c4MTw9LtoB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1666090988975321088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 6, 2023&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/put-an-end-to-postcode-lottery-for-bone-health-demands-judith-cummins-mp/" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/FLS-Report-2022-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" alt="Put an end to postcode lottery for bone health, demands Judith" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith Cummins MP on Tuesday called for the government to step up and provide 100% coverage for Fracture Liaison Services in England.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Osteoporosis is a long-term health condition characterised by weak bones prone to breaking or fracture. It affects 3.5m people across the UK: a fifth of men and half&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: fracture, people, services, judith, england, fractures, nhs, health, osteoporosis, will&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/levelling-up-bradford-left-behind-by-this-government-once-again/" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/SDP3245-0810-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" alt="Levelling Up: Bradford left behind by this Government once again" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Last night, the Government announced that Bradford had not been successful in its levelling up bid to regenerate the Odsal area of Bradford South Speaking in Parliament in response to the announcement, Judith asked: “Would the Minister agree with me that the British people have an innate sense of fair&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, government, judith, minister, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-immediate-action-on-nhs-dentistry-at-crisis-point/" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/FWWBpmGXwAEOSnB-150x150.png" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" alt="Judith demands immediate action on NHS dentistry at crisis point" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has demanded that the Government act now to halt the crisis in NHS Dentistry. Yesterday, Judith led a cross-party debate in the Commons, calling on the Government to take urgent steps to deal with chronic lack of access to NHS dentistry before it is too&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-decisive-action-on-access-to-nhs-dentistry/" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" alt="Judith calls for decisive action on access to NHS dentistry" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Yesterday in Parliament, Judith called on the new Health Secretary to take decisive action on improving access to NHS dentistry, saying the Government’s proposals do not go nearly far enough. Making her first statement in the House of Commons today, Secretary of State Thérèse Coffey MP announced health reforms. Questioning&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: nhs, judith, minister, health, bradford, government, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;Government has 'lots of words - but very little action'&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;79&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/government-has-lots-of-words-but-very-little-action/" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/SDP3245-0255-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" alt="Government has &amp;#039;lots of words - but very little action&amp;#039;" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;In her latest editorial in the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus, Judith talks about her recent work on a range of important local and national issues: I hope that people have managed to get a break during the summer. Over the summer months we saw terrible events unfold in Afghanistan. Afghanistan is&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: government, will, care, people, issue, local, bradford, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As many people die from preventable hip fractures as from lung cancer or diabetes, Judith Cummins MP has revealed. Speaking on Tuesday in the House of Commons, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins called on the Government to step up its game on bone fracture prevention and save lives. Judith has been vocal on the issue […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2741</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T14:46:46Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Asylum Backlog &amp; Small Boats on Channel 4</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/asylum-backlog-small-boats-on-channel-4/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>joshuatuck</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=3459</id>
    <published>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-06T11:47:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-93/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">On the 22<sup>nd</sup> May, International Biodiversity Day, I attended a joint meeting of the International Conservation APPG and the Climate Change APPG, organised and chaired by Barry Gardiner MP who is chair of the former. The topic for discussion was “Biomass: Bad for Biodiversity and Bad for Climate Change”, which provided a timely opportunity to talk about all the biodiversity issues surrounding biomass and BECC, especially with the UK Government’s biomass strategy expected to be published in the near future. The speakers included: Matt Williams, senior advocate Forest Protection Nature Program, NRDC; Prof Mike Norton, Environment Programme Director at the European Academies’ Science Advisory Council (EASAC); Eamonn Ives, former special advisor to UK COP President Alok Sharma, Head of Research, The Entrepreneurs; Duncan Brac, Environmental Policy analyst and advisor, former SpAd at the Department of Energy and Climate Change.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The main business in the Chamber was the return of the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-05-22/debates/DE7D768F-2624-49B7-A053-2A644CD0B2CE/Strikes(MinimumServiceLevels)Bill">Strikes (Minimum Service Level) Bill</a> from the Lords, who had made 7 amendments and we voted on Amendments 1,2,4, and 5 (because 6&amp;7 are consequential on 5) at the end of the debate. The procedure is that each Lords Amendment must be accepted, altered, replaced, or rejected by MPs. The UK Government were opposed to all Lords Amendments, and voted to reject them. Amendment 1 would insert new subsections to Clause 4 to restrict its application to only England. The Government won by 288-227 votes. Amendment 2 would require consultation and review by a committee of each House takes place before the Secretary of State makes new regulations under s234B to specify minimum service levels. The UK Government won by 286-231. Amendment 4 would insert a new section 234CA to require a copy of a work notice to be given to a person who will be subject to it, employers must prove they’ve done this, and failure to comply with the work notice is not a breach of contract of employment, so the person cannot be dismissed or suffer detriment as a result. The Government won by 286-232 votes. Amendment 5 would remove s234E (no protection if trade union fails to take reasonable steps) to ensure that trade unions do not have any responsibility or obligation to ensure their members comply with a work notice. The Government won by 287-232 votes, and therefore, Amendments 6/7 were not voted on. The Bill has gone back to the Lords for them to consider whether to insist on any of their original Amendments or offer alternatives, and send them back to the Commons, known as “ping-pong”.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was elected a vice chair at the AGM of APPG for Ukraine, and Bob Seely MP and Alex Sobel MP were re-elected co-chairs. We received a confidential briefing about the current state of the Russian invasion of Ukraine and we all agreed that NATO should vote to proscribe the Wagner Group.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the <a href="https://www.dignityindying.org.uk/">Dignity in Dying</a> reception organised by its patron Dame Prue Leith to pledge my ongoing support for the campaign for a national conversation on assisted dying which is currently happening in Scotland, Jersey, Isle of Man, Ireland and France. Prue has called on Party leaders to listen to the voices of dying people and the public at large who are overwhelmingly supportive of a change in the law.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was honoured to be re-elected chair at the AGM of the APPG for Sepsis, and I look forward to continuing to work with the <a href="https://sepsistrust.org/">UK Sepsis Trust</a> to help to improve lives of people and families who have been affected by sepsis.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As chair of the APPG for Vegetarianism and Veganism, I attended the launch of the Vegetarian for Life report “Diet and Identity in Care Settings: A Systematic Literature Review”. Anna Boardman, lead researcher for the report, presented its aims and objectives. Food is often a meaningful activity in our lives. For those who follow a religion, food can be an extension of their faith, or a means by which to exercise one’s ethical, political, or philosophical beliefs, regarding the environment, animal welfare, or animal rights. Food can play a symbolic role in the way we view ourselves, as part of families, and members of society. The changes in aging can mean choices become limited, restricted, or superseded. Mealtimes can be the highlight of residents’ days, but often the meals served do not reflect the diversity in the resident’s needs. There are examples of vegans and vegetarians being served meat. The report aimed to explore existing research and identify the gaps in knowledge. Barriers to food provision came through knowledge and education, carers made nutrition choices, rather than beliefs and preferences, residents were not good self-advocates, temporary untrained food assistants, medicines without animal products. The research focused on care homes and the older demographic, but indicates it is pertinent where people have reduced autonomy.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I am supporting Anna Firth MP who introduced the first reading of her <a href="https://www.conservativeanimalwelfarefoundation.org/legislation-policy-bills/conservative-animal-welfare-foundation-patron-anna-firth-mp-leads-first-reading-of-emilies-law/">10-Minute Rule Bill “Animal Welfare (Responsibility for Dog Attacks)”</a> in the chamber this week. The Bill will seek to criminalise fatal dog-on-dog attacks because currently dog owners are not liable when their dog fatally attacks another dog. Anna has called her Bill ‘Emilie’s Law’ after her constituent Michael’s bichon fris called Emilie was tragically killed in a dog attack in 2021.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the <a href="https://www.sra.org.uk/">Solicitors’ Regulation Authority</a> (SRA) Parliamentary Reception for Welsh MPs and Peers to meet the chair, board members, and senior management team. Speakers included: Shadow Secretary of State for Wales, Jo Stevens MP; Plaid Cymru Justice Spokesperson, Liz Saville-Roberts MP; and Secretary of State for Wales, David TC Davies MP. The SRA is the largest regulator of legal services in England and Wales, covering 90% of the legal market. In Wales, the SRA oversees 4000 solicitors, and more than 400 law firms who have their head offices based in Wales. The SRA works to set and maintain high professional standards, protect members of the public and support the rule of law and administration of justice. The SRA recently set out a commitment to develop its presence in Wales, and take full account of Wales throughout its work, in particular, taking account of Welsh Law in the new Solicitor’s Qualifying Exa, and developing opportunities for aspiring solicitors to sit this exam through the medium of Welsh. In 2021, the SRA recruited its first Head of Welsh Affairs, and opened an office in Cardiff. I hope to visit the new office in the near future.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The business in the Chamber was the Official Opposition Day, and there were two debates: Leasehold Reform (England only); Safety of School Buildings (Education is devolved to Wales and to Scotland). At the end of each debate there was a vote. The UK Government instructed their Conservative MPs not to take part in the Leasehold Reform vote, which the official opposition and other parties won 174-0. The vote on the second debate was lost by 171-296 votes.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was re-elected a vice chair at the AGM of the APPG for Flooding, my friend Rachael Maskell MP was re-elected chair. The business for the forthcoming year will include Flood Defence Grant in Aid Scheme (FDGIA), Levelling Up, Planning, Property Flood Resilience, Frequently Flooded Communities, and Riparian Ownership. At this meeting we had an update from the frequently flooded area, Shrewsbury Flood Action Group, which stated that it had flooded 18 times since 1977, but they don’t qualify for the criteria under the FDGIA, and these criteria need to be changed. The mental health of frequently flooded people is being seriously affected, as well as the costs of repairing houses and replacing contents. It’s also difficult to obtain house and contents insurance under these circumstances. Peter Grant, Funding Manager at the Environment Agency, explained that the FDGIA is based on a partnership funding model, the more a scheme costs the more grant is available, it’s a big town model, so it’s more complicated for dispersed houses that don’t reach the criteria which DEFRA sets. Some schemes cost more than the grant available. I stated that the criteria should be updated to include inflation and building oncosts, so that the grants are increased to reflect actual flooding costs.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was pleased to support the #KnowYourSkin Melanoma Awareness Month drop-in event in Parliament, organised by the charity <a href="https://melanomafocus.org/">Melanoma Focus</a>, and hosted by Sir Chris Bryant MP. We were encouraged to check our skin and contact our GP if there’s a new change in moles/lesions and protect our skin with SPF30+ sunscreen. The charity has found that 86% of melanoma skin cancer is preventable, which is increasing to over 16,000 new cases per annum, in 15-44 age group melanoma is the second most common cancer in males and the third most common in females, and it is the deadliest cancer. Several cancer charities are campaigning for high factor protective creams to be VAT exempt, which is now at 20%, because the cost-of-living crisis has caused many people and families to struggle to buy these essential items, and could be contributing to the rise in cancer in the UK.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As vice chair of the <a href="https://rjappg.co.uk/">APPG for Restorative Justice</a> (RJ), I attended our regular monthly meeting to listen to an update from our 2023 Workstreams which were set up to progress the recommendations made in our report “Restorative Practices 2021/22”, following an enquiry bringing 50 leading practitioners together to take evidence. At this meeting we heard from the Devolved Administration Group; Internal Management Group; and External Management Group. We also discussed the forthcoming “Victims and Prisoners Bill” which does not mention RJ and the possibility of APPG members tabling an RJ amendment to the Committee Stage of the Bill.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I supported the launch of the <a href="https://batonofhopeuk.org/">Baton of Hope</a> Workplace Charter. The founder John McCarthy believes that “suicides are preventable, and everyone can play a part in supporting a move towards a zero suicide society”. In the UK there are still 17 suicides a day, despite numerous initiatives. The six principles of the charter are: make suicide awareness, support, and prevention a workplace priority; use clear and consistent messaging about suicide for internal communication and induction training; implement suicide prevention, early detection, prevention and supportive services; embrace those with lived experience; promote crisis services, suicide prevention advice, counselling, training and support; and promote the charter to increase awareness. Employers have a crucial role to play in suicide prevention.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I have been a supporter of the <a href="https://www.league.org.uk/">League Against Cruel Sports</a> (LACS) for many years, and was pleased to attend their event to highlight that hunting with dogs has continued in England and Wales because of the weaknesses in the Hunting Act, and the use of “trail” hunting as a smokescreen for illegal hunting. There are nine exemptions and a loophole that allows hunts to claim that chasing and killing an animal was accidental, so the law fails to protect animals from cruelty. During the 2022-23 hunting season, the LACS compiled 1367 incidents of fox hunts wreaking havoc and involved or suspected of illegal hunting, drawn from the LACS Crimewatch service and hunt monitors. 841 cases of hunt havoc such as railway trespass, chasing pets, and 526 reports of illegal hunting, including 400 cases of a hunt been seen chasing a fox, involving 122 hunts, across 50 counties in the UK. The UK Government has refused to strengthen the law, but police cannot enforce it because it is not fit for purpose. The UK Government allows hunting on its Ministry of Defence land, granting 22 licences for “trail” hunting in 2022. In January 2023, the Scottish Government passed Hunting with Dogs (Scotland) Act to close loopholes in the law exploited by Scottish hunts, and bans “trail” hunting. Calculus Polling in 2022 found 78% of British voters support strengthening the hunting ban, 71% in rural constituencies, of which 87% are Labour voters, 81% Liberal Democrat voters, 71% Conservative voters. The LACS is calling for the Hunting Act to be strengthened by removing exemptions, banning “trail” hunting, and introducing custodial sentences.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined representatives from the <a href="https://www.youthsporttrust.org/">Youth Sport Trust</a> to support National Schools Sports Week, which will take place from 19-25th June. National Schools Sports Week aims to address the fact that less than half (47%) of all young people across the UK are active for at least 60 minutes of moderate exercise a day as recommended by the Chief Medical Officers. The campaign will see activities take place across the UK to “play for fun-play for 60” which is so important when children’s wellbeing is in decline, obesity and type 2 diabetes cases are rising. The schools in Neath that have already signed up to support this very worthwhile initiative are Cwmnedd Primary and Llangatwg Community School, but I am proud to support this fantastic campaign that helps young people experience the benefit of PE, Sports, and play, and I’m looking forward to working with schools and parents in my Neath constituency to take part and reach their full potential. As a former Welsh Squash International and former Development Officer and National Coach for Squash Wales I realise the importance of taking part in sport to improve physical and mental wellbeing.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The APPG for Sport held a Community and Social Sport event to promote the <a href="https://www.sportfordevelopmentcoalition.org/sites/default/files/file/Sport%20for%20Development%20Coalition%20-%20%23OpenGoal%20Annual%20Report%202022-23.pdf">Annual Report for the Sport for Development Coalition 2022-23 #OpenGoal</a>. The room was packed full of sport and community representatives, including some from Wales. The chair of the Coalition Andy Reed OBE, appointed in 2020, introduced the report, emphasising that sport and physical activity have a big part to play in building a fairer, more equitable, and sustainable future, and there is a generational crisis involving substantial health, economic, and societal impacts. The report aims to demonstrate the value of targeted sport-based interventions being delivered within communities in the greatest need of levelling up. As a former Welsh Squash International and former Squash Wales National coach, I pledged my support to the very commendable aims of the Coalition to use sport to make a positive difference to people’s lives.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The main business in the Chamber on the penultimate day before recess was the Lords sending their Amendments back to the Commons after the MPs had previously disagreed with their Amendments to the <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/commons/2023-05-24/debates/7B12F8E3-6C97-4C3B-8FD8-716107DF4252/RetainedEULaw(RevocationAndReform)Bill">Retained EU Law (Revocation and Reform) Bill</a> known as “ping-pong”. We voted on 4 Amendments that the Lords sent back and the UK Government won all the votes again, after instructing Conservative MPs to disagree. Lords Amendment 1 was about Joint Committee scrutiny of the sunset schedule, and the UK Government won by 298-216 votes. Lords Amendment 6 to which the Commons previously disagreed because the retention of anything which is retained by EU law by virtue of section 4 of the EU (Withdrawal) Act 2018 would be inconsistent with the principle of supremacy of EU law, was defeated again by 296-215 votes. Lords Amendment 15 to which the Commons previously disagreed because the Commons do not consider this amendment necessary in order to maintain environmental protection or food standards was defeated again by 294-217 votes. And Lords Amendment 42 to which the Commons previously disagreed because the Commons consider the scrutiny procedure imposed by the Lords Amendment to be inappropriate was defeated again by 294-217 votes. The Bill has been “ping-ponged” to the Lords again for their consideration after recess on Tuesday 6th June.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">Back in Neath, at the end of my week, I called into <a href="https://twitter.com/StDavidsNeath?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor">St David’s Church</a> to support the volunteers at the Saturday morning shop, and watched our highly skilled flower arranger Rosemary preparing the church for up and coming services. I also called into St Thomas’s Church to see the fantastic exhibition of weddings past and present organised by Neath Mothers’ Union (NMU). Many members of NMU and church had lent their wedding gowns, memorabilia, photographs/albums, and the Parish Marriage Records were on display.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On the 22nd May, International Biodiversity Day, I attended a joint meeting of the International Conservation APPG and the Climate Change APPG, organised and chaired by Barry Gardiner MP who is chair of the former. The topic for discussion was “Biomass: Bad for Biodiversity and Bad for Climate Change”, which provided a timely opportunity to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2743</id>
    <published>2023-06-05T13:48:30Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-05T13:48:30Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My statement on the continued closure of the High Wycombe driving test centre</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2023/06/my-statement-on-the-continued-closure-of-the-high-wycombe-driving-test-centre/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I understand the frustration the continued closure of the driving test centre is causing. I share that frustration. Constituents are routinely writing to me requesting an update on its planned reopening, illustrating the reasons I believe it is essential we have a functional driving test centre in High Wycombe. As many of my constituents know, we have, of course, been here before. Twice now, I have worked with key stakeholders in our area to save the driving test centre in […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Shearer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18663</id>
    <published>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-02T11:30:18Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#DrivingTestCentre"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Driving Test Centre"/>
    <category term="High Wycombe"/>
    <category term="Working4Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>London Road Level Crossing Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Barrier down time at the London Road level crossing has long been a cause of concern in Bicester. This is an issue which I have worked on since I was first elected, chairing meetings with previous administrations at the District and County Council, and meeting multiple Rail Ministers to discuss it…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/london-road-level-crossing-update</id>
    <published>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/05/26/snp-call-for-uk-government-to-scrap-prohibitive-visa-requirements-to-support-fishing-industry/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10851</id>
		<updated>2023-05-26T13:57:55Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-26T13:42:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Earlier this week, the UK Government announced that several fishing industry roles were to be added to the UK&#8217;s occupation shortage list. The Scottish fishing sector has been hugely struggling to employ enough deckhands and fishing related staff since the UK left the European Union. The combination of labour shortages, red-tape with the EU and ... <a title="SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2023/05/26/snp-call-for-uk-government-to-scrap-prohibitive-visa-requirements-to-support-fishing-industry/" aria-label="More on SNP call for UK Government to scrap prohibitive visa requirements to support fishing industry">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Westminster_Hall_25_05_23_14_41_07-1-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="43959823" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>QUEEN ELIZABETH HOSPITAL TO BE REBUILT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/queen-elizabeth-hospital-be-rebuilt" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> FUNDING SECURED FOR QEH REBUILD
 The Health Secretary has announced the full rebuild of Queen Elizabeth Hospital in Kings Lynn by 2030. This will hugely improve patient care, quality and outcomes as well as support the wider healthcare sector in Norfolk and is additional to the total rebuild of…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/queen-elizabeth-hospital-be-rebuilt</id>
    <published>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-05-25T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The new Executive</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2023/05/22/the-new-executive/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor David Mellen will remain as Leader of the council, continuing the hard work of continuing the hard work of himself, Cllr Adele Williams, Cllr Sally Longford and all previous and current executive and backbench members. He is responsible for continuing devolution, strategic regeneration, development and work on the city’s ambitious plan to be carbon neutral by 2028, as well as promoting the vision of the council and supporting all of his Portfolio Holders in their work. There is much work to be done over the next term and the new executive will be key in achieving the goals Nottingham Labour want for the city.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Audra Wynter has been confirmed as the new Deputy Leader and she will have responsibility for the finance and HR portfolios. With a background in finance work, Councillor Wynter will ensure the council remains on track in delivering a balanced budget and sticking to the Medium-Term Financial Plan, while delivering high-quality services for residents.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-small-font-size"&gt;Councillor Corall Jenkins will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Energy, Environment and Waste Services and Parks. She will have responsibility for key services such as bin collection and disposal, keeping our city’s streets clean and maintaining all of our wonderful parks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Cheryl Barnard will remain as Portfolio Holder for Children, Young People and Education. She will continue to be responsible for leading our children’s services, working with Ofsted to improve it where necessary, ensuring children’s safeguarding and working with academy trusts across the city on schools, ensuring attendance and working to reduce exclusions, so that all children get the best start in life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Steve Battlemuch will be taking up the reins as Portfolio Holder for Skills, Growth, Economic Development and Property. He will lead on skills and employment, ensuring that the workforce in the city is prepared for any changes in the way we work, and that the people of this city have the right opportunities. He will also oversee the management of the city centre, attracting investment and helping to ensure that Nottingham is promoted nationally and internationally to business and tourism.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Jay Hayes has been confirmed as the new Portfolio Holder for Housing. He will lead on managing the council housing service, student housing, private rented properties and areas such as selective licensing and homelessness. Housing is incredibly important, all those who live in the city deserve to have a property that is safe, secure and that can be called home, whether they rent in the private sector or have social housing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Sajid Mohammed will lead as Portfolio Holder for Neighbourhoods, Safety and Inclusion. This covers areas such as community protection, domestic violence work, licensing, taxi strategy and more. It is so important that Nottingham is a safe place to work and live in. Councillor Mohammed with many years of experience of community work and as director of Himmah will bring the required expertise to lead in these vital areas, and he will also lead on refugee and asylum seeker work, to ensure that Nottingham is a welcoming city for all, and that those vulnerable refugees and asylum seekers can integrate and make new lives in Nottingham.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Pavlos Kotsonis will continue as Portfolio Holder for Leisure and Culture. He will ensure that we continue to offer an outstanding events programme. He will also oversee the reopening and flourishing of the Castle, the continued running of Wollaton Hall and Newstead Abbey as well as leisure centres, markets, libraries and community centres across the city. Access to cultural events and key things like libraries and leisure centres is so important for allowing the people of the city to thrive and create.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Councillor Linda Woodings will also remain as Portfolio Holder for Adult Social Care and Health. She will continue to work on Public Health and Wellbeing, tackling health inequalities and working to reduce smoking prevalence, working on mental health and generally improving the health of residents in the city. She will also lead on independent living. All of these will help to improve the quality and length of life for residents in the city for years to come.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Finally, Councillor Angela Kandola will be taking over as Portfolio Holder for Highways, Transport and Planning. She will oversee public transport such as buses and the tram. She will also lead on greener transport such as cycling and cycling links in the city, ensure highways are correctly managed and repaired as well as the Workplace Parking Levy to help increase public transport usage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is just a short summary of the responsibilities that the Executive will have for the next year. They will bring both their expertise and new views to help ensure that there is strong and effective political leadership at the council. This will continue both our journey with the Improvement and Assurance Board but also enable us to bring in the pledges that we made to the residents of the city in our manifesto in the May local elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nottingham Labour confirmed today (22 May) at Full Council the political and civic leadership of the city, after securing an increased majority at the local elections. A total of 51 out of 55 councillors at Nottingham City Council, are now Labour. This gives us a strong mandate to implement the manifesto over the next four years and continue to fight for and improve the lives of Nottingham residents.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=3074</id>
    <published>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-22T15:39:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Arboretum"/>
    <category term="Aspley"/>
    <category term="Basford"/>
    <category term="Berridge"/>
    <category term="Bestwood"/>
    <category term="Bilborough"/>
    <category term="Bulwell"/>
    <category term="Bulwell Forest"/>
    <category term="Castle"/>
    <category term="Dales"/>
    <category term="election"/>
    <category term="Housing"/>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
    <category term="government"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree was a beneficiary of the programme which is backed by £1.8 billion of government funding over this financial year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps was thrilled to see that Peartree had benefited from this funding and looks forward to seeing their transformation. In the past, Mr Shapps helped free up playground space at Peartree by getting a disused Victorian loo block removed which has helped generations of pupils enjoy a little more&amp;nbsp;open&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps also met with student members of the school council who asked him an array of questions about his career, local issues and his life as the constituency&amp;#8217;s parliament member. The members of the school council are aged between five and eleven and are elected by their classmates to give them a voice in Peartree School’s vision, projects and events.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps commented on his visit and on his time with members of the school council:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to catch up with staff and visit pupils at Peartree School last week. The children are clearly enjoying their time there very much, and it was really helpful to get an insight from Miss Hardy and her team as to how everyone’s getting on. Plus, I enjoyed a brilliant sit-down with the School Council &amp;#8211; they really put me through my paces with their questions.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Megan Hardy, the Head of School at Peartree, thanked Mr Shapps for visiting and meeting with the staff and students:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It was a pleasure to show Mr Shapps around Peartree and to talk to him about our plans for the school’s transformation over the coming years.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She continued:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The children were really excited to meet their MP and they came up with plenty of interesting questions to ask him. They were very inspired by his visit, so we may even have a future prime minister among us!”&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mr Shapps thanks Peartree for having him visit and wishes the staff and students all the best for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/"&gt;Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com"&gt;The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Grant Shapps, the local MP for Welwyn Hatfield, visited Peartree Primary School in his constituency and met with staff and students. During his visit, Mr Shapps caught up with the staff of Peartree and learnt all about their plans for transformation over the next few years. Thanks to the Conservative Government’s School Rebuilding programme, Peartree […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com/peartree-primary-school-student-council-members-meet-with-local-mp/">Peartree Primary School Student Council Members Meet with Local MP</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.shapps.com">The Rt Hon Grant Shapps MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>William Yarwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.shapps.com/?p=48284</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T14:05:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Welwyn Hatfield"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Catherine McKinnell, Member of Parliament for Newcastle North, has shown her support for people living with diabetes in Parliament alongside Diabetes UK.  Diabetes UK’s new “Diabetes Is Serious” campaign, highlights the challenges facing the five million people living with diabetes in the UK. The report includes shocking new figures showing that there were 7,000 excess deaths connected … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-backs-calls-for-improved-diabetes-care/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE BACKS CALLS FOR IMPROVED DIABETES CARE</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7946</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T10:26:48Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Health and Social Care"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/2023/05/17/april-newsletter-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>liamtaggart</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=333</id>
    <published>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-17T09:51:02Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Newsletters"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3374</id>
		<updated>2023-05-16T11:22:21Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-16T11:22:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160; Dear Constituent, Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[
<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my latest email newsletter to provide you with some updates on what&#8217;s been happening both in Parliament and around Amber Valley. Below you&#8217;ll find an update on some of the things that have been progressing through the Houses in London as well as some of the local visits I&#8217;ve been on.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Illegal migration bill update:</u></strong></p>



<p>The main piece of legislation that has been going through the House of Commons in the last few weeks is the Illegal Migration Bill. I’ve heard from a number of constituents with a diverse range of views on this topic. On the 26<sup>th</sup> of April the bill completed its remaining stages in the Commons and is now moving through the House of Lords, before it will return to the Commons for a final review.</p>



<p>This Bill is set to enhance the powers of the Government to tackle illegal migration, including the ability to remove illegal migrants from the UK to safe countries, new ways to determine ages of migrants without formal identification, additional protections for child migrants, and tougher sentences for those found guilty of people smuggling. The Bill was also amended during its remaining stages to include the Government’s commitment to review the safe and legal routes that are available.</p>



<p>It is clear that we need an asylum system that does work for those families truly in need, but is also tough on those who are trying to exploit the process to gain entry to the UK and on human traffickers who are exploiting vulnerable people and worsening the crisis. The new bill tackles the latter problems, while leaving open safe and legal routes for those in need.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sewage &amp; storm overflows update:</u></strong></p>



<p>Another key development in Parliament was new plans to further increase water quality targets and reduce sewage being released into our waterways.</p>



<p>The Government has announced its plan to enshrine the Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published last August, into law through the Environment Act. This will make its target to reduce storm overflows legally binding. The Government’s Storm Overflows Discharge Reduction Plan, published in August 2022, set out stringent targets to protect people and the environment and is backed up by up to £56 billion capital investment, which is the largest infrastructure programme in water company history.</p>



<p>Further, the Government is now consulting on proposals for unlimited fines to be imposed on water companies that break the rules. More than £142 million has already been levied in fines since 2015 and I am aware that money from fines and penalties will now be channelled back into the environment.</p>



<p><strong><u>East Midlands APPG:</u></strong></p>



<p>Outside the Chamber, the focus seemed to be local issues over the last few weeks, and we had another meeting of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on the East Midlands. This group brings together MPs from across the Chamber to discuss issues that are especially important to our region.</p>



<p>The most recent meeting was on the future of Infrastructure in the East Midlands. We heard from the East Midlands Chamber of Commerce and East Midlands Councils on infrastructure in our area and the need for infrastructure investment to fulfil our environmental commitments, to make it easier for people living here to travel and get to work, and to encourage businesses to move here.</p>



<p>Moving forward, we will continue to push for our region to receive funding in the future, by collecting evidence on the wider benefits of infrastructure projects to the local economy and local businesses and use this in future proposals for funding.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ferrero sustainable palm oil event:</u></strong></p>



<p>I was also able to welcome Ferrero, who own the Thornton’s factory in Somercotes, to Parliament. They hosted an event alongside Chester Zoo and the Orangutan Land Trust on Sustainable Palm Oil, where they discussed the damage palm oil farming has inflicted on jungles and local habitats of orangutans around the world. While many food producers have moved away from palm oil for these reasons, the same problems of deforestation and habitat destruction continue to persist regardless of the plant used.</p>



<p>Because of this, Ferrero highlighted the use of certified sustainable palm-oil to that avoids these poor practices by working with local wildlife experts, stopping further deforestation for farming land, and reducing the impact on the environment.</p>



<p>It was great to hear from a business that operates locally in our area that is tackling global issues and to talk to the charitable organisations that were supporting these efforts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="667" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3376" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1.jpeg 1000w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1-768x512.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Amber Valley Borough Council elections 4th May 2023 &amp; Parish/Town Council elections:</u></strong></p>



<p>On the 4th May 2023, elections were held for Amber Valley Borough Council. For the first time in a long time, elections were held for all 42 councillors over 18 wards (rather than the previous recent system of electing a third of councillors each year).</p>



<p>As a result of the election, the Labour Group took control of the Council and have 26 councillors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congratulations to all who were elected and I look forward to working with the new Borough Council where needed and holding them to account where necessary too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can find your borough councillor <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All the parish and town councils in Amber Valley were also up for election. You can find the results of these <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/councillors-and-elections/parish-and-town-councils/">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Access to Cash &#8211; Nationwide Heanor:</u></strong></p>



<p>I know for many constituents a key concern has been the closures of bank branches in our area.</p>



<p>Although banking is increasingly moving online, in-person branches are still relied upon by many in our communities and are staples in our high streets. People need access to bank branches so that they can speak to someone in person about their accounts and finances.</p>



<p>I was able to visit Nationwide in Heanor to discuss this issue and was reassured that they understood the important role they play on our high streets and intend to stay open for the foreseeable future.</p>



<p>I was also able to discuss the work they are doing to help vulnerable people more broadly, including their cost-of-living helpline, fraud prevention and work to teach useful financial skills to young people.</p>



<p>I’ll continue to support maintaining access to bank branches and cash in our communities and town centres.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="636" height="791" src="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-3375" srcset="https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.jpeg 636w, https://nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-241x300.jpeg 241w" sizes="(max-width: 636px) 100vw, 636px" /></figure>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Nieper Foundation visit:</u></strong></p>



<p>In Alfreton I joined Robert Halfon, the Minister for Skills, Apprenticeships and Higher Education, in a visit related to the Christopher Nieper Education Trust. The Trust was set up to allow David Nieper Ltd to invest in local education and help young people into long-term, rewarding employment.</p>



<p>We visited David Nieper Ltd and met with Dr Hobbs, the Headteacher of David Nieper Academy, others who are supporting the work of the Trust and met with a student to do an interview for the Spirit of Alfreton. &nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684233937.JPG" alt=""/></figure>



<p><strong><u>Local primary school visits:</u></strong></p>



<p>I have also able to visit both Mundy Junior School and Heage Primary School to speak to teachers and school leaders about funding.</p>



<p>With schools also being hit with high energy bills, there was concern that planned increases to teacher’s salaries and additional provisions for students would not be fully funded if prices for heating stay high. I was able to talk to teachers about the worry this is causing.</p>



<p>It is only right that any increases to staff pay are properly covered by increased investment into schools and it is important that the Government has contingency plans and funding in place to reassure schools that they will be supported should energy bills stay high.</p>



<p><strong><u>Windows for Ukraine:</u></strong></p>



<p>I also took part in a visit to CPR Manufacturing in Alfreton, who are supporting a project called Windows for Ukraine. Cromwell Polythene is manufacturing polyethylene film used to make effective temporary windows as part of a project called Insulate Ukraine. The company have donated some of the film being used, which is an alternative to glass and insulates homes better than double-glazing. The local business usually manufactures bin liner products.</p>



<p><strong><u>Collis engineering visit &amp; 5G masts:</u></strong></p>



<p>To look at their new 5G masts I&#8217;ve also been to see Collis Engineering Ltd. They&#8217;re manufacturing a new mast and tower system to support the rollout of 5G and which has a high headload capacity, meaning several operators can share the same structure and system. Collis are an important local employer and it was good to learn more about this innovation that is being manufactured right here in the heart of Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that access to telephone and broadband signal remains an issue for many residents, so hopefully this innovation will help with that, and I&#8217;ll continue to pursue solutions for areas where there are concerns or problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://cloudy.email/app/uploads/1684234142.jpg" alt=""/></figure>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading">Street Watch:</h1>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading"><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-may-newsletter-2/">Nigel&#8217;s May Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>CH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Time To Put Children First]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6927</id>
		<updated>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</updated>
		<published>2023-05-04T10:36:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Education"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="birmingham"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="education"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership. It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Time To Put Children First</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img data-attachment-id="6590" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-7/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6590" width="870" height="179" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2-1.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I visited Kings Heath Boys School last week which has just had a fine Ofsted report reflecting real progress achieved under four years of the current Head’s leadership.</p>



<p>It’s only by providing good schools that we can equip our children and grandchildren for the future. There’s always been a link between poor areas and school success. Labour understands this. In the 60s and 70s the Wilson government created Educational Priority Areas and after 18 years of Tory rule, the last Labour government introduced Education Action Zones to once again boost the chances of children from poorer backgrounds.</p>



<p>It’s by working with parents and carers and putting schools at the centre of communities that we build the solid foundations from which children succeed. Over 13 years of Tory rule, we’ve seen teachers abused and experts ridiculed and an attempt to return schools to teaching models experienced by too many government ministers, in private schools, over the past 50 years. It’s not structures like free schools or academisation or gimmicks about a smattering of Latin that matter. We need support for parents and programmes to attract the best teachers to disadvantaged areas.</p>



<p>Almost every successful person has a story about the teacher who influenced their direction and put them on a path to success. We need to rediscover an ambition and love for education.</p>



<p>At Kings Heath Boys they’re not planning to rest on their laurels but open up choice and opportunity by changing to an intake of boys and girls. We’re blessed with several outstanding schools in south Birmingham, they do a remarkable job despite squeezed budgets, teacher retention problems and children’s mental health issues. These are all things the government should be addressing.</p>



<p>I hope the local community will get behind plans for Kings Heath Boys which will give more children a chance to attend a school that’s best for them. I’m hungry for a Labour government that treats teachers with the respect they deserve and puts our children first.</p>



<p>It’s time to focus on a system where the talents of every child can be nurtured and where their achievements are the priority.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2023/05/04/time-to-put-children-first/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bob Stewart welcomes 3,468 extra police officers for Met Police</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Member of Parliament for Beckenham, Bob Stewart, has welcomed the announcement that 3,468 extra police officers have been recruited for the Metropolitan Police since September 2019, bringing the total number of officers up to 35,411.
 
The recruitment drive is part of the Government’s Beating Crime…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/bob-stewart-welcomes-3468-extra-police-officers-met-police</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Social Security Health Assessments System <span style="color:#06396a;">Has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>The cross party Work and Pensions Select Committee responsible for scrutinising the Department for Work and Pensions’ (DWP) policies, has published a damning report on the Government’s health assessments system which is used to screen whether sick and disabled people should have access to vital social security payments.</p>
<p>These payments provide financial support to a working age person who is unable to work because of their health condition or disability; the assessment for this is the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) and is for either Employment Support Allowance or Universal Credit Limited Capability to Work. In addition there is also the Personal Independence Payment (PIP) assessment process to access support to cover the extra costs disabled people face because of their disability which are estimated at over £580 a month on average; this is for the Personal Independence Payment.</p>
<p>The report exposed the detrimental impact of the assessment process itself on the health and well being of claimants.</p>
<p>Giving evidence to the Committee, Professor Ben Barr, from the University of Liverpool, was asked about research he carried out in 2015 which looked at the impacts of the WCA as claimants were reassessed to move onto Employment Support Allowance. His analysis estimated that across England, the WCA had caused an additional 600 suicides, 300,000 additional cases of mental health problems and a large rise in the prescribing of antidepressants over a nine-year period.</p>
<p>“We looked at whether it could be explained by other factors or other economic trends, but there was quite a unique pattern in the increase in mental health problems, and the most likely explanation was that it was due to the reassessment process”, he told the committee. He said it is difficult to assess improvements since this study as “there are no systems in place” to monitor the impact of the health assessments and the potential adverse outcomes.</p>
<p>A survey by the University of Kent last year found half of claimants who have been through the WCA process said it made their mental health worse. Dr Ben Baumberg Geiger, who led the research, told the committee: “It is not sufficient to say that this is a historical problem and that everything is fine now. If there was more transparency, it would be easier to know a bit more about it, but the evidence suggests that there are still major problems with the WCA that could lead to an increased risk of poor mental health.”</p>
<p>Debbie Abrahams the Member of Parliament for Oldham East and Saddleworth and a Member of the Work and Pensions Select Committee said:</p>
<p><em>“The evidence is clear – the current system is not fit for purpose. The DWP’s own figures show that <strong><u>274 people a month</u></strong> <strong><u>die 6 months after being found fit for work </u></strong>and <strong><u>60 people a month die 3 months after having PIP refused. </u></strong>These are poorly people not the shirkers and scroungers that some Conservatives refer to when discussing social security claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“We heard evidence during the inquiry that when people were being reassessed between 2010 and 2013, there were 600 additional suicides. In 2020, National Audit Office has said that the claimant deaths that the DWP had investigated were the tip of the iceberg. The current approach is contributing, directly and indirectly, to the physical and mental health harm of claimants. </em></p>
<p><em>“Last year the Equality Watchdog, The Equality and Human Rights Commission, issued a Section 23 order against the Department of Work and Pensions over their discriminatory treatment of disabled claimants.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Government itself has effectively acknowledged a different approach is needed when they announced that they would abolition the Work Capability Assessments, something I have been calling for years, but the detail of the future process is too opaque and doesn’t provide reassurance. Given it will take place several years to replace, what happens until then?</em></p>
<p><em>“I remain deeply concerned about these health assessments but also about the punitive nature of the sanctions regime, introduced in 2012 and, once again, on the rise. </em></p>
<p><em>“I believe it is these social security policies, as well as the inadequacy of the social security support especially for working age people, and the dehumanising culture that claimants too often experience that collectively contribute to the adverse health effects is the It is so detrimental to vulnerable people especially, but to all people as well.</em></p>
<p><em>“Given the failure of the Government to make many of the changes recommended in our predecessor Committee in 2018, I hold little hope in them taking on board the improvements set out in the report.”</em></p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/social-security-health-assessments-system-has-contributed-to-the-deaths-of-claimants/">Social Security Health Assessments System has Contributed to the Deaths of Claimants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7098</id>
    <published>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-27T11:53:40Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Health"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Work &amp; Pensions"/>
    <category term="Department for Work and Pensions"/>
    <category term="Health Assessment"/>
    <category term="Social Security"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>St Helens Mobile Pantry</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2023/04/18/st-helens-mobile-pantry/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7624</id>
    <published>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-18T13:38:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP welcomes school debaters to Downing Street</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2023/03/29/matt-warman-mp-welcomes-school-debaters-to-downing-street/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament before their visit to Number Ten. The day was rounded off by a Q&amp;amp;A session with Matt and the competition judges as well as guests from Parliament including House of Commons Library Director of Research Edward Wood. The panel passed on their careers advice as well as explaining some of the opportunities available in politics besides being an MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4189 aligncenter" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Downing-Street-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking after the visit &lt;strong&gt;Matt Warman MP commented&lt;/strong&gt; ‘I was keen to establish a debating competition to encourage students to think deeply about some of the issues facing our society and, crucially, to equip them with the skills to consider both sides of a complex argument. Today’s visit to the home of modern democracy was an excellent opportunity to see those skills in action with students having the chance to observe opposition MPs challenging Ministers at the despatch box. I look forward to next year’s programme and on a broader note, am always happy to welcome schools in my constituency to Parliament.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chair of Governors at Boston High School Lisa Smith&lt;/strong&gt; who accompanied the visit said ‘This was a wonderful opportunity for our students to see democracy in action – and to be inspired by the opportunities for careers in parliament. We are grateful to Matt for arranging the debate competition and the visit and look forward to defending our winner’s trophy next year!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4187 alignnone" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA-768x576.png 768w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/QA.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-4188 alignright" srcset="https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized-300x225.png 300w, https://mattwarman.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/Westminster-Hall-resized.png 591w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The famous black door of Number Ten Downing Street was the backdrop this week for a visit from Boston and Skegness sixth formers. The students, who in November had participated in the inaugural William Waynflete debate competition organised by Matt Warman MP, enjoyed a tour of the Houses of Parliament […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4186</id>
    <published>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-29T14:17:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have been positive, while others have been more negative. In this blog post, we’ll explore some of the key impacts of distance learning in education. We’ll also look at how this new model is likely to evolve in the future.</p>



<h2><strong>Define distance learning and its purpose in education</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning is a form of education that takes place between an instructor and students who are not interacting in the same physical location. Distance learning courses typically take place online, where students can access course materials and engage in <a href="https://www.cde.ca.gov/ci/cr/dl/lessonsfrfld.asp">remote lessons</a> with their instructors from the comfort of their own homes. The primary purpose of distance learning is convenience: it gives students the opportunity to pursue studies at any time, from virtually anywhere. Distance learning also allows students to fit an education into otherwise busy lives. Students who may be unable to enroll in <a href="https://serc.carleton.edu/sp/cause/campusbased/what.html">campus-based schooling</a> due to geographic obstacles, health issues or obligations such as employment or family care duties all benefit from being able to receive instruction, interact with peers and complete coursework remotely with distance learning courses.</p>



<h2><strong>Describe how distance learning has changed over the years</strong></h2>



<p>Over the years, distance learning has evolved from a simple pen pal type of correspondence to a complex online system. Instead of having to wait weeks for someone to return a single letter, now students can communicate almost instantly with teachers and fellow classmates as well as access curricula and educational resources provided by their school. This shift in technology allows instructors to deliver lessons through <a href="https://drexel.edu/soe/resources/teacher-resources/virtual-classroom/">virtual classrooms</a>, use interactive technological tools such as quizzes and videos to engage their students, and offer new ways for pupils to demonstrate their mastery of material. Despite its advantages, the growth of distance learning still faces challenges such as lack of face-to-face interaction between teachers and students, high levels of student motivation required to succeed in an online course, security issues associated with personal data sharing over the internet, and lower access by underserved communities due to cost or a lack of available technology resources. The field of distance learning is ever growing though, offering increased opportunities for those seeking alternative ways to receive their education</p>



<h2><strong>Discuss the advantages and disadvantages of distance learning</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning has come a long way since its inception and can offer an excellent alternative to standard coursework writing. In many ways, it is more convenient than traditional studying, as students are able to fit coursework into their daily lives without having to take time off for commuting or attending lectures. Furthermore, distance learning can be particularly useful for learners who have trouble fitting into the traditional classroom setting or who struggle with certain course topics due to lack of face-to-face instruction. However, distance learning also has some drawbacks; most courses require students to have significant levels of <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brentgleeson/2020/08/25/8-powerful-ways-to-cultivate-extreme-self-discipline/">self-discipline</a> in order to stay motivated while juggling <a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/12/14/best-coursework-writing-service-top-5-online-services-for-students/">their coursework</a> with other commitments, and often times course instructors may not be easily accessible if struggles arise during coursework writing. Nonetheless, with proper motivation and preparation distance learning can be great tool for those seeking educational options.</p>



<h2><strong>Offer examples of successful distance learning programs</strong></h2>



<p>Distance learning programs have become increasingly popular in recent years as educators and learners alike explore new ways to bridge the gap between traditional education and modern technology. Successful distance learning programs can be seen across many different sectors, whether for academic purposes or for professional development. For example, online universities like Open University offer degrees and courses in a variety of different disciplines, allowing learners to complete their degree in an unprecedented amount of time compared to traditional brick-and-mortar universities. Professional organizations like Toastmasters utilize video conferencing tools to offer staff seminars and other training sessions without having to send staff members out of town. These distance learning solutions save organizations time and money while still managing to deliver quality services and instruction.</p>



<h2><strong>Summarize the impact of distance learning in education overall</strong></h2>



<p>The introduction of distance learning in education has profoundly impacted education overall. Through the use of digital tools, teachers have been able to reach more students and expand their classroom <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/geographical-boundary">across geographical boundaries</a>. Additionally, it has increased access to educational materials as well as leveled out the playing field among different socioeconomic backgrounds. Distance learning has allowed schools to create innovative ways of teaching and engaging with students. It not only gives teachers the ability to interact directly with students but also provides ways for students to collaborate and connect with their peers from around the world. All in all, distance learning has shown itself to be a powerful tool that can help students receive a better education no matter where they are located or their financial situation.</p>



<p>Though it has been around in some form since the 19th century, distance learning has seen a surge in popularity in recent years. This is largely due to advances in technology that have made online education more accessible and affordable than ever before. While there are many advantages to distance learning, such as increased flexibility and the ability to learn at your own pace, there are also some disadvantages to consider. With so many options available, it can be difficult to choose the right program for you. But with careful research and planning, you can find an online education option that meets your needs and helps you achieve your educational goals. Are you considering pursuing a degree through distance learning? What are some of the factors you’re taking into consideration?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The current COVID-19 pandemic has forced many schools and educational institutions to move to a distance learning model. This has had a significant impact on the way education is delivered. Some of the impacts have […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/what-is-the-impact-of-distance-learning-in-education/">What is the Impact of Distance Learning in Education</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=230</id>
    <published>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-03T22:05:15Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, https://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://www.dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="//blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgPGr6SMD45ood6qhiuu4blT62kHviIBP6ckpE65JIBe6BV4lwfD_ljqSW6Yfh3INMQ01Hq2IglXwA8RYJBvaG3TNP9bm646Qr4SeQjTadGOm9f0ATEqV7u3pFvBanBHg/s220/Labour+4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=ROJpTLyg" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-648ad8f919e8e" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-648ad8f919e8e').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"648ad8f919e8e","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-648ad8f919e8e" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-648ad8f919e8e" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="648ad8f919e8e" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_648ad8f919e8e" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_648ad8f919e8e" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_648ad8f919e8e" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_648ad8f919e8e" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_648ad8f919e8e" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_648ad8f919e8e" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_648ad8f919e8e_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-648ad8f919e8e script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxci1IoY1cJ7BtrpNFDjOb7Iq2CtOYCeBrBamWU39AVUbtFqsZj0CIZJuFGasBlUtFo1R3ljJpwwFKdsyyceg' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="2 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>2</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
