<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@dave.org.uk</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2021-06-18T02:40:29Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="http://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>http://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
    <title>Local  MP is calling for all Basingstoke residents to share Prostate Cancer UK thirty-second risk checker </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-calling-all-basingstoke-residents-share-prostate-cancer-uk-thirty-second-risk-checker" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Local  MP is calling for all Basingstoke residents to share Prostate Cancer UK thirty-second risk checker 
Over 49,000 men in England were diagnosed with prostate cancer in 2018, making it the most commonly diagnosed cancer. However, the pandemic has made it more difficult for men to approach their…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/local-mp-calling-all-basingstoke-residents-share-prostate-cancer-uk-thirty-second-risk-checker</id>
    <published>2021-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-18T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham welcomes £1 million fund to boost STEM skills in Beverley &amp; Holderness primary schools</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/2021/06/graham-welcomes-1-million-fund-to-boost-stem-skills-in-beverley-holderness-primary-schools/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div style="width: 1920px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-11484-1" width="1920" height="1080" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/B-roll-Dogger-Bank-see-time-code-document-for-explanations_Trim.mp4?_=1"/><a href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/B-roll-Dogger-Bank-see-time-code-document-for-explanations_Trim.mp4">https://www.grahamstuart.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/B-roll-Dogger-Bank-see-time-code-document-for-explanations_Trim.mp4</a></video></div>
<p>Young people across Beverley and Holderness will benefit from a share of a £1 million investment from Dogger Bank Wind Farm to prepare them for working life in a net-zero world, one of the largest commitments to skills ever made by the offshore wind sector.</p>
<p>In a programme being developed in partnership with local authorities, a total of £1 million has been allocated during the construction of the wind farm, to put science, technology, engineering and maths (STEM) at the heart of children’s education, helping them prepare for jobs that will be vital to the green economic recovery of the UK. Additional community funding will be allocated throughout the operational phase of the windfarm.</p>
<p>The programme has been developed with local skills and education stakeholders to ensure it meets local priorities, with a focus on early years in East Riding of Yorkshire.</p>
<p>All 124 primary schools in East Riding of Yorkshire will have the chance to increase and expand their current STEM provision, while there will also be a boost to career advice services for school leavers.</p>
<p>In addition to enhancing STEM provision in the classroom, during the construction of the wind farm 50 students from East Yorkshire and South Tyneside will receive scholarships to help with the cost of further education qualifications in STEM subjects.</p>
<p>Graham said, “This investment from Dogger Bank Wind Farm is really welcome news, and it’s great that it will benefit children across the East Riding and in my constituency of Beverley &amp; Holderness.</p>
<p>“Building up our domestic offshore wind capacity is bringing multiple benefits – from helping us meet our renewable energy commitments, to bringing skilled jobs to the area, to investing in our children’s education.</p>
<p>“I look forward to supporting Dogger Bank into the future as they generate tens of millions of pounds worth of investment into our area.”</p>
<p>In addition to this STEM fund, Dogger Bank Wind Farm will invest £13.5 million in the Offshore Wind Growth Partnership during its lifetime, a programme set up to support the growth of the UK offshore wind supply chain. Furthermore, 50% of the wind farm’s rental payments to the Crown Estate will support the Coastal Communities Fund, a UK Government-funded initiative to support the economic growth of coastal areas. Under the current arrangement the funds received by the Coastal Communities Fund will equate to 1% of the wind farm’s gross revenue, which could amount to tens of millions of pounds being invested in coastal communities during the operation of Dogger Bank Wind Farm.</p>
<p>The £1 million investment also includes an Operators Fund to support other local causes to the value of up to £500. Community projects and local organisations will be able to apply at www.doggerbank.com/about/community.</p>
<p>Apprenticeships and Skills Minister, Gillian Keegan, added: “As we recover from the pandemic, we’re investing billions of pounds to help the UK become a global leader in green technologies. This includes the creation of up to 250,000 jobs by 2030 through our Ten Point Plan, which will be critical in delivering a green industrial revolution.</p>
<p>“It’s fantastic to see the developers of Dogger Bank Wind Farm supporting this by investing in science, technology, engineering and maths skills. Not only is the world’s largest offshore wind farm pioneering new technology, it is also innovating in the way it’s supporting coastal communities to ensure young people are equipped to access the green jobs of the future.”</p>
<p>Dogger Bank Wind Farm will be located more than 130 km off the Yorkshire coast and will generate enough renewable energy to power six million UK homes. A joint venture between SSE Renewables, Equinor and Eni, SSE Renewables is leading on Dogger Bank construction and delivery while Equinor will operate the wind farm for its lifetime, from a new base to be constructed at Port of Tyne.</p>
<p>Work is already underway on the first two phases of the development in East Riding to prepare the 30km cable route from Ulrome to Creyke Beck Substation, near Beverley.</p>
<p>Steve Wilson, Project Director for Dogger Bank Wind Farm, said: “We are proud that alongside the jobs and supply chain investments we’ve already attracted to these local economies, we can also help make a real difference to the lives of people in our local communities with this innovative package of support. We estimate more than 25,000 young people from 142 schools in the North and North East of England will benefit from this funding, as we open their eyes to the green industry opportunities of our net-zero future.</p>
<p>“Renewable energy will increasingly become a source of skilled jobs in the UK as we come through the pandemic, and rebuild our economy. This is one of the most significant investments the offshore wind industry has made in future skills, and could be the key to unlocking the future potential of many young people, as we put STEM skills at the very heart of their learning.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Young people across Beverley and Holderness will benefit from a share of a £1 million investment from Dogger Bank Wind Farm to prepare them for...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/?p=11484</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T23:01:31Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T23:01:31Z</updated>
    <category term="General News"/>
    <category term="Beverley"/>
    <category term="Beverley and Holderness"/>
    <category term="Council"/>
    <category term="Dogger Bank"/>
    <category term="Dogger Bank Wind Farm"/>
    <category term="East Riding"/>
    <category term="Education"/>
    <category term="Employment"/>
    <category term="Environment"/>
    <category term="Gillian Keegan"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Graham Stuart MP"/>
    <category term="Jobs"/>
    <category term="Offshore wind"/>
    <category term="Schools"/>
    <category term="Skills"/>
    <category term="Skills Minister"/>
    <category term="STEM"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Answer to my Parliamentary Question on areas of the economy with labour shortages</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2021/06/17/answer-to-my-parliamentary-question-on-areas-with-labour-shortages/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The Department for Work and Pensions has provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (12056):</p>
<p><strong>Question:</strong><br/>
To ask the Secretary of State for Work and Pensions, what steps she is taking to train more people to fill shortages in (a) HGV driving, (b) farming, (c) construction and (d) other areas with labour shortages. (12056)</p>
<p>Tabled on: 08 June 2021</p>
<p><strong>Answer:</strong><br/>
Mims Davies:<br/>
The Department is continuing to work with the Department for Education, Devolved Authorities in Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland as well as other Government Departments to fill vacancies in construction, logistics, farming and other sectors, offering training for those who need it, and securing jobs directly for those ready to move into roles.</p>
<p>DWP’s Sector-Based Work Academy Programme (SWAP) helps employers to fill job vacancies in sectors with a high demand for workers. In the haulage sector we have been running SWAPs in partnership with employers and trade associations, including the Road Haulage Association (RHA) and Eddie Stobart Logistics, to deliver tailored training to our customers so that they can obtain their HGV licence and the skills they need to enter the logistics sector as a HGV driver.</p>
<p>In agriculture we have worked with DEFRA and key Trade Associations, including the National Farmers Union, to develop a regional recruitment strategy that utilises DWP’s Jobcentre Plus network, fosters strong local links between employers and Work Coaches, and gives jobseekers the skills and knowledge they need to enter the sector.</p>
<p>In construction, DWP support the Construction Skills Delivery Group to improve and promote the existing range of training offers which include new occupational traineeships, T Levels, flexible apprenticeships, Skills Bootcamps, and free L3 qualifications for adults who do not already have A levels or equivalent.</p>
<p>The answer was submitted on 17 Jun 2021 at 15:54.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Department for Work and Pensions has provided the following answer to your written parliamentary question (12056): Question: To ask the Secretary of State for Work and Pensions, what steps she is taking to train more people to fill shortages in (a) HGV driving, (b) farming, (c) construction and (d) other areas with labour shortages.…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=30551</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T15:26:10Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T15:26:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Wokingham and West Berkshire Issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>CATHERINE TAKES WEST DENTON LEISURE BID TO PARLIAMENT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-takes-west-denton-leisure-bid-to-parliament/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Newcastle North MP has taken her support for the bid to redevelop the West Denton Pool into a new state-of-the-art, net-zero carbon leisure development to Parliament, and again called on the Government to back the Levelling Up Fund bid. Catherine has worked with Newcastle City Council to submit a bid to the Levelling Up Fund … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/catherine-takes-west-denton-leisure-bid-to-parliament/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">CATHERINE TAKES WEST DENTON LEISURE BID TO PARLIAMENT</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7258</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T14:46:32Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T14:46:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Latest"/>
    <category term="Sport"/>
    <category term="featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Citizens Advice Scam Awareness Week</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2021/06/17/citizens-advice-scam-awareness-week/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Scams and fraud are a massive issue and these crimes can happen to anyone. We can all play our part in spreading awareness and look out for potential scams. As a result of coronavirus, many people are facing issues with employment, debt, housing and health, and scammers are exploiting people during this particularly difficult time. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2021/06/17/citizens-advice-scam-awareness-week/">Citizens Advice Scam Awareness Week</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=4864</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T12:55:42Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T12:55:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Council agrees programme of improvements for Capital’s parks, green spaces and cemeteries</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13237/council-agrees-programme-of-improvements-for-capital-s-parks-green-spaces-and-cemeteries" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Plans for how over £4m will be invested in parks, green spaces and cemeteries in a programme of priority works being rolled out across 2021 and 2022 have been approved by councillors.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13237/council-agrees-programme-of-improvements-for-capital-s-parks-green-spaces-and-cemeteries</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T13:52:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T13:52:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“Education is an investment – it’s the interest that pays” – Karin Smyth MP calls on Government to support young people</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/06/17/education-is-an-investment-its-the-interest-that-pays-karin-smyth-mp-calls-on-government-to-support-young-people/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=education-is-an-investment-its-the-interest-that-pays-karin-smyth-mp-calls-on-government-to-support-young-people" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, joined the Labour Party this week in triggering a vote to force the Chancellor to explain to MPs and constituents the Government’s decision to reject the recommendations for an education recovery from Sir Kevan Collins, the former education expert who quit as a result of this rejection.</p>
<p>The Labour Party have set out their plans for education recovery, which include extracurricular activities and an emphasis on mental health. These plans include: breakfast clubs and new activities for every child; quality mental health support in every school; small group tutoring for all who need it, not just 1%; continued development for teachers; an Education Recovery Premium; and expanded plans for free school meals.</p>
<p>Labour are calling particularly for a recognition of the impact of the pandemic on early years and the socialisation that has not been able to happen for our youngest members of society as well as adequate support for those in exam years and those in higher education and vocational training schools.<br/>
Locally, Karin secured a roundtable meeting between the Education Minister, Nick Gibb MP, and the Regional Schools Commissioner. This meeting, arranged by Karin, ensured that the minister could hear of the difficulties being faced by South Bristol schools.</p>
<p>Karin Smyth MP said:</p>
<p>“Our young people are our future and the Government owe it to them to ensure that their futures are not put in jeopardy because of the pandemic. Unfortunately, this Government seem determined to ignore the needs of our children and young people and are not putting in place the support and resources that they need.</p>
<p>“It has been an incredibly challenging year for our children and young people. We have to recognise that they have not only lost out academically. Children turning a year old may not have met many other people; they will not have had the experiences of being out and about with their parents in busy environments and other young children will have been a year without much socialisation. Teachers will need a lot of support to help our children process this and parents need the assurance that their children will be fully supported.</p>
<p>“The Government need to explain why they have rejected experts’ recommendations on education recovery and if they cannot do so satisfactorily, then they need to change tack and ensure that sufficient resources are deployed to support an education recovery. Without it, Britain’s recovery will be far more difficult.”</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/06/17/education-is-an-investment-its-the-interest-that-pays-karin-smyth-mp-calls-on-government-to-support-young-people/">“Education is an investment – it’s the interest that pays” – Karin Smyth MP calls on Government to support young people</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Karin Smyth, MP for Bristol South, joined the Labour Party this week in triggering a vote to force the Chancellor […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2021/06/17/education-is-an-investment-its-the-interest-that-pays-karin-smyth-mp-calls-on-government-to-support-young-people/">“Education is an investment – it’s the interest that pays” – Karin Smyth MP calls on Government to support young people</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T12:36:24Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T12:36:24Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
    <category term="Education"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>New UK-USA deal to protect jobs and support investment, global Britain in action</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1844-new-uk-usa-deal-to-protect-jobs-and-support-investment-global-britain-in-action"/>
		<published>2021-06-17T13:28:38+01:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-17T13:28:38+01:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/1844-new-uk-usa-deal-to-protect-jobs-and-support-investment-global-britain-in-action</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;New UK 🇬🇧 USA 🇺🇸 deal to protect jobs and support investment. Global Britain in action 👍 &lt;a href="https://t.co/8t3oHE9g3a"&gt;pic.twitter.com/8t3oHE9g3a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1405490354443505664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;New UK 🇬🇧 USA 🇺🇸 deal to protect jobs and support investment. Global Britain in action 👍 &lt;a href="https://t.co/8t3oHE9g3a"&gt;pic.twitter.com/8t3oHE9g3a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1405490354443505664?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;June 17, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Clean Air Day 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/clean-air-day-2021" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-field-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/styles/large/public/field/image/Clean-Air-Day-Logo.jpg?itok=VnQbGT7z" width="740" height="423" alt=""/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded">
              <p class="MsoNormal"> </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">Today is Clean Air Day 2021 and this year the theme is “protect our children’s health from air pollution”. Clean Air Day is the UK's largest air pollution campaign which helps to drive a positive shift in public knowledge and action; and is a chance to find out more about air pollution, share information, and make the air cleaner and healthier for everyone.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">2020 was a wake-up call. In the face of the global pandemic and the wider challenge of the climate crisis, we must build a healthier future for our children. Children need access to clean air, to safe walking and cycling routes to school, to healthy spaces to learn and play safely. Clean air has never been more important as we recover from the pandemic and to secure the health of future generations.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">Dagenham and Rainham, spanning both Barking and Dagenham and Havering, has some of the worst recorded air quality in London. Jon Cruddas MP has long campaigned to clean up the air locally, including an 18-month campaign against a mass waste incinerator at Belvedere.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal"><strong>Jon Cruddas MP said:</strong> <em>“The hospital admissions and mortality rate resulting from harmful emissions are higher in Dagenham and Rainham than anywhere in London. I have been campaigning to clean up our air since 2018. I commend the work of Barking and Dagenham Council over the last year but more needs to be done in government to protect the health of residents, and children in particular, who are more susceptible to harm from air pollution.”</em></p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">At the end of 2020 Barking and Dagenham launched their Air Quality Action Plan, a strategy to address air pollution in the borough which looks across sectors at how we can reduce particulates and CO2. Some of the schemes in the AQAP include retrofitting older homes, improving road surfaces, electrifying the council vehicle fleet, increasing active travel options with a walking and cycling strategy, ramping up air quality monitoring capacity, and working to educate local people about how they can help.</p>
              <p class="MsoNormal"><strong>Cllr Margaret Mullane, Cabinet Member for Enforcement and Community Safety said:</strong> <em>“The health and safety of our residents and the children of the borough is a top priority, which is why we are determined to reduce air pollution in Barking and Dagenham. We’re encouraging all residents to see if there are any ways that they could personally reduce the amount of pollution in the air.”</em></p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">
                <strong>Cllr Andrew Achilleos, Member Champion for Climate Change said:</strong>
                <em> “I’m incredibly proud of our ambitious Air Quality Action Plan and hope that residents use Clean Air Day to have a look at it, but also to find out more about how some of our everyday activities contribute to air pollution. We all have a role to play in keeping the borough healthy.”</em>
              </p>
              <p class="MsoNormal">The LBBD AQAP can be found by clicking <a href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/sites/default/files/Draft%20Air%20Quality%20Action%20Plan%20-%20London%20Borough%20of%20Barking%20and%20Dagenham%20%281%29.pdf"><strong>HERE</strong></a></p>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-taxonomy-vocabulary-2 field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/dagenham" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Dagenham</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-1">
              <a href="/tags/havering" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">havering</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-2">
              <a href="/tags/air-quality" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Air Quality</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-3">
              <a href="/tags/pollution" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Pollution</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-4">
              <a href="/tags/health" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">Health</a>
            </li>
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-5">
              <a href="/tags/community" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">community</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1522 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T11:58:07Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T11:58:07Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>‘Golden opportunity’ for Australia but not for Scotland’s food &amp; drink sector</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2021/06/17/golden-opportunity-for-australia-but-not-for-scotlands-food-drink-sector/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Today in the House of Commons, I questioned the Trade Secretary Liz Truss on the UK government’s rush to sign a trade deal with Australia which could see us flooded with cheap exports of beef, lamb and dairy to the detriment of many of our own producers. I said: “Argyll &amp; Bute overwhelmingly rejected Brexit […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=9375</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T11:27:16Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T11:27:16Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Coronavirus (COVID-19)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-35/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear constituent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing to you with another update about the Coronavirus pandemic and some other local issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, as you will probably be aware, the Prime Minister has taken a decision to extend the remaining restrictions until the end of the 18th July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CORONAVIRUS RESTRICTIONS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A summary of the current rules is &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/covid-19-coronavirus-restrictions-what-you-can-and-cannot-do"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WEDDINGS AND CIVIL PARTNERSHIP CEREMONIES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two exceptions to this. The first is that the limit of 30 people allowed to attend a wedding has been removed, though a number of conditions remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full details of this are &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-wedding-and-civil-partnership-ceremonies-receptions-and-celebrations"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CARE HOME RESIDENTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition care home residents are now allowed to spend a night away from their homes without having to isolate on their return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Details are here:&lt;br /&gt;
https://www.gov.uk/government/news/care-home-residents-can-stay-overnight-as-visiting-restrictions-ease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SURREY COVID CASES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent increase in cases in Surrey has mostly affected younger people who are yet to be vaccinated and those who have only had a single jab. This does underline how important it is that people who are still unvaccinated or who have yet to book in for their second jab and are eligible to do so book an appointment now. You can do so via the NHS website at;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/coronavirus-vaccination/book-coronavirus-vaccination/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest figures for Surrey are &lt;a href="https://www.surreycc.gov.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0009/263691/Surrey_covid-19_infographic_1106.pdf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHALK PIT EPSOM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know many people remain extremely concerned about the noise and dust nuisance coming from the Chalk Pit in College Road, Epsom at the moment. I have been working with local residents on the issue and pushing the Environment Agency to act. I have had several meetings with the Agency and they have been working through a formal process which I hope will reach a resolution in the next few days. Please keep updating me if you experience serious noise or dust from the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CITIZENS ADVICE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Epsom and Ewell Citizens Advice team have asked me to remind people that if they are having difficulties as a result of the pandemic or some other issue, they are often able to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For their latest details and contacts &lt;a href="http://www.caee.org.uk/get-advice/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much hope that we can move on from the pandemic very soon and everyone will be able to enjoy the rest of the summer. As always, if you have questions or issues please feel free to email me, though please use my Parliamentary address as this message comes from a no reply service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best wishes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RT Hon Chris Grayling MP&lt;br /&gt;
Member of Parliament for Epsom and Ewell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-35/"&gt;Coronavirus (COVID-19)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net"&gt;Chris Grayling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to you with another update about the Coronavirus pandemic and some other local issues. Firstly, as you will probably be aware, the Prime Minister has taken a decision to extend the remaining restrictions until the end of the 18th July. CORONAVIRUS RESTRICTIONS A summary of the current rules is here. [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/coronavirus-covid-19-35/">Coronavirus (COVID-19)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6135</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T11:05:02Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T11:05:02Z</updated>
    <category term="Coronavirus (COVID19)"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Emma Asked the Prime Minister to Defend South Tyneside Hospital During PMQs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/emma-asked-the-prime-minister-to-defend-south-tyneside-hospital-during-pmqs/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Last week I was lucky enough to be drawn to ask a question during Prime Minister’s Question Time. This came at the perfect time as later that day I was presenting a petition on behalf of more than 40,000 constituents who are against the disastrous cuts to South Tyneside Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I took this opportunity to remind the Prime Minister of all the things he said about out NHS, including “Our greatest national asset” “Best of this country” “Record increase in funding” “Saved my life—no question” “My No.1 priority”. Yet, during a worldwide pandemic our award-winning South Tyneside Hospital is being stripped of acute services causing a disaster for the people of South Tyneside and causing undue pressure on our neighbouring Sunderland A&amp;amp;E. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The past year and a half has shown that our NHS is needed more than ever however, in the hands of the Tories it’s very future is uncertain. The Government must step in and show they are serious about protecting the NHS, listen to our concerns, stop more cuts to South Tyneside Hospital and return the services we have already lost.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Crucially, in my speech I asked the Prime Minister if he would match his rhetoric with some action by blocking cuts to our hospital but unsurprisingly, he failed to provide us with any support or reassurance.&amp;nbsp; This shows us all the Prime Minister does not care about the NHS which saved his life. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;South Tyneside and Sunderland campaigners have worked incredibly hard to raise awareness of the dismantling of our local hospital services, even coming down to Westminster to hand me the 44,000 strong petition. However, on the very same day campaigners stood outside of Parliament, the Government once again chose to stand against us.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can read my PMQ speech by clicking &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2021-06-09/debates/DEF5FB4C-C539-4D6C-8B6E-55AA4C219716/Engagements#contribution-B14DDCDD-18AC-4C10-91C1-FF26840130A9"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the petition speech &lt;a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2021-06-09/debates/65959B2B-100D-42BC-B83D-D3F5033A026C/SouthTynesideHospital#contribution-33A058B7-ECD2-4CF8-A0B6-99101609E870"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Last week I was lucky enough to be drawn to ask a question during Prime Minister’s Question Time. This came at the perfect time as later that day I was presenting a petition on behalf of more than 40,000 constituents who are against the disastrous cuts to South Tyneside Hospital. I took this opportunity to […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Joan Whelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.emma-lewell-buck.net/?p=3016</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T10:56:54Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T10:56:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Latest News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What we can learn from the incredible work of Pauline Town MBE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/what-we-can-learn-from-the-incredible-work-of-pauline-town-mbe/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=what-we-can-learn-from-the-incredible-work-of-pauline-town-mbe" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft size-large wp-image-233702" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Pauline-Town.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/><br/>
Pauline Town MBE. That’s an honour that Pauline never expected and never asked for, but one that is thoroughly deserved. What a year it has been for her. Pauline runs the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheStationHotelAUL/">Station Hotel</a> in Ashton-Under-Lyne – a pub which also operates as the town’s We Shall Overcome Hub.</p>
<p>It all started in 2013, when a man named Ben knocked on the door of the pub in 2013. He struggled with mental health issues, had learning difficulties, and was begging on the street. Pauline let him come in for a cup of tea and spent over five months setting up his personal independence payments and accommodation.</p>
<p>Pauline has now helped more than 200 homeless people off the streets and gives out around 100 packed lunches a day. She is, to put it simply, and absolute inspiration. Last year, Tameside Council’s Homelessness Team set up the Town House (named after Pauline) in Ashton on Burlington Street.</p>
<p>The Town House acts as a community hub and overnight hostel, providing support and care to people who are homeless.</p>
<p>The Homelessness Team has done tremendous work in helping people in the Borough. The A Bed Every Night programme has been a fantastic success. The council recorded a drop in rough sleeping between 2018 to 2019 of 86%, and in April of this year no rough sleepers were recorded in Tameside. It is hard to overstate this achievement, and it is down to the hard work of people like Pauline and the Council.</p>
<p>I strongly believe that the innovative work of the Homelessness Team can be applied across the country. The team focusses on tailoring services to individuals’ needs and recognises that ongoing support is crucial to prevent people falling back into rough sleeping.</p>
<p>Homelessness is complex, and should be tackled with empathy, organisation, and long-term care. Last year, Crisis estimated that around 200,000 people nationally were experiencing core homelessness – the most severe form of homelessness.</p>
<p>Over the next few months, as furlough ends and the impact of the pandemic on the economy and jobs is truly felt, we need to be even more prepared to help those in need. Local authority and Government spending must be increased, and the Government needs to recognise the work of councils such as Tameside and individuals like Pauline to champion similar projects across the country.</p>
<p>The future after the pandemic is uncertain, but if we learn from people like Pauline, and schemes like A Bed Every Night, I’m certain that we can build a society where we all look out for one another and are proud to help those most in need.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/what-we-can-learn-from-the-incredible-work-of-pauline-town-mbe/">What we can learn from the incredible work of Pauline Town MBE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Pauline Town MBE. That’s an honour that Pauline never expected and never asked for, but one that is thoroughly deserved. What a year it has been for her. Pauline runs the Station Hotel in Ashton-Under-Lyne – a pub which also operates as the town’s We Shall Overcome Hub. It all started in 2013, when a […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/what-we-can-learn-from-the-incredible-work-of-pauline-town-mbe/">What we can learn from the incredible work of Pauline Town MBE</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=233701</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T10:42:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T10:42:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
    <category term="Media"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christina Rees MP demands dramatic improvements to border controls to stop the spread of Covid-19 variants</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/christina-rees-mp-demands-dramatic-improvements-to-border-controls-to-stop-the-spread-of-covid-19-variants/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Christina Rees, MP for Neath, this week supported Labour’s calls for the UK Government to scrap the Amber List and have a limited Green List to prevent any further variants of Covid-19 disrupting the opening up of the country and the economy.</p>
<p>Labour are pointing to the fact that the UK Government added Bangladesh and Pakistan to the Red List on 9 April, when cases started to rise, but delayed for a further 14 days to add India to the Red List even though India had case increases. They are accusing the UK Government of dither and delay and allowing the widespread transmission of the Delta variant which SAGE has confirmed is 60% more transmissible.</p>
<p>Figures from the Civil Aviation Authority show that thousands of people have continued to fly between high-risk areas and the UK and airports have struggled to separate those entering the UK from high-risk and low-risk countries.</p>
<p><strong>Christina Rees MP said:</strong></p>
<p>“This UK Tory Government has put trade deal photo ops above the safety and security of the UK. To make matters worse, the quarantine system is failing to work adequately with many slipping under the radar and others enduring sub-standard accommodation.</p>
<p>“The Traffic Light System is not working and we are now seeing the consequences of that: the delayed lifting of lockdown restrictions. This UK Government has continued to put shine above substance and the UK public deserve better.</p>
<p>“Our NHS staff are working so hard to roll out the vaccination programme and the UK Tory Government should not be undermining their task. It is time for them to put the country first and eliminate the Amber List. The UK Government must make it clear that if people must travel then they can only do so to Green List countries. The UK Government have played fast and loose with our border security: putting the hard work of everyone in the UK at risk.”</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Christina Rees, MP for Neath, this week supported Labour’s calls for the UK Government to scrap the Amber List and have a limited Green List to prevent any further variants of Covid-19 disrupting the opening up of the country and the economy. Labour are pointing to the fact that the UK Government added Bangladesh and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2510</id>
    <published>2021-06-17T09:24:27Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-17T09:24:27Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex responds to SBC&#8217;s Levelling Up Fund bid for Billingham Town Centre]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/06/alex-responds-to-sbcs-levelling-up-fund-bid-for-billingham-town-centre/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14122</id>
		<updated>2021-06-17T08:17:36Z</updated>
		<published>2021-06-17T08:17:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Responding to Stockton Borough Council’s plans to take back control of Billingham Town Centre, Alex said: “Over the years the Labour-led Stockton Borough Council has taken an active role in revitalising our town centres and has been held up nationally as an example of best practice. This has most recently been seen in the Council’s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2021/06/alex-responds-to-sbcs-levelling-up-fund-bid-for-billingham-town-centre/">Alex responds to SBC&#8217;s Levelling Up Fund bid for Billingham Town Centre</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>TIGRR</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk/news/tigrr" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="2133" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;16 June 2021&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;TIGRR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;What is the Regulatory Dividend of Brexit? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Much has been promised &amp; alleged.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Brexit sceptics have said “it can only be a race to the bottom slashing protections”. &lt;strong&gt;Not true.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Today we have set out our TaskForce on Innovation &amp; Regulation Report (TIGRR) with 120 Recommendations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;To read more:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Find the &lt;strong&gt;TIGRR Report&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/taskforce-on-innovation-growth-and-regulatory-reform-independent-report"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Read my article in &lt;strong&gt;ConHome&lt;/strong&gt; today: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.conservativehome.com/platform/2021/06/george-freeman-this-new-report-shows-how-we-can-build-on-britains-vaccine-success-to-make-the-best-of-brexit.html"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;See &lt;strong&gt;The Telegraph &lt;/strong&gt;article I co-authored with Iain Duncan Smith and Theresa Villiers: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/politics/2021/06/15/power-create-laws-can-take-lead-high-tech-industries-future/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Watch my interview on&lt;strong&gt; GB news&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/mImDCr8AwCqqxRGh7paeR?domain=youtu.be"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;See my appearance on&lt;strong&gt; BBC Politics Live &lt;/strong&gt;this morning: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/mzVMCBN35CGG39Phz9agd?domain=bbc.co.uk"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Read the article in the &lt;strong&gt;Financial Times&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/ed2d0a61-a056-470d-8597-082310b4beb9"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--video paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
            
        &lt;div class="video-relative"&gt;
            
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-video field--type-video-embed-field field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;div class="video-embed-field-provider-youtube video-embed-field-responsive-video form-group"&gt;&lt;iframe width="854" height="480" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" class="embed-video" id="embed-video-19643" allowscriptaccess="always" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/PD2q7Zv0e6s?autoplay=1&amp;start=0&amp;rel=0&amp;enablejsapi=1"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="overlay"&gt;
                &lt;div class="paragraph-image-wrapper" style="background-image: url()"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="caption"&gt;
            
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>2133 at https://www.georgefreeman.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-06-16T15:03:26Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T15:03:26Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>South Cumbria stroke and neurological group welcomes news of new provider for Holehird care home</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1407598/south-cumbria-stroke-and-neurological-group-welcomes-news-of-new-provider-for-holehird-care-home"/>
  <updated>2021-06-16T14:28:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2021/1407598/south-cumbria-stroke-and-neurological-group-welcomes-news-of-new-provider-for-holehird-care-home</id>
  <summary type="text">A group representing stroke and neurological patients and carers in South Cumbria has welcomed the news that a new provider has been found to take over Holehird care home in Windermere.
Last week, St Gregory's Homecare, Leonard Cheshire, the Holehird Trust and Tim Farron MP issued a joint statement on the future of the care home, which said: "Since Leonard Cheshire took the decision that it could no longer provide care at Holehird, we've been working hard to try to find a new provider to take over the running of the home.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A group representing stroke and neurological patients and carers in South Cumbria has welcomed the news that a new provider has been found to take over Holehird care home in Windermere.</p>
<p>Last week, St Gregory's Homecare, Leonard Cheshire, the Holehird Trust and Tim Farron MP issued a joint statement on the future of the care home, which said: <em>"Since Leonard Cheshire took the decision that it could no longer provide care at Holehird, we've been working hard to try to find a new provider to take over the running of the home.</em></p>
<p><em>"Holehird has provided amazing care for people of all ages with physical disabilities and complex needs for the past 60 years.</em></p>
<p><em>"So we're delighted that St Gregory's Homecare have come forward to offer to take over the running of Holehird and we've been working together to try to make this a reality.</em></p>
<p><em>"There are still several hurdles to overcome and there is no certainty that it will be achieved, but we wanted to make this statement to give confidence that we are committed to ensuring the best possible outcome for Holehird and the wider community."</em></p>
<p>Commenting on the news, Chair of the Patient and Carer Integrated Stroke and Neurorehabilitation Delivery Network Assurance Group for Lancashire &amp; South Cumbria Phil Woodford said: <em>"I'd like to thank everyone involved in working to secure this transition to a new provider, it is incredible what can be achieved when people come together with a common purpose.</em></p>
<p><em>"This hasn't been about securing the future of a building, it is much bigger than that, Holehird is home to a group of people who require specialist care and support.</em></p>
<p><em>"It must remain a very anxious time for the staff involved too, my thanks goes out to them for everything that they do to care for these people.</em></p>
<p><em>"I hope to visit Holehird after the new provider takes over and meet some of the residents and staff myself.</em></p>
<p><em>"There's still a little way to go to make it a certainty, but I wish everyone involved the very best and again, thank you.</em></p>
<p><em>"As a Stroke survivor myself I know how valuable such specialist care is."</em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Pausing Step 4 of the roadmap</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/pausing-step-4-of-the-roadmap/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Wednesday 16 June 2021 We’ve made great progress this year in bringing the spread of the coronavirus under control, reducing infection and hospitalisation rates, and vaccinating over 50% of all adults with both jabs of the vaccine. We’ve successfully unlocked our economy and society without seeing a significant rise in infections, but despite all that […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>pierre</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=5737</id>
    <published>2021-06-16T08:47:42Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-16T08:47:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[DIVIDED IN POLITICS, UNITED IN GRIEF]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/06/16/divided-in-politics-united-in-grief/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=361</id>
		<updated>2021-06-16T08:18:11Z</updated>
		<published>2021-06-16T08:18:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/06/16/divided-in-politics-united-in-grief/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/06/16/divided-in-politics-united-in-grief/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2021/06/16/divided-in-politics-united-in-grief/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Telegraph: Let&#8217;s honour our entrepreneurs!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/06/16/the-telegraph-lets-honour-our-entrepreneurs/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=4786</id>
		<updated>2021-06-16T06:30:19Z</updated>
		<published>2021-06-16T06:30:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Local Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Low Cost Britain"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="National Campaigns"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Press Cuttings"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Regenerating Weston"/><category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="UK Productivity &amp; Growth"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[THE Government should create a new honours order that is dedicated to entrepreneurs who start fast-growing businesses, a think tank has suggested. Under plans drawn up by the Entrepreneurs Network, more than 200 start-up founders each year would join a new &#8220;Elizabethan Order&#8221; and be handed medals featuring an owl to honour Athena, the ancient [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2021/06/16/the-telegraph-lets-honour-our-entrepreneurs/"><![CDATA[
<p>THE Government should create a new honours order that is dedicated to entrepreneurs who start fast-growing businesses, a think tank has suggested.</p>



<p>Under plans drawn up by the Entrepreneurs Network, more than 200 start-up founders each year would join a new &#8220;Elizabethan Order&#8221; and be handed medals featuring an owl to honour Athena, the ancient Greek goddess of wisdom.</p>



<p>The Queen could award founders using this new order from 2022 instead of handing them MBEs and OBEs, the group suggested, Its proposals were backed by&nbsp;<strong>John Penrose</strong>, a Conservative MP and the Anti-Corruption Champion at the Cabinet Office.</p>



<p>He said: &#8220;Britain has always been better at recognising the achievements of people who rise to the top of established professions and industries, rather than the innovators who create new ones.</p>



<p>&#8220;But ultimately, the power of ideas is what drives the technologies that create new jobs and economic growth, and that fuel our society and culture, too. This is a creative and interesting idea to redress that balance.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is estimated the scheme would cost £66,000 a year to run, following an bill of up to £20,000 to establish the order.</p>



<p>The Entrepreneurs Network&#8217;s proposal said: &#8220;The creation of a new order of chivalry for inventors and innovators would show that the UK is serious about its intended aim of being the best place in the world to be a scientist, entrepreneur or inventor.&#8221;</p>



<p>While a number of start-up founders and investors were handed honours during David Cameron&#8217;s time in No10, this trend tailed off under Theresa May and the latest list last Friday featured no technology founders.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne organises second export event, as UK signs Trade Agreement with Australia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-organises-second-export-event-uk-signs-trade-agreement-australia" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">  &lt;div data-history-node-id="6977" class="layout layout--onecol"&gt;
    &lt;div class="layout__region layout__region--content"&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;15 June 2021&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items"&gt;
              &lt;div class="field--item"&gt;  &lt;div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default"&gt;
          
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dunne organises second export event, as UK signs Trade Agreement with Australia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
            &lt;div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;South Shropshire MP Philip Dunne has announced he is organising a second event to help local businesses looking to export products around the world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The government today announced a free trade agreement with Australia, so businesses who sign up to attend the event will be able to learn more about how to export their products to Australian customers, as well as other markets around the world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Businesses will receive tailored updates and guidance from the Department for International Trade on how to expand their business and access new markets, as well as hearing from: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A local Export Champion who is reaping the benefits of international trade, who will share their export journey, experience and tips on breaking into a new market&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A DIT official to provide an update on the doors being opened through new trade deals&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;An International Trade Adviser who will share information on the tools available to grow your business through international sales&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The event will take place online on Monday 19th July, from 4pm to 5pm, and will conclude with a Q&amp;A session. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Mr Dunne, who is a founding member of the Parliamentary Export Programme where selected cross party MPs organise and chair virtual meetings with experts from business and government to support local businesses in their exporting journey, said: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“I am delighted to be organising my second interactive virtual export event, with support from the Department for International Trade, to help businesses in South Shropshire access new markets and customers across the globe. This is a free event, with expert advice from officials and other businesses who have found success through exporting. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“This will be a good opportunity to discover how today’s announcement of a free trade agreement with Australia will open up new opportunities for South Shropshire businesses to export, as well as offering young people who want to work in Australia easier access to visas.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;“I encourage businesses to sign up for free at &lt;a href="https://eu.eventscloud.com/website/3735/"&gt;https://eu.eventscloud.com/website/3735/&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The UK-Australia trade relationship was worth £13.9 billion last year and is set to grow under the under the agreement. British farmers will be protected by a cap on tariff-free imports for 15 years, using tariff rate quotas and other safeguards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Under the Free Trade Agreement between the UK and Australia, movement between the two countries for young people will be made easier. At present, UK citizens under 30 who spend a year in Australia must undertake 88 days of farm work if they wish to stay for another year. This requirement is removed under the trade deal, and the maximum age for visa is also being raised to 35.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
  
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>6977 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T16:43:08Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T16:43:08Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith welcomes agreement on Bulls Elite Academy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/mp-welcomes-agreement-on-bulls-elite-academy/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Reacting to news that Bradford Bulls will now continue to run an Elite Academy, Bradford South Labour MP Judith Cummins said, “I’m pleased that the club and the RFL have reached a resolution that enables Bradford to continue to run an Elite Academy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It would, however, have been better for all concerned to have avoided the worry and trauma in the first place,” she added.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ms Cummins had challenged the RFL on the process and decision that saw Bradford losing out in the award of Elite Academy licences. She questioned whether quotas rather than an assessment of record, performance and deep roots into the community game had been given little weight in the consideration.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“The Bulls Academy has been productive and respected for its work, a rich source of playing talent. Leon Pryce, Sam Burgess, and John Bateman to name but a few of the players to have come through the academy and gone onto star at the highest levels of our sport.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There remain challenges ahead but I’m looking forward to working with and supporting the club and the RFL to make sure that the sport has a healthy future,” said Ms Cummins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/rlf-ead/" title="Worrying Questions over RFL&amp;#039;s elite academy decision"&gt;Worrying Questions over RFL's elite academy decision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;84&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;As Chair of the All Party Parliamentary Rugby League Group, Judith has written to the RFL seeking an explanation on its elite academy decision. Re: Award of Elite Academy licenses for 2022-2027 I am concerned at the recent announcement from the Rugby Football League (RFL) on the award of Elite&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: academy, elite, decision, sport, bradford, game, community, award, rfl, players&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;78&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;77&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/santander-picture.jpg.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" alt="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has said that banking provision in the constituency has been totally wiped out. "People will have to travel over three miles to get to a bank,” she said, adding that the bank has “failed to take into account the social costs to the local area of removing this vital&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, will, working, local, bradford, south, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-cummins-mp-launches-food-pantry-to-support-local-families/" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families"&gt;Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;77&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-cummins-mp-launches-food-pantry-to-support-local-families/" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/132720401_661727764520958_1473415729086859036_o-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families" alt="Judith Cummins MP launches Food Pantry to support local families" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Bradford South MP Judith Cummins visited The Sutton Centre in BD4 to launch their new Food Pantry which provides essential food and hygiene products to local families. Open every Wednesday, the pantry asks for a donation of just £3 to fill a bag with a range of tinned goods, cereals&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, mp, local, cummins, community, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;76&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/bradford-must-have-a-northern-powerhouse-rail-stop/" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/282909116.gallery-1-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" alt="Bradford MUST have a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith, alongside Susan Hinchcliffe, leader of the council and Tracy Brabin, candidate for West Yorkshire Mayor, has called for the Government to ensure there is a Northern Powerhouse Rail stop in the city centre. Representing all three of Bradford's Labour MPs, Judith said: "There is a world out there that&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, labour, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Reacting to news that Bradford Bulls will now continue to run an Elite Academy, Bradford South Labour MP Judith Cummins said, “I’m pleased that the club and the RFL have reached a resolution that enables Bradford to continue to run an Elite Academy.” “It would, however, have been better for all concerned to have avoided […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2509</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T15:42:55Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T15:42:55Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>North East has huge health inequalities, it is important we are part of clinical trials for new treatments &amp; medicines</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2021/06/north-east-has-huge-health-inequalities-it-is-important-we-are-part-of-clinical-trials-for-new-treatments-medicines/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The North East faces huge health inequalities, it is important we are part of clinical trials for new treatments &amp; medicines. When I asked the Minister she claimed the govt are taking steps to ensure representative participation, particularly for areas with the greatest disease burden; yet when I asked how many patients were recruited from each NHS Trust she wouldn’t tell me . Either she doesn’t have the data or she is  embarrassed about it. Whatever the reason, its not what she promised.</p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="11231" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2021/06/north-east-has-huge-health-inequalities-it-is-important-we-are-part-of-clinical-trials-for-new-treatments-medicines/clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qaj2/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?fit=800%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="800,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Clinical trials equal opps june qAj2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?fit=700%2C394&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11231" src="https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?resize=700%2C394&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="394" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i1.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/Clinical-trials-equal-opps-june-qAj2.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
<p><img data-attachment-id="11232" data-permalink="https://chionwurahmp.com/2021/06/north-east-has-huge-health-inequalities-it-is-important-we-are-part-of-clinical-trials-for-new-treatments-medicines/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-u-7gg/" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?fit=800%2C450&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="800,450" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="clinical trials patients recruited by year june U-7gg" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?fit=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?fit=700%2C394&amp;ssl=1" loading="lazy" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11232" src="https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?resize=700%2C394&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="700" height="394" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?w=800&amp;ssl=1 800w, https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?resize=300%2C169&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i2.wp.com/chionwurahmp.com/wp-content/uploads/clinical-trials-patients-recruited-by-year-june-U-7gg.png?resize=768%2C432&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" data-recalc-dims="1"/></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The North East faces huge health inequalities, it is important we are part of clinical trials for new treatments &amp; medicines. When I asked the Minister she claimed the govt are taking steps to ensure representative participation, particularly for areas… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=11230</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T14:34:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T14:34:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Correspondence"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>National Insurance Contributions Bill 2021 - Robin speaks in favour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/national-insurance-contributions-bill-2021-robin-speaks-favour" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The National Insurance Contributions Bill was introduced on 12 May 2021. The Second Reading was held on 14 June 2021. The Bill, with its explanatory notes, is published on the Bill’s page on Parliament.uk, which also provides details of its parliamentary progress to date.  
The  House of Commons…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/national-insurance-contributions-bill-2021-robin-speaks-favour</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MPs team up with nursing champion to end domestic violence</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/mps-team-nursing-champion-end-domestic-violence" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Lee Anderson, MP for Ashfield and Eastwood, and Ben Bradley, MP for Mansfield, recently met with Sarah Atkinson – Ashfield and Mansfield’s  Primary Care Liaison Nurse for people with Learning Disabilities.
 
The meeting was set about to discuss a Domestic Violence and Abuse (DVA)  project  launched…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/mps-team-nursing-champion-end-domestic-violence</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Delay to Step 4 of the roadmap: Q&amp;A</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/delay-step-4-roadmap-qa" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Overview
The February roadmap set out four steps to easing of coronavirus restrictions.  The final step, was due to take place no earlier than 21 June, and the Prime Minister confirmed the date will be 19 July. England remains in Step 3 with some restrictions remaining on capacity and numbers are…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/delay-step-4-roadmap-qa</id>
    <published>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-15T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-121" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> 
This evening, the Prime Minister announced a further 4-week extension to the current lockdown meaning that Monday 21st June now becomes 19th July. Like many of you, I am very much against this decision and am worried about a further delay post the 19th.
We, quite rightly, understand that the…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-121</id>
    <published>2021-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali MP Statement on Grenfell's Fourth Anniversary</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_4th_grenfell_anniversary" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div>
<div dir="ltr">
<p><span>Today marks the fourth anniversary of the Grenfell Tower disaster. During the night of 14 June 2017, a fire broke out in the 24-story tower block and 72 people were killed.</span></p>
<div>
<p><span> </span></p>
</div>
<p><span>Rushanara Ali MP for Bethnal Green and Bow said:</span></p>
</div>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_mp_statement_on_the_4th_grenfell_anniversary</id>
    <published>2021-06-14T12:18:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-14T12:18:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly round-up #Working4Wycombe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2021/06/weekly-round-up-working4wycombe-16/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">What I have been up to this week #Working4Wycombe: Thanked agencies helping with the situation in St. Vincent &amp; the Grenadines following the eruption of La Soufrière What About Weddings?: Asked the Minister for Small Businesses and the Govt to please allow people to get married and celebrate with their friends and family Asked the Foreign Secretary to examine whether cuts to aid spending could be done more sympathetically with respect to those most in need As part of Treasury […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Lucy-Anne Hickey</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18462</id>
    <published>2021-06-11T16:12:08Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-11T16:12:08Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
    <category term="#Working4Wycombe"/>
    <category term="#Wycombe"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Government failing people with autism and learning disabilities]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/government-failing-people-with-autism-and-learning-disabilities/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11106</id>
		<updated>2021-06-11T14:43:04Z</updated>
		<published>2021-06-11T14:42:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Homepage"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Liz in the news"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="liz kendall"/><category scheme="https://lizkendall.org" term="Social Care"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I spoke in a Westminster Hall Debate in Parliament on ‘Winterbourne View Hospital and the Transforming Care Programme’<br />
On the 31st May 2011 a BBC Panorama documentary revealed appalling abuse of people with a learning disability and/or autism at the Winterbourne View Assessment and Treatment Unit (ATU).<br />
Footage of patients being repeatedly assaulted and mocked by staff shocked people across the country. In response the Government promised to take people with a learning disability and/or autism out of ATUs and instead support them to live in the community.<br />
10 years of missed ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/government-failing-people-with-autism-and-learning-disabilities/">Government failing people with autism and learning disabilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/government-failing-people-with-autism-and-learning-disabilities/"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I spoke in a Westminster Hall Debate in Parliament on ‘Winterbourne View Hospital and the Transforming Care Programme’</p>
<p>On the 31<sup>st</sup> May 2011 a <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-bristol-20084254">BBC Panorama documentary</a> revealed appalling abuse of people with a learning disability and/or autism at the Winterbourne View Assessment and Treatment Unit (ATU).</p>
<p>Footage of patients being repeatedly assaulted and mocked by staff shocked people across the country. In response the Government promised to take people with a learning disability and/or autism out of ATUs and instead support them to live in the community.</p>
<p>10 years of missed targets later and there are still 2,040 people with a learning disability and/or autism living in ATUs that are completely inappropriate for their needs. The decade of failure to deliver on promises made after Winterboune View is the worst I’ve seen in 25 years of working in health and social care.</p>
<p>You can read my full speech <a href="https://hansard.parliament.uk/Commons/2021-06-10/debates/5D7244C3-A7AD-4EBD-AFBB-0769CD30601F/WinterbourneViewHospitalAndTheTransformingCareProgramme#contribution-EC751F03-D711-40B2-A1EF-5219D855372F">here</a>, or watch it <a href="https://www.parliamentlive.tv/Event/Index/28633de5-547b-49b8-8626-dde8f2b4b1cd">here</a>.</p>
<div style="width: 720px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-11106-1" width="720" height="720" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WhatsApp-Video-2021-06-11-at-12.11.15-1.mp4?_=1" /><a href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WhatsApp-Video-2021-06-11-at-12.11.15-1.mp4">https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WhatsApp-Video-2021-06-11-at-12.11.15-1.mp4</a></video></div>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-5008" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-west-business-forum-25th-january-2013/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/1.jpg" alt="Leicester West Business Forum 25th January 2013" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/leicester-west-business-forum-25th-january-2013/" class="wp_rp_title">Leicester West Business Forum 25th January 2013</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-6938" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/mansion-tax-plans-to-fund-scottish-nurses-causes-furious-labour-row-the-mirror-6-january/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/5.jpg" alt="Mansion tax plans to fund Scottish nurses causes furious Labour row (The Mirror, 6 January)" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/mansion-tax-plans-to-fund-scottish-nurses-causes-furious-labour-row-the-mirror-6-january/" class="wp_rp_title">Mansion tax plans to fund Scottish nurses causes furious Labour row (The Mirror, 6 January)</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-6313" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-hosts-public-meeting-on-crime-around-the-narborough-road/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/13.jpg" alt="Liz hosts public meeting on crime around the Narborough Road" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-hosts-public-meeting-on-crime-around-the-narborough-road/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz hosts public meeting on crime around the Narborough Road</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-6237" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/teens-share-video-tips-on-web-use-leicester-mercury-28-march/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/20.jpg" alt="Teens share video tips on web use (Leicester Mercury, 28 March)" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/teens-share-video-tips-on-web-use-leicester-mercury-28-march/" class="wp_rp_title">Teens share video tips on web use (Leicester Mercury, 28 March)</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-5367" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-in-family-fun-day/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Summers-Cafe-260x2191-150x150.jpg" alt="Liz joins in family fun day" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-joins-in-family-fun-day/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz joins in family fun day</a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/government-failing-people-with-autism-and-learning-disabilities/">Government failing people with autism and learning disabilities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
		<link href="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WhatsApp-Video-2021-06-11-at-12.11.15-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="0" type=""/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>East West Rail Consultation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/east-west-rail-consultation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Djanogly responds to the East West Rail Company’s non-statutory consultation. &lt;span class='read-more'&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jonathandjanogly.com/content/east-west-rail-consultation" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;read&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;&amp;raquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>5034 at https://www.jonathandjanogly.com</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T14:13:41Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T14:13:41Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Job advert – Constituency Engagement Officer / Caseworker</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/job-advert-constituency-engagement-officer-caseworker/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team to support her constituency work.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This role will be full-time, based in Tulip’s constituency of Hampstead and Kilburn. We are happy to discuss options for flexible working at any stage.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The successful applicant will have a strong understanding of politics and campaigning, an unstoppable work ethic, a team-first mentality and meticulous attention to detail.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key responsibilities:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;• Manage relationships with the many and varied communities in Hampstead and Kilburn;&lt;br&gt;• Monitor local media and work with stakeholders in the constituency to ensure our office is aware of ongoing issues;&lt;br&gt;• Ensure local stakeholders are kept up-to-date with the latest relevant news from Parliament and maintain databases of contacts;&lt;br&gt;• Arrange and assist with surgeries, public meetings and other visits, and follow up as appropriate;&lt;br&gt;• Deal professionally and confidentially with standard queries from members of the public, as well as assisting on more complex cases;&lt;br&gt;• Respond directly to constituents by phone and email, log and monitor casework progress &amp;#8211; gathering relevant information and following up as required;&lt;br&gt;• Correspond and liaise with Government departments, executive agencies, local government and charities to resolve constituency matters;&lt;br&gt;• Ensure records are kept in line with the data protection legislation;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills and values:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;• Sound judgement in dealing with sensitive issues;&lt;br&gt;• Strong awareness of local and national politics;&lt;br&gt;• Excellent attention to detail;&lt;br&gt;• Ability to prioritise and manage a large workload independently;&lt;br&gt;• Fluent and clear written style;&lt;br&gt;• Good communication and teamwork skills;&lt;br&gt;• Proficiency in basic IT;&lt;br&gt;• Sympathetic to the aims and values of the Labour Party;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Upon appointment you will be required to comply with the Baseline Personnel Security Standard, undertaken by the Members’ Staff Verification Office (MSVO). See&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.w4mp.org/jobs-listings-events/jobs/members-staff-security-verification-questionnaire/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;Members’ Staff Verification Office (MSVO)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;page for further info. MPs generally pay staff in accordance with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.w4mp.org/library/guides/researchguides/your-employment-status/staff-salary-scales/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;IPSA guidelines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closing Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 21 June 2021&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Interviews will be held in the week beginning 26 June 2021&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applicants should send their CV with a covering letter to:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="&amp;#x6d;&amp;#97;il&amp;#x74;&amp;#x6f;:t&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#105;p.&amp;#x73;&amp;#105;dd&amp;#x69;&amp;#x71;&amp;#46;m&amp;#x70;&amp;#x40;&amp;#112;ar&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x69;am&amp;#x65;&amp;#x6e;&amp;#116;.&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6b;"&gt;tu&amp;#108;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x70;.si&amp;#100;&amp;#x64;&amp;#x69;q.m&amp;#112;&amp;#x40;&amp;#x70;ar&amp;#108;&amp;#x69;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x6d;en&amp;#116;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#x75;&amp;#x6b;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the title “Job application: &amp;lt;your name&amp;gt;”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The covering letter should include an explanation why your skills, experience and knowledge make you suitable for this specific role for the Member of Parliament for Hampstead and Kilburn and why you would like to work in this community.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Tulip Siddiq MP is looking for an enthusiastic and responsible individual to join her busy team to support her constituency work. This role will be full-time, based in Tulip’s constituency of Hampstead and Kilburn. We are happy to discuss options for flexible working at any stage. The successful applicant will […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5458</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T13:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T13:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaigning"/>
    <category term="caseworker"/>
    <category term="constituency engagement"/>
    <category term="Job ad"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>World first for Dafen Primary!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2021/06/world-first-for-dafen-primary/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8166" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2021/06/world-first-for-dafen-primary/210609-dafen-primary-group/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=1777%2C1121&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1777,1121" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="210609 Dafen Primary Group" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=300%2C189&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=790%2C498&amp;ssl=1"/>
<p>Great to be at Dafen Primary School yesterday to see them become the world’s first Global Entrecompedu Pioneer School.</p>



<p>Pupils, staff and many others involved with the school have worked really hard to embrace the scheme which gives children of all year groups the skills and knowledge needed to understand the world of business and commerce.</p>



<p>Particularly inspiring to hear directly from the children about how they put protecting the environment and collaborating with others at the centre of their work.</p>



<p>Congratulations to everyone involved and good luck with helping to share your experiences with other schools in the local area and across the UK and Europe!</p>



<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/hashtag/entrecompedu?__eep__=6&amp;__cft__[0]=AZX0hqFA5h2kRJduGv-2iKetVYE1PdXkxr764BEE0Xt4zyM3G9lXi3gGhl5Rz_MP43sOFS5zwABk58iJ77huGvy_yOPXVXh_9YcXOcLE8LFF29NFfB_9aDKH7oo32XVRPU5qiWxJ9bYcwCFDxwTtgp2EaCOWoJ3KrxfmTnF4Rh9MSdIphyAELTF_Z6GwZHuUwjc&amp;__tn__=*NK-R">#EntreCompEdu</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/hashtag/proudmp?__eep__=6&amp;__cft__[0]=AZX0hqFA5h2kRJduGv-2iKetVYE1PdXkxr764BEE0Xt4zyM3G9lXi3gGhl5Rz_MP43sOFS5zwABk58iJ77huGvy_yOPXVXh_9YcXOcLE8LFF29NFfB_9aDKH7oo32XVRPU5qiWxJ9bYcwCFDxwTtgp2EaCOWoJ3KrxfmTnF4Rh9MSdIphyAELTF_Z6GwZHuUwjc&amp;__tn__=*NK-R">#ProudMP</a></p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><img width="500" height="277" src="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1" class="attachment-charitas-lite-medium-thumb size-charitas-lite-medium-thumb wp-post-image" alt="" style="float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;" srcset="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=272%2C150&amp;ssl=1 272w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?resize=500%2C277&amp;ssl=1 500w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?zoom=2&amp;resize=500%2C277 1000w, https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?zoom=3&amp;resize=500%2C277 1500w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" data-attachment-id="8166" data-permalink="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2021/06/world-first-for-dafen-primary/210609-dafen-primary-group/" data-orig-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=1777%2C1121&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1777,1121" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="210609 Dafen Primary Group" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=300%2C189&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i1.wp.com/niagriffith.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/210609-Dafen-Primary-Group.jpg?fit=790%2C498&amp;ssl=1"/>Great to be at Dafen Primary School yesterday to see them become the world’s first Global Entrecompedu Pioneer School. Pupils, staff and many others involved with the school have worked really hard to embrace the scheme which gives children of all year groups the skills and knowledge needed to understand the world of business and […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8165</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T12:54:44Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T12:54:44Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP urges EU citizens to apply to Settlement Scheme</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/06/10/mp-urges-eu-citizens-to-apply-to-settlement-scheme/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Angus MacNeil MP for Na h-Eileanan an Iar is urging any constituent who is an EU citizen to ensure they have applied to the EU Settlement Scheme (EUSS) before the deadline of June 30.</p>



<p>Irish citizens and people with indefinite leave to remain do not have to apply but all other EU citizens must apply to the scheme to continue living or working in Scotland.</p>



<p>Both adults and children need to apply.</p>



<p>Mr MacNeil said: “It is the Scottish Government’s view that EU citizens should not need to apply to protect the right they already have to live, work and study here but the UK Government has made it a requirement.</p>



<p>“The deadline is the end of this month and so I would urge any constituent who is an EU citizen who has not already done so, to apply.”</p>



<p>Scotland’s Europe Minister Jenny Gilruth has requested that the UK Government make a series of urgent changes to the EU Settlement Scheme (EUSS) – including extending the 30 June deadline.</p>



<p>Full details on how to apply can be found here: <a href="https://www.mygov.scot/help-eu-citizens">https://www.mygov.scot/help-eu-citizens</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg"><img data-attachment-id="3022" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/ab6a/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg" data-orig-size="640,481" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="ab6a" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-3022" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg 640w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2020/05/ab6a.jpg?w=300 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px"/></a></figure>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Angus MacNeil MP for Na h-Eileanan an Iar is urging any constituent who is an EU citizen to ensure they …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2021/06/10/mp-urges-eu-citizens-to-apply-to-settlement-scheme/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=3511</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T11:35:08Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T11:35:08Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health inequalities in St Helens North</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2021/06/10/health-inequalities-in-st-helens-north/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>mancyia.uddin@parliament.uk</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=6538</id>
    <published>2021-06-10T11:31:50Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-10T11:31:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Covid mortality rate for Sikhs worsened between the first and second wave </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/covid-mortality-rate-sikhs-worsened-between-first-and-second-wave" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"><p>Preet Kaur Gill MP has called on the Government to urgently address health disparities between religious groups after new Covid data shows growing divergence.  </p>
<p>The latest ONS data emphasises the alarming Covid mortality rates among Sikhs, Hindus, Jews and Muslims compared to Christians and people of no faith. </p>
<p>Even more worryingly, this data shows that the Covid mortality rate for Sikhs and Muslims compared to Christians has worsened between the first and second wave. For Sikh men, the age-adjusted risk increased from 1.3 times to that of Christians, to 1.7 times. </p>
<p>Preet Kaur Gill, MP for Edgbaston in Birmingham said, “Given the great pain experienced by the Sikh community during the worst of the first wave last year, it is extremely disturbing to see that not only has the work done on health disparities failed to keep up with the problem, it’s gone backwards” </p>
<p>“We know that structural inequalities stretch through every aspect of life and have a part to play in the enormous differences we have seen between different ethnic groups. However, these inequalities cannot be explained by ethnicity alone, and this new data paints a complex picture.  </p>
<p>“I have written to the equalities minister to ask that the lack of routine data collected on Sikhs is addressed. Currently, the ONS advises public bodies to only use the existing ethnic categories in the census to deliver public services. This excludes information for groups including Sikhs and Jews. Given the fact that this new information on Covid mortality rates shows stark differences between majority Asian religious groups, it seems increasingly misguided to ignore these factors. </p>
<p>“Better data and knowledge is integral in addressing disparities, especially when as it stands routine data collection for Sikhs does not exist. Public bodies must have better information on the communities they serve in order to address these shocking health inequalities.” </p>
<p>Dr Sukdev Singh, a resident in Edgbaston constituency, not only sadly lost a loved one to Covid but is also Chair of the Sikh Doctor’s Association and has had to support patients and families throughout the pandemic.  </p>
<p>He commented, “It is really concerning to see inequalities seemingly grow between Sikh people and those from other backgrounds. I’ve seen first-hand how devastating this virus has been to my family and my community. It’s disappointing that the Government hasn’t done more to protect those that are being the worst affected by the pandemic, particularly given the national debate on equality that was widely publicised following the first wave. </p>
<p>“The Government now needs to step up and support those who are worse affected so that we can recover from this crisis. But before these inequalities can be put remedied, the Government needs to start with understanding exactly how many people are from a Sikh ethnic background so that the right resource and funding can be sent to those communities.” </p>
<p>To read the letter from Preet Kaur Gill MP to the equalities minister, where she asks for an explanation on the steps being taken to ensure the disproportionate impact of Covid-19 on Sikhs is explained and in turn addressed with future monitoring of public service provision, please visit: <a href="https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-responds-news-covid-death-inequalities-worsened-between-waves" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">https://preetkaurgill.com/content/preet-responds-news-covid-death-inequalities-worsened-between-waves</a> </p>
<p><strong>ENDS </strong></p>
<p><em>Information for editors: </em></p>
<p>For the latest ONS data release on deaths involving Covid-19 by religious group, please see here: <a href="https://www.ons.gov.uk/releases/deathsinvolvingcovid19byreligiousgroupenglanddeathsoccurringbetween24january2020and28february2021" rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank">https://www.ons.gov.uk/releases/deathsinvolvingcovid19byreligiousgroupenglanddeathsoccurringbetween24january2020and28february2021</a> </p>
</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-term field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-hidden clearfix">
          <ul class="links">
            <li class="taxonomy-term-reference-0">
              <a href="/tags/news" typeof="skos:Concept" property="rdfs:label skos:prefLabel" datatype="">News</a>
            </li>
          </ul>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-format field-type-list-text field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">Standard (Image)</div>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="field field-name-field-post-image field-type-image field-label-hidden">
          <div class="field-items">
            <div class="field-item even">
              <img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://preetkaurgill.com/sites/default/files/Screenshot%202021-06-09%20145506.jpg" width="456" height="625" alt="Letter from Preet Kaur Gill MP on health inequalities"/>
            </div>
          </div>
        </div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Editor</name>
    </author>
    <id>972 at https://preetkaurgill.com</id>
    <published>2021-06-09T13:59:39Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-09T13:59:39Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bill Wiggin MP Celebrates 20 years of Representing Leominster/North Herefordshire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2021/06/08/bill-wiggin-mp-celebrates-20-years-of-representing-leominster-north-herefordshire/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">“Today marks the 20th anniversary of my election as Member of Parliament for Leominster and North Herefordshire. I clearly remember the feeling of immense responsibility, and excitement that I had on that night – the 6th June 2001. It is... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2021/06/08/bill-wiggin-mp-celebrates-20-years-of-representing-leominster-north-herefordshire/#more-3917">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=3917</id>
    <published>2021-06-08T16:57:50Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-08T16:57:50Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local MP joins ‘Great British Spring Clean’ at Hatfield Station</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.shapps.com/local-mp-joins-great-british-spring-clean-at-hatfield-station/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=local-mp-joins-great-british-spring-clean-at-hatfield-station" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="et_pb_section et_pb_section_0 et_section_regular">
				
				
				
				
					<div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_0">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_0  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_text et_pb_text_0  et_pb_text_align_left et_pb_bg_layout_light">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_text_inner"><p><strong>Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps joins Network Rail staff as he drives to get rail network clean as country moves to re-open</strong></p>
<p>Mr Shapps attended a clean-up at the front of the station, helping clean the area of litter, as part of the ‘Great British Spring Clean- organised by Keep Britain Tidy.</p>
<p>At the station Mr Shapps met with Network Rail and station staff, donning protective gloves and a litter picker.</p>
<p>Of the visit, Mr Shapps said: “I’ve challenged Network Rail to clean up the network as much as possible before people start coming back, as we hope, get to the next stage of the unlock.</p>
<p>“I think it’s really important to make people feel more confident about being on the railway. I’m a big believer that if people find that the environment around them is clean, they feel happier and healthier. It helps people’s mental health [and] also helps with physical health as well.</p>
<p>“The Great British Spring Clean is a fantastic initiative, and I’m incredibly happy to be able to support it.”</p>
<p>Paul Rutter, Chief Environment and Sustainability Officer for Network Rail said: “So far, the local team have cleared 500 bags- nearly 5 tonnes rubbish- in the local area between Hatfield and Brookmans Park. Now we’re going to continue through to Finsbury Park and closer to London.</p>
<p>“[We are doing this] not just to make it look better, but also safer for employees and the travelling public.”</p>
<p>The Spring Clean runs until the 13<sup>th</sup> June. So far over 160,000 volunteers have pledged to tidy over 1 million miles of roads, rivers, beaches, and countryside.</p>
<p>Details about the campaign can be found here: <a href="http://www.keepbritaintidy.org">www.keepbritaintidy.org</a></p>
<p>A video was produced during the visit, which can be viewed below.<span style="font-size: 14px;"> </span></p></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_text -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row --><div class="et_pb_row et_pb_row_1">
				<div class="et_pb_column et_pb_column_4_4 et_pb_column_1  et_pb_css_mix_blend_mode_passthrough et-last-child">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_module et_pb_code et_pb_code_0">
				
				
				<div class="et_pb_code_inner"><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=314&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fgrant.shapps%2Fvideos%2F1217240758727562%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" width="1000" height="450" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowFullScreen="true"/></div>
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_code -->
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_column -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_row -->
				
				
			</div> <!-- .et_pb_section -->
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Welwyn Hatfield MP Grant Shapps joins Network Rail staff as he drives to get rail network clean as country moves to re-open</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Jacob Groet</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.shapps.com/?p=35022</id>
    <published>2021-06-04T15:49:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T15:49:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Transport"/>
    <category term="Grant Shapps"/>
    <category term="Great British Spring Clean"/>
    <category term="Hatfield"/>
    <category term="Hatfield Station"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on proposals for Dunston Grange extension</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/tobyperkinsmp/~3/Bn9p3cVlDrY/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>chriswilliams</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=4792</id>
    <published>2021-06-04T14:12:28Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T14:12:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Borderers benefit from UK Government support</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borderers-benefit-uk-government-support" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Since July 2020, self-employed business owners in the Borders have been able to apply for four consecutive grants to help alleviate the economic impact of Covid-19.
In the Borders, 2,800 individual claims were made, and a total of £8,000,000 was awarded across these claims. The average value per…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/news/borderers-benefit-uk-government-support</id>
    <published>2021-06-04T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-04T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate Action Newcastle]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2021/06/03/climate-action-newcastle/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=507</id>
		<updated>2021-06-03T18:43:28Z</updated>
		<published>2021-06-03T18:32:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2021/06/03/climate-action-newcastle/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE MOVING TO LEVEL 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-moving-to-level-1/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In a statement today to the Scottish Parliament, First Minister Nicola Sturgeon confirmed that West Dunbartonshire will move from Level 2 to Level 1 covid-19 protection measures from 00:01 on Saturday 5 June 2021. The full list of local authority … <a href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-moving-to-level-1/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot/west-dunbartonshire-moving-to-level-1/">WEST DUNBARTONSHIRE MOVING TO LEVEL 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://martindocherty.scot">Martin Docherty-Hughes MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://martindocherty.scot/?p=1569996</id>
    <published>2021-06-01T15:13:42Z</published>
    <updated>2021-06-01T15:13:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Campaign Emails"/>
    <category term="Latest Issues"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>May 2021 E-Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/may-2021-e-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Debbie's <span style="color:#06396a;">monthly update</span></h3></div><div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>

	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>This edition contains  an update on Covid-19 and my activities across the constituency and in Parliament.</p>
<p>Read the <a href="https://mailchi.mp/847f992cd5a7/news-from-debbie-abrahams-mp-may-4768638">full edition here.</a></p>

		</div>
	</div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/may-2021-e-newsletter/">May 2021 E-Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/may-2021-e-newsletter/">May 2021 E-Newsletter</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=6811</id>
    <published>2021-05-31T14:08:41Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-31T14:08:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Localism"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Oldham &amp; Saddleworth"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="E-newsletter"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/05/28/funding-opportunities/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><h3 style="text-align: center">Funding Sources</h3>
<p>Below is an updated list of funding for Voluntary Organisations and Charities  as of 28th May 2021.</p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/External-Funding-Newsletter-as-at-14th-May-2021.docx">External Funding Newsletter as at 14th May 2021</a></p>
<p><a href="https://whitford.scot/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/External-Funding-Newsletter-as-at-28th-May-2021.docx">External Funding Newsletter as at 28th May 2021</a></p>


<p/>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook a2a_counter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_facebook_messenger" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook_messenger?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Facebook Messenger" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_whatsapp" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/whatsapp?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="WhatsApp" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_button_copy_link" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/copy_link?linkurl=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;linkname=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" title="Copy Link" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"/><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https%3A%2F%2Fwhitford.scot%2F2021%2F05%2F28%2Ffunding-opportunities%2F&amp;title=Funding%20Opportunities%20for%20Voluntary%20Organisations%20%26%20Charities" data-a2a-url="https://whitford.scot/2021/05/28/funding-opportunities/" data-a2a-title="Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities"/></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/05/28/funding-opportunities/">Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Funding Sources Below is an updated list of funding for Voluntary Organisations and Charities  as ... <a title="Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities" class="read-more" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/05/28/funding-opportunities/">Click to Read More</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot/2021/05/28/funding-opportunities/">Funding Opportunities for Voluntary Organisations &amp; Charities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://whitford.scot">Dr Philippa Whitford</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Heather Knox</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://whitford.scot/?p=2133</id>
    <published>2021-05-28T22:06:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-28T22:06:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Constituency"/>
    <category term="Events &amp; Community Groups"/>
    <category term="charities"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="voluntary groups"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Railway</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-railway" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week life has been dominated by talk about trains. There are two separate issues which will affect us in Ashford: the reform of the railways across the country and the new rescue package for Eurostar.
On the first, the replacement of the franchise system with a model based on Transport for…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-railway</id>
    <published>2021-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-27T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>JOB ADVERT: Communications Intern</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/job-advert-communications-intern/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=job-advert-communications-intern" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">		&lt;div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="6105" class="elementor elementor-6105" data-elementor-settings="[]"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-inner"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-section-wrap"&gt;
							&lt;section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-50c47387 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="50c47387" data-element_type="section"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-row"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-3fea2c95" data-id="3fea2c95" data-element_type="column"&gt;
			&lt;div class="elementor-column-wrap elementor-element-populated"&gt;
							&lt;div class="elementor-widget-wrap"&gt;
						&lt;div class="elementor-element elementor-element-5c2b4e15 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="5c2b4e15" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default"&gt;
				&lt;div class="elementor-widget-container"&gt;
					&lt;div class="elementor-text-editor elementor-clearfix"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Communications Intern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Inverness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hours: &amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;span style="color: var( --e-global-color-text ); font-family: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-family ); font-weight: var( --e-global-typography-text-font-weight );"&gt;35.00 hours per week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salary Band:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Meets Scottish Living Wage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration: &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;3 months (Fixed Term)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is part of a rolling internship programme created by Drew Hendry MP to provide young people living in the &lt;strong&gt;Inverness, Nairn, Badenoch &amp;amp; Strathspey&lt;/strong&gt; constituency with the opportunity to work in a parliamentary office.&amp;nbsp; The postholder will work with Drew and his team for a 3-month fixed period as Communications Intern. This role is best suited to a young person who has already studied communication or multimedia, or someone interested in a career in Communications or in Politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal candidate will be able to demonstrate they share our team values of &lt;strong&gt;empathy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;professionalism, responsibility and pragmaticism&amp;nbsp; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Responsibilities &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with MP to promote work in the community, liaising with community leaders and local businesses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping up to date with current media developments in the local and national press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assisting in the management of social media channels, including using and monitoring to communicate with stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for creating high-quality digital content, including social media images, newsletters, and video clips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare press releases on local and national campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fostering good working relationships with community groups, press contacts and other stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributing to communications plan and media strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support the work of the MP in parliament by attending events and meetings as required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Undertake research and create briefings papers as required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining systems as required to support communications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responding to enquiries by telephone and email, passing on queries to other team members/MP as appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Person Specification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passionate about improving outcomes for people and communities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Knowledge of politics and current affairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excellent written and oral communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT literate, including competence in the MS Office Suite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience in using social media and ability to share content across platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to write high-quality press releases and produce briefings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to work independently and as part of a team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proven ability to produce high quality, detailed work within tight timeframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible approach to working with the ability to work on own initiative and under time pressure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon appointment, the candidate will be required to comply with UK Parliament security checks. Any offer of employment is dependent on the prospective employee meeting the Baseline Personnel Security Standard, undertaken by the Members’ Staff Verification Office (MSVO).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closing Date: 14 June 2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application Details: Applications in the form of a CV with a covering letter describing your skills and experience in relation to the requirements of the job to &lt;a href="mailto:frances.simmonds@parliament.uk"&gt;frances.simmonds@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
								&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;/section&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
						&lt;/div&gt;
					&lt;/div&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/job-advert-communications-intern/"&gt;JOB ADVERT: Communications Intern&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"&gt;Drew Hendry MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Post Title:           Communications Intern Location:             Inverness Hours:      ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/job-advert-communications-intern/">JOB ADVERT: Communications Intern</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot">Drew Hendry MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6105</id>
    <published>2021-05-25T15:41:51Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-25T15:41:51Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Melksham Hub Cafe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-hub-cafe/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>I was delighted to formally open the brand new Melksham Hub Café the other week. The café and community space at Melksham Railway Station is located in a former commercial depot building and is a fantastic addition to the railway station. There is an extensive menu, and from today you can eat in as well as takeaway.</p>



<p>This is an amazing community effort involving Wiltshire Council, Melksham Area Board, TransWilts and commercial partners Knorr-Bremse as well many others to make Melksham Railway Station a really attractive and user friendly place to travel to and from the town, be sure to check it out!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><a href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n.jpg"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="792" src="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-1024x792.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-34019" srcset="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-1024x792.jpg 1024w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-300x232.jpg 300w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-768x594.jpg 768w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-1536x1188.jpg 1536w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-710x549.jpg 710w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n-1030x796.jpg 1030w, https://michelledonelan.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/188285848_2408546482613272_1490935144495939503_n.jpg 1821w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px"/></a></figure>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-hub-cafe/">Melksham Hub Cafe</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was delighted to formally open the brand new Melksham Hub Café the other week. The café and community space at Melksham Railway Station is located in a former commercial depot building and is a fantastic addition to the railway station. There is an extensive menu, and from today you can eat in as well...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk/melksham-hub-cafe/">Melksham Hub Cafe</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://michelledonelan.co.uk">Michelle Donelan MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Donelan</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://michelledonelan.co.uk/?p=34018</id>
    <published>2021-05-19T16:06:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-19T16:06:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Melksham"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Vision for Social Care</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/05/13/a-vision-for-social-care/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In the Queens Speech there was a noticeable absence of plans for adult social care, despite the Prime Minister saying as he entered Downing Street in 2019 “we will fix the crisis in social care once and for all” and despite promises of a White Paper since 2017. People in Nottingham and the rest of the country desperately need a social care system that is adequately funded over the long term and  free at the point of use. Everyone contributes, everyone’s covered – just like our NHS. Local councils like ours will still need to lead in this area as we are best placed to support people to be independent and live the lives they want to, given the range of ways that our wider work and partnerships touch everyone’s lives. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has shown how important social care is for people and though social care workers do an amazing job, the growing demand alongside chronic underfunding is pushing the sector further into crisis. In March I wrote to the Government along with local Labour MPs highlighting the need for a fair and adequate funding system for social care, quoting the Association of Directors of Adult Social Services (ADASS) who said that £1,3 billion is needed to cover demographic and inflationary pressures in 2021, Cllr Williams has  yet to receive a reply.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;Social care workers in our city support people to live well, maximising independence, choice and control. But they and the people they support, alongside their unpaid carers need a national  long term plan for social care that recognises that this is skilled  and vital work to support adults  of all ages to make their own choices, and the best of their lives at every stage. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Government’s current approach has been the adult social care precept, hitting Nottingham’s hard pressed council tax payers. This precept represents a significant sum to local households, but makes a negligible impact on the pressures to the Council’s budget in this area. An inadequate sticking plaster that costs Nottingham tax payers dearly – hitting household incomes at a time of economic crisis. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;In March I wrote to the Government highlighting the need for a fair and adequate funding system for social care that covers everyone. I have yet to receive a reply. The absence of any plans in the Queen’s Speech  makes clear that  Government is going to leave those supported by adult social care, those who are paid to care, and unpaid carers left without a long term solution to the issues they experience every day. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In Wales and Scotland their Government’s are rising to the
challenges with commitments to paying care workers a real living wage and
considering a “National Care Service”. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is a real failure to grasp the reality and urgency
&amp;nbsp;of the problem. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We urge the government to listen to the nation. Just as we
have raised our voices when needed to defend our NHS, when we clapped for
carers, we meant it. They would do well to listen –
and act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/05/13/a-vision-for-social-care/"&gt;A Vision for Social Care&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk"&gt;Nottingham Labour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>In the Queens Speech there was a noticeable absence of plans for adult social care, despite the Prime Minister saying as he entered Downing Street in 2019 “we will fix the crisis in social care once and for all” and despite promises of a White Paper since 2017. People in Nottingham and the rest of...</p>
<p><a class="moretag" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/05/13/a-vision-for-social-care/">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2021/05/13/a-vision-for-social-care/">A Vision for Social Care</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk">Nottingham Labour</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Craig Stanley</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2673</id>
    <published>2021-05-13T07:52:20Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-13T07:52:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Speaking to Stop Vexatious Claims Against Northern Ireland Veterans on 11 May 2021</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/speaking-stop-vexatious-claims-against-northern-ireland-veterans-11-may-2021" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I listened very carefully to the Gracious Speech, and I made the assumption that the promise to address the legacy of the past with regard to Northern Ireland refers to a Government commitment to protect veterans from vexatious and repeated prosecutions. That assurance was solidified when I looked…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/speaking-stop-vexatious-claims-against-northern-ireland-veterans-11-may-2021</id>
    <published>2021-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-12T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When it comes to aid, the Devil, as always, is in the detail</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/when-it-comes-aid-devil-always-detail" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">My comments on the aid situation;  https://www.thearticle.com/when-it-comes-to-aid-the-devil-as-always-is-…
 
When the extent of the pandemic became clear in the early part of 2020, the Government’s understandable concern became how to pay for what was anticipated, correctly, to be an unprecedented…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.alistair-burt.co.uk/news/when-it-comes-aid-devil-always-detail</id>
    <published>2021-05-04T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-04T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis - Message of Solidarity on Worker's Memorial Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/iwmd21" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Worker’s Memorial Day is always a poignant moment each year. It’s an opportunity to reflect on those workers who’ve lost their lives in the workplace. It’s a chance to pay tribute to the incredible campaigning efforts of our trade union and labour movement. And it’s a chance to recommit ourselves to the fight for a better, safer world of work.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/iwmd21</id>
    <published>2021-04-28T07:44:33+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-04-28T07:44:33+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The vaccine roll-out continues</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/the-vaccine-roll-out-continues/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">I am delighted to see the continued success of the vaccine rollout, not just here in the West Midlands, but across the country.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">The NHS has administered a total of 44.4 million vaccines across the UK, helping to cut infection rates and reduce the spread of the virus. Over 60% of all adults have now been vaccinated, with over 11.1 million people receiving both doses.</div>
<div dir="auto"/>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto">The NHS are now requesting all those aged 45 or over to book an appointment. You can do so here: <a class="oajrlxb2 g5ia77u1 qu0x051f esr5mh6w e9989ue4 r7d6kgcz rq0escxv nhd2j8a9 nc684nl6 p7hjln8o kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x jb3vyjys rz4wbd8a qt6c0cv9 a8nywdso i1ao9s8h esuyzwwr f1sip0of lzcic4wl py34i1dx gpro0wi8" tabindex="0" role="link" href="https://www.nhs.uk/conditions/coronavirus-covid-19/coronavirus-vaccination/book-coronavirus-vaccination/?fbclid=IwAR2tmMGxsncizkRs7P90Relhk-6u-c0yE05sajem_nXiS6xW6mOuaeZTS5Q" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.nhs.uk/…/coro…/book-coronavirus-vaccination/</a></div>
</div>
<div class="o9v6fnle cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x c1et5uql ii04i59q">
<div dir="auto"/>
<div dir="auto">I pass on my thanks and gratitude to all the fantastic NHS staff and volunteers who are making the rollout so successful.</div>
</div>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to see the continued success of the vaccine rollout, not just here in the West Midlands, but across the country. The NHS has administered a total of 44.4 million vaccines across the UK, helping to cut infection rates and reduce the spread of the virus. Over 60% of all adults have now […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=3633</id>
    <published>2021-04-26T14:23:37Z</published>
    <updated>2021-04-26T14:23:37Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>March Roundup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/march-roundup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;img width="150" height="150" src="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-570x570.jpeg 570w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the vaccine rollout continues across Birmingham we can start to see some light at the end of the tunnel after what has been a truly difficult year for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We all know someone whose health or employment has been affected by the events of the past 12 months, and as we look to the end of the covid restrictions I&amp;#8217;m determined to see the government provide Birmingham with the support it needs to rebuild its healthcare and employment capacity.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;While the numbers of covid patients is decreasing, our NHS will have a mountain to climb to provide care for those with other conditions whose treatment has been deferred. Recent figures show 300,000 patients now waiting a year or more to receive care as a result of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Please don&amp;#8217;t hesitate to&amp;nbsp; contact me in the coming months if you have been affected by these issues and I can help in any way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Birmingham Coronavirus Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Following the first stage of the unlocking process, the following changes to the coronavirus restrictions came into effect on the 8th March:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wraparound childcare and other supervised children’s activities can resume where they enable parents to work, seek work, attend education, seek medical care or attend a support group&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Care home residents will be allowed one regular visitor provided they are tested and wear PPE&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Stay at Home requirement will remain, but people can leave home for recreation outdoors such as a coffee or picnic with their household or support bubble, or with one person outside their household&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some university students on practical courses will be able to return to face to face learning&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call for an independent inquiry into the Government&amp;#8217;s handling of the pandemic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;img loading="lazy" width="1000" height="430" src="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/liam-update.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-8068" srcset="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/liam-update.jpeg 1000w, https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/liam-update-300x129.jpeg 300w, https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/liam-update-768x330.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alongside my fellow Birmingham Labour MPs and Council leader Ian Ward, I have called for a full independent public inquiry into the government’s handling of the Covid pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many residents have raised this issue with me, and want to know why the UK had the highest death rates in the world and whether these deaths were preventable. I believe we have a duty to those who have lost loved ones to ensure a full, independent, and transparent investigation into how our country has handled the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;The pandemic has undoubtedly presented unprecedented challenges to governments around the world. There has not been a crisis like this is living memory and combatting this deadly virus was always going to be difficult. However, it must be acknowledged that the UK has seen one of the highest death tolls in the world and questions are now rightly being asked about what led us to this position.&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can read the full letter &lt;a href="https://liambyrnemp.co.uk/sites/default/files/Letter%20to%20Rt%20Hon%20B%20Johnson%20Prime%20Minister.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support for a nurses pay rise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Over the past year our health workers have given everything while under historic pressure to save lives and cope with the huge number of extra patients in our hospitals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After all they&amp;#8217;ve been through it cannot be right that the 12,289 nurses in Birmingham have been offered a real terms pay cut by the government. We must do better for them than that, after all they&amp;#8217;ve done for the country there must be a fair pay settlement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve all been encouraged to show our appreciation throughout this crisis, but claps don&amp;#8217;t pay the bills. I sincerely hope that the government will reconsider its recommended 1% pay increase.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebrating St Patrick&amp;#8217;s Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This St Patrick’s Day was unlike any other in generations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Coming from an Irish family, I saw the great solidarity and cohesion of the Irish community in Britain. It is heart-warming to witness this togetherness reaffirm itself during these challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I hope that all members of the Irish community in Hodge Hill found a way to mark the day, and that next year we will be able to come together as usual!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fighting to safeguard employment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Second only to the health impact of Coronavirus is its impact on the economy and employment. That is why I&amp;#8217;ve written to the Chancellor Rishi Sunak calling for a £7.8 billion Budget ‘fair share funding’ boost for our area to tackle the jobs crisis.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Businesses need help to bounce back from the Covid crisis, and we must do every we can to support them by extending the furlough scheme in a targeted way, extending business interruption and bounce back loans, enabling interest free deferral of VAT, and extending targeted business rate relief.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alongside help for existing business we must make sure big projects such as HS2 and the Commonwealth Games deliver jobs and long term benefits for local people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can currently apply for one of over 200 vacancies with HS2 and its partners at the following link: &lt;a href="https://www.hs2.org.uk/careers/careers-with-our-supply-chain/jobs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://www.hs2.org.uk/careers/careers-with-our-supply-chain/jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/march-roundup/"&gt;March Roundup&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk"&gt;Liam Byrne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><img width="150" height="150" src="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-150x150.jpeg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail wp-post-image" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-150x150.jpeg 150w, https://liambyrne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/IMG_2088-1024x731-1-570x570.jpeg 570w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px"/>As the vaccine rollout continues across Birmingham we can start to see some light at the end of the tunnel after what has been a truly difficult year for all of us. We all know someone whose health or employment has been affected by the events of the past 12 months, and as we look […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk/march-roundup/">March Roundup</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://liambyrne.co.uk">Liam Byrne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Liam Byrne</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://liambyrne.co.uk/?p=8066</id>
    <published>2021-03-31T09:47:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-31T09:47:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Economics"/>
    <category term="Hodge Hill"/>
    <category term="NHS"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Diana stands up for Britain's Red Arrows</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/diana-stands-britains-red-arrows" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diana Johnson stood up for skilled jobs and the red arrows in the House of Commons today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diana asked the Minister:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field field-name-field-tags field-type-taxonomy-term-reference field-label-above"&gt;&lt;div class="field-label"&gt;Tags:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/14"&gt;Parliament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item odd"&gt;&lt;a href="/tags/jobs"&gt;jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even"&gt;&lt;a href="/taxonomy/term/15"&gt;Constituency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>diana</name>
    </author>
    <id>911 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-03-23T11:31:04Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-23T11:31:04Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1615380759618">

<div id="text-block-2" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- ">

	
	<p>Steve Reed has asked Croydon Council to listen to local people over the future of South Norwood Library.  The library’s future is uncertain because the Conservative Government has cut funding to Croydon by 70% and pushed it into a financial crisis.</p>
<p>Local MP Steve Reed has spoken to residents and campaign groups who are fighting to save the library.  He’s now written to the Council asking them to consider how closing the library will affect the areas poorest residents who may not have access to WiFi or quiet spaces for learning or reading at home.  He’s also asked the Council to fully involve the local community before taking any decisions.</p>
<p>Steve Reed said: “Croydon Council is faced with some really difficult decisions after ten years of Conservative funding cuts.  But they do not have to go it alone. Now more than ever people want a say over what happens in their area. The Council should harness this enthusiasm and work with residents to come up with plan that could protect library services for South Norwood.”</p>
<p><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/ue8jCq7zvFrArvJhZnZ9o?domain=stevereedmp.co.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-auth="NotApplicable">You can see the full letter here.</a></p>
<p>If you would like to get involved in the campaign to save South Norwood library, email Steve at steve.reed@croydonlabour.org.uk</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	<div class="templatera_shortcode">
<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false     js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-12 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="padding-5" class="mk-padding-divider jupiter-donut-  jupiter-donut-clearfix"/>

<div class="vc_separator wpb_content_element vc_separator_align_center vc_sep_width_100 vc_sep_border_width_2 vc_sep_pos_align_center"><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_l"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span><div class="vc_icon_element vc_icon_element-outer vc_icon_element-align-left"><div class="vc_icon_element-inner vc_icon_element-color-custom vc_icon_element-size-md vc_icon_element-style- vc_icon_element-background-color-grey"><span class="vc_icon_element-icon fa fa-ravelry" style="color:#e4003b !important"/></div></div><span class="vc_sep_holder vc_sep_holder_r"><span style="border-color:#e4003b;" class="vc_sep_line"/></span>
</div></div>
	</div>

<div data-mk-stretch-content="true" class="wpb_row vc_row vc_row-fluid jupiter-donut- mk-fullwidth-false  attched-false srmp-news-biog-row   vc_custom_1565524828402  js-master-row  mk-grid">
				
<div class="vc_col-sm-3 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
	
<div id="box-7" class="mk-employees jupiter-donut-margin-bottom-10 jupiter-donut-margin-top-10 one-column u6col u5col u4col u3col o0col  simple c_cs srmp-news-biog-picture jupiter-donut-">
	<ul>

	
		<li class="mk-employee-item jupiter-donut-colitem jupiter-donut-align-center jupiter-donut-display-inline-block jupiter-donut-float-left m_7">
			<div class="item-holder">
				<div class="team-thumbnail jupiter-donut-position-relative jupiter-donut-width-100-per jupiter-donut-height-100-per jupiter-donut-overflow-hidden rounded-true">
							<img alt="Steve Reed" title="Steve Reed" src="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/bfi_thumb/dummy-transparent-p7ncr68rldpmeabl0klitslzdo3peli33t8kue4se0.png" data-mk-image-src-set="{&quot;default&quot;:&quot;https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/MAY-17-Jo-Cox-charity-single-300x300.jpg&quot;,&quot;2x&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;mobile&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;responsive&quot;:&quot;true&quot;}"/>


					
				</div>

				<div class="team-info-wrapper m_7" itemscope="itemscope" itemtype="https://schema.org/Person">
						<span class="team-member-name jupiter-donut-font-16 jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-font-weight-bold jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-color-333">Steve Reed</span>
					<span class="team-member-position jupiter-donut-font-12 jupiter-donut-text-transform-up jupiter-donut-display-block jupiter-donut-color-777 jupiter-donut-letter-spacing-1">Member of Parliment for Croydon North</span>
					
					<div class="clearboth"/>

					
<ul class="mk-employeee-networks">
			<li><a target="_blank" href="mailto:steve.reed.mp@parliament.uk" title="Get In Touch With Steve Reed"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-envelope" data-cacheid="icon-60cc07cb4b5a8" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1792 710v794q0 66-47 113t-113 47h-1472q-66 0-113-47t-47-113v-794q44 49 101 87 362 246 497 345 57 42 92.5 65.5t94.5 48 110 24.5h2q51 0 110-24.5t94.5-48 92.5-65.5q170-123 498-345 57-39 100-87zm0-294q0 79-49 151t-122 123q-376 261-468 325-10 7-42.5 30.5t-54 38-52 32.5-57.5 27-50 9h-2q-23 0-50-9t-57.5-27-52-32.5-54-38-42.5-30.5q-91-64-262-182.5t-205-142.5q-62-42-117-115.5t-55-136.5q0-78 41.5-130t118.5-52h1472q65 0 112.5 47t47.5 113z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.facebook.com/SteveReedMP/" title="Steve Reed On Facebook"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-facebook" data-cacheid="icon-60cc07cb4b75e" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M287.935 512h-95.935v-256h-64v-88.225l64-.029-.104-51.976c0-71.976 19.517-115.77 104.299-115.77h70.588v88.242h-44.115c-33.016 0-34.603 12.328-34.603 35.342l-.131 44.162h79.345l-9.352 88.225-69.927.029-.065 256z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/stevereedmp" title="Steve Reed On Twitter"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-moon-twitter" data-cacheid="icon-60cc07cb4b8db" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path d="M512 97.209c-18.838 8.354-39.082 14.001-60.33 16.54 21.686-13 38.343-33.585 46.186-58.115-20.298 12.039-42.778 20.78-66.705 25.49-19.16-20.415-46.461-33.17-76.673-33.17-58.011 0-105.044 47.029-105.044 105.039 0 8.233.929 16.25 2.72 23.939-87.3-4.382-164.701-46.2-216.509-109.753-9.042 15.514-14.223 33.558-14.223 52.809 0 36.444 18.544 68.596 46.73 87.433-17.219-.546-33.416-5.271-47.577-13.139-.01.438-.01.878-.01 1.321 0 50.894 36.209 93.348 84.261 103-8.813 2.4-18.094 3.686-27.674 3.686-6.769 0-13.349-.66-19.764-1.886 13.368 41.73 52.16 72.103 98.126 72.948-35.95 28.175-81.243 44.967-130.458 44.967-8.479 0-16.84-.497-25.058-1.47 46.486 29.805 101.701 47.197 161.021 47.197 193.211 0 298.868-160.062 298.868-298.872 0-4.554-.103-9.084-.305-13.59 20.528-14.81 38.336-33.31 52.418-54.374z"/></svg></a></li>
			<li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.instagram.com/stevereedmp/" title="Steve Reed On Instagram"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" class="mk-svg-icon" data-name="mk-icon-instagram" data-cacheid="icon-60cc07cb4b9ca" style=" height:16px; width: 16px; " viewBox="0 0 1792 1792"><path d="M1152 896q0-106-75-181t-181-75-181 75-75 181 75 181 181 75 181-75 75-181zm138 0q0 164-115 279t-279 115-279-115-115-279 115-279 279-115 279 115 115 279zm108-410q0 38-27 65t-65 27-65-27-27-65 27-65 65-27 65 27 27 65zm-502-220q-7 0-76.5-.5t-105.5 0-96.5 3-103 10-71.5 18.5q-50 20-88 58t-58 88q-11 29-18.5 71.5t-10 103-3 96.5 0 105.5.5 76.5-.5 76.5 0 105.5 3 96.5 10 103 18.5 71.5q20 50 58 88t88 58q29 11 71.5 18.5t103 10 96.5 3 105.5 0 76.5-.5 76.5.5 105.5 0 96.5-3 103-10 71.5-18.5q50-20 88-58t58-88q11-29 18.5-71.5t10-103 3-96.5 0-105.5-.5-76.5.5-76.5 0-105.5-3-96.5-10-103-18.5-71.5q-20-50-58-88t-88-58q-29-11-71.5-18.5t-103-10-96.5-3-105.5 0-76.5.5zm768 630q0 229-5 317-10 208-124 322t-322 124q-88 5-317 5t-317-5q-208-10-322-124t-124-322q-5-88-5-317t5-317q10-208 124-322t322-124q88-5 317-5t317 5q208 10 322 124t124 322q5 88 5 317z"/></svg></a></li>
	</ul>
				</div>
			</div>
		</li>

					<div class="clearboth"/>
			</ul>
<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>
</div>

<div class="vc_col-sm-9 wpb_column column_container  jupiter-donut- _ jupiter-donut-height-full">
		<div class=" vc_custom_1566604184155">

<div id="text-block-9" class="mk-text-block  jupiter-donut- srmp-news-biog-text">

	
	<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Reed_(politician)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steven Reed</a> is Labour MP for Croydon North and Shadow Minister for Children and Families. In 2018 his private member’s bill on <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2018/07/06/mental-health-campaigners-celebrate-as-senis-law-passes-through-the-commons/">reducing violent mental health restraint</a> became law. In June 2019 he launched <a href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/achievements/inequality/">Labour’s civil society strategy</a> outlining radical plans to empower citizens and communities.</p>
<p>Steve chairs the Cooperative Councils Innovation Network, co-chairs the All-Party Parliamentary Group for London, was Leader of Lambeth Council 2006-12 where he led the council’s children’s services to become best-rated in the country and pioneered the public-health approach to tackling violent youth crime. He worked in publishing for 16 years and was an elected trade union branch secretary.</p>

	<div class="clearboth"/>
</div>

	</div>
</div>
	</div>
</div></div>
	</div>

<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/2021/03/08/steve-challenges-council-to-address-residents-concerns-over-closure-of-south-norwood-library/">Steve Reed calls on Council to work with residents to save South Norwood Library</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk">Steve Reed MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Steve Reed MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevereedmp.co.uk/?p=10621</id>
    <published>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</published>
    <updated>2021-03-08T11:17:51Z</updated>
    <category term="Croydon Community Notice Board"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett backs PM’s roadmap and highlights support for businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-pms-roadmap-and-highlights-support-businesses" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford and Vice Chairman of the Conservative Party, spoke virtually in the House of Commons debate yesterday (23 February) on Supporting Businesses and Individuals.
Sir David began his speech by welcoming the roadmap that will guide us cautiously…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-backs-pms-roadmap-and-highlights-support-businesses</id>
    <published>2021-02-24T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-24T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=ZveoKaCX" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>


</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>*Cold Weather Payments*</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2021/cold-weather-payments/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=cold-weather-payments" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The cold weather has been harsh enough recently to trigger the Cold Weather Payments System, and some residents will receive an additional £25 towards the costs of heating.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eligibility of CWPS is for those who are currently in receipt of some benefits, with pension credit serving as the most common eligibility criteria.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Residents in the following postcodes will be eligible; RG28, SO21, SP10, SP11, SP4, SP9, RG19, RG20, RG21, RG22, RG23, RG25, RG26, RG7&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A full list of eligibility criteria can be found at:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://l.facebook.com/l.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.gov.uk%2Fcold-weather-payment%2Feligibility%3Ffbclid%3DIwAR2KSAMnLquwZ-GrJEvkTUoHI5Pkaf2CVc5V0cLiwjNeQvXIIaI3OfAURfs&amp;amp;h=AT3IH1TahltgHRS9HV5x1PLwV5TxJpX85UsGq5s9nuk0F9JVVq5AmyD4GJ1NMQxPg-xQfsJo6pZLYQfYo4Wvu0YmoAonvugiW2mRjq3vgK8hbLr0tBYQZnIkvZAleqzIW1W-giiQykibBs_GfePie-Uw_KejhvTKHmdQBoBuKOvTrr5UD75mVyL-ET2QBfGr0xX8rxn79tqojyVitnusl2XsnSUAA8gVjhj0LBEc0qjiL4LTqTgUNGwlWcfZmoKa9MJetHK_3A26I2do8eq4oJr_C8BROH6YiaEh3ERfAKjEMR5BSXNw_AUhBj5VSU6cWrqIei1Rlqudx7ZUdoYWs4l_UMBn8Z648LUsjkfTq8BM6egNBKAhszqO6e8ZXZSMgaImrCF7mGb1o0gKAFsPDTKUfSPqe4hOuX2IGf9Z1fkHcCF5iRZPZ6jy24-bBLYQiHkf7gF0gwlC0B3yf1JL3XDdoFuE06n77Nga7pLNX-W3afcFiZdGxCMaODYpPCAr_z7MX2k4WmFJMxk437BsMulynszmG7QfVY8HcLOuaYlBWJb9POEz3aozKDg-y33CRgan183XuYgyE7U5js2-8w" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;https://www.gov.uk/cold-weather-payment/eligibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The cold weather has been harsh enough recently to trigger the Cold Weather Payments System, and some residents will receive an additional £25 towards the costs of heating. Eligibility of CWPS is for those who are currently in receipt of some benefits, with pension credit serving as the most common eligibility criteria. Residents in the […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Charles Hosmer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2845</id>
    <published>2021-02-09T15:32:23Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-09T15:32:23Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus.</p>
<p>Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others.</p>
<p>Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to it is changing daily.</p>
<p>Read the regulations here: <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/national-lockdown-stay-at-home">FAQs- what you can and can’t do.</a></p>
<p>Testing</p>
<p>Anybody with symptoms can book a test. To book a test <a href="https://www.gov.uk/guidance/coronavirus-covid-19-getting-tested">click here.</a></p>
<p>Vaccine</p>
<p>The UK medical regulatory agency has approved two vaccines for COVID-19. The Government has begun the largest nationwide vaccination programme in history, starting with key clinically vulnerable groups. Your GP will contact you directly with a date to get your vaccine. </p>
<p>Volunteer Support</p>
<p>Alec is working with local Leeds City Councillors to best co-ordinate volunteer efforts in our community. If you’re able to offer help please go to <a href="https://doinggoodleeds.org.uk/">www.doinggoodleeds.org.uk</a></p>
<p>Help from Alec</p>
<p>If you have a unique issue to raise with Alec that is not covered in the information above, please get in touch at alec.shelbrooke.mp@parliament.uk or via 01937 589 002. In line with national guidance, Alec and his team are working remotely but are working hard to get back to constituents as soon as possible.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>COVID-19 is a new illness that can affect your lungs and airways. It’s caused by a virus called coronavirus. Alec is advising all constituents to follow Public Health England advice for their own safety and the safety of others. Please read, share and regularly check the Government guidance as the situation and the response to...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/" title="ReadCOVID-19 Advice and Assistance">Read more »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/covid-19-advice-assistance/">COVID-19 Advice and Assistance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk">Alec Shelbrooke</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Alec Shelbrooke</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.alecshelbrooke.co.uk/?p=1737</id>
    <published>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-07T15:54:58Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brexit Deal or No Deal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2021/01/02/brexit-deal-or-no-deal/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="x_MsoNormal">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of Commons.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">From the outset, I have sought to respect the decision of the referendum in 2016 and have been happy to work with colleagues in Parliament to deliver a compromise between those 16 million people who voted to remain in the EU, and the 17 million who voted to leave with the myriad of different options that would entail. It has become clear to me over the last 4 years that many people who voted to leave the EU in Gateshead, did so for very different reasons and with very different expectations of our future relationship ranging from close alignment like Norway, to what has now been termed a hard Brexit, essentially no formal trading relationship with the European Union, operating on basic WTO rules instead. I was re-elected to represent Gateshead at the last General Election on the pledge to respect the result of the referendum and to negotiate a deal that would meet the 6 key tests.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">It would seem that successive Conservative Prime Ministers have seem set on rail-roading their respective deals through Parliament without proper scrutiny our accountability, and this week is no different. It appears to be the case that the Government may have sought to hold out for demands within the negotiations that they knew could not be agreed, around fishing quotas as an example, knowing that once these demands were dropped a deal could be agreed between both sides. They have then sought to drop these demands as Parliament goes into recess for the Christmas period, and bring back a deal of some 1200 pages for 5 hours of debate at 3 working days’ notice; 48 hours before the UK would end the transition period with no deal if this was not agreed.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">The deal itself does not satisfy the 6 key tests I was elected on, and the way in which the Government appear to have manipulated the Parliamentary calendar to force MP’s into a vote quite literally between this deal or no deal, brings great shame on any type of Parliamentary Sovereignty. What we now have in the UK is Government sovereignty without proper input or scrutiny from democratically elected Members of Parliament.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">To this end, I found that while a deal, even this deal, is better than a no deal, I could not in good conscience vote in favour of a deal which did not satisfy the key tests in the manifesto on which I was elected, and in essence to vote to help the Government extricate themselves from a mess entirely of their own making. It is the Government who have sought to negotiate this deal alone, it is they who have forced the timetable for approval and who have removed any Parliamentary Sovereignty and scrutiny from the timetable and it is the Government who must be judged on the success or failure of this deal.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">As a local resident of Gateshead for over 40 years, I absolutely hope that this deal goes far enough to safeguard jobs and livelihoods of families across the North East. I also hope that this does not lead to shortage of supplies or price increases. This affects us all, and in many ways I do not wish the Government deal to fail to protect us from any negative consequences of it. However, with the way the whole process has been manipulated to force MP’s into a corner, and with the deal not meeting the 6 key tests set out in the manifesto on which I was elected, I could not see fit to vote in favour.</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">This is the Conservative Government’s deal, their deliberate mismanagement has brought it to Parliament, on a timetable manufactured by them, with no time for appropriate scrutiny, it’s their deal and they should own it!</p>
<p class="x_MsoNormal">I hope this sets out my reasoning, as ever please do get in touch should you have any further questions.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I wanted to take a moment to explain my reasoning behind abstaining from the vote in Parliament on Wednesday (30/12) as the Governments’ Brexit deal returned to the House of</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20758</id>
    <published>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-01-02T11:19:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Gateshead"/>
    <category term="Ians views"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s December Newsletter]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"/>
		<id>http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3047</id>
		<updated>2020-12-30T11:33:26Z</updated>
		<published>2020-12-30T11:32:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com" term="All News"/>		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters here</p>
<p></p>
<p>Dear Constituent,</p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">Subscribe to my future newsletters <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/newsletter/">here</a></p>
<p><em><img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" /></em></p>
<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>
<p>Welcome to my December email newsletter. I know this year has been incredibly difficult for many families, and will continue to be very challenging, especially given the new variant of Covid, but the rollout of vaccines and community testing, which are gathering pace in Derbyshire, gives some hope for the new year. I&#8217;m sure, like me, you particularly welcome today&#8217;s announcement of the approval of the Oxford vaccine for rollout in our communities. Under these challenging circumstances, I nevertheless wish you a very safe and happy new year in 2021.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Heanor Future High Streets Fund bid success &#8211; £8.5 million:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following Heanor&#8217;s bid towards the Government&#8217;s £830 million Future High Streets Fund, I&#8217;m delighted that Heanor has been successful and has been awarded over £8.5 million to help transform its town centre and recover from the pandemic. You can find the full details of the Borough Council&#8217;s bid <a href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.ambervalley.gov.uk/business/future-high-street-fund/">here</a>, which focuses on plans to regenerate the Market Place and Grammar School site. The Council now have a few months to confirm the final version of their plans, and I look forward to continuing to support and work with them to ensure we can maximise this funding.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Brexit deal latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>On Christmas Eve, the Prime Minister reached a deal with the EU regarding our future relationship after the end of the transition period, from the 1st January 2021. Parliament has been recalled today, on the 30th December, to consider the deal and vote on it. You can read the deal <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/agreements-reached-between-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and-northern-ireland-and-the-european-union">here</a> and the legislation enabling it <a href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf" data-cke-saved-href="https://publications.parliament.uk/pa/bills/cbill/58-01/0236/20236.pdf">here</a>. The select committee on the Future Relationship with the EU on which I serve has published a report on the deal this morning, which you can read <a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/" data-cke-saved-href="https://committees.parliament.uk/committee/366/committee-on-the-future-relationship-with-the-european-union/news/138129/announcement-of-euuk-trade-and-cooperation-agreement-allows-no-deal-to-be-averted-but-significant-change-still-imminent-says-committee/">here</a>.</p>
<p>I can confirm I will be supporting the deal when it comes to a vote later.</p>
<p>Many constituents have contacted me throughout the negotiation period, and I think this deal delivers on the key areas whilst also providing certainty and security for businesses and residents already impacted by Covid-19.</p>
<p>This deal delivers on Brexit, the referendum and last year&#8217;s election result by taking back control of our laws, borders, money, trade and fisheries.</p>
<p>&#8211; there is no role for the European Court of Justice and no requirement for the UK to follow EU law, so <strong>regaining parliamentary sovereignty</strong>;</p>
<p>&#8211; we will <strong>trade with the EU on the basis of zero tariffs and zero quotas</strong>, which will allow businesses to be able to trade smoothly and continue to access EU markets;</p>
<p>&#8211; <strong>Allows us to introduce our own modern subsidy system. </strong>This new subsidies system will operate in a that best suits the interests of UK industries &#8211; outside the EU State Aid regime.</p>
<p><strong>-</strong> offers streamlined <strong>co-operation on law enforcement</strong>, ensuring we continue to effectively tackle serious organised crime and counter terrorism, protecting the public, and bringing criminals to justice. It also provides for future cooperation between the UK and EU on emerging security challenges, such as cyber and health security, including continuing to work together on tackling the spread of Covid-19.</p>
<p><strong>- Recognises UK sovereignty over our fishing waters and puts us in a position to rebuild our fishing fleet and increase quotas, overturning the inequity that British fishermen have faced for over four decades. </strong>By the end of the five year transition we will have full control of our waters and the amount of fish available to UK fishermen will have risen from half to two-thirds.</p>
<p><strong><strong>- Provides for the UK’s participation in certain EU programmes, furthering our commitment to making the UK a science and research superpower. </strong></strong>This deal will fulfil our manifesto commitment to participate in the Horizon Europe programme, but also the Euratom Research and Training programme, and the space programme, Copernicus.</p>
<p>The deal also includes arrangements for airlines and hauliers that provides them with certainty, and gives people the ability to travel to and from the EU easily for work and holidays; a social security agreement that has practical benefits for UK citizens including accessing healthcare when travelling in the EU; and agreements on energy which will benefit consumers by helping to keep prices down.</p>
<p>As I set out in previous newsletters, compromises were necessary to achieve a deal, especially on fishing and the level playing field. Having been through the deal I am satisfied that these compromises are acceptable in the context of the importance of tariff free access to the EU market. This is a good deal achieved at great speed and gives us the best possible platform to make a success of Brexit.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus guidance latest:</span></strong></p>
<p>Following the last review of the tier restrictions on 16 December, Amber Valley and all of Derbyshire remained in the tier 3 restrictions. The next review takes place today. Amber Valley currently has a high case rate, of 332 cases per 100k, which is one of the highest in Derbyshire, and up 44% on the previous week. This is a very concerning situation and may lead to further restrictions being out in place locally.</p>
<p>On the positive side, mass testing has started in Swadlincote in the south of the County and will spread further in the county, including to Amber Valley early in the new year. This programme, along with similar roll outs in health, care and school settings will help identify cases earlier and slow the spread.</p>
<p>Vaccines are also now starting to be rolled out across the County, and I&#8217;m pleased that Ripley is one of the first primary care centres to begin rolling out the vaccine, which you can read more about <a href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.derbyandderbyshireccg.nhs.uk/news/news-articles-2020/derbyshire-gps-plan-to-open-first-vaccination-sites-in-dronfield-and-ripley/">here</a>. Now that the Oxford vaccine has been approved for us, the roll out of vaccination should increase rapidly at dedicated centres as well as local GPs and pharmacies. Please do wait to be contacted about the vaccine though rather than asking your GP.</p>
<p>We are now at a critical point in this pandemic with cases rising rapidly and the problems of 2 new variants. But the end is in sight now we can rapidly vaccinate the most vulnerable. At this time we all need to show as much caution as possible to reduce the number of cases and minimise the new restrictions needed. We’ve got this far, let’s not ease off now.</p>
<p>I will continue to engage with ministers, the public health team and the local NHS to ensure that this area sees the full roll out of the vaccines and mass testing as soon as possible and that support is in place for those who can’t work and those businesses forced to close as a result of the tier measures.</p>
<p>You can read my contributions in Parliament here including on highlighting the need to roll out the vaccine to people who are unable to leave their homes as soon as logistics allow <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-08b.715.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g725.4">here</a> and about consideration of more localised geography for tier restrictions <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-14b.23.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g32.0">here</a>.</p>
<p>As always, you can find the latest Covid-19 guidance, and support available, <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Coronavirus &#8211; support for local businesses &amp; high streets:</span></strong></p>
<p>In Parliament, I&#8217;ve continued to highlight the difficulties faces by our local businesses, such as the events industry and conference centres (you can read my question to the Secretary of State for Business on this <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-15a.136.1&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g137.4">here</a>), and supporting local high streets (which you can read more on <a href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.theyworkforyou.com/debates/?id=2020-12-02a.313.0&amp;s=speaker%3A24965#g327.4">here</a>).</p>
<p>I welcome the Chancellor&#8217;s announcement of the extension of the furlough scheme until the end of April 2021, and the extension of the business loan schemes until the end of March. You can find more information on the support and grants available for you or your business <a href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.gov.uk/coronavirus/business-support?priority-taxon=774cee22-d896-44c1-a611-e3109cce8eae">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Street Watch:</span></strong></p>
<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></span></p>
<p>Data laws have recently changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation. You can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></span></p>
<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></span></p>
<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills" data-cke-saved-href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like me on Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>
<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" alt="" data-cke-saved-src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg" /></p>
<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re receiving this newsletter because you subscribed to my mailing list.</p>
<p>Would you like to unsubscribe? Unsubscribe from this Newsletter <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20" data-cke-saved-href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/2020/12/30/nigels-december-newsletter-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How to write a script for an e-course</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may not be a hero and a plot. Therefore, in the scenario it is enough to describe on which slide what to tell: for example, on the first – about the main characteristics of the product, on the second – about the advantages over competitors.</p>



<p>Intermediate level: motivational courses. The main goal is to motivate employees to change their approach to work or attitude to something. For example, staff do not follow fire safety rules in the workplace, and you need to motivate employees.</p>



<p>In such courses, the character works well – involves in training. In the material about fire safety, a fire instructor will look logical. He will tell you what the neglect of the rules leads to and how to avoid an emergency. It is also important to add more practical assignments.</p>



<p>Difficult level: training course. The main goal is to pump up an old skill or develop a new one. There must be a history. Here it is important to think about the plot, the conflict, the place and time of the action, the main character and more.</p>



<p>Below I will tell you how to write a script for a training course. If you take this height, it is easy to handle tasks easier.</p>



<p>The results of the step: you have determined what type of course will best solve the tasks.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/">How to write a script for an e-course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Easy level: information courses. The main goal is to inform employees and tell how to use the acquired knowledge in work. For example, to get acquainted with a new product of the company. There may […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/how-to-write-a-script-for-an-e-course/">How to write a script for an e-course</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://lucianaberger.com/?p=23</id>
    <published>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-11T11:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Statement on Tata Steel Group Announcement</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/statement-on-tata-steel-group-announcement/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>carimorgans</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stephenkinnock.co.uk/?p=2299</id>
    <published>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-13T18:20:20Z</updated>
    <category term="Press &amp; Articles"/>
    <category term="Press Release"/>
    <category term="Steel"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ROBERT JENRICK DAILY TELEGRAPH OP-ED 2.11.2020</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://robertjenrick.com/dailytelegraph2-11-20/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them.</p>
<p>As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health.</p>
<p>Throughout this pandemic we have sought to protect our businesses and limit the intrusions on personal liberty as much as possible. For those of us who came into politics to help hardworking people and small businesses to thrive, it is heartbreaking to place these burdens upon them. For those of us who value personal freedom deeply, it pains us to inhibit it in this way.</p>
<p>But the data left us with no choice, but to take this course of action and introduce new restrictions until 2nd December.</p>
<p>As Local Government Secretary, I strongly believe that we were right in pursuing a local and regional approach to tackling this virus. I want to thank the millions who have put up with local restrictions and the local leaders who have stepped up to deliver this approach. Councils and local leaders have done wonderful work to help tackle the virus in their areas, and I firmly believe that in the longer term that is the approach that works best.</p>
<p>That’s why after we ease restrictions on 2nd December we are planning to continue with a local approach according to the latest data and trends.</p>
<p>But for now, the stark reality is that infections, hospitalisations and deaths continue to double, meaning that the virus is now a national problem.</p>
<p>The NHS and its workforce is weeks from being placed in an impossible situation. And those concerns are shared by our NHS colleagues from rural Cornwall to Nottingham to Newcastle. And a significantly higher death toll than the first wave is now predicted without taking further restrictions. We owe it to the country to act, and to act swiftly.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister made a decision that any responsible leader would make when presented with the new medical evidence last week and will set out his plans to parliament ahead of a vote on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Non-Covid healthcare can continue as normal – so that you can continue to use the NHS for your treatments, appointments and scans.</p>
<p>And the furlough scheme has been extended for a further month, covering 80% of employees’ wages. The Prime Minister and Chancellor have always been clear that we will do whatever it takes to protect businesses and their employees.</p>
<p>These are tough national measures, but they are different from those in the Spring. Our schools, colleges and universities remain open and we should resist those who would close them. As a parent I know there is simply no substitute for face to face teaching and our children’s education must not be set back again.</p>
<p>Unlimited exercise outdoor is permitted and single person households can form a support bubble. Children under school age who are with their parents will not count towards the limit on two people meeting outside, meaning that a parent can see a friend or family member with their baby or young children, and children and adults who are dependent on round-the-clock care, such as those with severe disabilities, will also be included in this exemption. Churches and places of worship will remain open,  providing solace and comfort for people, albeit for private prayer rather than communal worship.</p>
<p>If you can work from home you should, but if not, you can and should go to work, following the relevant guidance for your workplace. Too many jobs and businesses have been lost already, with all the harm that comes with that, so we must do everything we can to keep working and we in Government will do all we can to support you.</p>
<p>As Housing Secretary, I can confirm that the housing market will remain open throughout this period as will construction sites, building the homes and sustaining the jobs we desperately need. Tradespeople like plumbers and electricians can come into your home as long as they follow social distancing guidance.</p>
<p>Those we previously asked to stay at home and shield, the clinically extremely vulnerable, will be given new guidance shortly that will be less restrictive. But nonetheless they should continue to be cautious.</p>
<p>These changes are important to protect our way of life and our livelihoods, but I am under no illusion that the things people really want to do are hug their grandchildren, finally have the postponed wedding or simply share a cup of tea with old friends. But it is by taking these tough decisions now that we will get through this together.</p>
<p>Members of the public have shown incredible forbearance, patience and dignity in responding to this unique situation, and shown the character that has always been present in this country at moments of great challenge.</p>
<p>Amidst this winter gloom, there are rays of light piercing through and raising our eyes to the horizon. We know more about this virus with every day that passes and there are ever better medicine and therapies, along with the realistic chance of a vaccine being available for those that need it most in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>We expect to have quick turnaround tests that will tell you whether or not you have the virus very soon – with a massive expansion of these planned in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>These are reasons for optimism – but there is no denying that there are hard days ahead of us.</p>
<p>But by acting now, it is our hope that families across the country can be together for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, from Thursday: rejoin in a further national effort to protect the NHS, save lives and move forward together.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">None of us wanted these new restrictions, and the Government has done everything in its power to avoid them. As the Prime Minister said on Saturday night, we understand the huge impact further restrictions have on jobs, on livelihoods and on people’s mental health. Throughout...</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Robert Jenrick</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://robertjenrick.com/?p=1427</id>
    <published>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-02T10:48:18Z</updated>
    <category term="News &amp; Events"/>
    <category term="Daily Telegraph"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-3822029382927366640</id>
    <published>2020-03-06T13:22:00.003+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-06T13:22:42.576+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Raise the rate"/>
    <title type="text">Raise the Rate debate</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="true" allowtransparency="true" frameborder="0" height="313" scrolling="no" src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FYvonneFovargue4Makerfield%2Fvideos%2F613975099449506%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560" style="border: none; overflow: hidden;" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/3822029382927366640/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/3822029382927366640"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2020/03/raise-rate-debate.html" title="Raise the Rate debate"/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-60cc076b0884d" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-60cc076b0884d').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"60cc076b0884d","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-60cc076b0884d" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-60cc076b0884d" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="60cc076b0884d" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_60cc076b0884d" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_60cc076b0884d" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_60cc076b0884d" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_60cc076b0884d" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_60cc076b0884d" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_60cc076b0884d" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_60cc076b0884d_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-60cc076b0884d script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dxLnGsfEG_1C2cA-xNh9IrKA7A8iOuMklzKjpCcMpDedawNIODNnyQHhepXFOEx-ErIGSGBJXU4TKOXKiuKRQ' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~3/QVJ5Ukdon9g/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip;&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NickHerbertNewsAndBlog/~4/QVJ5Ukdon9g" height="1" width="1" alt=""/&gt;</content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thank you</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" rel="attachment wp-att-281"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="281" data-permalink="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you/photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2" data-orig-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" data-orig-size="640,396" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="Photo 09-06-2017, 10 43 04 (2)" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=300%2C186" data-large-file="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?fit=640%2C396" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-281" src="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=640%2C396" alt="" width="640" height="396" srcset="https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?w=640 640w, https://i2.wp.com/carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Photo-09-06-2017-10-43-04-2.jpg?resize=300%2C186 300w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" data-recalc-dims="1" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me.&lt;br /&gt;
I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website will be closing down shortly, but you can keep up to date with my work on my &lt;a href="http://www.carolynharris.org.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;main webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolyn x&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_button_google_plus" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/google_plus?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;amp;linkname=Thank%20you" title="Google+" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fcarolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk%2Fthank-you&amp;#038;title=Thank%20you" data-a2a-url="http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/thank-you" data-a2a-title="Thank you"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  We did it! Thank you to each and every one of you that volunteered time to canvass with me, deliver leaflets, stuff envelopes and most importantly those who voted for me. I cannot wait to get back up to Westminster and be the voice for Swansea East. This website will be closing down shortly, […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>linzi_isaac</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://carolynharris4swanseaeast.co.uk/?p=279</id>
    <published>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-12T11:01:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Blog"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
