<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Planet Westminster</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="text/html"/>
  <subtitle>Aggregating MPs' Blogs</subtitle>
  <author>
    <name>Dave Cross</name>
    <email>dave@theplanetarium.org</email>
  </author>
  <updated>2022-12-11T00:40:33Z</updated>
  <link rel="self" href="https://mps.theplanetarium.org/" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <id>https://mps.theplanetarium.org/</id>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tom Bridge</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Liz slams Tory failure on GP access]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-slams-tory-failure-on-gp-access/"/>

		<id>https://lizkendall.org/?p=11944</id>
		<updated>2022-12-10T11:30:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-10T11:30:19Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://lizkendall.org/" term="Homepage"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Figures released this week show that 10,541 people in Leicester faced a wait of 28 days or more to see a GP in October alone. A further 22,691&#160;people had to wait more than two weeks. Almost two million people in England had to wait more than 28 days in October, while a further 4.3 million had to wait more than two weeks.&#160;<br />
The fact that patients in Leicester and across the country are finding it impossible to see a GP when they need to is a damming indictment of 12 years ...</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-slams-tory-failure-on-gp-access/">Liz slams Tory failure on GP access</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://lizkendall.org/liz-slams-tory-failure-on-gp-access/"><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-11942 size-large" src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure-540x359.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="359" srcset="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure-540x359.jpg 540w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure-260x173.jpg 260w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure-184x122.jpg 184w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure-768x511.jpg 768w, https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/0_high-blood-pressure.jpg 810w" sizes="(max-width: 540px) 100vw, 540px" /></p>
<p>Figures released this week show that <span class="x_ContentPasted0">10,541 people in Leicester faced a wait of 28 days or more to see a GP in October alone. A further 22,691</span>&nbsp;<span class="x_ContentPasted0">people had to wait more than two weeks. </span><span class="x_ContentPasted0">Almost two million people in England had to wait more than 28 days in October, while a further 4.3 million had to wait more than two weeks.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>The fact that patients in Leicester and across the country are finding it impossible to see a GP when they need to is a damming indictment of 12 years of Tory failure on the NHS.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Labour has a plan that will see patients guaranteed a face-to-face appointment with a GP if they want one. We would:</p>
<p class="x_xxxxmsonospacing"><span class="x_ContentPasted0">·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="x_ContentPasted0">Double the number of medical school places, training 15,000 new doctors a year</span></p>
<p class="x_xxxxmsonospacing"><span class="x_ContentPasted0">·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="x_ContentPasted0">Train 10,000 additional nurses and midwives every year</span></p>
<p class="x_xxxxmsonospacing"><span class="x_ContentPasted0">·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="x_ContentPasted0">Double the number of district nurses qualifying each year</span></p>
<p class="x_xxxxmsonospacing"><span class="x_ContentPasted0">·&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span class="x_ContentPasted0">Train 5,000 new health visitors</span></p>
<p>This would be paid for by <span class="x_ContentPasted0">abolishing the non-dom tax status, which allows some wealthy people who live in Britain to pay their taxes overseas.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>You can see coverage of this story in the Leicester Mercury <a href="https://www.leicestermercury.co.uk/news/leicester-news/fears-thousands-patients-leicester-who-7907657">here.</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

<div class="wp_rp_wrap  wp_rp_vertical_m" id="wp_rp_first"><div class="wp_rp_content"><h3 class="related_post_title">Related posts</h3><ul class="related_post wp_rp"><li data-position="0" data-poid="in-2340" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-new-heart-research-centre-at-glenfield/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/5.jpg" alt="Liz visits new heart research centre at Glenfield" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-visits-new-heart-research-centre-at-glenfield/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz visits new heart research centre at Glenfield</a></li><li data-position="1" data-poid="in-9529" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-thanks-those-who-volunteer-in-our-local-community/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Liz-visit-to-VAL--150x150.jpg" alt="Liz thanks those who volunteer in our local community" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-thanks-those-who-volunteer-in-our-local-community/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz thanks those who volunteer in our local community</a></li><li data-position="2" data-poid="in-5159" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/the-words-its-cancer-stay-with-you-forever/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/2-150x150.png" alt="The words “its cancer” stay with you forever" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/the-words-its-cancer-stay-with-you-forever/" class="wp_rp_title">The words “its cancer” stay with you forever</a></li><li data-position="3" data-poid="in-3623" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-champions-the-rights-of-people-with-learning-disabilities/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/plugins/wordpress-23-related-posts-plugin/static/thumbs/16.jpg" alt="Liz champions the rights of people with learning disabilities" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-champions-the-rights-of-people-with-learning-disabilities/" class="wp_rp_title">Liz champions the rights of people with learning disabilities</a></li><li data-position="4" data-poid="in-6773" data-post-type="none" ><a href="https://lizkendall.org/giving-children-the-digital-skills-they-need-to-succeed/" class="wp_rp_thumbnail"><img src="https://lizkendall.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/DSCF58251-150x150.jpg" alt="Giving children the digital skills they need to succeed " width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="https://lizkendall.org/giving-children-the-digital-skills-they-need-to-succeed/" class="wp_rp_title">Giving children the digital skills they need to succeed </a></li></ul></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org/liz-slams-tory-failure-on-gp-access/">Liz slams Tory failure on GP access</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://lizkendall.org">Liz Kendall</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>In-Comm Training</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://wendymorton.co.uk/in-comm-training/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>It was great to catch up with Gareth Jones and the team at InComm Training and Business Services recently.</p>
<p>It was a pleasure once more to see so many young people take the opportunity of experiencing a further insight in to what opportunities InComm has to offer.</p>
<p>We are extremely fortunate to have InComm Training and Business Services in the constituency and I was pleased to be able to meet with staff and the next generation of apprentices.</p>
<p>Our local employers are to be congratulated for their willingness to invest time and money into apprentices. Without such continued support and investment the skills and employability gap would be much wider.</p>
<p>Thank you, Gareth and the team, for another great visit.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was great to catch up with Gareth Jones and the team at InComm Training and Business Services recently. It was a pleasure once more to see so many young […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Wendy Morton MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://wendymorton.co.uk/?p=4420</id>
    <published>2022-12-10T10:01:50Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-10T10:01:50Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Speech at the Parliamentary Debate on the Future of BBC Local Radio</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://johnredwoodsdiary.com/2022/12/10/my-speech-at-the-backbench-business-debate-on-the-future-of-bbc-local-radio/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><strong>Rt Hon Sir John Redwood MP (Wokingham) (Con)</strong>: I entirely agree with that passionate defence of localism by Rachael Maskell. Local must mean local and we do not want people in the BBC in London imposing on us their views on how our local radio should be conducted and how big our locality should be. I see behind the centralised planning at the BBC a distorted version of what our constitution should look like within the United Kingdom, and a wish to impose that—against the clear majority wishes of people, whenever they have been asked about these subjects in referendums and elections.</p>
<p>It is not just that the BBC wishes to create phony regional groupings instead of truly local radio, but that it has a very distorted view of devolution. The BBC seems to be an enthusiast for devolution to Northern Ireland, Scotland and Wales, but it does not even know England exists. It always wants lopsided devolution. One of the four important constituent parts of the United Kingdom is scarcely ever mentioned; it is never suggested it should have any powers or right to self-government and there is no engagement with English issues on BBC radio in the way that there is a clear engagement with Scottish, Welsh or Northern Ireland issues. That causes enormous resentment.</p>
<p>In my own case, local radio is organised at the county level, at Radio Berkshire. That makes sense, because it is an area that we can recognise and there is some loyalty to our royal and ancient county. Many people now do not know that it had its borders artificially compressed in a local government reorganisation some 50 years ago, under a Conservative Government that I think made some mistakes. The county retains an enormous amount of goodwill and residual loyalty, and people are very happy for our local radio to be organised at that scale. If people had real choice, however, I think Wokingham would rather have a different radio from Reading, and I think we would probably rather have a different radio from Windsor, because we have a different set of issues. But we accept that there have to be some compromises because talented people need to be appointed and paid wages, and that cannot be done to a sensible budget at very local levels.</p>
<p>I urge the BBC to look in the mirror and understand why, in many respects, it is getting so out of touch with its audiences. It has a very narrow range of views and issues that it will allow people to discuss, and it has a particularly warped perspective on how we feel about our areas and what our loyalties belong to. I am allowed to express views from time to time on BBC Radio Berkshire. It does not put me through the ordeal of a pre-interview to find out whether my views are acceptable and fit its caricature of a Conservative in the way that nearly always happens if national radio is thinking of interviewing me. Then, I always have the double interview, and I quite often fail the first interview test because my views are clearly too interesting or unacceptable, or do not fit the caricature that the radio wishes to put into its particular drama. So people are spared my voice on radio and I have more free time, which is perhaps a wonderful outcome from those events.</p>
<p>I do not find that my local radio quite plots the drama as strongly as national BBC radio and television. I am very grateful for that because I think that good, independent broadcasting of the kind that the BBC says it believes in should allow people of decent views—not extremists who want to break the law, or racists—to conduct civilised conversations and debates through the medium of the BBC. But all too often, that is truncated or impossible because of the way in which the editors operate and their pre-conceived set of views, about which they wish to create some kind of drama.</p>
<p>Colleagues have made extremely good points, which I will emphasise, about the treatment of staff and the way these kinds of proposals are planned. If the BBC wishes to run truly local services, it must listen to us—the local people and the local people’s representatives—and treat its staff well, and be aware that they have given good service in the past and should be taken on a journey of change that makes sense for them as well as for the BBC. This all looks rather top-down, abrupt and unpleasant. Successful organisations understand that their own journeys, evolving as institutions, are best conducted if, at the same time, they allow good journeys for the staff who give them loyal service. That does not seem to be happening in this case.</p>
<p>I will spare you a bit of time, Madam Deputy Speaker—I have made the main points that I wished to make. The BBC needs to be more open to a wider range of views. If it wants to be local, it has to ask us what local means.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir John Redwood MP (Wokingham) (Con): I entirely agree with that passionate defence of localism by Rachael Maskell. Local must mean local and we do not want people in the BBC in London imposing on us their views on how our local radio should be conducted and how big our locality should be. I…</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>johnredwood</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://johnredwoodsdiary.com/?p=34023</id>
    <published>2022-12-10T05:00:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-10T05:00:06Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cumbrian Coal Mine : Tories make wrong choice for working people and the planet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chionwurahmp.com/2022/12/13037/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Chaos in Parliament as sitting suspended twice after the Levelling Up SoS couldn&amp;#39;t provide his statement on the Cumbrian &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CoalMine?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#CoalMine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now can&amp;#39;t ask the Q I wanted to, so Michael Gove here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do Tories always make the wrong choices for working people and the planet? &lt;a href="https://t.co/xZ6GUnIEcV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/xZ6GUnIEcV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chi Onwurah &lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f499.png" alt="💙" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; (@ChiOnwurah) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ChiOnwurah/status/1600818555565801473?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;December 8, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chaos in Parliament as sitting suspended twice after the Levelling Up SoS couldn't provide his statement on the Cumbrian #CoalMine. I now can't ask the Q I wanted to, so Michael Gove here it is: Why do Tories always make… </div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chi Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://chionwurahmp.com/?p=13037</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T16:30:30Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T16:30:30Z</updated>
    <category term="Admin"/>
    <category term="Chi TV"/>
    <category term="Featured"/>
    <category term="Front Page"/>
    <category term="Keeping You Informed"/>
    <category term="Other"/>
    <category term="Your community"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Round-Up 12 December 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/09/weekly-round-up-12-december-2022/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=weekly-round-up-12-december-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="fb-root"/>
<p>A busy week kicked off with a brilliant online event marking the 16 days of activism targeting violence against women and girls. I spoke in a Westminster Hall debate on this issue last week, and have been overwhelmed by the response online following my speech. At Monday’s event, I was delighted to welcome Shadow Home Secretary Yvette Cooper to an online “in conversation” event with some of my wonderful Labour women colleagues from across Bristol. </p>
<p>The discussion was engaging and passionate, and Yvette generous with both her time and her insight. As well as recognising the progress made in some areas, there was no underestimating the scale of the challenge that lies ahead to stem the epidemic of violence against women and girls that this country, like countless others, is currently in the grip of.</p>
<p>Tuesday’s meeting of the Public Administration and Constitutional Affairs Committee (PACAC) focussed on lobbying and access. This followed on from last week’s Greensill report, where we focussed on lobbying. There are many things in common between Greensill and our recent meeting. The systemic failings of the 2014 ‘Lobbying Act’, from regulating the revolving door of business appointments to broader issues covering public appointments, the Ministerial Code and ethics watchdogs all need addressing. The session gave members the opportunity to hear how the EU regime for regulating lobbying operates, and to consider the extent to which some of its features could be adopted in the UK. </p>
<p>During the session, I was struck by quite how quickly the Greensill debacle has faded from public memory, despite the extraordinary shortcomings it exposed. It perhaps speaks to the number and nature of subsequent scandals that have engulfed this Government that a scandal involving a former Prime Minister exploiting his position for personal gain – albeit within the allowed parameters – is almost forgotten. </p>
<p>I was also able to speak in Labour’s Opposition Day debate on Tuesday, focusing on the ever-more-important issue of the NHS workforce. With retention of staff a real and growing problem, I repeated my call for the government to act sensibly and swiftly to address the challenges. With more than 80% of NHS staff homegrown, we need a step change in how we engage with local Further and Higher Education centres, a serious look at housing, and a meaningful move to empower local communities. Only then can we start to deliver a regional solution to the NHS workforce problems. </p>
<p>The issue of probity and common decency in public life that were the focus of PACAC returned in Wednesday’s Prime Minister’s Questions. Keir Starmer, and a number of my Labour colleagues, all pressed the Prime Minister to explain quite how Conservative Peer Michelle Mone apparently came to benefit to the tune of £20 million from the sale of pandemic PPE by a company she helped establish. Despite an avalanche of evidence and revelations, the Prime Minister shamelessly skirted the issue, failing to answer a single one of the simple questions put to him on the issue.   </p>
<p>A reminder of everything that is good with our world, however, was to be found at the 90th birthday celebration for Lord Alf Dubbs. A man who has devoted himself for decades to the protection, betterment celebration of others, Alf remains a tireless advocate and campaigner for social justice. The affection and respect in which he is held could be seen by the number of colleagues in attendance, from all political parties and none. </p>
<p>This week also saw the 100 year anniversary of the Anglo-Irish Treaty coming into effect. The excellent House of Commons Library team published a great briefing note on the subject, which also provides some useful markers as to why we are still having some of the debates on the issue. You can read the report here. I was also pleased to see Keir Starmer meeting with Ivana Bacik, the leader of the Irish Labour Party. Their discussion focused on working together to build economic growth and prosperity, and underscored Labour’s commitment to shaping a relationship with Ireland with partnership and an understanding of shared challenges at its foundation. </p>
<p>Like me, Frances O’Grady is a feminist who is proud of her Irish roots. After almost two decades of service at the TUC, including an extraordinary tenure as General Secretary, Frances has been nominated to serve as a working Labour Peer. It was good to join with friends and colleagues to mark the end of her time at the TUC.</p>
<p>If there are issues you want to raise with me as your local MP, please get in touch by emailing Karin.smyth.mp@parliament.uk or by calling 0117 953 3575.</p>The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/09/weekly-round-up-12-december-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 12 December 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A busy week kicked off with a brilliant online event marking the 16 days of activism targeting violence against women […]</p>
The post <a href="http://karinsmyth.com/2022/12/09/weekly-round-up-12-december-2022/">Weekly Round-Up 12 December 2022</a> first appeared on <a href="http://karinsmyth.com">Karin Smyth</a>.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>karin@karinsmyth.com</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://karinsmyth.com/?p=3394</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T14:08:28Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T14:08:28Z</updated>
    <category term="Bristol South"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Robin encourages veterans to have their say</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-encourages-veterans-have-their-say" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Robin with the founders of Llandudno's Military Minds FC
Robin is encouraging veterans to have their say by participating in the UK Government’s first ever UK-wide survey for ex-servicemen and women and their families.
Over the next 10 weeks, veterans across throughout the United Kingdom can…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.robin-millar.org.uk/news/robin-encourages-veterans-have-their-say</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amazon Delivery Depot in Banbury</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/amazon-delivery-depot-banbury" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was great to visit Amazon’s delivery depot in Banbury on Friday. I met Site Manager Andy, who gave me a tour of the site alongside members of the senior leadership team. I was pleased to be able to discuss their operations in Banbury and also their efforts to improve engagement with the local…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.victoriaprentis.com/news/amazon-delivery-depot-banbury</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly update 👇</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/weekly-update-4" type="text/html"/>
    <id>https://www.maria4basingstoke.co.uk/news/weekly-update-4</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Brendan Clarke-Smith MP welcomes Government’s new campaign to boost take up of pension credit in Bassetlaw</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-welcomes-governments-new-campaign-boost-take-pension-credit-bassetlaw" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Press Release 
 
Date: 9 December 2022
 
Brendan Clarke-Smith has welcomed a new campaign from the Conservative Government to boost the take up of Pension Credit, giving more vulnerable pensioners across Bassetlaw the support they need.
 
There are already around 2,354 claimants in Bassetlaw, but…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.brendanclarkesmith.com/news/brendan-clarke-smith-mp-welcomes-governments-new-campaign-boost-take-pension-credit-bassetlaw</id>
    <published>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Team JP</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[John responds to being named December&#8217;s Parliamentary Tech Champion]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/12/09/john-responds-to-being-named-decembers-parliamentary-tech-champion/"/>

		<id>http://johnpenrose.org/wp/?p=5604</id>
		<updated>2022-12-09T05:30:12Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-09T05:30:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://johnpenrose.org/wp" term="Press Cuttings"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m honoured to be this month’s ‘Parliamentary Tech Champion’, because of the role technology can play in sharpening competition to create big, powerful citizen-consumers so markets work for people rather than the other way round.  This is a key theme in my Government-commissioned report on Competition Policy, Power to the People which made the case [&#8230;]]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://johnpenrose.org/wp/2022/12/09/john-responds-to-being-named-decembers-parliamentary-tech-champion/"><![CDATA[
<p><strong>I’m honoured to be this month’s ‘Parliamentary Tech Champion’, because of the role technology can play in sharpening competition to create big, powerful citizen-consumers so markets work for people rather than the other way round. </strong><br><br>This is a key theme in my Government-commissioned report on Competition Policy, Power to the People which made the case for a strong, pro-competitive but tightly-ringfenced Digital Market Unit to erode the power of online network monopolies which have emerged in the last few decades, giving consumers more choice and better deals as well as opening up more opportunities for entrepreneurs and wealth-creators too. <br><br>An example of what this means in practice is the UK’s world-leading changes in Open Banking, which are weakening the longstanding current-account stranglehold of incumbent high-street banks. By opening up data portability with APIs for third party payments providers (TPPs), banking customers suddenly have a growing choice of different and creative services to choose from, and we’ve created a thriving Open Banking FinTech eco-system in the process. The next challenge is to extend this success from current accounts to the whole of the financial sector (Open Finance), and then on to other industries like online retailing and utilities too (Open Everything). <br><br>Last but not least, consumers can become more powerful through transparency, partly because we can all make better-informed decisions about what we buy if the data is at our fingertips whenever we need it, and partly by shining a light on subsidies or sweetheart deals given to incumbents and special interests too. The recent Subsidy Control Bill improves transparency significantly, and there’s another opportunity in the upcoming the Online Safety Bill if we grasp the opportunity to protect people from lies or only seeing one set of views about anything from products and services to vaccines and political campaigns.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Edinburgh opens city-wide network of ‘Warm and Welcoming Spaces’ </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13614/edinburgh-opens-city-wide-network-of-warm-and-welcoming-spaces-" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">With the colder months of the year now upon us we are pleased to announce the launch of a network of Warm and Welcoming Spaces across the capital.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.edinburgh.gov.uk/news/article/13614/edinburgh-opens-city-wide-network-of-warm-and-welcoming-spaces-</id>
    <published>2022-12-08T16:11:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-08T16:11:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
  <title>MP meets with Health Minister to discuss Cumbria’s cancer crisis</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1438705/mp-meets-with-health-minister-to-discuss-cumbria-s-cancer-crisis"/>
  <updated>2022-12-08T15:29:00Z</updated>
  <id>http://timfarron.co.uk/en/article/2022/1438705/mp-meets-with-health-minister-to-discuss-cumbria-s-cancer-crisis</id>
  <summary type="text">Last night, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron and senior clinicians met with the Health Minister Helen Whately to call for urgent action to address Britain's cancer crisis.
Tim, who is the chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Radiotherapy, made the case for investment into tackling the lengthy waiting times for cancer treatment.</summary>
  <content type="xhtml"><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Last night, Cumbrian MP Tim Farron and senior clinicians met with the Health Minister Helen Whately to call for urgent action to address Britain's cancer crisis.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Tim, who is the chair of the All Party Parliamentary Group on Radiotherapy, made the case for investment into tackling the lengthy waiting times for cancer treatment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">According to the latest NHS waiting times, more than four in 10 (43%) cancer patients had to wait more than two months to receive their first treatment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Meanwhile in South Cumbria and North Lancashire, 35% of cancer patients were waiting more than 62 days.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Tim also encouraged the minister to look at investing in new satellite radiotherapy units across the country, including at Kendal's Westmorland General Hospital, to tackle the backlog.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">Speaking after the meeting, Tim said: <em>"I'm really grateful to the Minister for her time.</em></span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"During the pandemic, we saw ministers rightly chuck everything at trying to deal with the covid crisis in order to save lives and protect the NHS.</span></em></p>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 12.0pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif;">"We desperately need that same level of focus and urgency if we are to tackle the cancer backlog and stop people tragically and unnecessarily dying from cancer."</span></em></p>
<address>  Published and promoted by P Trollope on behalf of T Farron and the Liberal Democrats, all at Yard 2, Stricklandgate, Kendal<br/>Printed (hosted) by <a href="https://www.praterraines.co.uk/">Prater Raines Ltd</a>, 98 Sandgate High Street, Folkestone CT20 3BY</address></div></content>
  <category term="Article"/>
</entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>JH</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[All Aboard the Midland Hub Express]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/"/>

		<id>https://stevemccabe.org/?p=6587</id>
		<updated>2022-12-08T15:02:58Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-08T15:02:58Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="Economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="economy"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="government"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="midland hub"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="railway"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="trains"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="transport"/><category scheme="https://stevemccabe.org" term="west midlands"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I started this week on a positive note by attending the launch of the Midland Hub at Birmingham Council House. It&#8217;s a plan to improve rail services across the region with more routes and increased frequency. Not entirely a new idea, I remember a version in the mid-90s when a young Councillor McCabe chaired Birmingham&#8217;s Transport<a class="more-link" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">All Aboard the Midland Hub Express</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/"><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img data-attachment-id="6589" data-permalink="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/steve-mccabe-mp-column-image-2-6/" data-orig-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=1024%2C211&amp;ssl=1" data-orig-size="1024,211" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;orientation&quot;:&quot;0&quot;}" data-image-title="Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1" data-large-file="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?fit=870%2C179&amp;ssl=1" decoding="async" width="870" height="179" src="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=870%2C179&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-6589" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?w=1024&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=300%2C62&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/stevemccabe.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Steve-McCabe-MP-Column-Image-2.webp?resize=768%2C158&amp;ssl=1 768w" sizes="(max-width: 870px) 100vw, 870px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></figure>



<p>I started this week on a positive note by attending the launch of the Midland Hub at Birmingham Council House. It&#8217;s a plan to improve rail services across the region with more routes and increased frequency. Not entirely a new idea, I remember a version in the mid-90s when a young Councillor McCabe chaired Birmingham&#8217;s Transport Committee, but it&#8217;s an idea whose time has come and Midland Connect, the body responsible since 2015, have done a fine job in marshalling the business case and benefits.</p>



<p>We desperately need some good news on the rail front. The chaotic Avanti West Coast service has been given a six-month reprieve at huge public expense, West Midlands Railways require urgent improvement, and it seems the government is determined to ensure rail strikes over Christmas. If all those foreign rail shareholders can receive their dividends, we can afford a better offer on pay and without strings that conjure up the bad old days of Railtrack, horrific accidents, and safety nightmares.</p>



<p>You&#8217;d think the government would give greater priority to transport, especially railways in a region like ours. The evidence is that investment of this kind promotes economic growth and prosperity.</p>



<p>Support for the Midland Hub was in Boris Johnson&#8217;s 2019 manifesto but that was back when &#8216;levelling up&#8217; was the Tory mantra of the day. Since then, we&#8217;ve had Liz Truss and her economic wrecking ball which left the economy with an £80 billion black hole. The mantra now seems to be that we all must tighten our belts although some, like public sector workers, more than others. Even with all that tightening, and tax increases, the Chancellor still intends to make about £27 billion of public spending cuts.</p>



<p>I really hope the Midland Hub is not a casualty of this new austerity because it&#8217;s a value for money project.</p>



<p>So come on Rishi, what we want for Christmas is the government to treat railways seriously. Make the Midland Hub a reality and authorise a genuine offer to resolve the dispute. The public deserves it, our region needs it, and our economy is crying out for it.</p>
]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://stevemccabe.org/2022/12/08/all-aboard-the-midland-hub-express/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Isles MP urges pensioners not to miss out on £324 cost-of-living grant</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/08/isles-mp-urges-pensioners-not-to-miss-out-on-324-cost-of-living-grant/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is urging all pensioners on low-incomes to make sure they’re signed up for Pension Credit to ensure they receive a special cost of living grant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the Tory-made cost of living crisis continues the Mr MacNeil MP has warned households could miss out on the vital payment if they don’t apply soon.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In May 2022, the UK Government originally announced a Cost-of-Living Payment to be paid to those in receipt of Pension Credit and other qualifying benefits.&amp;nbsp;To be eligible for the payment, an older person must have been entitled to a Pension Credit payment (or later found to be entitled to a payment) between 26 August and 25 September.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Applications for Pension Credit can be backdated by three months &amp;#8211; those who begin the claiming process by Sunday 18 December and are successful can be eligible for the second Cost-of-Living Payment of £324.00.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Applicants can begin their application 4 months before they reach pensionable age and apply anytime afterwards and can do so online, by post, or over the phone.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenting Mr MacNeil said:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As the Tory-made cost-of-living crisis continues to ravage household finances, more and more people are set to see a reduction in their living standards, particularly those on lower incomes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Increasing food bills, rents, mortgage payments and energy prices are all heaping on the pressure, and pensioners especially can be vulnerable this winter.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Pension Credit is money to which people are entitled, and I would urge all low-income pensioners to make an application today.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Organisations such as the Citizens Advice can assist with applications, and the extra cash can go a long way in alleviating some of the stress and worry over the colder months.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-image size-large"&gt;&lt;a href="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img data-attachment-id="4015" data-permalink="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/pic2/" data-orig-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg" data-orig-size="3341,1856" data-comments-opened="0" data-image-meta="{&amp;quot;aperture&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1.8&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;credit&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;camera&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;SM-G780F&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;caption&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;created_timestamp&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1669377401&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;focal_length&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;5.4&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;iso&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;shutter_speed&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;0.003125&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;title&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;orientation&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;58.1891392&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;-6.3795028&amp;quot;}" data-image-title="pic2" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=529" src="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-4015" srcset="https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=1024 1024w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=2048 2048w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=150 150w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=300 300w, https://hebridesmpandmsp.files.wordpress.com/2022/11/pic2.jpg?w=768 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Na h-Eileanan an Iar SNP MP Angus MacNeil is urging all pensioners on low-incomes to make sure they’re signed up …<p><a href="https://angusmacneilsnp.com/2022/12/08/isles-mp-urges-pensioners-not-to-miss-out-on-324-cost-of-living-grant/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>macdonaldrm</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://angusmacneilsnp.com/?p=4072</id>
    <published>2022-12-08T14:40:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-08T14:40:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lee Anderson MP welcomes £2 billion extra school funding, helping schools and colleges in Ashfield with the highest real terms spending on schools in history</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mp-welcomes-ps2-billion-extra-school-funding-helping-schools-and-colleges" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Lee Anderson MP has welcomed extra funding from the Conservative Government, providing a share of £2 billion this year and next for primary schools, secondary schools, and high needs pupils in Ashfield.
The £2 billion for schools over each of the next two years, announced at the Autumn Statement…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.leeanderson.org.uk/news/lee-anderson-mp-welcomes-ps2-billion-extra-school-funding-helping-schools-and-colleges</id>
    <published>2022-12-08T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scott Benton MP welcomes Conservative Government’s new campaign to boost take up of pension credit in Blackpool South</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-conservative-governments-new-campaign-boost-take-pension-credit" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Scott Benton MP has welcomed a new campaign from the Conservative Government to boost the take up of Pension Credit, giving more vulnerable pensioners across Blackpool South the support they need.
There are already around 3,107 claimants in Blackpool South, but more people are eligible for an…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.scottbenton.org.uk/news/scott-benton-mp-welcomes-conservative-governments-new-campaign-boost-take-pension-credit</id>
    <published>2022-12-08T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-08T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Gwynne calls for urgent improvements to armed service accommodation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-calls-for-urgent-improvements-to-armed-service-accommodation/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gwynne-calls-for-urgent-improvements-to-armed-service-accommodation" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235913" src="http://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen-1024x535.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="535" srcset="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen-1024x535.jpg 1024w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen-300x157.jpg 300w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen-768x401.jpg 768w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen-1080x564.jpg 1080w, https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/Gwynne-calls-urgen.jpg 1455w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has urged the Government to deliver good-quality homes for those serving in the armed services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gwynne’s intervention comes after MoD data uncovered by Labour revealed that over 36% of service personnel in Greater Manchester were living in the lowest grade of service accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the country, 40% of personnel living in Single Living Accommodation occupy ‘Grade 4 accommodation’ &amp;#8211; the lowest rating given by the Ministry of Defence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A further 4,360 personnel live in accommodation so poor that no rental charge is levied. Just 21% live in the top ‘Grade 1’ accommodation, the lowest proportion since 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Defence awards grades to its Single Living Accommodation based on ‘deficiency points’ allocated across 14 categories. Points are apportioned for the condition of bedroom decoration, fixtures and fittings, adequacy of heating systems and the proximity of toilet and washing facilities, among other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is currently no minimum quality standard set for Single Living Accommodation and no minimum acceptable conditions that service personnel should expect. A 2021 National Audit Office report on Single Living Accommodation exposed ‘decades of underinvestment’ and ‘problems with heating and hot water.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Armed Forces Continuous Attitude survey reveals that 41% of tri-service personnel live in Single Living Accommodation during the working week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same survey shows 40% of tri-service personnel were dissatisfied with the overall standard of their accommodation. A majority of 52% said they were dissatisfied with the responses to maintenance request and repairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Andrew Gwynne said: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our Armed Forces personnel are heroes, and they should have access to good-quality accommodation that reflects their exceptional work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is scandalous that after 12 years of Tory rule, the condition of housing for service personnel has plummeted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ll do everything I can to press the Government to do more and ensure that personnel get the standard of accommodation they deserve.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Defence Secretary John Healey said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Conservatives are failing in their duty to our Armed Forces, who are forced to live in discomfort as properties fall into disrepair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The standard of accommodation has been consistently low and getting worse under this government yet nothing’s changed. These conditions wouldn’t be acceptable in civilian life, and they certainly aren’t acceptable for actively serving personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The government must deliver homes fit for those serving our country.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-calls-for-urgent-improvements-to-armed-service-accommodation/"&gt;Gwynne calls for urgent improvements to armed service accommodation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk"&gt;Andrew Gwynne MP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Andrew Gwynne, MP for Denton and Reddish, has urged the Government to deliver good-quality homes for those serving in the armed services. Gwynne’s intervention comes after MoD data uncovered by Labour revealed that over 36% of service personnel in Greater Manchester were living in the lowest grade of service accommodation. Across the country, 40% of […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/gwynne-calls-for-urgent-improvements-to-armed-service-accommodation/">Gwynne calls for urgent improvements to armed service accommodation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://andrewgwynne.co.uk">Andrew Gwynne MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Gwynne MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://andrewgwynne.co.uk/?p=235912</id>
    <published>2022-12-08T11:33:36Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-08T11:33:36Z</updated>
    <category term="Local"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Green Heart Hero awards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/2022/12/07/green-heart-hero-awards/" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>conormcginn</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.conormcginn.co.uk/?p=7576</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T15:21:43Z</updated>
    <category term="Conor in St Helens"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Yasmin Qureshi</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chemical Pollution in UK Waters]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/10/chemical-pollution-in-uk-waters/"/>

		<id>https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/?p=1711</id>
		<updated>2022-12-07T14:43:47Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-10T14:42:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="News"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="25-Year Environment Plan"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="climate"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Environment"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="Oceans"/><category scheme="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk" term="plastic"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.yasminqureshi.org.uk/news/2022/12/10/chemical-pollution-in-uk-waters/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Graham Stuart MP Welcomes Two New Centres to Tackle Covid Backlog in Beverley and Holderness</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-two-new-centres-tackle-covid-backlog-beverley-and-holderness" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">East Riding Community Hospital and Withernsea Community Hospital to be designated Community Diagnostic Centres, delivering more life-saving checks, tests and scans and speed up diagnoses for local patients
These hospitals are two of 19 across England which have been designated as such.
This is a…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.grahamstuart.com/news/graham-stuart-mp-welcomes-two-new-centres-tackle-covid-backlog-beverley-and-holderness</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Evennett continues campaign against Southeastern timetable changes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rt Hon Sir David Evennett, MP for Bexleyheath and Crayford, is continuing to campaign for changes to the new Southeastern railway timetable, which will be implemented from Sunday 11 December.
To date, Sir David has held meetings with Southeastern Managing Director, Steve White, the Rail Minister,…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bexleyheathandcrayford.com/news/evennett-continues-campaign-against-southeastern-timetable-changes</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Itchen College Students in Parliament</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/07/itchen-college-students-in-parliament-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was pleased to meet students from Itchen College in Parliament yesterday. It was good to see the students engage in a lively mock debate and I enjoyed answering some very interesting questions.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/2022/12/07/itchen-college-students-in-parliament-2/">Itchen College Students in Parliament</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk">Royston Smith MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Royston Smith</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.roystonsmith.co.uk/?p=5078</id>
    <published>2022-12-07T10:29:16Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-07T10:29:16Z</updated>
    <category term="Diary"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dunne welcomes £2 billion extra school funding</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.philipdunne.com/news/dunne-welcomes-ps2-billion-extra-school-funding" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">  <div data-history-node-id="7315" class="layout layout--onecol">
    <div class="layout__region layout__region--content">
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-date field--type-datetime field--label-hidden field--item">6 December 2022</div>
      
      <div class="field field--name-field-page-builder field--type-entity-reference-revisions field--label-hidden field--items">
              <div class="field--item">  <div class="paragraph paragraph--type--text paragraph--view-mode--default">
          
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-title field--type-string field--label-hidden field--item"><span>Dunne welcomes £2 billion extra school funding</span></div>
      
            <div class="field field--name-field-paragraph-text field--type-text-long field--label-hidden field--item"><p><span><span/></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Philip Dunne MP has welcomed extra funding from the Government, providing a share of £2 billion this year and next for primary schools, secondary schools, and high needs pupils in South Shropshire.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The £2 billion for schools over each of the next two years, announced at the Autumn Statement last month will increase schools spending to the highest real terms levels in history.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>For a typical primary school with 200 pupils, the extra funding from the Autumn Statement will equate to approximately £28,000, and approximately £170,000 for a typical secondary school with 900 pupils.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>The Institute for Fiscal Studies has highlighted this uplift will mean 2024-25 will be the highest spending year in history for schools.  In total the schools budget will be £58.8 billion in 2024-25 – meaning the Government is putting more into school than ever before.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Average funding per pupil for mainstream schools will increase by approximately five percent overall in the next financial year compared to 2022-23. As part of this funding local councils will also receive an extra £400 million for high needs budgets to help support children with special education needs or disabilities.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>School leaders continue to be supported by the Government to invest in high quality teaching and tutoring. Over two million tutoring courses have now been started and an additional £24 million is being invested to boost children’s literacy skills to support children adversely impacted by the pandemic, alongside £60 million this year and next for the Maths Hub Programme.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>Commenting, Philip Dunne said:</span></span></span></span></p>

<blockquote>
<p><span><span><span><span>“I am committed to delivering on our community’s priorities, including education investment – supporting young people to reach their full potential, particularly those who face challenges or who need extra support.”</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>“That is why I welcome that the Government delivering the highest real terms spending on schools in history, providing a share of £2 billion this year and next for primary schools, secondary schools, and high needs pupils in South Shropshire.</span></span></span></span></p>

<p><span><span><span><span>“We are delivering on our commitment to provide a good education and deliver opportunity for all – wherever they come from and whatever their background.”</span></span></span></span></p>
</blockquote>

<p><span><span/></span></p></div>
      
      </div>
</div>
          </div>
  
    </div>
  </div>

</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>jon</name>
    </author>
    <id>7315 at https://www.philipdunne.com</id>
    <published>2022-12-06T18:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-06T18:20:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Stockton North Labour Team</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t miss out on vital support, says Alex as he backs Pension Credit take-up campaign]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/12/dont-miss-out-on-vital-support-says-alex-as-he-backs-pension-credit-take-up-campaign/"/>

		<id>https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/?p=14582</id>
		<updated>2022-12-06T15:13:34Z</updated>
		<published>2022-12-07T10:10:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stockton North MP Alex Cunningham is backing the Pension Credit take-up campaign as it emerges those entitled to it could be missing out on £3300 a year in financial support. Currently, over 1.4 million pensioners in Britain receive Pension Credit. However, many eligible pensioners including in Stockton North are still not claiming this extra financial [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com/2022/12/dont-miss-out-on-vital-support-says-alex-as-he-backs-pension-credit-take-up-campaign/">Don’t miss out on vital support, says Alex as he backs Pension Credit take-up campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.alexcunninghammp.com">Alex Cunningham MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Protecting Young People Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://damiancollins.com/protecting-young-people-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This week the Online Safety Bill returned to parliament, for the first time since the government changes of the summer and autumn. As readers of this column will know this is an issue I have been campaigning on for years and was for a time also the responsible Minister for this Bill at the Department […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>damian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://damiancollins.com/?p=6191</id>
    <published>2022-12-06T13:49:17Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-06T13:49:17Z</updated>
    <category term="Weekly Blog"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Greg calls on Ministers to ensure additional work coach time to support people back into work</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-calls-ministers-ensure-additional-work-coach-time-support-people-back-work" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text">Yesterday in the House of Commons during Work &amp; Pensions Questions, Greg Smith MP praised the lowering of the Universal Credit taper rate, but called on Ministers to ensure other critical elements of supporting people back into work are delivered, not least extending the time available for…</content>
    <id>https://www.gregsmith.co.uk/news/greg-calls-ministers-ensure-additional-work-coach-time-support-people-back-work</id>
    <published>2022-12-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Anne Marie's Weekly Column</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-181" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Finance Bill implementing the provisions set out in the Autumn Statement was the main business in the House this week, but there was plenty of news and debate as regards the union.
The Northern Ireland (Executive Formation etc) Bill formally extended the period for a new government to be put in…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.annemariemorris.co.uk/news/anne-maries-weekly-column-181</id>
    <published>2022-12-06T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-06T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>General Election Now</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/12/05/generalelectionnow/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/12/05/generalelectionnow/">General Election Now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/2022/12/05/generalelectionnow/">General Election Now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk">Toby Perkins Labour MP</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>craigbusby</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.tobyperkins.org.uk/?p=5149</id>
    <published>2022-12-05T12:49:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-05T12:49:11Z</updated>
    <category term="Featured"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MARTIN CHALLENGES UK ENERGY SECRETARY ON RISING HOUSEHOLD BILLS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/12/05/martin-challenges-uk-energy-secretary-on-rising-household-bills/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has urged the UK government to do more to tackle rising energy bills, as a study by &lt;a href="https://www.cas.org.uk/news/2-million-estimated-have-cut-back-household-spending-due-high-energy-bills"&gt;Citizens Advice Scotland&lt;/a&gt; reveals nearly half of adults are estimated to have cut back on household spending.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes challenged UK Energy Secretary Grant Shapps over rising energy costs during question time in the House of Commons. The SNP MP highlighted &lt;a href="https://www.heraldscotland.com/news/homenews/23032417.revealed-parts-scotland-pay-nearly-double-liz-trusss-energy-price-guarantee-bills-freeze/"&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; showing that the typical household in Scotland faces dual fuel bills of £3,300 a year: over £800 more than what the UK government says households should be paying on average under the current energy price guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;UK Energy Secretary Grant Shapps responded saying that the government had “put a comprehensive range of different support in place”, including the energy price guarantee – which is due to rise again in April to £3,000.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-video"&gt;&lt;video controls src="https://martindocherty.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/House_of_Commons_29_11_22_11_35_43_Trim.mp4"&gt;&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It comes as new research published by Citizens Advice Scotland suggests over 2 million adults in Scotland are estimated to have cut back on household spending because of rising energy costs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes met recently with representatives of West Dunbartonshire Citizens Advice Bureau (CAB) to discuss the impact of the cost-of-living crisis, and hear about the advice network’s new community outreach service.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Anyone worried about the cost of rising energy bills in West Dunbartonshire is encouraged to contact their local Citizens Advice Bureau for support online &lt;a href="http://www.wdcab.co.uk"&gt;www.wdcab.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; or via their free helpline on 0800 484 0136.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commenting, Martin Docherty-Hughes MP said:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“As the temperature drops, I’m hearing from more people across West Dunbartonshire deeply worried about the soaring costs of energy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“It’s deplorable that in an energy-rich country like ours, families are being left with no other option than to keep the heating off or skip meals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Whilst the energy price guarantee has helped stabilise bills for some, many in Scotland still face much higher typical gas and electricity costs due to colder and wetter weather. And average energy bills across the UK are still treble what they were this time last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Yet, rather than delivering real and targeted support to deal with rocketing bills, the Westminster government has instead chosen to impose an austerity budget which will further entrench poverty here.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“With the winter weather setting in I’d encourage anyone struggling with energy bills to reach out for support. I work closely with the area’s network of support groups, including West Dunbartonshire Citizens Advice Bureau (CAB), who can help households ease the cost-of-living.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">West Dunbartonshire’s MP Martin Docherty-Hughes has urged the UK government to do more to tackle rising energy bills, as a study by Citizens Advice Scotland reveals nearly half of adults are estimated to have cut back on household spending. Local MP Martin Docherty-Hughes challenged UK Energy Secretary Grant Shapps over rising energy costs during question ... <p class="read-more-container"><a title="MARTIN CHALLENGES UK ENERGY SECRETARY ON RISING HOUSEHOLD BILLS" class="read-more button" href="https://martindocherty.scot/2022/12/05/martin-challenges-uk-energy-secretary-on-rising-household-bills/#more-1821481" aria-label="More on MARTIN CHALLENGES UK ENERGY SECRETARY ON RISING HOUSEHOLD BILLS">Read more</a></p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Communications Officer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://martindocherty.scot/?p=1821481</id>
    <published>2022-12-05T12:15:11Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-05T12:15:11Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Citizens Advice Scotland"/>
    <category term="Cost of living Crisis"/>
    <category term="Energy bills"/>
    <category term="Martin Docherty-Hughes MP"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire"/>
    <category term="West Dunbartonshire CAB"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Weekly Round-up</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.christinarees.org/my-weekly-round-up-83/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p style="font-weight: 400;">There were many Urgent Oral Questions (UQs) and UK Government Ministerial Oral Statements in the Chamber.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">UQs included: Migration Update; Iran Treatment of Protesters, and Statements included: UN Peacekeeping Mission in Mali; Missile Incident in Poland; Social Housing Standards; G20 Summit in Indonesia; and The Autumn Statement: Chancellor of the Exchequer.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I also attended many events outside the chamber. I dropped into “<a href="https://www.bmh.manchester.ac.uk/stories/cancer/tomorrows-medicines/">Bringing Tomorrow’s Science to today’s NHS: Cell and Gene Therapies</a>” which advocated keeping the UK at the forefront of global access to revolutionary cell and gene therapies. These are transformative types of medical treatments which may aim to restore the normal function of missing or faulty sets of cells and genes. And treat the root cause of diseases and disorders by augmenting, repairing, replacing, or regenerating organs, tissues, cells, genes, and metabolic processes in the body. These revolutionary treatments can have life changing and life saving potential for patients with previously incurable diseases, for example, severe combined immunodeficiency disorder, spinal muscular atrophy, and lymphomas. I support the call for the UK Government to bring different parts of the system together and ensure patients gain the earliest possible access to forthcoming cell and gene therapies.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the “<a href="https://www.actionagainsthunger.org.uk/press-releases/east-africa-cannot-wait">Famine in East Africa Cannot Wait</a>” event hosted by 12 charities. Over 21 million people across Ethiopia, Kenya, and Somalia face acute hunger, more than double the number who experienced acute hunger in the 2011 drought, when more than a quarter of a million died. Currently, 1.8 million children in the region are severely malnourished due to ongoing drought. Climate change shocks have contributed to people already facing poverty, conflict, weak social protections, destroyed food and income sources, so food is hard to find and money to buy food is minimal. But are responsible for a mere 0.1% of global emissions. The UK Government should commit funding to local communities, in advance of anticipated crises, deliver UK climate change targets, support a financial facility to address loss and damage.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The EGM of the All Party Parliamentary Group (APPG) for Sport elected Kim Leadbeater as chair, and I was elected vice chair, along with my dear friends, Baroness Tanni Grey-Thompson, Lord Addington, and Baroness Amanda Sater. Molly Hartill represented the Sport and Recreation Alliance who continue as secretariat for the APPG.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As vice chair of the APPG for the Environment I supported its event to launch its first published report, “<a href="https://environment.inparliament.uk/sites/environment.inparliament.uk/files/2022-10/appg_report_10_points_vis_5.pdf">The 10 point plan for climate and nature</a>“, which is a cross-cutting report providing UK Government with a menu of policies to reach net zero by 2050 and to restore nature by 2030.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I dropped into the Law Commission’s launch of its report “<a href="https://www.lawcom.gov.uk/project/weddings/">Celebrating Marriage: A New Weddings Law</a>” hosted by the Association of Independent Celebrants Ltd (AOIC), which proposes a move to an officiant-based system for marriage ceremonies in England and Wales. The report calls for regulation of the officiant not the venue, and universal rules for all weddings. The AOIC wants to provide celebrants with the support, Continuous Professional Development, and resources they need to create truly special ceremonies for every one of their clients. The UK Government has 6 months to provide an interim response and a full response within 12 months. If the UK Government accepts the Law Commission proposals, it will introduce a Bill to make it law.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the Bhopal Gas Disaster event hosted by my friend Navendu Mishra MP to raise awareness of the tragedy that took place 38 years ago and was the worst industrial catastrophe in history, when 25,000 people were killed in the event or later of their injuries, and 120,000 remain seriously ill with no hope of being cured. I pledged my support to the “<a href="https://actionforbhopal.org/">Action for Bhopal</a>” groups who have been campaigning for justice for the victims of the tragedy.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined the Public and Commercial Services Union (PCS) Justice meeting for updates from the Professional Trades Union for Prison, Correctional and Secure Psychiatric Workers (POA); His Majesty’s Courts and Tribunals Service (HMCTS) Common Platform; Police Federation; the National Association of Probation Officers (NAPO); and University and College Union (UCU). The POA is campaigning for MPs to support its call for a Royal Commission on Prisons and the Wider Criminal Justice System. The UK Government promised this in its 2019 manifesto and Queen’s Speech but have not yet delivered. It is needed now more than ever because prisons have changed from being places of support and rehabilitation to engines of criminality and have not recovered from 12 years of Tory austerity. The POA plan to publish a series of documents looking at different parts of the prison system and will highlight previously transformative accepted recommendations that have not been implemented. The HMCTS roll out of the Common Platform (CP) courts case management system has been a disaster, causing high levels of staff stress, impacting on the timeliness and quality of delivery of justice. The roll out was paused by the Senior Presiding Judge in August 2021 and this was followed by a 10 week testing phase in Bedfordshire, Cambridgeshire, and Hertfordshire. The CP is supposed to be a shared interface between all criminal justice process users where all details of a case can be entered, recorded and accessed as appropriate by each agency. PCS warned from the start of the roll out in September 2020, that the CP is flawed because it is unfeasible for Legal Advisors and Court Associates to digitally record the outcome of cases in real time without the assistance of administrative staff, and all criminal courts are not the same. Crown courts are different from Magistrates courts, where for legal reasons, charges and indictments are drafted in different ways. The PCS maintain that the CP is not fit for purpose, for example, last week in Cardiff Crown Court, Judge Jeremy Jenkins stated he was unable to proceed with a case after he and a prosecuting barrister could not work out from the CP which offences a defendant had pleaded guilty to and which he had asked to be taken into consideration. The judged told the court it was the fault of the IT system, which is supposed to assist not do the opposite. The CPS are now using their own case management system in preference to the CP, and the Lord Chief Justice has admitted the CP has a lot of technical problems. The Police Federation of England and Wales (PFEW) launched a campaign #SimplifyDG6 last August after the Attorney General’s Review of Disclosure was made public. The Review, published in May, recognised some of the shortcomings in the CPS Disclosure Guidance 2021 leading to significant pressure on police officers regarding submission of police files to the CPS for charging decisions, but failed to make recommendations to mitigate.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The campaign resulted in the National Police Chiefs’ Council (NPCC) engaging quickly with PFEW, and produced revised Joint Principles for Redaction, plus the inclusion of Ben Hudson, chair of Police Federation National Detectives’ Forum (PFNDF) on the National Disclosure Improvement Board. However, even though the revised guidance will reduce the redaction burden on police officers whilst complying with the legal framework, the current requirement for personal data needs amending so that the police can share data with the CPS, and remove the requirement for redaction until after cases have been charged, freeing up thousands of police officers hours, allowing them to be in their communities.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The National Association of Probation Officers (NAPO) updated us about the continuing staffing and workload crisis in the Probation Service. A decade ago officers were on the equivalent salary of a Police Sergeant but today it’s comparable to a Constable. Stress related absences are at a record high of 40%, with many suffering severe mental health issues. This poses a direct risk to public safety, with a recent HMIP report warning that very little meaningful rehabilitation taking place with clients.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The University and College Union (UCU) Prison Educators updated us on the negotiations between the four main prison education providers: Novus, Milton Keynes, People Plus and Weston College. Novus staff balloted to strike in October, but after talks at ACAS, accepted the improved pay and conditions offer where the lowest paid receive 8.4% and most members receiving 5-6%, and the pay review will move from November to April 2023. Milton Keynes staff accepted a pay increase of £1500 for staff up to £33,000, £1000 for staff over £33,000, capped above £66,000, backdated to 1st July 2022. People Plus staff accepted an improved offer of £4.5%. Weston College agreed a pay deal averaging 3.5%. But the Prison Education Service should set unified pay scales for all its staff.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was very honoured that my <a href="https://parliamentlive.tv/Event/Index/f522b3a6-2328-4419-ac38-b4cbe0fb3832">Shark Fins Private Members’ Bill</a>, which will ban the import and export of shark fins which have been cut off sharks whilst they are still alive, and the sharks are then thrown back into the sea to die a horrendous death, passed through its Committee Stage with a unanimous vote. My Bill now progresses through the House of Commons to its Report Stage, which will be held on Friday 20th January 2023. It was wonderful to have cross party support from all members of the Committee. There were some excellent interventions from Tracey Couch MP, Kevin Foster MP, Virginia Crosby MP, and Peter Dowd MP. The opposition spokesperson for the SNP, John McNally MP, and the official opposition spokesperson, Alex Sobel MP, extolled the very positive progress that my bill will make to improve marine animal welfare. And the Under Secretary of State for the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs, Rebecca Pow, pledged UK Government support for my Bill at Committee Stage and at the forthcoming Report Stage. She said that her UK Government are determined to get banning the import of shark finning into and from the UK into law.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I was among many MPs and Peers who supported the PCS “<a href="https://care4calais.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Safe-Passage-Policy-Paper.pdf">Care 4 Calais – Safe passage for refugees: humane alternative to the Rwanda policy</a>” report launch chaired by Olivia Blake MP with guest speakers including Lord Alf Dubs. The UK Government announced in April 2022 that they intended to send asylum seekers to Rwanda in an attempt to deter people from making the journey across the English Channel, and since this was announced the numbers have hit an all time high. The policy’s legality is being challenged in the courts. The report sets out the case for a Safe Passage Visa which would allow people a travel visa so they can cross the channel safely and so wouldn’t risk their lives, and break the traffic smugglers’ business model. On arrival in the UK they would seek asylum under the normal asylum procedure and if they fail to satisfy the requirements their claims would fail. A similar system was set up in response to the Russian invasion of Ukraine, and there has been no case of a Ukrainian crossing the Channel in a small boat or drowning. The PCS has called for a quicker and more efficient asylum application system process that would reduce the expense of refugees staying in UK hotels and rented accommodation at taxpayers expense. This could be spent on a better system. The report also calls for reform of immigration detention centres.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I dropped into the “<a href="http://www.tacklinggamblingstigma.com/">Tackling Gambling Stigma</a>” project which highlighted the feelings of guilt and shame that stop people seeking help for difficulties through gambling, which is made worse by the way gambling harm is seen by the public, media, and policy makers, who often hold negative stereotypes about it. This stigma leads to discrimination in how gambling is dealt with in regulations, financial services, health services, and the justice system. The project is an online resource of the stories of those affected by gambling harm, which is a multi-media website to help others understand through reading, listening, and watching people share their life experiences.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a vice chair of the APPG for Music, it was a pleasure to support my friend Kevin Brennan MP, who is the chair, at the “Establishing meaningful change in the UK music industry” session delivered by Roger and Cherise of Black Lives in Music (BLIM). Roger told us he has been involved in teaching music for 32 years and the barriers to progression for black and diverse people are still the same today. BLIM has 85 partners in the UK and been collating data. The evidence is that the problem is endemic, including lack of self-confidence and low self-esteem. Paulette representing the Music Industry, said that black people are often stereotyped into music that the record companies think they ought to be performing e.g. Reggae. And some have had to change the type of music they want to play in order to get a contract, which causes mental health issues. BLIM want to move from talking to action. Shingy of the Noisettes spoke eloquently about her journey as a diverse artist. She has written the official anthem for the Africa World Cup team.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The PM made a Statement on the G20 Summit in Indonesia, but started by saying that Russia once again has shown its barbarity by launching over 80 missiles at innocent people and infrastructure in Ukraine, and he will stand with Ukraine in the face of Russian criminal aggression. Almost all G20 members declared “today’s era must not be one of war”, and will uphold International Law, and the global economy. Two thirds of Ukraine wheat goes to developing countries, and Russia must not stand in its way.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">The Chancellor presented his Autumn Budget. I’ll concentrate on his pledge to provide £1.2 million in Barnet Consequentials to Welsh Government, and what this really means. After 12 years of UK Conservative Government and a decade of austerity, the UK is in deep recession and households are facing the biggest fall in living standards on record. The Autumn Statement was a missed opportunity to give hard-working public sector workers a much-needed inflation-matching pay rise. Additional funding for the Welsh Government of £1.2bn over two years will not fill the gaps. Wales’ settlement over the three year spending review 2022-23 to 2024-25 is still lower than expected in real terms. The impact of inflation means it is £3bn lower in real terms and up to £12bn lower next year. As a result of UK Government post-EU funding arrangements Wales has a £1.1bn shortfall for structural and rural funds. Working-age benefits will be uprated by inflation next year but will still be below real value by 6% of pre pandemic levels, £500 per year for an average out of work claimant, according to the Institute of Fiscal Studies. The Resolution Foundation claims that had wages grown at the same rate before the financial crisis of 2008, they would be £15,000 higher now. The Welsh Government will work through social partnership structures and bring together trade unions, employers, and deliver the best possible outcomes within the funding it has available.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I attended the <a href="https://cwmpas.coop/latest/european-summit-future-cooperation-europe/">Young People &amp; The Future of Cooperation in Europe Conference</a> organised by Cwmpas held in the Norwegian Church and Techniquest, Cardiff. The two day conference brought together young cooperators from all over the world to discuss themes including: exploring cooperative perspectives; inspiring a new generation to cooperate; young people and entrepreneurship through a cooperative lens; cooperative solutions for the energy crisis and green transition; Cooperatives Europe Strategy Workshop; and Cwmpas Showcase. Derek Walker, Chair of Cwmpas welcomed all cooperative delegates. Speakers included: Dawn Bowden MS, Deputy Minister for Arts, Sports &amp; Chief Whip; Susan Westhausen, President of Cooperatives Europe; Huw Thomas, Leader of Cardiff Council; Ana Aguirre, President of ICA Youth Committee; Rose Marley, Co-ops UK; George Kokkinidis and Peter Bloom, Essex University; Pete Westall and Amelia Crews, Mid-Counties Cooperative; Lesley Williams, Welsh ICE; Elsa Brander and Emma Pedersen, Kooperationen project Orexund. The President of Co-op France, Jean-Louis Bancel, spoke about the future challenges facing world cooperators. Cwmpas was showcased by Derek Walker, Glenn Bowen, Martin Downes, Catherine Evans, and other staff who made this conference a wonderful experience for all delegates and guest speakers.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">It was a privilege to <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1595703782641278976?cxt=HHwWgIClsdmIiqUsAAAA">speak with the Cubs of Clydach – 2nd Swansea Valley Scout Group</a> about being a Member of Parliament and how this fits in with different levels of government in Wales. The 16 cubs were very knowledgeable about democracy and asked me some very probing questions. I described Oral Questions and debates in the Chamber; Westminster Hall debates; APPGs; drop-in events; and Committees. We also discussed wide ranging topics from climate change to animal welfare, tax and welfare benefits, and Veganism. My thanks to Neath’s Finest Cub Scout Leader Noel Davies for arranging my visit which was thoroughly enjoyable and I’m pleased that all Cubs received their Democracy Badges.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined the University and College Union (UCU) Rising “Enough is Enough” Picket Line at Swansea Bay University. Striking is always a last resort and UCU members do not want to harm student’s education, but management have left them with no choice but to defend pay, pensions and conditions. They are striking because pay has been cut by 25% since 2009; employers have offered just 3%, which a massive cut relative to inflation; USS pensions have been cut by 35%, despite the scheme being in surplus; overwork, insecurity and poor pay impact student’s learning. They are asking for a fair pay deal; closing equality pay gaps; elimination of casualisation; action on workloads; restoration of USS pension benefits; and a new valuation of USS pension scheme. Employers ended 2020-21 with £2.4bn more in the bank than they started with, but have not invested in staff, and the people running universities are paid more than £500,000 plus expenses each. There was massive support on the picket line from staff and students, despite the poor weather.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I joined the Royal Mail Picket Line at Neath Sorting Office. The Royal Mail Group (RMG) made record profits of £758m in May 2022, but allege they are losing £1m per day. <a href="https://twitter.com/CWUnews/status/1596865315224313858?cxt=HHwWhICzweWimqksAAAA">Dave Ward, General Secretary of CWU</a>, says that the RMG CEO and its Board have not acted with transparency nor integrity in dealings with the CWU since the beginning of 2022, and are not interested in building a sustainable Royal Mail that serves our communities. Careless mistakes and an unwillingness to listen to the workforce has led directly to the RMG announcing 10,000 job losses, which the CWU can’t accept and would be disastrous for the service. The RMG has not explained: why it walked away from the “Pathway to Change” agreement dealing with the decline in parcel volume and expanding the role of postal workers; prioritising handing £567m to shareholders rather than supporting its workers; why they pressed on with unagreed and unacceptable changes which inevitably led to a national dispute; renaming the Royal Mail company “International Distributions Services PLC”. RMG may be considering approaching the UK Government to end 6 day deliveries. Postal workers and Royal Mail connect communities in a way no other service does, and are part of the social fabric of the UK, serving 32 million addresses on a daily basis. Royal Mail can continue to be a major contributor to the British economy and provide secure well paid jobs whilst modernising, but this can only happen if the Board agree an alternative business approach that can leverage the unique competitive advantage afforded to Royal Mail alongside diversification of new services and products.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">I dropped in to the Vale of <a href="https://valeofneath.foodbank.org.uk/">Neath Trussell Trust Foodbank at Peniel Church Glynneath</a> and met the wonderful volunteers who work tirelessly and compassionately to help those families facing the cost of living crisis. My sincere thanks to Phil and his dedicated volunteers.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">On White Ribbon Day, <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1596139848531836934?cxt=HHwWjICwuYmv0KYsAAAA">I continued to campaign</a> to end violence against women and girls. We must work together to make sure that this horrific evil ends. Everyday we have a duty to stand up and ensure women and girls are protected against mental and physical abuse.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">As a member of St Davids Church Neath congregation, I was proud to attend the amazing <a href="https://twitter.com/Rees4Neath/status/1597198624861175809?cxt=HHwWgoC-6fvrsaosAAAA">Christmas Market church fundraiser</a>. There were many stalls which offered an opportunity to buy some superb homemade Christmas decorations and gifts. Lots of raffles, delicious refreshments, and festive spirit. It was so good to meet up with many old friends and make some new ones.</p>
<p style="font-weight: 400;">My Christmas Card Competition is open to all constituents in Neath. I will be using the winner as my 2022 Christmas Card. Please send a photograph or a scan of your design to my email address: christina.rees.mp@parliament.uk. Closing date 9th December 2022. We have received some fantastic designs, but there’s still time to send yours in.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">There were many Urgent Oral Questions (UQs) and UK Government Ministerial Oral Statements in the Chamber. UQs included: Migration Update; Iran Treatment of Protesters, and Statements included: UN Peacekeeping Mission in Mali; Missile Incident in Poland; Social Housing Standards; G20 Summit in Indonesia; and The Autumn Statement: Chancellor of the Exchequer. I also attended many events […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Christina Rees</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.christinarees.org/?p=2705</id>
    <published>2022-12-01T16:05:07Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T16:05:07Z</updated>
    <category term="My Weekly Round-up"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Man in Westminster - Mersham Sports Club</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-mersham-sports-club" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Some plans take a long time to come to fruition, so I very much enjoyed a visit to Mersham Sports Club. It is the best part of ten years since they approached me about buying some land from the Church Commissioners to extend their facilities, which are in great demand.
Finally last week I was able…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.damiangreen.co.uk/news/our-man-westminster-mersham-sports-club</id>
    <published>2022-12-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Cost of Living Fact Sheet</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/cost-living-fact-sheet" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">The Government and I recognise that we are living through a tough period. That is why the Government has provided support to all households across the UK. Below is a fact sheet which outlines all of the support available during the current cost of living increase.</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.teamtrevelyan.co.uk/news/cost-living-fact-sheet</id>
    <published>2022-12-01T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-12-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Llanelli Star Column – The importance of supporting local small businesses</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://niagriffith.org.uk/2022/11/llanelli-star-column-the-importance-of-supporting-local-small-businesses/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, local businesses throughout Llanelli will be marking Small Business Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According
to the Federation of Small Businesses, SMEs make up 99% of the business
population in the UK and create 16 million jobs. Now in its tenth year, Small
Business Saturday celebrates this success and encourages consumers to &amp;#8216;shop
local&amp;#8217; and to support businesses in their own communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Small businesses are facing many
difficulties including a crashed economy, soaring energy costs and supply chain
issues. The Tory Government’s Autumn Statement with its high tax, low growth
agenda will leave even less money in people’s pockets making things even
harder. They need our support not only to survive but to thrive.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Small businesses do much to enrich our lives
and our communities, providing jobs, training and driving economic growth.&amp;nbsp; For them to succeed, they need a UK Government
that is pro-worker and pro-business and one that is a strong and effective
partner, bringing stability and practical support.&amp;nbsp; The current Tory chaos cannot provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Only a change of government at a UK level
can deliver the change that small businesses need.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Labour already has
a plan that will help business owners looking to get on, both immediately and
in the long-term.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our industrial
strategy will set out a long-term framework for business policy, ensuring
certainty, stability and no unexpected changes.&amp;nbsp;
A UK Labour Government would keep energy bills down for good, with a
credible strategy to increase the availability of cheap, clean, home-grown
sources of power.&amp;nbsp; Support for the
self-employed is also part of the equation and a UK Labour Government will
extend the protections for self-employed workers including the right to sick
pay.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This weekend, I
will be supporting local small businesses in my constituency at every
opportunity.&amp;nbsp; I hope that you will be
able to too.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This Saturday, local businesses throughout Llanelli will be marking Small Business Saturday. According to the Federation of Small Businesses, SMEs make up 99% of the business population in the UK and create 16 million jobs. Now in its tenth year, Small Business Saturday celebrates this success and encourages consumers to ‘shop local’ and to support […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nia Griffith</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://niagriffith.org.uk/?p=8648</id>
    <published>2022-11-30T15:41:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-30T15:41:10Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<title>Apply for Pension Credit by 18 Dec, you could qualify for £324 Cost of Living Payment</title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2147-apply-for-pension-credit-by-18-dec-you-could-qualify-for-324-cost-of-living-payment"/>
		<published>2022-11-30T11:46:47+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-11-30T11:46:47+00:00</updated>
		<id>https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/news/2147-apply-for-pension-credit-by-18-dec-you-could-qualify-for-324-cost-of-living-payment</id>
		<author>
			<name>Webmaster</name>
			<email>kathie@stephen-mcpartland.com</email>
		</author>
		<summary type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you apply for Pension Credit by 18 December you could qualify for a £324 Cost of Living Payment &amp;amp; could be on average £3,500 a year better off. Check if you, parents, loved ones are eligible: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ws34t9xmHe"&gt;https://t.co/ws34t9xmHe&lt;/a&gt; or call 0800 99 1234 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HelpForHouseholds?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HelpForHouseholds&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/XOQsEdAuxg"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XOQsEdAuxg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1597844193678086144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 30, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class="feed-description"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;If you apply for Pension Credit by 18 December you could qualify for a £324 Cost of Living Payment &amp;amp; could be on average £3,500 a year better off. Check if you, parents, loved ones are eligible: &lt;a href="https://t.co/ws34t9xmHe"&gt;https://t.co/ws34t9xmHe&lt;/a&gt; or call 0800 99 1234 &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/HelpForHouseholds?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#HelpForHouseholds&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/XOQsEdAuxg"&gt;pic.twitter.com/XOQsEdAuxg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rt Hon Stephen McPartland (@SMcPartland) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland/status/1597844193678086144?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 30, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/SMcPartland" data-size="large" data-dnt="true" data-show-count="false"&gt;Follow @SMcPartland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to let me know what you think &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/90-second-survey" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="90 Second Survey"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sign up to my &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Newsletter"&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt; and click &lt;a href="https://www.stephen-mcpartland.com/help-stephen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="Help Stephen"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to help me make a difference&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
		<category term="Featured"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
		<category term="Local News"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Beam Park Station Update Nov 22</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://joncruddas.org.uk/beam-park-station-update-nov-22" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">Beam Park Station Update Nov 22</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" about="https://joncruddas.org.uk/user/12" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Andrew</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2022-11-30T10:29:00+00:00">Wed, 11/30/2022 - 10:29</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew</name>
    </author>
    <id>1168 at https://joncruddas.org.uk</id>
    <published>2022-11-30T10:29:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-30T10:29:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Presentation of my Carbon Emissions Buildings Bill to the House of Commons</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/presentation-my-carbon-emissions-buildings-bill-house-commons" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This country has led the world in addressing climate change. However, buildings and construction are hardly accounted for and yet contribute 25% of UK carbon emissions.  My Carbon Emissions (Buildings) Bill, which had its Second Reading in the House of Commons today, takes the first step in…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.jeromemayhew.org.uk/news/presentation-my-carbon-emissions-buildings-bill-house-commons</id>
    <published>2022-11-25T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-25T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Christmas Card Competition 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.johnlamont.org/christmas" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over the last few weeks, schools across the Scottish Borders have been taking part in a Christmas Card Competition run by Rachael Hamilton MSP and I. Now it's your chance to pick the winner.
We received hundreds of fantastic designs and have now whittled them down to 12 finalists. You can see each…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.johnlamont.org/christmas</id>
    <published>2022-11-23T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-23T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Local Update – Local Plan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/6324-2/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent</p>
<p>I am writing to share with you my contribution to the debate about the Epsom and Ewell Local Plan which is now beginning its formal process. I expect the Borough Council to publish its initial thinking about the plan shortly.</p>
<p>Epsom and Ewell Borough Council is currently in the process of publishing and developing its local plan for the area for the next 10-15 years. Every local authority is obliged to do this, and to explain how it will meet housing need, look after its local economy and protect its local environment.</p>
<p>Each council has also prepared an assessment of local housing need, based on national guidance of how to do this.</p>
<p>We clearly have a need for new homes locally. There are too many young people who grow up or are educated here but cannot afford to remain in the area. And we have a serious shortage of social housing.</p>
<p>The housing assessment for Epsom and Ewell is though impossibly high, and I have been clear both nationally and locally that we need to use the provisions in the National Planning Policy Framework that limit what is expected from a local council. Very probably this involves a battle with national planning inspectors, but I am ready to fight that battle for our area.</p>
<p>But we do need to do all we can to meet the housing need, and I have proposed a comprehensive redevelopment of the Kiln Lane and Longmead areas of Epsom to achieve this without building all over our green belt.</p>
<p>Since that time I have had several conversations with the Borough, and also organised the preparation of a draft masterplan by a firm of architects with local connections.</p>
<p>The picture below gives an overview of the plan:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6326" src="http://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Masterplan.jpg" alt="" width="338" height="246" srcset="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Masterplan-200x146.jpg 200w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Masterplan-300x218.jpg 300w, https://www.chrisgrayling.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/Masterplan.jpg 338w" sizes="(max-width: 338px) 100vw, 338px"/></p>
<p>The plan involves the construction of a mixed use area of development, with retail and offices on the lower floors and flats above, with some terraced housing on the site as well. This kind of mix is typical of what is being done elsewhere. The buildings would be no higher than those already in and around the town centre.</p>
<p>The scheme provides a comparable amount of commercial space to the present plus nearly 5,000 homes. The plan would be to have car showrooms and parking areas built upwards rather than across large areas of parking as at present. But over time I would expect the commercial space to attract more creative businesses, given the presence in Epsom of the University of the Creative Arts which is now one of the country’s leading institutions of its kind. It would also aim to provide more homes for younger people rather than simply building more executive homes on open land. My worry is that developing the green belt is an easy option for the Council. It is always more complicated to reorganise what has already been developed than to build on a green field, but in our area it is much better to take the more difficult approach.</p>
<p>I hope this plan serves as a route for Epsom and Ewell Borough Council to plot a different way forward and protect our open spaces.</p>
<h2>Epsom and Ewell Energy Efficiency Scheme</h2>
<p>And just a couple of updates about the Energy Crisis locally.</p>
<p>Firstly a reminder that if you do not need your £400 rebate from the Government and are happy to use it to support the Epsom and Ewell Energy Efficiency Scheme, being organised with the Foodbank and Citizens Advice in Epsom to help those struggling with their bills, you can do so via this link.</p>
<p><a href="https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/98eeCRO3xsv5ggnEf9CRxP?domain=justgiving.com">https://www.justgiving.com/campaign/epsom-ewell-energy-support-scheme</a></p>
<p>Both organisations cover a wider area including Epsom Downs, Ashtead and Leatherhead, and so if you are based there your contribution will also be a big help.</p>
<h2>Warm Space Schemes</h2>
<p>In addition two local churches have also asked me to let you know that they are running Warm Spaces schemes – where when the weather is colder those worried about their bills can spend a few hours in the warm.</p>
<p><strong>Ruxley Church</strong> is launching their Warm Welcome, Warm Space on Thursday 24<sup>th</sup> November from 11.30am to 2.30pm. As well as a warm welcome, people will be able to enjoy complimentary hot drinks, soup and a roll, read a newspaper or book, play a game, chat with others or simply sit quietly.</p>
<p>The church is in Ruxley Lane, KT19 0AF. People are welcome to drop in on any Thursday between now and the end of March 2023.</p>
<p>And the café at <strong>St George’s Churc</strong>h in Barnett Wood Lane in Ashtead is also joining the scheme. People are welcome to come and be in the café for a while or all day…….if they can buy one hot drink the team there will then offer them coffee/tea for free.</p>
<p>With best wishes</p>
<p>Chris</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/6324-2/">Local Update – Local Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Dear constituent I am writing to share with you my contribution to the debate about the Epsom and Ewell Local Plan which is now beginning its formal process. I expect the Borough Council to publish its initial thinking about the plan shortly. Epsom and Ewell Borough Council is currently in the process of publishing and [...]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net/6324-2/">Local Update – Local Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisgrayling.net">Chris Grayling</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Sara Olsen</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisgrayling.net/?p=6324</id>
    <published>2022-11-23T08:51:41Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-23T08:51:41Z</updated>
    <category term="Local Plan"/>
    <category term="Local Update"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>oliverrosina@aol.com</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[GIVING TUESDAY]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"/>

		<id>https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/?p=469</id>
		<updated>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-21T08:48:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk" term="NEWS"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.angelarayner.co.uk/2022/11/21/giving-tuesday/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nigel Mills MP</name>
							<uri>https://www.nigelmillsmp.com</uri>
						</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"/>

		<id>https://nigelmillsmp.com/?p=3358</id>
		<updated>2022-11-18T12:46:07Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-18T12:46:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://nigelmillsmp.com/" term="Local News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Constituent, Welcome to my November&#160;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&#160; Autumn Statement: Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/"><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/cloudycdn/uploads/1507626306.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p><em>Dear Constituent,</em></p>



<p>Welcome to my November&nbsp;email newsletter. The focus is on yesterday&#8217;s Autumn Statement delivered by the Chancellor, with details on what this means for you, but there are also updates on local campaigns and on the ongoing issue of the Channel Crossings.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Autumn Statement:</h1>



<p>Yesterday, the Chancellor delivered the Government’s highly anticipated Autumn Statement. In which he detailed how the Government intends to restore economic stability and tackle inflation.</p>



<p>Like many countries around the world, the UK is facing profound economic challenges. Supply disruption caused by the world’s economies emerging from lockdown has been compounded by Putin’s illegal invasion of Ukraine and deliberate interference with Europe’s energy supply to create massive increases in the cost of energy. This has led to high inflation and high interest rates across many of the world’s major economies, and the UK is no different.</p>



<p>I welcome the proposals in the Autumn Statement. To achieve long-term, sustainable growth we need to grip inflation, balance the books, and get debt falling as a share of GDP. The plan presented by the Chancellor yesterday takes the tough decisions to face up to this situation without passing the buck onto future generations. What’s more, it protects the hard-working majority by enacting no headline tax increases, and protects the most vulnerable by maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation – something I have personally been campaigning for. All while protecting and maintaining public spending for the next two years at the levels set out in 2021.</p>



<p>The plan involves a roughly equal split between tax rises and spending cuts, with the greatest burden falling on those who can afford it most. Specifically, the plan:</p>



<p><strong>Increases taxpayer funding for our NHS and schools by an extra £11 billion over the next two years.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Government will provide £4 billion in additional funding to schools and £7.7 billion in additional funding to the NHS and social care sector over the next two years. Prioritising the public services that matter most.</p>



<p>&#8211; £2–3 billion in additional funding for the NHS in each of the next two years so we can bring down ambulance waiting times, tackle the Covid backlog, and improve access to GPs. Also providing £2.8 billion next year and £4.7 billion the year after for adult social care, which aims to double the number of people leaving hospitals on time and into care by 2024, addressing unmet needs and boosting low pay in the sector.</p>



<p>&#8211; £4 billion in additional funding for schools over the next two years. We are increasing the schools budget by £2 billion this year and £2 billion next year to help schools with rising costs as a result of inflation. Which is more than Labour has pledged to give schools.</p>



<p><strong>Introduces no headline tax increases.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Autumn Statement raises £25 billion in additional taxes over the forecast period but there are no increases in the headline rates of tax. By targeting tax rises toward businesses, wealthier households, and the oil and gas industry, the Government has ensured that it can honour its manifesto commitment not to increase Income Tax, National Insurance, or VAT.</p>



<p>&#8211; Instead of raising rates, the Government is freezing personal tax thresholds for a further two years. There are also reforms to the Additional Rate threshold, so that a taxpayer who earns more than £150,000 will pay £1,200 more in tax per year.</p>



<p>&#8211; It is only fair that companies who have made genuine windfall profits as a result of the war in Ukraine make an additional contribution to pay for the support we have outlined. So from 2023, the Energy Profits Levy rate will rise from 25per cent to 35per cent and will continue until the end of March 2028. A 45per cent Levy will be applied to extraordinary returns made by electricity generators. In total these windfall taxes will raise £52 billion over six years. This is more ambitious than Labour’s proposal.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting and maintaining public spending.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; For the next two years public spending will remain at the levels set out in 2021 and then increase by one per cent in real terms each year until 2027–28.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting every household with their energy bills.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; The Energy Price Guarantee will continue to support everyone for another year. This winter, the price households pay for the energy they use will be capped, so that a typical household will pay £2,500. From April 2023, the price cap will rise so that a typical household will pay £3,000. The Energy Price Guarantee will then end in April 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting the most vulnerable through maintaining the pensions triple lock and raising benefits in line with inflation.</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; I have been publicly campaigning for benefits and pensions to be increased in line with inflation for some time now, and so was very pleased to see the Chancellor yesterday confirm that this would be part of the Government’s plan.</p>



<p>&#8211; To protect the most vulnerable, benefits will now be increased in line with inflation for 2023–24. More than 10 million households in receipt of working-age and disability benefits will see an increase in their benefit payments.</p>



<p>&#8211; The pensions triple lock will also be protected. Because of the difficult but necessary decisions the Government has taken elsewhere, the triple lock for pensions will be protected in full. This means that in April, the State Pension will increase in line with inflation, which is the biggest cash increase in the State Pension ever.</p>



<p><strong>Additional support for the most vulnerable.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Over £12 billion of additional targeted support is assigned to help the most vulnerable households. The Government will continue providing this year’s cost of living payments and next year it will provide extra one-off payments of £900 for the 8 million households on means-tested benefits, £300 to pensioners, and £150 for disability benefit recipients. The Government is also providing £1 billion of extra funding by extending the Household Support Fund for another year.</p>



<p>The OBR has confirmed that these plans will restore the public finances to a sustainable position and help reduce inflation and unemployment. And I look forward to engaging with my ministerial colleagues as these policies are rolled out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Remembrance Sunday:</h1>



<p>This year for Remembrance Sunday on 13th November, I was honoured to lay wreaths in Ripley and Kilburn in memory of those who have served our county, and in honour of those who are still serving. There are a multitude of remembrance services held across our constituency every year, so it is unfortunately impossible for me to attend all of them. However, every year I try to rotate which services I attend. This year it was a memorial service at Ripley War Memorial in the morning and another in Kilburn in the afternoon.</p>



<p>This has been a particularly important period of remembrance as we mark 40 years since the end of the Falkland’s war, and we commemorate the 255 British personnel who lost their lives in defence of the islands. Their courage and sacrifice must never be forgotten. Thank you to everyone who organised or supported the remembrance services and parades across Amber Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<h1>Alfreton Solar Farm Update:</h1>



<p>On 21st October, I spoke at the public inquiry into plans from Kronos Solar to build a 50-megawatt solar farm between Alfreton and Oakerthorpe. Many of you will remember that Amber Valley Borough Council’s (AVBC) planning authorities rejected the proposal last December, stating that the project’s scale and impact on the landscape outweighed any environmental benefits the site would provide. However, Kronos Solar have since filed an appeal to overturn the decision of AVBC and get the site approved, resulting in this enquiry.</p>



<p>I have been opposing the project on behalf of local residents and businesses throughout the process, a great many of whom have contacted me about the proposals. I very much support the expansion of our clean energy network, and in the right place a solar farm would be an asset. However, there are good reasons why this site was refused planning permission. We all want renewable energy expansion but not at any cost.</p>



<p>To begin with, much of the land is north facing, which means the site would need to be overly large. The impact on the amenity of local residents, the impact on the countryside area, and the impact on the various heritage assets is just too great. And that is before we consider Alfreton Park and Alfreton Park Community School, which looks after children with the very highest level of need, very close in the vicinity.</p>



<p>It is clear to me that this is a totally unsuitable site for this intensity of development. Frankly, I believe this proposal was not based on a thorough search for suitable land for a solar farm, instead, it looks to me to be based on a search for a suitable sub-station, with the proposal then trying to force some land to suit.</p>



<p>I will continue to keep residents updated on any developments. And at present, a decision is expected at some point in the next few months.</p>



<h1>Pollution and our waterways:</h1>



<p>I have recently welcomed the Department for Environment, Food, and Rural Affairs’ (DEFRA) plans to raise the civil penalty for water companies who pollute our environment by one thousand times, from £250,000 up to £250 million. I am hopeful that increasing the penalties the Environment Agency can enforce without a lengthy and costly court process will enable swifter and stronger action to be taken against water companies that illegally pollute our environment.</p>



<p>Many residents have contacted me about pollution and the use of storm drains in our sewage system. There has also been a great deal of misinformation circulating on social media regarding the Government’s campaign to address these issues.</p>



<p>Last year, the Government introduced the Environment Act 2021 which was a bill designed to tackle this problem and reduce sewage pollution ignored by previous Governments. When the Environment Act was going through Parliament the Duke of Wellington, a hereditary peer, introduced an amendment that would legislate the complete elimination of storm drains and therefore of storm overflow sewage into our waterways. This of course sounds admirable, and indeed is something I support in principle. However, this amendment came without a plan for how it could be delivered and how such a vast project could be funded.</p>



<p>Initial assessments suggested elimination would cost between £150 &#8211; £650 billion. To put those figures in perspective, £150 billion was more than the entire schools, policing, and defence budgets put together. Therefore, the Government did not support the amendment, and I did not vote for it. In my view, the last thing people wanted was for their water bill to go through the roof.</p>



<p>Twitter mis-informers seized this opportunity and claimed we had all voted in favour of water companies dumping raw sewage into our rivers. Which was totally false, and ironically punished the Government for actually trying to do something about the problem ignored by previous Governments.</p>



<p>With this most recent announcement by DEFRA, I am glad to see the Government continuing the campaign to improve the quality of our waterways. To hold water companies to account, and ensure any polluter pays for the environmental harm they cause, the Environment Agency must take advantage of these new powers.</p>



<h1>Illegal crossings over the Channel:</h1>



<p>Many of you have contacted me about the number of small boats illegally crossing the English Channel in recent months. I appreciate the strength of feeling on this alarming issue and want to outline my position to you and explain some of the challenges we face in tackling this problem.</p>



<p>The number of illegal entries into the United Kingdom via small boats crossing the English Channel is too high. It endangers the lives of those making the journey, puts money into the pockets of ruthless and brutal people smuggling gangs, and puts undue pressure on our existing asylum system as well as our public services. I remain committed to an immigration policy that welcomes people to the UK through safe and legal routes, and an immigration policy that allows us to provide asylum to those in genuine need. However, it is clear many of those arriving in small boats are not here in genuine need of asylum, and as a result, the current situation cannot go on.</p>



<p>One reason for small boat crossings increasing in frequency is the success the Government has had in tackling other forms of illegal immigration. Such as increased checks and security for lorries and freight crossing the channel, effectively reducing the number of illegal entries into the UK through these means, and increasing the number of people turning to small boats as a way to enter the UK. The problem that now presents itself is how to police and secure hundreds of miles of coastline 24/7.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, Parliament passed the Nationality and Borders Act which overhauled our approach to asylum and illegal migration. The legislation includes fairness towards those who need our help, and in welcoming people through safe and legal routes, but firmness in tackling abuse of the system and expediting the removal of those who have no legitimate claim for protection. It is worth noting that Labour opposed this Act designed to toughen our immigration system.</p>



<p>Further to changing the law in this country, the Government has recently signed a joint UK-France arrangement on tackling small boat crossings in the Channel which includes a 40% increase in the number of UK-funded officers patrolling French beaches. The new agreement lays the foundations for deeper UK-French co-operation to tackle illegal migration. The arrangement means, for the first time, specialist UK officers will be able to observe French officials at work in control rooms and on the ground patrolling the coastline.</p>



<p>It is clear, however, that big challenges still lie ahead, and that the number of small boats currently crossing the channel is unacceptable. The Prime Minister speaking recently on GB News said that tackling illegal immigration was a huge priority for his Government, and that while the recent joint UK -France arrangement was a big step in the right direction there was more that needs to be done. I share the Prime Minister’s view, and will continue engaging with my ministerial and Parliamentary colleagues to make the case for further measures to reduce cross channel migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Street Watch &#8211; report it:</strong></p>



<p>As always, if there are any street repairs in your area, such as potholes, pavement repairs or broken street lights, you can report these issues and concerns to me quickly and easily&nbsp;<a href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/amber-valley-street-watch/">here</a> so I can ask for the repairs to be investigated and addressed.</p>



<p><strong>GDPR and privacy notice:</strong></p>



<p>Data laws&nbsp;changed with the introduction of the new GDPR legislation: you can find my office’s privacy policy <a href="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/privacy/">here</a> and, if you don’t want to receive these emails anymore, you can unsubscribe <a href="mailto:nigel@nigelmillsmp.com?subject=Unsubscribe&amp;body=Unsubscribe%20from%20newsletter.%20">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Get in Touch!</strong></p>



<p>As always, you can contact me by hitting the &#8216;reply&#8217; button on this email, or you can ring my office on 01773 744341.</p>



<p><strong>Twitter and Facebook</strong></p>



<p>You can also follow me on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/nigelmills">@NigelMills </a>and like&nbsp;me on Facebook&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/nigelmillsofficial/">here</a> to stay up to date with news and events in Amber Valley throughout the month.</p>



<p><em>Yours sincerely,</em></p>



<h1><em>Nigel</em><img decoding="async" alt="" src="http://www.nigelmillsmp.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Nigel-signature.jpg"></h1>



<p>Promoted by Nigel Mills MP, of Unicorn House, Wellington Street, Ripley, Derbyshire, DE5 3EH.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com/nigels-november-newsletter-autumn-statement-update/">Nigel&#8217;s November Newsletter &#038; Autumn Statement update</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://nigelmillsmp.com">Nigel Mills MP</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Nothing new for a country in crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/nothing-new-for-a-country-in-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Responding to the Chancellor’s Autumn Statement, Newcastle North MP, Catherine McKinnell, commented: “Families are grappling with the biggest wage squeeze in a generation. Twelve years of Conservative failure exacerbated by twelve weeks of mini budget chaos has left our economy stagnant, borrowing costs up, prices skyrocketing, and ordinary people unable to meet their most basic … <a href="https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/nothing-new-for-a-country-in-crisis/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Nothing new for a country in crisis</span> <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Catherine McKinnell</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.catherinemckinnellmp.co.uk/?p=7773</id>
    <published>2022-11-17T16:45:38Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-17T16:45:38Z</updated>
    <category term="Economy"/>
    <category term="Families"/>
    <category term="Features"/>
    <category term="Health and Social Care"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rushanara Ali article on why Iran should be removed from UN commission</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Rushanara Ali</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.rushanaraali.org/rushanara_ali_on_the_protests_in_iran</id>
    <published>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-16T12:05:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title " style="text-align:left"><h3 style="font-size:45px;line-height: normal;display:block;margin:0px 0px 10px 0px;color:#ed1c24;">Kind Fest <span style="color:#06396a;">Compassion in Politics?</span></h3></div>
	<div class="wpb_text_column wpb_content_element ">
		<div class="wpb_wrapper">
			<p>It’s a pleasure to be speaking with you today as the co-Chair of the All-Party Parliamentary Group on Compassionate Politics. For those of you not familiar with our Parliamentary system, APPGs consist of members from different parties and from both Houses. We aim to work collaboratively together to address specific issues; in this case we want to shift the culture of politics to one that’s more compassionate.</p>
<h4><strong>WHAT’S WRONG WITH OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM?</strong></h4>
<p>My co-Chair Baroness Sayeeda Warsi and I convened the APPG on Compassionate Politics with the support of Matt &amp; Jennifer and the Compassion in Politics team back in 2019 as we shared the same concerns, as did many of our colleagues, about the increased divisiveness in politics which had steadily grown since 2016.</p>
<p>Many of us recognised that the division and discord being played out in Parliament, and also in some local authorities, was negatively impacting on our communities and how people were treating each other. A climate of fear, hostility and blame has been emanating from our politics. There was another effect: an escalating lack of trust in politics and politicians. A recent CiP poll showed that <a href="https://assets.nationbuilder.com/cip/pages/304/attachments/original/1663327185/OP19111_Compassion_in_Politics_Trust_and_Civility_-_Final_Tables.xlsx?1663327185">7 in 10 people don’t trust anything politicians say</a>. <a href="https://www.opinium.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/OP12494-Compassion-in-%20Politics-tables.xlsx">9 in 10 don’t think politicians have their interests at heart</a> and <a href="https://www.electoral-reform.org.uk/new-polling-reveals-just-how-powerless-people-feel-over-westminster/">2 in 3 feel completely powerless over the decisions being made at Westminster</a>. This incredibly disturbing for the health of our democracy.</p>
<p>However, as much as there are kindred spirits across the political spectrum, we’ve had a party-political system for centuries in this country which has been largely based on tribalism and narrow party rivalries, on making the electorate believe that each party has the answers to make their life better/fairer/safer for them and, unfortunately, negative campaigning has been seen by some to be part of that.</p>
<p>Negative campaigning has been successfully aided by a negative and partisan media, again, over many years. But over the last 16 years or so we’ve had another dimension: the wild west that is social media, where there is little policing of unlawful content by either the platforms or law enforcement agencies, let alone disinformation or misinformation; even legal but harmful content which includes platforms pushing information on suicide to school-age children is apparently off limits. Collectively, these exponentially ramp up the negativity, and even the hate.</p>
<h4><strong>SO WHAT SHOULD WE DO ABOUT IT? </strong></h4>
<p>Many of you will already know that as human beings we have an immense and innate capacity for compassion &amp; kindness: it’s what drives us to care for our family, look out for our friends, and help our neighbours. Within our communities, it can be nurtured and enabled, or it can be stifled and suppressed. The key to cultivating this compassion and kindness is leadership: leadership in our schools, leadership at work and, fundamentally leadership by politicians.</p>
<p>Again, as many of you will also know, ‘Compassion’ as defined by psychologists, involves an awareness of suffering with a commitment to alleviate and prevent it. Compassion is built on empathy, sympathy, and understanding – a tuning into the experience of self and others. Secondly, it requires commitment. Compassion doesn’t zero-in on the distress of others only to turn away, castigate, or blame. It seeks to understand and learn. Thirdly, it requires action – and action not only to alleviate the symptoms of suffering but to uproot their cause.</p>
<p>The recent pledges from the new Prime Minister and Chancellor for compassion and compassionate Conservatism are welcome but what do they mean?</p>
<p>To govern effectively through compassion will require a commitment to not only help those who are suffering today but also create conditions in which everyone can thrive tomorrow. Those instincts need to be activated and championed because, right now, we live according to quite alternate values. Refugees, social security users, and others are being decried, vilified, and shamed. This approach not only weakens us as a society, but it is also injurious to political engagement, to our very democracy.</p>
<p>A compassionate Government would recognise our common humanity, and that all human beings are equal. And within this, a compassionate immigration system in a country which upholds the rule of law, would abide by our obligations under the UN Refugee Convention which the UK is not only a signatory to, but helped to develop, after the horrors of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>As a Labour politician I would argue that the market doesn’t have all the answers to the economic crisis millions are facing, and that the immediate compassionate response to this crisis would be to recognise and address the fact that the <strong>richest 1% of individuals</strong> <strong>pay 12.5% of their income in tax</strong> compared with the <strong>50% lowest earners who pay 25.5% of their income in tax</strong>. Similarly, I would argue that the tax from corporations has flatlined over the last 12 years at about 2% and that some companies, for example, energy companies like BP have reported their highest quarterly profits for 14 years. Their figures are eclipsed by Shell who delivered second quarter profits of over £9bn.</p>
<p>I have argued that a compassionate Government would reflect this in their Autumn Statement next week.</p>
<p>There’s so much more policy-wise that could reflect compassion in the Government’s response to these very real issues and hardships so many in our country face.</p>
<p>But hand-in-hand with this, is an effort to reform the culture of our politics. Good policies can only come from good politics and if our government is truly committed to a compassionate future, it needs to create the right environment for such a future to grow and prosper. That has to start with the conduct of those in high office. We need to put the Ministerial and Members’ codes on a statutory footing so that they can be universally read and be properly enforced. The Prime Minister needs to appoint and then empower the government ethics advisor to launch independent investigations into ministerial conduct and strengthen the rules to prevent politicians from wilfully lying to the public.</p>
<p>Compassionate governance also means working alongside those we seek to serve, not dictating policies from the centre. We need to look at how we can reconnect politicians to the people we serve by shifting power away from Westminster. Establishing citizen and constituency assemblies as part of developing active and empowered citizens would be an important start.</p>
<p>Finally, this crisis in politics is not just a UK phenomenon; democracies across the world are facing the same issues. The last year’s insurrection at the Capitol is just one example of this. I would urge the like-minded to work together internationally for a new and compassionate politics.</p>

		</div>
	</div>
<div class="vc_empty_space" style="height: 20px"><span class="vc_empty_space_inner"/></div>
</div></div></div></div><div class="vc_row wpb_row vc_row-fluid vc_custom_1547808642785 vc_row-has-fill"><div class="wpb_column vc_column_container vc_col-sm-12"><div class="vc_column-inner"><div class="wpb_wrapper"><div class="themeum-title-donate " style="text-align:center"><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-title-call no-padding"><h2 class="call-to-title" style="color:#ffffff;font-size:24px;font-weight:700;text-transform:capitalize;">Feel strongly about this article? </h2></div><div class="col-sm-12 col-md-12 col-lg-6 col-xs-12 themeum-join-campaign text-right no-padding"><a class="bordered-button champ btn btn-transparent " href="http://debbieabrahams.org.uk/contact">Contact Debbie</a></div></div></div></div></div></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/kind-fest-compassion-in-politics/">Kind Fest: Compassion in Politics?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://debbieabrahams.org.uk">Debbie Abrahams, MP for Oldham East and Saddleworth</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Constituency Office</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://debbieabrahams.org.uk/?p=7065</id>
    <published>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-14T09:33:47Z</updated>
    <category term="Children &amp; Families"/>
    <category term="Constituents"/>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Profile"/>
    <category term="Brexit"/>
    <category term="Stella Creasy"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Sir Bill plants a Remembrance stake in the Constituency Garden of Remembrance</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Monday, Sir Bill Wiggin MP planted a wooden cross to pay tribute to service personnel from his constituency of North Herefordshire who have died in service to our country.  The Speaker of the House of Commons, Sir Lindsay Hoyle... <a class="more-link" href="https://billwiggin.wordpress.com/2022/11/11/sir-bill-plants-a-remembrance-stake-in-the-constituency-garden-of-remembrance/#more-4548">Continue Reading →</a></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>bwmp</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://billwiggin.wordpress.com/?p=4548</id>
    <published>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-11T10:15:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Media Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Network Rail Confirm Beckenham Junction Foot Bridge Repairs Timetable </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Following pressure from Member of Parliament Bob Stewart, jointly with local Councillor Michael Tickner and London Assembly Member Peter Fortune; Network Rail have set out the timetable to replace the footbridge at Beckenham Junction. 
 
Bob, Michael and Peter wrote to Network Rail in October to…</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.bobstewart.org.uk/news/network-rail-confirm-beckenham-junction-foot-bridge-repairs-timetable</id>
    <published>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Berry Bros &amp; Rudd New Warehouse in Andover</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://kitmalthouse.com/2022/berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=berry-bros-rudd-new-warehouse-in-andover" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. </p>



<p>While much of their business is selling wine, most of it is helping wine buyers and collectors look after their stock, and the warehouse is where it is all stored. As I was shown round, I marvelled at the famous names on the shelves: Lafitte, Latour, Petrus etc. </p>



<p>The Warehouse is chilled to 12 degrees throughout, but happily due to solar panels on the roof, will be carbon neutral. </p>



<p>It’s a great vote of confidence in Andover and in the UK wine industry which I hope will continue to lead the world, with possibly the biggest collection of fine wines on the planet, here in North West Hampshire. </p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">It was fascinating to visit the vast new Berry Bros warehouse in Andover recently. This family owned business is one of the world’s oldest and biggest wine merchants and they have just opened a spanking new multi million pound facility on the Andover Business Park. While much of their business is selling wine, most of […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kit Malthouse</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://kitmalthouse.com/?p=2968</id>
    <published>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-05T08:26:32Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Matt Warman MP secures key commitment on visas for international GPs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mattwarman.co.uk/2022/11/04/matt-warman-mp-secures-key-commitment-on-visas-for-international-gps/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><ul>
<li>In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS.<br/>
• To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve this challenge’, for example working with the sector to explore umbrella sponsors for international GPs and holding meetings with the sector to encourage more GP surgeries to become visa sponsoring practices.</li>
</ul>
<p>On Wednesday (2nd November), a Westminster Hall debate took place in which the House<br/>
considered visas for international doctors.</p>
<p>Matt Warman MP raised the point that under current legislation, GPs who have come from abroad to train in the UK are in a position whereby it is difficult to obtain employment after they graduate. This is mainly because, in order for a General Practice to hire an international graduate, they must be registered as a ‘sponsoring practice’. This requires a large amount of complicated engagement with the Home Office, both on the international GP’s behalf and that of the practice hoping to sponsor them.</p>
<p>Following a discussion of members from different parties, the Minister for Immigration, Robert<br/>
Jenrick MP, acknowledged the issues raised and agreed to look at ways to make this process easier. The Minister assured that the Home Office will ‘reflect carefully on the points raised’ and stated that he will ‘task Home Office officials to work with stakeholders in the sector to give greater consideration to the central question of whether there is a simpler way in which GP practices can apply for relevant visas.’</p>
<p>The Minister for Immigration also pledged to ‘ask my officials to work with the sector to see whether there is a way forward to create umbrella bodies, if there is mutual support on both sides’, as well as agreeing to run further engagement events with the sector to discuss the process of becoming a sponsor.</p>
<p>Commenting on the positive outcome of this debate, Matt Warman said: <em>‘The Minister has </em><br/>
<em>demonstrated more progress on this important issue in the commitment that he has made to us </em><br/>
<em>today than we have seen in some years … I am immensely grateful to all Members who have brought the issue to life, and I look forward to continuing to work with the Minister on the outcome of the review, which will make a real difference to our constituents, and to doctors up and down the country.’</em></p>
<p>Matt will continue to liaise with the Home Office, the NHS and the Royal Colleges in order to turn this promise into action as quickly as possible.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">In response to a debate called in Westminster Hall on Wednesday 2nd November, the Home Office agreed to look at how restrictions can be eased on international GPs working for the NHS. • To deliver on this mission, the Minister for Immigration pledged to focus on ‘creative ways to resolve […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Ayesha</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://mattwarman.co.uk/?p=4133</id>
    <published>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-04T17:41:42Z</updated>
    <category term="Press Releases"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>Editor</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/"/>

		<id>https://brendanoharamp.scot/?p=10619</id>
		<updated>2022-11-02T14:30:19Z</updated>
		<published>2022-11-02T13:54:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://brendanoharamp.scot" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Tuesday, I spoke in the House of Commons after several whistleblowers and victims of sexual harassment came forward to speak of their traumatic experiences whilst serving in the Royal Navy. Many woman have spoken out about the continued sexual harassment that they experienced over a number of years, at the hands of colleagues at ... <a title="Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims" class="read-more" href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/2022/11/02/press-release-brendan-ohara-mp-calls-for-fully-independent-investigation-into-royal-navy-sexual-harrassment-claims/" aria-label="More on Press Release: Brendan O&#8217;Hara MP calls for fully independent investigation into Royal Navy sexual harrassment claims">Read more</a>]]></summary>

		
		<link href="https://brendanoharamp.scot/wp-content/uploads/2022/11/final_6360f1545675000011d02fda_764768-1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="6873214" type="video/mp4"/>
	</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="dslc-theme-content"><div id="dslc-theme-content-inner"><p><span class="searchHighlight">Halloween</span> is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for years, picking up speed in the past weeks and months as breathless newscasters break the news of more dark intrigue and betrayal. Make no mistake, this may look like a rollercoaster ride, but it is a dirty old carousel with the same old dangerously unfit horses going round and round in ever-decreasing circles.</p>
<p>Of course, seeing the first Asian Hindu take office is truly welcome, but this isn’t a new broom with Prime Minister Rishi Sunak. The Tories have been in office for over 12 years. He’s the ‘Party gate Chancellor” who broke his own laws. He isn’t going to make things better; he’s continuing their long-running austerity programme, degrading public services and growing food bank dependency. As a Brexiteer, he happily wedded us all to the deeply toxic Brexit ideology harming our businesses, starving them of vital staff and turbocharging inflation – especially basic food items, now running at up to 60% more.</p>
<p>Westminster’s hall of mirrors also shows Labour wedded to “make Brexit work”. It’s a nonsensical stance that, hand in hand with their stated belief that the Tories are not deporting enough people quickly enough is a chilling reflection.</p>
<p>And just when you thought that one of the most frightening apparitions had been removed, it is back where it was. Suella Braverman, the Home Secretary, whose dream is *not* of a brighter future for families, or a reduced skills shortage or even an end to people trafficking. No, it is her stated “dream and obsession” to see a flight take asylum seekers to Rwanda. Sacked only 6 days earlier having broken the ministerial code, she is back in the job tasked with upholding law and order and breached national security. She is back alongside colleagues at the helm of the ghostly pirate ship that is the Tory Government.</p>
<p>It’s a horror show we should be done with. The UK is substantially poorer than independent counties comparable to Scotland, with wider inequality, higher child and pensioner poverty and lower productivity. It is time for Scotland to choose a better path.</p>
</div></div><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Halloween is a time when scary things are supposed to happen. Ghosts, zombies, and ghouls are the order of the day. Westminster, however, hasn’t waited and has been playing out its own real-life horror stories within the crumbling walls of the Palace. Like some ghastly rickety fanfare, we’ve seen frightening and dangerous things unfold for …</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</span> Read More »</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/article-we-need-to-get-scotland-away-from-the-horror-show/">ARTICLE: We need to get Scotland away from the horror show</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.drewhendrymp.scot"/>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Drew Hendry MP</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.drewhendrymp.scot/?p=6525</id>
    <published>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-11-01T11:21:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Article"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Judith wants Bradford at the centre of the next Rugby League World Cup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-wants-bradford-at-the-centre-of-the-next-rugby-league-world-cup/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities in her Bradford South constituency:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“Week in, week out, local communities come together to support their clubs, their local kids’ teams and young players.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“However, levels of investment and opportunities haven’t always matched the pride we feel in our towns and cities, but it’s moments like the world cup that will give communities the opportunities to stand tall and showcase where they live to the world.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“A compelling levelling-up bid has been submitted to government for a world-class stadium and training complex for elite sports with a Rugby League Skills, Training and Education centre in Odsal to serve the people of Yorkshire and the North. I can’t wait to host the world cup again in a decade’s time and be standing in our very own Odsal stadium in Bradford cheering England on!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Responding to Judith’s invitation to visit Odsal, Sports Minister Stuart Andrew MP said: “If I’m still in post by the end of the week I’ll still come but, if not, I’ll leave a note to my successor that their first trip needs to be to Bradford!”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The 2022 Cup’s world-leading social impact programme has invested more than £26 million in equipment and facilities, volunteering, mental health, culture and education, to transform clubs into hubs for their communities. And, for the first time, the men’s, women’s and wheelchair tournaments will be held concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A study from the Sheffield Hallam University shows that investment in sport and physical activity gives back four times the investment in social value, equivalent to around £72 billion each year across the UK, improving people’s health and wellbeing, creating jobs and stimulating local economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Judith is fighting for Bradford to have its share:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;“When the competition is over and the winning teams raise their trophies, it is only the start of the story for communities, not the end. With the Rugby League world cup in full swing, Bradford’s year as capital of culture in 2025, and Bradford’s bid for a world-class stadium and sports complex that will bring over a billion pounds of benefits to Bradford, now is the time to ensure that people of Bradford benefit from this legacy.”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;figure class="wp-block-embed-twitter wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter"&gt;&lt;div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f3c9.png" alt="🏉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt;The Rugby League World Cup &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RLWC2021?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@RLWC2021&lt;/a&gt; is more than just a competition – it’s a force for good that can transform the fortunes and unlock the potential of towns and cities like Bradford.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.0/72x72/1f447.png" alt="👇" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /&gt; Today I led a debate in Parliament celebrating this fantastic sport. &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheRFL?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@TheRFL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/ysM6QHjEO9"&gt;pic.twitter.com/ysM6QHjEO9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Judith Cummins (@JudithCummins) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1584880580881063937?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 25, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 class="cprp_section_title"&gt;Related Posts&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_items list "&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;88&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-pushed-govt-to-commit-to-levelling-up-and-regeneration-in-bradford/" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/JCChamberPink-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" alt="Judith pushes Govt to commit to levelling up and regeneration in Bradford" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Today in Parliament, Bradford South MP Judith Cummins has invited the Sports Minister to visit Odsal Stadium to discuss its regeneration, amidst her concerns that economic uncertainty could put levelling up bids at risk. Questioning Stuart Andrew MP, Sports Minister for Digital, Culture, Media &amp;amp; Sport (DCMS) in Parliament this&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, culture, sports, stadium, odsal, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-calls-for-action-on-vandalism-to-bus-services/" title="Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services"&gt;Judith calls for action on vandalism to bus services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;A spate of bus attacks in robbing residents of a vital service and Judith has called for immediate action to put a stop to this vandalism. You can read the full article on the Telegraph &amp;amp; Argus by clicking here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-urges-santander-to-rethink-closure-which-will-leave-bradford-south-with-no-banks/" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/santander-picture.jpg.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" alt="Judith urges Santander to rethink closure which will leave Bradford South with no banks" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has said that banking provision in the constituency has been totally wiped out. "People will have to travel over three miles to get to a bank,” she said, adding that the bank has “failed to take into account the social costs to the local area of removing this vital&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: judith, will, local, bradford, people, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;83&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-speaks-in-the-commons-on-bradford-restrictions/" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions"&gt;&lt;img src="https://judithcummins.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/Judith-Commons2.JPG.gallery-150x150.jpg" class="cprp_thumbnail" title="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" alt="Judith speaks in the Commons on Bradford restrictions" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Watch Judith's speech in the Commons on local restrictions in Bradford. Bradford South constituents deserve consistency in how the decisions are made and clarity in how they are announced. https://twitter.com/JudithCummins/status/1314188579044761605&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, local, news&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_data"&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_title"&gt;&lt;a href="https://judithcummins.org.uk/judith-demands-government-sorts-out-coronavirus-testing-problems/" title="Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems"&gt;Video: Judith demands government sorts out coronavirus testing problems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_percentage"&gt;82&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_excerpt"&gt;&lt;span class="cprp_excerpt_content"&gt;Judith has spoken in the House of Commons to raise the case of a constituent unable to get a test for her 8-year old asthmatic son in Bradford, who had been advised to travel to Scotland to get a test. Speaking after, Judith said: The Government has promised a ‘world&amp;hellip;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="cprp_tags"&gt;Tags: bradford, judith, people, news, local&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Judith Cummins MP has called on the government to use the power of sport as a ‘force for good’ to bring investment into Bradford. Speaking in a debate on the contribution of the Rugby League world cup to culture and sport in the UK, Judith highlighted how sport is at the heart of local communities […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Thornton</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://judithcummins.org.uk/?p=2685</id>
    <published>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-26T11:28:10Z</updated>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dan Jarvis MP: Statement Regarding Sentencing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>I was deeply concerned to read the decision taken by the Court in this <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-south-yorkshire-63313556">case</a>.</p>
<p>Given the very serious nature of the crimes committed, and that the perpetrator pleaded guilty to all 10 offences, I find it very difficult to understand how he was not deemed a serious threat to the public and remanded in custody.</p>
<p>I will be urgently raising these concerns with the Crown Prosecution Service and the Attorney General’s office.</p></div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Admin</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.danjarvis.org/statement_regarding_sentencing</id>
    <published>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-20T17:01:54+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Joy Morrissey MP welcomes Prime Minister Liz Truss speech to Conservative Party Conference 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">This morning the Prime Minister set out our Conservative vision for the future. A country focussed on growth, aspiration and enterprise. Turning away from those who say much and do little, the anti-growth coalition we are so used to seeing on our screens and in the hall today.
</div>
    </content>
    <id>https://www.joymorrissey.uk/news/joy-morrissey-mp-welcomes-prime-minister-liz-truss-speech-conservative-party-conference-2022</id>
    <published>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-05T13:00:00+01:00</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>September 2022 Newsletter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/september-2022-newsletter/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-medium"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441"><img loading="lazy" width="300" height="169" src="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png" alt="" class="wp-image-5588" srcset="http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-300x169.png 300w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1024x576.png 1024w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-768x432.png 768w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-1536x864.png 1536w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-98x55.png 98w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-622x350.png 622w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September-630x354.png 630w, http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Tulip-Siddiq-MP-September.png 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px"/></a></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" data-type="URL" data-id="https://mailchi.mp/7491f923d18f/tulip-siddiq-mp-august-2022-enewsletter-5251441" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Click here</a> to view my newsletter for September 2022.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Click here to view my newsletter for September 2022.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Tulip Siddiq</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.tulipsiddiq.com/?p=5587</id>
    <published>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-30T13:27:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Causes"/>
    <category term="2022"/>
    <category term="newsletter"/>
    <category term="September"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bust Budget</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/2022/09/27/bust-budget/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</p>



<p>The tax cuts in this mini budget, are mainly for the super wealthy, for corporations and for the bankers. The top tax rate of 45p (%) has been completely removed, which is great news for those lucky few that earn over £150,000 a year. Corporation tax increases have been discarded, and the cap on bankers’ bonuses brought in after the financial crisis of 2008 have been scrapped.</p>



<p>But the Tories aren’t content with just giving handouts to the rich, they have also increased the number of Universal Credit recipients who have to actively search for work and attend weekly or fortnightly job centre appointments, if they are working up to 15 hours a week. If they don’t then their benefits will be reduced. Unsurprisingly the mini-budget also attacks trade union rights further, making it harder for working people to strike for the pay and conditions they deserve.</p>



<p>While they have suspended National Insurance increases and cut stamp duty, this support is minute compare to the support for those best off in society. Even in terms of energy bill support, prices being frozen where they are now, simply means they are only twice what they were last year, at the same time that the price for everything else from food to transport is increasing, while wages and benefits remain completely stagnant.</p>



<p>This budget does not serve the needs of the people of Nottingham, it does not help those who need help the most. People earning £20,000 will only save £167 a year. What it will do is drive Britain into an inflationary spiral. It will cause the prices of the goods that residents need to survive to increase further, at a time where benefits and wages are not rising. This will wipe out any gains that residents in the city see from this mini-budget.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg"><img src="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2931" width="398" height="271" srcset="https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1024x698.jpg 1024w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-300x205.jpg 300w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-768x524.jpg 768w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920-1536x1047.jpg 1536w, https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/coins-g06f3a83a2_1920.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 398px) 100vw, 398px"/></a><figcaption>the Tory mini-budget will only give most people small change</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Tories say their budget will stimulate growth; it remains to be seen if it will. What is certain though is that growth in the economy is pointless if it does not lead to increased wages for the average person, if people are not supported to re-skill and obtain jobs in growing sectors, and if people do not have access to suitable affordable housing, whether that’s via home ownership or renting.</p>



<p>The mini budget does nothing to help achieve these aims, Nottingham Labour strongly believe that the budget will not help the people of Nottingham, it will only help a tiny minority of people. A Labour government is needed nationally to give the people of this country and of Nottingham the support and help that they need, and that they deserve.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">On Friday the new Chancellor of the Exchequer announced what he described as a mini-budget to help deal with the cost of living crisis. The only thing mini about it was the amount of support it provides to the average family and individual in Britain. This completely un-costed budget, will give out the largest tax cuts since 1972, most of which are aimed at the wealthiest in society. That budget in 1972 lead to a short-lived boom, and a much longer bust, with the infamous three-day week and the failure of key services.</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Nottingham Labour</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://nottinghamlabour.org.uk/?p=2929</id>
    <published>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-27T10:46:40Z</updated>
    <category term="east midlands"/>
    <category term="funding"/>
    <category term="Local News"/>
    <category term="Nottingham City"/>
    <category term="budget"/>
    <category term="Cuts"/>
    <category term="debt"/>
    <category term="inflation"/>
    <category term="Labour"/>
    <category term="nottingham"/>
    <category term="taxes"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I am Removing Trolls from my Social Media</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.stevebaker.info/2022/09/why-i-am-removing-trolls-from-my-social-media/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">As an MP since 2010, I am used to having abuse hurled at me. Every Member of Parliament gets used to it, often from our time as candidates. To an extent, facing anger is part of being what one pillar of our community described as being the safety valve on the pressure cooker that is society. But things daily go too far. Apart from several threats of death and grievous assault, vicious abuse under my posts on social media has […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Harry Richer</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.stevebaker.info/?p=18588</id>
    <published>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2022-09-05T08:55:00Z</updated>
    <category term="Politics"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom</h2>



<p>The availability of free education is a gift, but only if it can come with high quality. Google Classroom has given students in classrooms around the country an online option to supplement their learning. A potential downside to these options is the inability to meet with professors and apply classroom learning. As a part of the University of Washington system, we have found the use of Google Classroom during the quarter distance courses produced good results for both parties. Distance learning is here to stay and has only grown over time. If you want to make sure you aren’t left behind in a digital world, you may want to consider your options and how they will help or hurt your future professional prospects.</p>



<p>Google Classroom is a reliable one-stop-shop for managing all of your coursework and communication. It is definitely worth checking out if you are in a distance learning program, or even just want to streamline some of your everyday communication tasks.</p>



<h3>Benefits and Drawbacks</h3>



<p>There are several other features that set Google Classroom apart from the competition. It is a free tool and it works on computers and mobile devices through the GAFE platform. The discussion features of Google Classroom do an excellent job at encouraging interaction between students and teachers, making it a very effective tool for working with groups of all sizes. The major drawback to Google Classroom is that it is a relatively new tool, so it does not work with iPads, Android tablets or Kindle Fires. The lessons created within Google Docs can be exported directly into Google Classroom on the computer, but in order to view or edit those documents or upload them onto the iPad tablet, students will have to use other third-party tools such as Documents 5 and iBooks Author.</p>



<h2>Integration</h2>



<p>If you are using Google Classroom for your teaching and learning, it is important to note that it does require integration with Google Apps for Education. This means that you are using Gmail along with Calendar and Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides) etc., so the other school faculty members need to have access to all of these tools. The obvious way to do this is through the use of a domain. It is required that you have a domain in order to use Google Classroom or any other GAFE tool/application.</p>



<p>By going through a step by step process, one can easily move one’s entire digital repository into Google Classroom for easy organization and management; therefore, allowing access to all student work without having to worry about losing any data or files that are not needed for a current class engagement.</p>



<h2>Google Classroom Future Prospects</h2>



<p>According to the Scholastic Parent &amp; Child list of the most popular educational apps , in 2015 Classroom wasn’t one of them, indicating that this tool is still relatively new and also relatively unknown. While the design is nothing particularly innovative, the new Google Classroom 2022 is a promising step towards more effective and efficient learning, especially in a classroom setting. Though it appears to be geared towards teachers, students will benefit from having access to Google Classroom, whether they’re in an online or a traditional classroom. With that said, it should be noted that it may take some time before this update fully penetrates into secondary schools and universities. But nonetheless, Google Classroom is off on the right foot, leaning further into an online world which we’ll all have to face sooner or later.</p>



<h2>Bottom Line</h2>



<p>Google Classroom has made a huge impact in the world of educational technology, especially for teachers who don’t have face-to-face access to students. It’s a powerful tool that will likely continue to be developed and improved upon, as educators keep gravitating towards it.</p>



<p>In the end, there is no one best way to teach and learn, but instead many valid options. Whether you are interested in the low-cost education of a MOOC or the high-end technology of Sketchfab virtual reality tours, it’s exciting to see that educational technology is progressing at a rapid rate. Let’s hope that as more schools begin to adopt innovative techniques like Google Classroom, we will continue to see positive changes in how students learn around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Google Classroom is a good idea. It’s going to help teachers create better lessons, keep students engaged and reach out to parents more. The real question is whether it’s worth the price of admission. Google […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com/guide-to-google-classroom-distance-learning-in-2022/">Guide to Google Classroom distance learning in 2022</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.lucianaberger.com">Berger</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>lambed</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.lucianaberger.com/?p=211</id>
    <published>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</published>
    <updated>2022-06-09T13:19:37Z</updated>
    <category term="Education"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://stephenjmorgan.org/%e3%82%a8%e3%82%b9%e3%82%af%e3%83%aa%e3%83%8b%e3%83%83%e3%82%af%e6%81%b5%e6%af%94%e5%af%bf%ef%bd%9c%e5%8c%bb%e7%99%82%e8%84%b1%e6%af%9b/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。&lt;br /&gt;
全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるように全スタッフが努めております。&lt;br /&gt;
もしお気づきの点がございましたら遠慮なくスタッフにお申し付けください。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;【サロン情報】&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-112 aligncenter" src="http://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png" alt="" width="300" height="66" srcset="https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a-300x66.png 300w, https://stephenjmorgan.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2053/e1bed392744129a790f3eea27a7e53b8e604d25d28dc3a876adc3ae60a8af69a.png 577w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /&gt;
&lt;table class="cps-table03"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;店舗名&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;住所&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;〒150-0013 東京都渋谷区恵比寿１丁目８番１号 サン栄ビル ３階&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;電話&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="tel:+81120544964"&gt;0120-544-964&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;サイトURL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.esclinic.jp/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;https://www.esclinic.jp//t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;GoogleMAP&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/%E3%82%A8%E3%82%B9%E3%82%AF%E3%83%AA%E3%83%8B%E3%83%83%E3%82%AF%E6%81%B5%E6%AF%94%E5%AF%BF%EF%BD%9C%E5%8C%BB%E7%99%82%E8%84%B1%E6%AF%9B/@35.648014,139.7079165,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x7532aa652d5452b2!8m2!3d35.648014!4d139.7101052" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿の医療脱毛なら『エスクリニック恵比寿｜医療脱毛』&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;提供サービス&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;td class="rankinginfo"&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿【医療脱毛】&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/maps/MGKDoHQzDqWNm2i88" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"&gt;恵比寿駅徒歩2分の渋谷・恵比寿の医療レーザー脱毛&lt;/a&gt;なら医療脱毛専門のエスクリニック恵比寿&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">エスクリニック恵比寿は、恵比寿駅徒歩2分にある「医療レーザー脱毛専門クリニック」です。 全室個室で患者様同士が極力会わないように動線作りをしっかりと整備することで、ストレスのない快適な空間で医療レーザー脱毛を提供できるよ</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>nakayama</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://stephenjmorgan.org/?p=111</id>
    <published>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-09T03:41:06Z</updated>
    <category term="未分類"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
		<author>
			<name>petermiddlehurst</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Climate and Environment Emergency: WWF Earth Hour]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"/>

		<id>https://www.nickbrownmp.com/?p=663</id>
		<updated>2022-04-12T20:20:46Z</updated>
		<published>2022-04-12T19:53:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.nickbrownmp.com" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.nickbrownmp.com/2022/04/12/climate-and-environment-emergency-wwf-earth-hour/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita melihat manfaat utama yang bisa Anda dapatkan dari perjudian online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mari kita ulas bersama tentang keuntungan yang akan di dapatkan saat memainkan situs judi slot online ini yaitu;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Apa Saja Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kenyamanan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faktor utama dalam pertumbuhan industri perjudian online adalah kenyamanan. Anda dapat memainkan game favorit anda kapan saja dan dari mana saja. akan tetapi masih banyak orang lebih suka bermain dari kenyamanan rumah mereka di mana mereka merasa paling santai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone dan laptop memiliki dampak yang signifikan juga. Bahkan ada penelitian yang dilakukan tentang kapan pengguna paling suka berjudi online. Hasilnya tampaknya mengarah ke waktu sela seperti saat bepergian, menunggu teman, atau membuat janji.  dan juga meningkatkan popularitas karena banyak penjudi yang rajin bermain game saat istirahat di kantor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semua game di bawah satu atap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino darat memiliki katalog permainan yang cukup luas, tidak ada yang mengalahkan variasi dan jumlah pilihan yang tersedia di kasino online. Pengguna bahkan dapat memanfaatkan tren teknologi terbaru dan berjudi di permainan dealer langsung.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slot Online khas Inggris akan menawarkan hal itu dan jika Anda ingin pengalaman yang sepenuhnya mendalam, kami pasti akan merekomendasikan Anda untuk memeriksanya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pengguna dengan temperamen dan preferensi yang berbeda dapat berharap untuk menemukan sesuatu atau yang lain yang sesuai dengan gaya mereka. Sebagian katalog terdiri dari judul slot termasuk slot 3-gulungan dan 5-gulungan, dan pengguna tidak perlu khawatir kehabisan permainan untuk dicoba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tawaran Promosi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saat Anda mengisi ulang, Anda pasti akan mendapatkan hadiah dan uang ekstra untuk dimainkan dalam hal bonus. Semakin banyak judul game yang Anda ingin mainkan, semakin banyak poin yang terakumulasi yang pada akhirnya mengarah pada lebih banyak hadiah dan peningkatan dalam uang mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penawaran lain juga tersedia di mana para pemain dapat mulai bermain tanpa harus menyetor satu sen pun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opsi Perbankan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opsi perbankan yang digunakan platform kasino online semuanya benar-benar aman dan memungkinkan seseorang untuk mendanai akunnya dengan mudah. Ada berbagai metode yang dapat dilakukan dan pengguna dapat memilih metode yang paling cocok untuk mereka. Bahkan banyak yang memberikan penawaran tambahan saat menggunakan layanan ini.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dapatkan Poin Hadiah&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pada setiap taruhan permainan meja atau mesin slot memungkinkan pengguna untuk mengumpulkan poin hadiah. Ini tercantum dalam akun pemain dan dapat tertukar dengan permainan, hadiah, atau manfaat lainnya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meskipun kasino tradisional juga memberikan poin hadiah, mereka biasanya membutuhkan waktu lebih lama untuk bertambah dengan platform online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pilih taruhan yang Anda inginkan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platform kasino online memberi Anda kebebasan untuk bermain di level mana pun yang Anda inginkan. Di sisi lain, rumah kasino tradisional memiliki batasan ketat pada tingkat di mana pengguna dapat bermain terutama karena mereka harus mempertahankan pendirian mereka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Di situs kasino online, seseorang dapat memulai dengan bermain secara gratis atau dengan taruhan minimum. Ini memungkinkan seseorang kesempatan untuk mengambilnya selangkah demi selangkah dan meningkatkannya secara progresif saat seseorang menjadi lebih nyaman, atau mendapatkan kemenangan beruntun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baca artikel lainnya di: &lt;a href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/link-situs-judi-bola-terpercaya-alternatif-solusi-paling-tepat-bermain/"&gt;Link Situs Judi Bola Terpercaya Alternatif, Solusi Paling Tepat Bermain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/"&gt;Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org"&gt;Chrisleslie&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online – Internet memiliki dampak luar biasa pada berbagai industri meskipun mungkin industri perjudian yang paling banyak mengalami perubahan. Perjudian online yang sederhana, dengan cepat menjadi industri multi-miliar dolar. Ada sejumlah situs judi online yang menyediakan layanan hiburan dan perjudian kepada pengguna dari setiap bagian dunia. Di sini kita […]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org/keuntungan-saat-memainkan-situs-judi-slot-online/">Keuntungan Saat Memainkan Situs Judi Slot Online</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.chrisleslie.org">Chrisleslie</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Bennett</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.chrisleslie.org/?p=36</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T09:19:25Z</updated>
    <category term="Slot Online"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Backbench Business Committee</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/2022/01/28/backbench-business-committee/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><div id="attachment_20766" style="width: 742px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="size-full wp-image-20766" src="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png" alt="" width="732" height="830" srcset="http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench.png 732w, http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/backbench-265x300.png 265w" sizes="(max-width: 732px) 100vw, 732px"/><p class="wp-caption-text">My article in House Magazine</p></div>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Ian Mearns</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.ianmearns.org.uk/?p=20765</id>
    <published>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</published>
    <updated>2022-01-28T11:06:12Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorised"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
		<author>
			<name>simonlefevre</name>
					</author>

		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Constituents Update &#8211; 10th November 2021]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"/>

		<id>https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/?p=378</id>
		<updated>2021-11-10T16:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2021-11-10T16:47:29Z</published>
		<category scheme="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk" term="News"/>
		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary>

					<content type="html" xml:base="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
		
					<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
			<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.jackdromey.co.uk/news/2021/11/10/constituents-update-10th-november-2021/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
			<thr:total>0</thr:total>
			</entry>
  <entry>
    <title>End Fire and Rehire</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dianajohnson.co.uk/content/end-fire-and-rehire" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<span property="schema:name">End Fire and Rehire</span>

<span rel="schema:author"><span lang="" typeof="schema:Person" property="schema:name" datatype="" xml:lang="">Anonymous (not verified)</span></span>

<span property="schema:dateCreated" content="2021-10-22T15:02:00+00:00">Fri, 10/22/2021 - 16:02</span>
</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Anonymous</name>
    </author>
    <id>2991 at https://dianajohnson.co.uk</id>
    <published>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2021-10-22T15:02:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-345317524971323199.post-4250728202477984388</id>
    <published>2021-07-29T14:08:00.002+01:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-29T14:09:18.499+01:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Visit my Facebook page </title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Visit my &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/YvonneFovargue4Makerfield" target="_blank"&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for upto date news on my work as your Member of Parliament.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/feeds/4250728202477984388/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html#comment-form" title="0 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/345317524971323199/posts/default/4250728202477984388"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://yvonnefovargue.blogspot.com/2021/07/visit-my-facebook-page.html" title="Visit my Facebook page "/>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Kenny</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/01249644035140316117</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="21" height="32" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-kiBV-e2Yo8U/Ulaa1GJcJoI/AAAAAAAABTk/f3_kl1dzuuA/s220/Labour%2B4.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>0</thr:total>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.markpritchard.com/news/new-gp-surgery-back-track-shifnal" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><span>New GP Surgery Back on Track for Shifnal</span>
            <div class="field-news-date"><time datetime="2021-02-16T12:00:00Z">Tuesday, 16 February, 2021</time></div>
      
<span>Tue, 16/02/2021 - 13:45</span>

  <div class="field-news-image-gallery">



  <div>
      <img loading="lazy" src="https://www.markpritchard.com/sites/www.markpritchard.com/files/styles/gallery_large/public/2021-02/Shifnal%20GP%20Surgery.png?itok=LKUcPCA9" width="830" height="540" alt="Shifnal GP Surgery Plans" typeof="foaf:Image"/></div>
</div>

            <div class="body"><p>The local Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed that the funding is in place to build a new GP surgery for Shifnal.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mark Pritchard MP said:</p>
<p>"I'm delighted that, in the last 24 hours, the Shropshire NHS Clinical Commissioning Group has confirmed to me that the new GP surgery in Shifnal will go ahead this year.  The building plans are well advanced and NHS England has provided the extra funding needed.  Local councillors and Shifnal Matters 2021 have supported me in pushing for this new surgery, and I'm glad that the NHS has listened to local needs."</p>
</div>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>425 at https://www.markpritchard.com</id>
    <published>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</published>
    <updated>2021-02-16T13:45:06Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk/2020/11/25/very-proud-day-today-the-law-change-i-fought-for-to-protect-pensioners-comes-into-force/">Very proud day today – the law change I fought for to protect pensioners comes into force</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.marktami.co.uk">Mark Tami</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Dan Rose</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.marktami.co.uk/?p=171</id>
    <published>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</published>
    <updated>2020-11-25T17:46:37Z</updated>
    <category term="news"/>
    <category term="AffectsAllofUs"/>
    <category term="Alyn&amp;Deeside"/>
    <category term="ChangeTheLaw"/>
    <category term="Government"/>
    <category term="Pension"/>
    <category term="Win"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New Hospital in Sutton Confirmed</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.scully.org.uk/news/new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=new-hospital-in-sutton-confirmed" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a &lt;strong&gt;£500 MILLION plan&lt;/strong&gt; that will not only &lt;strong&gt;build a brand new state of the art hospital&lt;/strong&gt; near to the Royal Marsden by 2025, but ALSO &lt;strong&gt;invest AT LEAST £80 MILLION into upgrades at St Helier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The new specialist emergency care hospital, just a few minutes from St Helier, would treat the sickest 15% of patients, those normally arriving by ambulance. This larger specialist team would be available 24 hours a day to diagnose what is wrong with patients more rapidly, start the best treatment faster, and help patients recover more quickly. St Helier and Epsom Hospitals will remain open 24/7, with updated and improved facilities, providing all the other services that they currently do.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;My children were born at St. Helier so healthcare provision in Sutton has been an issue that is a very personal one to me. Ever since being a councillor in Carshalton, some 14 years ago, I have been campaigning for a solution that protects the future of St. Helier whilst ensuring that Sutton residents have access to the very best treatment in cutting edge modern healthcare facilities. I believe that this decision can finally put to rest the political arguments so that we can get on with doing what’s best for residents across the whole of the borough of Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this plan, the refurbished St Helier Hospital is here to stay providing the majority of local health services, and the sickest patients will get state-of-the-art treatment in the brand-new specialist emergency hospital right here in our area.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about the plans, including the answers to some frequently asked questions at the NHS’ website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact them at &lt;a href="mailto:hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk"&gt;hello@improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, or get in touch with me with any queries.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;IMPORTANT QUESTIONS &amp;amp; ANSWERS ABOUT THESE PROPOSALS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Why is this being done?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To improve the care that we receive. As St Helier’s buildings continue to age over time, it’s necessary to upgrade our healthcare facilities to improve outcomes. Surviving illness and recovering quickly is the number one priority.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier closing?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;No, quite the opposite. St Helier is here to stay with a multi-million-pound improvement package.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is a new hospital being built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. A new specialist emergency care hospital will be built in Sutton, in addition to improving St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Is St Helier getting an upgrade?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. At least £80 million of the funding promised will go towards improving the facilities at St Helier hospital.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Who developed these proposals?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the first time, we have a plan that was developed by local clinicians, not national bureaucrats or politicians. Local healthcare professionals made the case for funding to deliver this improvement, which has been rewarded with a £500 million investment. Sutton Council also supported the proposals last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will I have to travel outside my area for services now?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the moment, if you have a stroke or heart attack you will be taken past St. Helier to be treated at St. George&amp;#8217;s. This plan means that we will still be able to treat people within the local area, not moving more services away from Sutton.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Will we still use St Helier?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Yes. From 2025, Epsom hospital, St Helier hospital and the new hospital at Sutton will all have a 24/7 Urgent Treatment Centre (UTC) (which already treats the vast majority of people going to St. Helier in an emergency). Under the plans, 85% of services will remain at St Helier. Both Epsom and St Helier hospitals will still have a 24/7 UTC.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Diagnostic tests, such as MRI, x-ray or ultrasound, the heart problem diagnosis unit, the dialysis unit, Croft Ward (which takes care of patients who are stable but not ready to leave hospital), the eye care unit, the gastroenterology unit, and so many more services are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about bed numbers?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The NHS have calculated that they will need the same number of beds as they do now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about A&amp;amp;E?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Unlike previous plans, which saw A&amp;amp;E diverted away into Tooting, A&amp;amp;E is now staying right here in our Borough at the new hospital. Most of the time you will still use St Helier for matters requiring immediate medical attention like broken limbs or cuts. Major trauma cases needing a blue light ambulance transfer will be treated in Sutton at the new state-of-the-art hospital next to The Royal Marsden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What about maternity services?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Maternity services have also been protected and kept locally. Post-natal and ante-natal care are staying put at Epsom and St Helier hospitals, and births will take place in the brand-new maternity unit at the new hospital in Sutton built to the very latest healthcare standards. Women need the very best care and facilities when giving birth, and the new plans will provide that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will children services be provided?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Most children will continue to receive care and treatment in the same place as they do now. Care for children who need to stay in hospital overnight – as a result of a serious illness or complex problems – will be treated at the new specialist emergency care hospital. This includes children’s surgery. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What will happen until the new hospital in Sutton is built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All services will continue to be carried out at Epsom and St Helier hospitals until such time the new hospital in Sutton is ready for patients.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Where will the new hospital be built?&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After consulting residents, patient groups and healthcare professionals, the decision was taken to build a brand-new specialist emergency care hospital in Sutton. This will be combined with the necessary infrastructure and transport links to ensure the site of the new hospital is accessible to all that need to use it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For more facts, and to find out what this multi-million-pound government investment in our local NHS will mean for you and your family, visit the following website: &lt;a href="http://www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq"&gt;www.improvinghealthcaretogether.org.uk/faq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">I am delighted to write and tell you that local NHS leaders have confirmed plans for a new hospital to be built in Sutton and to upgrade facilities at St Helier. This represents a £500 MILLION plan that will not only build a brand new state of the art hospital near to the Royal Marsden […]</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Scully</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.scully.org.uk/?p=5400</id>
    <published>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</published>
    <updated>2020-07-17T10:14:25Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
    <category term="Healthcare"/>
    <category term="Here For St Helier"/>
    <category term="Sutton"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&amp;amp;E @ the Glam &amp;#8211; Strength in Unity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. If you wish to do so then please let me know by filling in the form at the bottom of this page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration of Emergency NHS services across Cwm Taf Morgannwg has changed over the years – and will continue to change along with medical advances and changes in the local population. We welcome, for instance, the development of the new Major Trauma Centre at UHW, which will almost certainly save lives and we recognise that for some specialist forms of care it will be necessary to travel to a regional centre of excellence such as the Burns Unit at Morriston. We also understand that there is a UK-wide shortage of Emergency Consultants. and that Cwm Taf Morgannwg is not in a unique position with the recruitment challenges it faces,but would note that 5 of the 7 LHBs in Wales have substantially increased emergency consultant numbers over the last 6 years whereas Cwm Taf Morgannwg has not. We would argue that the uncertainty created over the future of the hospital due to the South Wales Programme has itself created a self-fulfilling prophecy about recruitment problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our starting point, however, is that all NHS services should be safe, efficient and delivered as close to people’s homes as is medically and logistically feasible. Time-critical medical interventions can make the difference between life and death in many emergency situations and we are concerned that if the A&amp;amp;E were permanently to close at any one of the three hospitals, significant numbers of patients in some of the most deprived communities would not be able to get to an Emergency Department in time. A&amp;amp;E cannot be seen in isolation from other services such as GP surgeries, local minor injuries units and out-of-hours support. Additional capacity in these services would almost certainly lighten the load in the Emergency Departments, but this must be put in place before any changes to the configuration of Emergency Care is considered, let alone implemented, with evidence that they have substantially reduced the load on Emergency departments required before any changes. Changes to A&amp;amp;E provision at any one of the hospitals would have serious implications for other services within the hospital, including ITU and theatre and might harm the recruitment of other specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There would be significant knock-on effects if the A&amp;amp;E at the Royal Glamorgan Hospital were to be downgraded to a Minor Injuries Unit, as the hospital would almost certainly lose its Intensive Care Unit and operating theatre. This could jeopardise the long-term future of the hospital. The RGH’s Emergency Department is the most used in the area, with roughly 65,000 attendances a year, and ranked the best in terms of viable outcomes.  We fear the two other Emergency Departments would find it impossible to cope with the additional workload and that many patients will travel instead to UHW, which is also already over-stretched. We are also concerned that extra A&amp;amp;E admissions to PCH and POW would put additional pressure on not just their respective A&amp;amp;E depts but onwards and throughout the hospital system. We are determined to work with people of all political parties and trades unions (and none) to get the best possible outcome for the communities we represent. We believe the eventual decision should be informed by clinical best practice and local experience on the ground – and not by any partisan consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to do the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) Rule out the closure of A&amp;amp;E at the RGH or changing it to a 24-hour Minor Injuries Unit.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Reinstate the option of maintaining a full consultant-led A&amp;amp;E at all three hospitals. This would require a serious new attempt at recruiting Emergency Consultants who would have secure full-time permanent posts working across all three hospitals. It would also require at least a ten-year commitment to RGH so that potential staff can apply with confidence.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Bring forward proposals to extend the opening hours of the Minor Injuries Unit at Ysbyty Cwm Rhondda and Ysbyty Cwm Cynon and make these units more readily accessible for walk-in patients.&lt;br /&gt;
4) Bring forward other proposals for community health services, including improvements in the out-of-hours GP service, that might alleviate the pressure on all three A&amp;amp;E departments&lt;br /&gt;
and bring services closer to local communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are calling on the Cwm Taf Morgannwg University Health Board to publish the following:&lt;br /&gt;
1) A socioeconomic and equality impact assessment of any proposed changes.&lt;br /&gt;
2) Detailed analyses of travel-to-hospital times, average ambulance response times and levels of car ownership, for all electoral wards in the area. that analyses such times during periods of poor weather.&lt;br /&gt;
3) Detailed statistics for levels of ischemic heart disease, diabetes, stroke and infant and adult mortality for all electoral wards in the area. and how they compare with the Welsh averages/wealthier wards in Wales.&lt;br /&gt;
4) An assessment of how many patients from each electoral ward would be affected by a proposal to move to an 8 to 8, and 8 to 10 and an 8 to midnight Emergency Department.&lt;br /&gt;
5) An assessment of capacity in the Emergency Departments at POW, PCH, and UHW and how they would cope with additional patients.&lt;br /&gt;
6) Statistics for the number of patients who are admitted on towards at each hospital from A&amp;amp;E.&lt;br /&gt;
7) An assessment of the impact to the Welsh Ambulance Service, Ambulance response times, handover response times, in terms of waiting times at hospitals, blue light trauma travel times&lt;br /&gt;
and non-emergency transport between hospitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="iphorm-outer-63952649b5a42" class="iphorm-outer iphorm-outer-5 iphorm-uniform-theme-default iphorm-responsive" &gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
        jQuery(document).ready(function($) {
                        $('#iphorm-63952649b5a42').iPhorm({"id":5,"uniqueId":"63952649b5a42","useAjax":true,"successMessageTimeout":10,"resetFormValues":"","clElementIds":[],"clDependentElementIds":[],"centerFancybox":true,"centerFancyboxSpeed":true});
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.qtip)) {
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'focus'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-hover', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-click', iPhorm.instance.$form).qtip({
                    style: {
                        classes: 'qtip-plain qtip-shadow'
                    },
                    position: {
                        my: 'left center',
                        at: 'right center'
                    },
                    show: {
                        event: 'click'
                    },
                    hide: {
                        event: 'unfocus'
                    },
                    content: {
                        text: function (api) {
                            return $(this).find('.iphorm-tooltip-icon-content').html();
                        }
                    }
                });
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label').hover(function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('show');
                }, function () {
                    $(this).siblings('.iphorm-input-wrap').find('.iphorm-tooltip-hover').qtip('hide');
                });
            }
                                    if ($.isFunction($.fn.uniform)) {
                $('select, input:checkbox, input:radio', iPhorm.instance.$form).uniform({context: iPhorm.instance.$form, selectAutoWidth: false});
            }
                        if ($.isFunction($.fn.inFieldLabels)) {
                $('.iphorm-labels-inside:not(.iphorm-element-wrap-recaptcha) &gt; .iphorm-element-spacer &gt; label', iPhorm.instance.$form).inFieldLabels();
            }
                        $('.iphorm-group-row &gt; div:last-child:not(:first-child)', iPhorm.instance.$form).add('.iphorm-group-row:last-child', iPhorm.instance.$form).addClass('last-child');
                    });
    &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;form id="iphorm-63952649b5a42" class="iphorm iphorm-form-5" action="/feed/#iphorm-63952649b5a42" method="post" enctype="multipart/form-data" novalidate="novalidate"&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-inner iphorm-inner-5" &gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_id" value="5" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="iphorm_uid" value="63952649b5a42" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="form_url" value="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/feed/" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="referring_url" value="" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_id" value="5238" /&gt;
            &lt;input type="hidden" name="post_title" value="A&amp;amp;E at The Royal Glam" /&gt;
                                                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-success-message iphorm-hidden" &gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                                        &lt;div class="iphorm-elements iphorm-elements-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                &lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_1-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_1_63952649b5a42" class="iphorm_5_1-outer-label" &gt;Name&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_1-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_1" id="iphorm_5_1_63952649b5a42" type="text" name="iphorm_5_1"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-required" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_2-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_2_63952649b5a42" class="iphorm_5_2-outer-label" &gt;Email address&lt;span class="iphorm-required"&gt;(required)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_2-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_2" id="iphorm_5_2_63952649b5a42" type="email" name="iphorm_5_2"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-text iphorm_5_3-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label for="iphorm_5_3_63952649b5a42" class="iphorm_5_3-outer-label" &gt;Post Code&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-text iphorm_5_3-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;input class="iphorm-element-text  iphorm_5_3" id="iphorm_5_3_63952649b5a42" type="text" name="iphorm_5_3"  value=""  /&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-element-wrap iphorm-element-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-wrap iphorm-clearfix iphorm-labels-above iphorm-element-optional" &gt;
    &lt;div class="iphorm-element-spacer iphorm-element-spacer-checkbox iphorm_5_4-element-spacer"&gt;
        &lt;label class="iphorm_5_4-outer-label" &gt;Signed&lt;/label&gt;        &lt;div class="iphorm-input-wrap iphorm-input-wrap-checkbox iphorm_5_4-input-wrap" &gt;
            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-ul iphorm-input-checkbox-ul iphorm_5_4-input-ul iphorm-options-block iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                            &lt;div class="iphorm-input-li iphorm-input-checkbox-li iphorm_5_4-input-li" &gt;
                    &lt;label  class="iphorm_5_4_1_label"&gt;
                        &lt;input class="iphorm-element-checkbox iphorm_5_4 iphorm_5_4_1" type="checkbox" name="iphorm_5_4[]" id="iphorm_5_4_63952649b5a42_1" value="Yes"  /&gt;
                        Yes                    &lt;/label&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class="iphorm-errors-wrap iphorm-hidden" &gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="iphorm-hidden"&gt;
    &lt;label&gt;This field should be left blank&lt;input type="text" name="iphorm_5_0" /&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;                &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-wrap iphorm-submit-wrap-5 iphorm-clearfix" &gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-submit-input-wrap iphorm-submit-input-wrap-5" &gt;
                        &lt;button class="iphorm-submit-element" type="submit" name="iphorm_submit" &gt;&lt;span &gt;&lt;em &gt;Send&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/button&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;div class="iphorm-loading-wrap"&gt;&lt;span class="iphorm-loading"&gt;Please wait...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
                                            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;
    jQuery('#iphorm-outer-63952649b5a42 script').remove();
    &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/"&gt;A&amp;#038;E at The Royal Glam&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk"&gt;Chris Bryant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A&amp;E @ the Glam – Strength in Unity I have said from the very beginning that if we are to ensure a 24 hour A&amp;E Service at RGH then we need to forget about Party Politics, and come together to work cross-party. We need you to play your part too, by signing the below letter. …</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/ae-at-the-royal-glam/">A&amp;E at The Royal Glam</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk">Chris Bryant</a>.</p>
</div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chris Bryant</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.chrisbryantmp.org.uk/?p=5238</id>
    <published>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-06T15:28:54Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Reflecting on Defeat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://richardburden.com/2019/12/reflecting-on-defeat/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">First of all, thank you to everyone who has sent such kind messages to me after last night’s result in Birmingham Northfield. Even though I never took this election – or any election – for granted, it is still a big blow to lose the seat I have represented for 27 years and which is […]</div>
    </content>
    <author>
      <name>Richard Burden</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://richardburden.com/?p=5222</id>
    <published>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-13T12:54:13Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-1154433042546714956.post-4629899519655446558</id>
    <published>2019-11-26T11:08:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-12-05T13:56:37.357+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Compensation package for Waspi women</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"&gt;&lt;img border="0" data-original-height="683" data-original-width="1024" height="213" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s320/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" width="320" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Labour has pledged compensation packages for millions of women hit by state pension age rises imposed by the Tories.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pay-outs of up to £31,000 will be made, with an average payment of £15,000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The scheme will be delivered within Labour's first full five year term of government.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Payments will go to women born in the 1950s who had their state pension age hiked.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;David Cameron's coalition government presided over a change in the law that increased the women's state pension age to 65 in November 2018 - followed by 66 in October 2020.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Labour will introduce a compensation scheme as rapidly as possible for the 3.7million women hit by the changes, which Cameron's Tory-Lib Dem government imposed in 2011.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It comes after Boris Johnson u-turned on his pledge to help those affected.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He dismissed the concerns of a woman who has lost out on her pension, telling her it’s “not possible” to right the huge wrong she and so many others have suffered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The next Labour government will compensate women who were unfairly hit by the rise in the state pension age and give them the respect they deserve.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They were not able to prepare and have had to suffer serious financial consequences as a result.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We have a historic debt of honour to them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen='allowfullscreen' webkitallowfullscreen='webkitallowfullscreen' mozallowfullscreen='mozallowfullscreen' width='320' height='266' src='https://www.blogger.com/video.g?token=AD6v5dzxd_1henlybn4hHIsJYnGURIMkCd_d2xwe_HbexPqCUWmwH1MDyVQX7jIt1bkF80SSE3mr_LDfSAZ_Q4REHA' class='b-hbp-video b-uploaded' frameborder='0'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/1154433042546714956/posts/default/4629899519655446558"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.johnhealey.net/2019/11/compensation-package-for-waspi-women.html" title="Compensation package for Waspi women"/>
    <author>
      <name>John</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/08342533248003133397</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="32" height="32" src="//3.bp.blogspot.com/-iAzFi22xBOs/XWAJQLrkqKI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/UbE6mNuxdqgcbSCzFyZ1UtoKJWNsRVfDACK4BGAYYCw/s220/healey_john-31.jpg"/>
    </author>
    <media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9aU0xFXMCAI/Xd0FHDpOMAI/AAAAAAAAASc/Cyv2qZ_ta-MUdsiIaJMTYCk644nOT6-LgCLcBGAsYHQ/s72-c/LC%2BWaspi.jpg" height="72" width="72"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/DIVdQViz-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3453" width="388" height="517"/><figcaption>Lisa Nandy MP</figcaption></figure>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election.</p>



<p>At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan Labour Party voted overwhelmingly to reselect Lisa. All affiliated organisations, including Unite the Union, the Communication Workers’ Union, GMB, Unison and Usdaw, also voted to reselect.</p>



<p>Lisa said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“I’m grateful to Labour members in Wigan for choosing to reselect me so overwhelmingly. Being the Member of Parliament for Wigan is the privilege of my life, and I couldn’t do it without the members who turn up year in, year out and in all weathers to campaign for the Labour Party. With a General Election looking likely, we will be out once again fighting for every vote and to put an end to the damage inflicted on Wigan by this reckless Conservative government.”</em></strong></p>



<p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party said:</p>



<p><strong><em>“We’re delighted to have reselected Lisa Nandy as our candidate for the next General Election. For 10 years Lisa has worked tirelessly to represent Wigan in Parliament, fighting for constituents hit hardest by this Conservative government’s brutal cuts and ensuring that Wigan’s voice is heard on the national stage. The overwhelming level of support Lisa received from local party members is testament to that work. We’re proud to have Lisa as our MP and we’re ready to fight and win the next General Election together.”</em></strong></p><p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Wigan Constituency Labour Party have reselected Lisa Nandy MP as their candidate for the next General Election. At meetings held over the last fortnight, members in all of the branches that make up Wigan...</p>
<p>The post <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/news/lisa-reselected-by-wigan-labour/" target="_blank">Lisa reselected by Wigan Labour</a> first appeared on <a href="http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Lisa Nandy MP</a>.</p></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>Lisa Nandy</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://www.lisanandy.co.uk/?p=3452</id>
    <published>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</published>
    <updated>2019-10-18T23:39:35Z</updated>
    <category term="News"/>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-211678171554897823.post-4880940159072933532</id>
    <published>2019-02-21T13:41:00.002+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-02-21T13:41:58.667+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text">Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime</title>
    <summary type="text"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/211678171554897823/posts/default/4880940159072933532"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://hhgrahamjones.blogspot.com/2019/02/columbian-ambassador-to-un-condemns.html" title="Columbian Ambassador to UN condemns the Venzuelan regime"/>
    <author>
      <name>Graham Jones</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/12327111110296204964</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-198408226569937494.post-3728993723159506617</id>
    <published>2018-12-03T11:02:00.004+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-03T11:02:53.843+00:00</updated>
    <title type="text"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;This website is discontinued. Please visit my new website: &lt;a href="http://stephenmetcalfe.org.uk/"&gt;StephenMetcalfe.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/198408226569937494/posts/default/3728993723159506617"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://stephenmetcalfe.blogspot.com/2018/12/this-website-is-discontinued.html" title=""/>
    <author>
      <name>Stephen Metcalfe</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/07129050400040545431</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>MP meets South Downs farmers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="text"> Arundel and South Downs MP Nick Herbert met South Downs farmers on Friday (19 January) to discuss the challenges they face as Britain leaves the EU and&amp;hellip; </content>
    <id>http://www.nickherbert.com/news.php/812/mp-meets-south-downs-farmers</id>
    <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mhairi Black to Young People: Don’t let the Tories leave you behind</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election.<span id="more-127"/><br/>
In government, the SNP has protected and expanded the Education Maintenance Allowance which has been scrapped south of the border, and has abolished university tuition fees in Scotland while the Tories have increased them to £27,000.</p>
<p>The SNP has also increased the number of Modern Apprenticeships, with a target of 30,000 new starts by the end of this Parliament.</p>
<p>The SNP manifesto commits to a real Living Wage – projected to be just over £10 by the end of the parliament for all workers aged 18 and above – creating a new single adult rate.</p>
<p>SNP MPs will also support a ban on exploitative zero-hours contracts and will support votes at 16 at all elections.</p>
<p>Commenting, Mhairi Black said:</p>
<p>“A vote for the SNP is a vote for a strong team of MPs who’ll stand up for young people – calling for a fair and equal minimum wage, protecting rights in the workplace and votes at 16 in all elections.</p>
<p>“The SNP are already delivering for Scotland’s young people, delivering free university education and with youth unemployment at the lowest level on record – while the Tory vision is just cut after cut.</p>
<p>“The Tories think they can do anything they want to young people and get away with it – from hiking tuition fees to slashing housing benefit for young people and much more.</p>
<p>“That’s why it’s so important that young people turn up and vote – don’t let the Tory government leave you behind.</p>
<p>“Any Tory MPs elected in Scotland will simply rubberstamp whatever the Tory government does to young people, and Labour can’t win this election in Scotland – meaning that voting Labour risks letting Tory MPs in by the back door.</p>
<p>“Now more than ever, it is vital to have strong SNP voices standing up for Scotland. Only then can we protect Scotland from the dangers of an unopposed Tory government at Westminster.”</p>
<p>Notes:</p>
<p>Here’s how strong SNP voices will stand up for young people at Westminster.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs won’t let the Tories trade away Scottish jobs in the Brexit negotiations – we will work to protect Scotland’s place in the Single Market.</p>
<p>– We will back a transition over the next parliamentary term towards payment of the real Living wage for all adults above the age of 18. This will mean a new single adult rate and will see the UK minimum wage to rise to the real Living Wage, projected to be just over £10.</p>
<p>– We will guarantee the continuation of free university education in Scotland, protecting students in Scotland from paying up to £27,000 of fees.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, we are mitigating the Tory decision to withdraw housing support from 18 to 21 year olds. We will fight for the restoration of this support across the UK, alongside scrapping the Bedroom Tax.</p>
<p>– SNP MPs will look to introduce our own legislative proposals to give 16 and 17 year olds a vote in all elections.</p>
<p>– In Scotland, youth unemployment is already at the lowest level on record. SNP MPs will support the devolution of employment and employability powers so we can extend our successful approach on youth employment.</p>
<p>– To help businesses create jobs, we will propose a doubling of the Employment Allowance – the discount businesses receive on National Insurance when they create jobs.</p>
<p>– We will press the UK government to ban exploitative zero-hours contracts, and to ensure that workers have appropriate rights and protections, including holiday and sick pay. And we will work to ensure that the rights and protections currently safeguarded by EU membership are not diminished.</p>
<p>– We will work to protect opportunities for young people to study and train in other European countries through the ERASMUS+ scheme.</p>
<p>– We will continue to work with Scotland’s universities and institutions to seek clarity from the UK government on what will replace EU research funding for Scotland’s universities.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">A vote for the SNP is a vote to stand up for young people against the Tories, Mhairi Black has said, she urged young voters to use their voice in this Thursday’s election. In government, the SNP has protected and … <a href="https://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/2017/06/05/mhairi-black-to-young-people-dont-let-the-tories-leave-you-behind/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">→</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>mhairiblack</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://mhairiblack.wordpress.com/?p=127</id>
    <published>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-05T12:54:19Z</updated>
    <category term="Uncategorized"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The refugee crisis</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p>Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know that so many of you not only share my anguish at the human cost of the crisis but agree with me that more needs to be done to help those seeking sanctuary from civil war, sectarian violence and authoritarian regimes.</p>
<p>The crisis is one of the biggest humanitarian challenges that Europe has faced since the Second World War. It is therefore shameful that so far the Government’s ‘Syrian Vulnerable Persons Relocation (VPR) scheme,’ begun in March 2014, has only assisted 216 Syrian refugees.</p>
<p>As a result of concerted public pressure the Prime Minister reluctantly agreed to welcome more Syrian refugees to Britain. In my view his Government is right to prioritise the most vulnerable Syrians – victims of sexual violence, elderly and disabled people, and victims of torture living in camps across the Middle East – for resettlement and to argue that we need to redouble efforts to help tackle the traffickers and people smugglers who prey on people’s fear and desperation. However, given the scale and immediacy of the present crisis the pledge the Prime Minister gave the House of Commons on Monday, to receive only 20,000 Syrian refugees over the course of the next five years, is woefully inadequate.</p>
<p>The Government should think again about taking more refugees – both directly from Syria and from Southern European countries who are bearing the brunt of this crisis. The Prime Minister should also engage with EU leaders to agree a process for dealing with this crisis at Europe’s borders and work with local authority leaders across the UK to see what more can be done in our local communities to support refugees and asylum seekers.<br/>
Please rest assured that I will continue to press the Government on this issue while also supporting local efforts by the council, community groups and individual residents to help those in need.</p>
</div>
    </content>
    <summary type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Over recent days I’ve received hundreds of emails from local residents about the refugee crisis. It’s extremely heartening to know… <a class="read-more" href="https://www.matthewpennycook.com/2015/09/12/the-refugee-crisis/">Read more <span class="screen-reader-text">The refugee crisis</span></a></div>
    </summary>
    <author>
      <name>pennycook</name>
    </author>
    <id>http://matthewpennycookmp.wordpress.com/?p=1</id>
    <published>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-12T10:27:13Z</updated>
    <category term="National issues"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The dangers for Unionism of internal divisions and a return to direct rule</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule" type="text/html"/>
    <content type="xhtml">
      <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>
	With Northern Ireland once again in politcial crisis and continuing divisions within unionism, we need to consider carefully the consequences, both for the Union itself and for efforts to create a shared future here.</p>
      </div>
    </content>
    <id>http://www.jeffreydonaldson.org/blog/specific/the-dangers-for-unionism-of-internal-divisions-and-a-return-to-direct-rule</id>
    <published>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-10T14:12:00Z</updated>
  </entry>
  <entry xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005" xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
    <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-4611157281567615666.post-7772867992931110571</id>
    <published>2011-11-01T13:58:00.000+00:00</published>
    <updated>2011-11-01T13:58:24.287+00:00</updated>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="council"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Counting Women In"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ian Davidson MP"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Labour"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="politics"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="snp"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Winnie Ewing"/>
    <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="women"/>
    <title type="text">On being a woman in politics</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;div dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;" trbidi="on"&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;A few things have recently been rattling around in my head which concern women in politics; I've been trying to gather some ideas as to why there aren't more of us, and how I might encourage female candidates to come forward. At the same time, I noticed that the launch of the &lt;a href="http://www.countingwomenin.org/"&gt;Counting Women In campaign&lt;/a&gt;, couldn't miss the &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-scotland-scotland-politics-15451876"&gt;outrageous attack&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;Dr Eilidh Whiteford MP&lt;/a&gt;, and I've been enjoying Winnie Ewing's very readable autobiography. I've also been out on the doorsteps for Ken Andrew in Hillhead.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;All of these together really say: the culture of politics in the UK is what's at fault. Women don't think it's for them and just disengage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Now, obviously that's a generalisation. I'm a woman, and I'm very engaged in politics. &lt;i&gt;I'm prepared to accept I'm a bit odd.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I chapped on a door the other week while canvassing. I had Alexander with me in the pram. A woman answered, I politely introduced myself and my purpose on her doorstep - she shook her head and told me she wasn't interested. I asked why. She firmly asserted that all politicians are just the same. I asked her if anyone from any political party had ever come to see her with a baby in a pram. She thought briefly, admitted that'd never happened, and sent me on my way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm not sure whether that experience tells me whether I ought to a) leave the wee man at home or b) work on my doorstep pizzaz, but I bet that woman had opinions on all kinds of things. I don't think she believes them to be particularly political - provision of care services, or bin collection, say - but in the end they're determined by politicians. I want women like her to tell me what she wants and why it matters. More than that, I want women who care about issues to join political parties to further that cause. There are all kinds of causes promoted within the SNP, and I will most likely welcome you in.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;I'm sure I've said before that I've always felt welcomed as a woman in the SNP, and that remains true. I'm not sure how Labour men treat women in general (&lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/editor-s-picks/city-councillor-is-sacked-over-rape-hearing-remarks-1.1089224"&gt;not great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/charges-dropped-against-councillor-1.1065376"&gt;by some accounts&lt;/a&gt;, which appear to be &lt;a href="http://www.eveningtimes.co.uk/news/13-councillors-lose-labour-appeal-1.1128955"&gt;no barrier to reselection&lt;/a&gt;), but they're certainly not great at giving SNP women the respect they are due. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I recalled hearing when Winnie's book came out that she had been bullied while at Westminster. The &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/lifestyle/people/mother_scotland_1_683301"&gt;Scotsman's 2007 interview put it thus:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;As the lone SNP member in the Commons - at best an intimidating place  for an inexperienced politician - she found herself without friends,  without party colleagues, without any supporting structures. She was  completely alone. She was hundreds of miles from her husband and her  children in an excessively macho and very hostile environment. "I was  treated as the enemy, I was shunned and despised. It's a peculiar  experience to suddenly find yourself hated. At times I did feel terribly  lonely, close to despair."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="font-family: &amp;quot;Trebuchet MS&amp;quot;,sans-serif; text-align: justify;"&gt;Reading the autobiography, you really get a vivid picture of the pressure Winnie Ewing was under as an MP on her own. Her every action was scrutinised; if she didn't attend a debate, the other parties would ensure it got in the papers. The nuances of what said were taken apart. She was under political and personal attack from all sides and, even more sinister, stalked by another MP. Interventions by others had some impact, but it must have been a great emotional strain.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What I didn't know was that when Winnie was appointed as an MEP (pre-democratic elections to Europe), the bad behaviour of two particular Labour bullies continued in the European Parliament when she was alone again, deliberately working to ridicule and undermine her for over a year. By the account in the autobiography, this only ended when the President of the Parliament intervened, threatening to have them withdrawn as being &lt;i&gt;"not fit to represent their country and Parliament in Europe"&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You might think that, around forty years later, a female SNP MP might expect some kind of change to have occurred in attitudes, as with wider society. Women are accepted in a range of jobs, universities are gaining majorities of female students, there are innumerable opportunities and directions for careers. And then, there's Ian Davidson MP.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eilidh has written &lt;a href="http://www.scotsman.com/news/cartoon/eilidh_whiteford_we_need_to_stand_up_to_bully_boy_culture_1_1938114"&gt;a revealing article in the Scotland on Sunday&lt;/a&gt; - I'd urge you to read the full article, but I think this small quote does illustrate the point perfectly:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;"It does not matter that all I had done was disagree with the  committee. In fact what inspired Mr Davidson’s remark is utterly  irrelevant. There is no action, no misbehaviour that justifies the  threat or act of “a doing”. We hear too often of women being told they  were “asking for it” in justification for intimidation or violence. I  never expected to hear that from an MP in Parliament.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;But this is  not simply an issue of aggression towards woman; it’s about a culture of  intimidation and bullying affecting men and women that seems to  flourish with impunity in the Westminster world."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The tragedy is that it's primarily through this Westminster lens that the viewing population sees politics and politicians. They see argument, they see confrontation; they see crowds of boorish suits moaning a weary "hear hear". And they switch off. They say "that's not for me". &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;They don't see a politician arguing the case with a housing association, trying to help a vulnerable tenant. They don't see someone working on a committee, trying to improve a policy that will help improve children's health. They don't see the joy that is presenting prizes to year groups of school students, with the hope that you can encourage them in that tiny second as you shake their hand. They don't know what a privilege it is to be invited into so many lives and homes, to meet with groups and organisations and offer what help you can.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The work of politics should never be that yah boo nonsense that men excel at and so many women hate. More women should be in politics for the fantastic difference they can make every day.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/feeds/7772867992931110571/comments/default" title="Post Comments"/>
    <link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=4611157281567615666&amp;postID=7772867992931110571" title="3 Comments"/>
    <link rel="edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.blogger.com/feeds/4611157281567615666/posts/default/7772867992931110571"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bellgrovebelle.blogspot.com/2011/11/on-being-woman-in-politics.html" title="On being a woman in politics"/>
    <author>
      <name>BellgroveBelle</name>
      <uri>http://www.blogger.com/profile/02011429534354744636</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail" width="16" height="16" src="https://img1.blogblog.com/img/b16-rounded.gif"/>
    </author>
    <thr:total>3</thr:total>
  </entry>
</feed>
